<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
			
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05619-014::ACTWU's Local 169 Records)//EN">KCL05619-014.xml</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to ACTWU's Local 169 Records<date/></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">ACTWU's Local 169 Records</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by O. Familoni</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
				<date>July 01, 2010</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by MarcEdit, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>July 01, 2010</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to ACTWU's Local 169 Records,<lb/><date type="inclusive" encodinganalog="245$g"> 1923-2003</date></titleproper>
			<num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc2796">Collection Number: 5619/014</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives <lb/>Cornell University Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/><extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/><extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref><lb/></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>March 08, 2010</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Randall Miles, July 2010</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2010 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245">ACTWU's Local 169 Records, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">1923-2003</unitdate></unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5619/014</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Local 169 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname><lb/>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. Local 169 (New York, N.Y.)</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">4 linear feet</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Correspondence, reports, publications.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">This collection consists of collective bargaining agreements, convention proceedings, meeting minutes, publications, 
				and files from the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, Local 169, and the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union, Local 169.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>, <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">Spanish</language>, and <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">Yiddish</language></langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a2" altrender="organization">ACWA/ACTWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
			<p>The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City 
				in 1914 as a breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in the tailors’ and cutters’ locals were the core of the 
				seceding group, which advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW’s craft organization, which they saw as conservative 
				and timid. Their diverging views had come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition 
				called the strike against the UGW leadership’s advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an arbitration system to 
				settle disputes. </p>
			<p>Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of 
				immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. 
				Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not change for 
				many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards’ by-laws having 
				precedence over those of locals.</p>
			<p>Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a 
				distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities 
				and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost 
				housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants.</p>
			<p>Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative 
				in Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, 
				and at the same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, 
				Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In order to help management meet the 
				competition of non-union firms, the union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the official publication of the 
				union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management. </p>
			<p>Hillman also understood the importance of labor’s involvement in national affairs and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the 
				Conference for Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although many members and officers were Socialists, the union 
				stopped short of officially endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were firmly curbed. Hillman’s participation in 
				national affairs and politics became prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D. Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. 
				He also served on the board of the National Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor’s Non Partisan League. 
				He was also named associate director of the Office of Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the war effort. 
				Hillman’s prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union, which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable.</p>
			<p>During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), 
				but the union’s political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms 
				relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that would lead to 
				the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing goods 
				steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union 
				efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the 
				Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such 
				as the Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union’s existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic 
				industry was sealed in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge 
				with the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile 
				Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a troubled union.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union --Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union. Local 169 (New York, N.Y.) --Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America --Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America. Local 169 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union --Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees --Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees. Local 169 (New York, N.Y.)--Archives</corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">UNITE HERE (Organization) --Archives</corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects:</head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Collective bargaining--Clothing industry--New York (State)</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers--Labor unions--New York (State)</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing trade--New York (State)</subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">Records</genreform>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655" source="aat">Correspondence</genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>ACTWU's Local 169 Records #5619/014. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<relatedmaterial>
			<head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
			<p>Related collections:<lb/>
				<extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619.html">
					5619: Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America</extref><lb/>
				All other 5619 collections, and <lb/>
					6000/016: UNITE's Local 169. Green &amp; Grocery Campaign files</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: A. Levine Incorporation - Ashland Uniform Company</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1939/1946">1939-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Bell Laundry - Buriable Pants Company</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933/1944">1933-1944</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: C and L Overall Company - Dun Rite Laundry Company</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1946">1937-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Edmund Muschel - Fur Fit Undergarment Incorporation</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1946">1941-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: General Sportwear Manufacturing Company - Hi Line Company Incorporated</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1946">1941-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: I. Schwartz and Son - Infant and Juvenile Manufacturers Association Incorporated</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1953">1937-1953</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: J.H Harris Corporation - Juvenile Guild Incorporation</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938/1946">1938-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Kaplan Janis Company - Lou Hy Sportswear Company</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1946">1937-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: M.E Greenfield Company - Mills Uniform Corporation0</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1954">1937-1954</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: National Family Laundry Incorporation - Oxford Pants Company</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1946">1937-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: P. Lichtment and Son Company - Pyramid Knitwear Company Incorporated</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1946">1937-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">12</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Queen Mary Togs Incorporated - Rubin Sportwear Incorporated</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1947">1937-1947</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: S and I Novelty Company Incorporated - Stanley Togs</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1946">1937-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Star Novelty Company Incorporated - Sweeney Block and Company Incorporated</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1946">1940-1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: T and S Sportswear Company Incorporated - Tom Tinochiano</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1947">1941-1947</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Uniform Manufacturer's Exchange Incorporated - White Duck Management Company</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1947">1937-1947</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle>Agreement: Youth Merit Wear Incorporated - Zone Novelty Company Incorporated</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945/1947">1945-1947</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unittitle>Mr. Bernstein - Miscellaneous</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unittitle>Miscellaneous Union Documents</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1950">1937-1950</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>ACWA Local 169</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Mostly Photographs</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unittitle>ACWA 23rd Biennial Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle>Unsigned Agreements</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1937/1953">1937-1953</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle>Mr. Thomas Flavell  (folder 1 of 2)</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Financial information for appealing companies in the Sweater and Knit Swimwear industry in Puerto Rico</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle>Mr. Thomas Flavell (folder 2 of 2)</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle>Puerto Rico: Additional statistical tables</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1968">1968</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>April</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977/2003">1977-2003</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle>Minute Book</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1923/1926">1923-1926</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Language: Yiddish</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unittitle>Local 169 A.C.W.A Minute Book</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1965">1953-1965</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unittitle>Executive Council Manual</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1955">1953-1955</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>Sick Benefit Minute Book</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1950">1940-1950</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unittitle>Minute Book</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1926/1932">1926-1932</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Language: Yiddish</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle>Executive Council Manual</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1950">1947-1950</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unittitle>Executive Council Recording Book</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936/1941">1936-1941</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle>Proceedings: Nineteenth Biennial Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1976">1976</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Textile Workers of America</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle>Proceedings: Merger Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1976">1976</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers; Washington D.C</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle>The United States Department of Labor</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Author: James P. Mitchell (secretary)</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle>How do Labor and Schools work together?</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>National Citizens Council for Better Schools</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle>"this union cause"</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>An illustrated history of Labor Unions in America</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unittitle>Special Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1976">1976</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Convention Proceedings</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unittitle>50th Anniversary Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>General Executive Board Report and Convention Proceedings; (2 copies)</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle>20th Biennial Convention (General Executive Board Report and Proceeding)</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>May 21-25</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unittitle>Resolutions: 23rd Biennial Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>May 14th</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle>18th Biennial Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>May 12-16; (4 copies)</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unittitle>20th Biennial Convention (General Executive Board Report)</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>2 copies</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">12</container>
					<unittitle>Correspondence</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">13</container>
					<unittitle>Amalgamated Mimeo Handbook</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Prepared by Barbara Wertheimer; Drawings by Frank Hanley</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">14</container>
					<unittitle>Clippings and Memo of Local 169's Past History</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942/1970">1942-1970</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">15</container>
					<unittitle>Report of the General Executive Board: 2nd Constitutional Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1981">1981</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>June 1-5</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">16</container>
					<unittitle>Textile Union Workers Union of America Volunteer Organizing Program</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">17</container>
					<unittitle>The Sweater and Knit Swimwear Industry in Puerto Rico</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>March</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">18</container>
					<unittitle>Mr. Bernstein Certificate of Membership to the 66 club</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">19</container>
					<unittitle>Immigration Law Material</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Language: English and Spanish</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">20</container>
					<unittitle>Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union Substance Abuse Manual</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">21</container>
					<unittitle>Estado Libre Asociado de Puerto Rico</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1985">1985</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Oficina de Asuntos Laborales (OAL); Language: English and Spanish</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">22</container>
					<unittitle>AFL-CIO Miscellaneous pamphlets</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">23</container>
					<unittitle>The Values We Cherish</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1963">1963</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Author: Walter P. Reuther</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">24</container>
					<unittitle>Convention Proceedings: 1st Constitutional Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>September 25-29</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">25</container>
					<unittitle>Pamphlets on Health Care for Senior Citizens</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1943/1963">1943-1963</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">26</container>
					<unittitle>The Sidney Hillman Foundation Incorporated: Fifteen Year Report</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948/1963">1948-1963</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">27</container>
					<unittitle>Profile of a Union</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">28</container>
					<unittitle>Handbook for Industry Committee Members</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1965">1965</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>United States Department of Labor</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">29</container>
					<unittitle>Annual Awards Celebration</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>New York Committee for Occupational Safety and Health</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">30</container>
					<unittitle>Retired and Remembered</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">31</container>
					<unittitle>The Story of a Bank: The Amalgamated Bank of New York</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1923/1963">1923-1963</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">32</container>
					<unittitle>Report of the General Executive Board: 1st Constitutional Convention</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>September 25-29</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">33</container>
					<unittitle>War Labor Board Decisions</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944/1945">1944-1945</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">34</container>
					<unittitle>Executive Summary: The Antitrust Controversy</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>February</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">35</container>
					<unittitle>Miscellaneous</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">36</container>
					<unittitle>Blue Shield in New York City: a report and program</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p> New York Labor-Management Council of Health and Welfare Plans, Incorporated</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">37</container>
					<unittitle> Songbook Compilation of Rhythm and Music from all over the World</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Compiler: Edith Berkowitz; Language: English and Spanish</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
