<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05406mf::Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05406mf</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on
                        Microfilm<date> 1910</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on
                    Microfilm</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 11, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 11,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20231219">12/19/2023</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on
                Microfilm</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5406 mf</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
                        Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, May 08, 2014</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Switchmen's Union of North
                America Arbitration on Microfilm, 1910
            </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1910</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5406 mf</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Switchmen's Union of North
                    America (SUNA)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">3 microfilm reels</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents), microfilm.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Arbitration proceedings in the matter of the Chicago and
                Eastern Illinois Railroad (Chicago Switching District); Chicago Great Western
                Railroad (System, except Twin Cities), Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railway
                (System, except Inver Grove); Chicago Terminal Transfer Railroad (System); Lake
                Shore and Michigan Southern Railway (Specified Yards); Michigan Central Railroad
                (West of Detroit River); Pere Marquette Railroad (System); Wisconsin Central Railway
                (Chicago Switching District); and Switchmen's Union of North America, representing
                the Yardmen. March 4, 1910.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.33 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>In 1898 Congress passed the Erdman Act which provided for the mediation and
                arbitration of disputes in the railroad industry which involved the operating
                brotherhoods, telegraphers and switchmen. Within a year after its adoption the
                switchmen, represented by the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, invoked the law,
                which resulted in the complete failure because its principles were repudiated by the
                leading railroad companies involved. </p>
            <p>The Act provided that when a controversy over rates of pay, working conditions or
                grievances arose, which could not be solved at the local level, a grand officer of
                the national organization would take the matter up with the railroads involved. If
                he failed to secure a settlement the matter was to be referred to the employees for
                a strike vote. If they voted to strike, a further effort was to be made by the
                national officer and the road to negotiate a settlement. If this failed either party
                could apply to the mediators designated in the Erdman Act for the use of their good
                offices to avert the strike. If the mediator was unable to get the parties to agree,
                he was authorized to try to get an agreement to submit the dispute to arbitration. </p>
            <p>The next attempt to use the Erdman Act's procedures did not come until 1996, but by
                the end of 1909 24 controversies had been submitted to the mediators. These were
                settled by the mediators without resort to arbitration in all but four cases. It was
                in 1906 that the railroad unions began what has been called the "concerted movement"
                as a method of handling negotiations. Under this plan the railroads in a given
                territory were served with a notice that the union desired to revise the agreements,
                and a committee of managers and a committee representing the employees met for this
                purpose. The firemen have been given credit for starting the second "concerted
                movement" to raise wages and improve working conditions in 1910, undoubtedly because
                26,000 men and 110,000 miles of railroad were involved, but the Switchmen's
                agreement to submit the issues to arbitration was signed on January 19, 1910 while
                that of the firemen was not signed until March 25, 1910. </p>
            <p>The agreement listed several issues which were to be decided by the arbitration
                board. It was also agreed that the award would be binding on both parties, the men
                would not resign, nor the employer discharge anyone for a period of three months
                after the award was made because they were not satisfied with the conditions of the
                award. </p>
            <p>The Board was composed of Carl R. Gray of St. Louis, Missouri, who represented the
                employers, S. E. Heberling of Moriority, New Mexico, represented the employees and
                S. S. Gregory was selected as the neutral chairman. </p>
            <p>Hearings were held in Chicago beginning on March 4, 1910. The first issue was a six
                cent raise for the switchmen. The following rates of pay were requested for all men
                on Chicago lines. </p>
            <p>Day foremen $.41 per hour </p>
            <p>Night foremen $.43 per hour </p>
            <p>Day helpers $.38 per hour </p>
            <p>Night helpers $.40 per hour </p>
            <p>In addition all the switch tenders, tower men and assistant yardmasters who were
                receiving less than this should be raised to the same scale as that of the helpers,
                anyone receiving more than this should have his rate increased accordingly. The
                switchmen based their request upon the increase in the cost of living which they
                estimated to be 50%; while the companies maintained that the cost of living was not
                a standard to be used in seating wage rates. </p>
            <p>The switchmen insisted that they were entitled to a wage increase because their
                efficiency had risen as a result of the improved equipment, such as the larger
                engines and modern cars which had been introduced. They also maintained that the
                heavier engines and improved equipment increased the risk in an occupation already
                very hazardous. </p>
            <p>The companies countered this by insisting the new equipment was not as hazardous, and
                accidents were not as frequent. If the switchmen's wages were raised, other
                employees would also demand increases, which the companies could not afford to pay,
                unless railroad rates were increased, which they could not do without permission. In
                addition, many roads were in the hands of receivers and wage increases would result
                in more receiverships. </p>
            <p>In its report issued on March 22, 1910 the Board discussed each of these issues and
                awarded a three cent increase, retroactive to February 10, 1910. </p>
            <p>In 1906 Switchmen's joined with the American Federation of Labor. SUNA was one of the
                first unions that started the Railway Labor Excutives' Association in 1926. They
                tried to start a merger of train movement unions in 1929 with the Brotherhood of
                Railroad Trainmen and the Order of Railway Conductors, but, were unsuccessful. In
                1935 SUNA joined with the Canadian Labour Congress. </p>
            <p>In 1950 the government seized the railroads after a series of disputes between the
                railroads and yard employees in connection with the 40-hour week. On June 15, 1950
                the Railway labor Act Emergency Board ruled in favor of the 40-hour basic work week,
                overtime pay for hours in excess of 40, and other improvements. </p>
            <p>The Switchmen's Union of North America had 275 lodges and 12,000 members in the
                United States and Canada by 1969. That year it combined with the Brotherhood of
                Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen and Order of
                Railway Conductors and Brakemen to form the United Transportation Union.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>Arbitration proceedings in the matter of the Chicago and Eastern Illinois Railroad
                (Chicago Switching District); Chicago Great Western Railroad (System, except Twin
                Cities), Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railway (System, except Inver Grove);
                Chicago Terminal Transfer Railroad (System); Lake Shore and Michigan Southern
                Railway (Specified Yards); Michigan Central Railroad (West of Detroit River); Pere
                Marquette Railroad (System); Wisconsin Central Railway (Chicago Switching District);
                and Switchmen's Union of North America, representing the Yardmen. March 4, 1910.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Switchmen's Union of North America. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Chicago &amp; Eastern Illinois Railroad Company. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions --
                    Illinois. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Collective labor agreements -- Railroads --
                    Illinois. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Collective bargaining -- Railroads -- Illinois. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Wages -- Railroads -- Illinois. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>Switchmen's Union of North America Arbitration on Microfilm #5406 mf. Kheel
                    Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
                    Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            
            <p>Related Collections:
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05034.html"> 5034:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05034mb.html"> 5034 MB:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Memorabilia</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05034p.html"> 5034 P:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Photographs</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05084.html"> 5084:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05405mf.html"> 5405 mf:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Constitutions on Microfilm</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05447.html"> 5447:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Unification Minutes and Convention
                    Proceedings</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05556.html"> 5556:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Additional Records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05556av.html"> 5556 AV:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Audio-Visual Materials</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05590.html"> 5590:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Lake Shore Lodge 55 Membership
                    Registers</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05613.html"> 5613:
                    Switchmen's Union of North America Oakland Lodge 158 Meeting Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05630.html"> 5630: W.B.
                    Meyers Papers</extref>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Record Group DB-12: Switchmen's Union of N.A. -
                        Arbitration, 1910</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1910">1910</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>reel 1 of 3 - negative</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Record Group DB-12: Switchmen's Union of N.A. -
                        Arbitration, 1910</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1910">1910</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>reel 2 of 3 - negative</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Record Group DB-12: Switchmen's Union of N.A. -
                        Arbitration, 1910</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1910">1910</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>reel 3 of 3 - negative</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>