<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
            publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL04345::W. Duane Evans Collections.)//EN"
            >KCL04345</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the W. Duane Evans Collections<date>
                    1939-1969</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Evans, W. Duane,  Collections</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by M. Clark</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 07, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 07,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the W. Duane Evans Collections<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: /4345</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
                            >kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center"
                            >http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>M. Clark, November 08, 2016</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>&#169; 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">W. Duane Evans Collections,
                    <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1939-1969</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">/4345</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Evans, W. Duane</persname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Kheel Center for
                    Labor-Management Documentation and Archives</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">11 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Papers (documents) .</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Papers mostly on the subject of statistics. <lb/> W. Duane
                Evans' material on income, economic growth, and productivity.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>, <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="fre">French</language>, <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="ita">Italian</language>, <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC
 041" langcode="por">Portuguese</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a4" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
            <p>Professor Evans was born on June 10, 1909, at Watertown, New York, the son of a
                Presbyterian minister who later became a chaplain in the U.S. Army. He studied
                chemical engineering at Clarkson College, receiving his Bachelor of Science degree
                in 1930. </p>
            <p>He began his career as an engineer at the National Bureau of Standards in Washington.
                However, as the federal government moved to deal with the social and economic
                problems of the thirties, he became involved with the research activities of a
                variety of agencies including the National Recovery Administration, the Works
                Progress Administration, the Department of Justice, and ultimately, in 1939, the
                U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. </p>
            <p>In addition to his formal duties, he found time in a busy schedule to teach and write
                on statistical techniques and the application of mathematics to economic problems.
                He made substantial contributions to the statistical theory of sampling. </p>
            <p>His affiliations and honors from the 1940s on indicate the scope and quality of his
                efforts. He served the Bureau of Labor Statistics as chief of the Productivity and
                Technological Development Division, as chief of the Division of Interindustry
                Economics, as chief economist, chief statistician and, after 1962, as associate
                commissioner. He was on the faculty of the American University from 1947 to 1964 as
                adjunct professor of economics, on the faculty of the U.S. Department of Agriculture
                Graduate School from 1940 to 1964, and on the Faculty of Economic and Political
                Science, Cambridge University, during 1953-54. He served as a consultant to the
                Anglo-American Productivity Council and was a member of the U.S. delegation,
                International Statistical Institute, in Rome in 1953, in Rio de Janeiro in 1955, in
                Stockholm in 1957, in Tokyo in 1960, and in Ottawa in 1963. He received the
                Rockefeller Public Service Award in 1953 and the award for Distinguished Service,
                U.S. Department of Labor, in 1953. Professor Evans was a fellow of the Washington
                Academy of Sciences, the American Statistical Association, and the A. A. A. S.; he
                was a member of the American Economic Association, the Econometric Society, and the
                Conference on Research in Income and Wealth. He published numerous articles and
                reports on input-output data and projections, on productivity and the effects of
                technological change, and on statistical methodology. The interindustry study of the
                U.S. economy for 1947, done with Marvin Hoffenberg, is a model for later search in
                this area. </p>
            <p>In 1964 Professor Evans retired from U.S. government service and joined the faculty
                of Cornell University with a joint appointment in the New York State School of
                Industrial and Labor Relations and the Department of Economics in the College of
                Arts and Sciences. He taught courses in mathematical economics for the Department of
                Economics and courses in statistics for ILR. He brought to bear on his teaching the
                wealth of experience that he had gained in working for the Bureau of Labor
                Statistics and attempted to instill in his students a feeling for the valuable
                contributions that can result from the judicious use of statistical methods in
                practical problems. His presentations were enhanced by a wry sense of humor. He was
                most helpful to graduate students in all stages of their training and was especially
                helpful to those whose backgrounds in statistics and mathematics were deficient. He
                was a valuable member of many ILR committees, especially the Graduate Committee, in
                which he served several terms as chairman. He contributed significantly to
                recruitment and to the development of academic programs in the Department of
                Economics.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Evans, W. Duane (Wilmoth Duane), 1909-1974 </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation
                    and Archives </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State School of Industrial and Labor
                    Relations --Faculty. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Papers (documents). </genreform>
            </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>W. Duane Evans Collections #/4345. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8"><extref
                            href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/3029:"> /3029: W.
                            Duane Evans Papers 1939-1966</extref></unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1939/1966">1939-1966</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>9 linear feet. W. Duane Evans' material on income, economic growth, and
                        productivity.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9"><extref
                            href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/3091:"> /3091: W.
                            Duane Evans Additional Papers 1952-1969</extref></unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952/1969">1952-1969</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>2 linear feet. Papers mostly on the subject of statistics.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
