<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
	<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
		<eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-170::ILGWU. People v. Benedict Macri. Legal transcripts and scrapbook,)//EN">KCL05780-170</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU. People v. Benedict Macri. Legal transcripts and
						scrapbook,<date>1949-1957.</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">ILGWU. People v. Benedict Macri. Legal transcripts and
					scrapbook,</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
					University Library</publisher>
				<date>July 2011</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by MarcEdit, Ead McTaggart, and Cheryl Beredo, <date>July
					2011</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	<revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU. People V. Benedict Macri. Legal Transcripts And
					Scrapbook,<date encodinganalog="245$f" type="inclusive">1949-1957.</date></titleproper>
			<num id="kc1156" type="kidb_reference_number">Collection Number: 5780/170</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Cornell
				University Library</publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item> Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
						P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
						Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183<extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref></item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Date completed:</label>
					<item>1999</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Casey Westerman, 2003Cheryl Beredo, July 2011</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2011 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library</date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			
			<unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245" label="Title:">ILGWU. People v. Benedict Macri
				Legal transcripts and scrapbook, 1949-1957.</unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245" type="inclusive">1949-1957.</unitdate>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/170</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:"><corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">International Ladies'
					Garment Workers' Union.</corpname></origination>
			<physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">1 linear foot</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records, scrapbook.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
				Archives, Cornell University Library</repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Collection consists of materials pertaining to the 1949
				murder of William Lurye, an organizer for the ILGWU, and the 1951 trial of Benedict
				Macri, who was acquitted of the crime. Documents include a scrapbook of news
				clippings on the case, a wanted poster for the fugitive suspect John Giusto, and the
				court transcript of Macri's trial.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language></langmaterial>
		<physdesc><extent>1 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			
			<p>The International Ladies’ Garment Workers’ Union was founded in New York City in 1900
				by mostly Socialist immigrant workers who sought to unite the various crafts in the
				growing women’s garment industry. The union soon reflected changes in the sector and
				rapidly organized thousands of unskilled and semi-skilled women, mostly Jewish and
				Italian young immigrants. Exemplifying the “new unionism,” the ILGWU led two of the
				most widespread and best-known industrial strikes of the early Twentieth Century:
				the shirtwaist makers’ strike of 1909 in New York City and the cloak makers’ strike
				of 1910 in Chicago. The union also tried to adapt to the fragmented and unstable
				nature of the industry. It adopted the “protocol of peace,” a system of industrial
				relations that attempted to ensure stability and limit strikes and production
				disruption by providing for an arbitration system to resolve disputes.</p>
			<p>The ILGWU exemplified the European-style social unionism of its founding members.
				They pursued bread and butter issues but provided educational opportunities,
				benefits, and social programs to union members as well. In 1919, the ILGWU became
				the first American union to negotiate an unemployment compensation fund that was
				contributed to by its employers. The ILGWU also pioneered in the establishment of an
				extremely progressive health care program for its members which included not only
				regional Union Health Centers but also a resort for union workers, known as Unity
				House. The Union also had an imaginative and pioneering Education Department which
				not only trained workers in traditional union techniques, but provided courses in
				citizenship and the English language.</p>
			<p>David Dubinsky, an immigrant from Belarus who came to the US in 1911, provided strong
				leadership that led to unprecedented growth in the union during his presidency from
				1932 to 1966. He led the union through successful internal anti-communist struggles,
				built on the ascendancy of industrial unionism by encouraging the formation of the
				Committee for Industrial Organization, and helped the union become an important
				political force in New York City and state politics, and in the national Democratic
				Party and Liberal Party as well.</p>
			<p>In the period following the Second World War, the union suffered a decline in
				membership as manufacturers avoided unionization and took advantage of less
				expensive labor by moving shops from the urban centers in the northeast to the
				south, and later abroad. The ethnic and racial character of the ILGWU also changed
				as European immigrants were supplanted by Asians, Latin Americans, African-
				Americans, and immigrants from the Caribbean.</p>
			<p>In July 1995 the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union
				(ACTWU) at a joint convention, forming UNITE (Union of Needletrades, Industrial and
				Textile Employees). At the time the new union had a membership of about 250,000 in
				the United States, Canada, and Puerto Rico. </p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			
			<p>Collection consists of materials pertaining to the 1949 murder of William Lurye, an
				organizer for the ILGWU, and the 1951 trial of Benedict Macri, who was acquitted of
				the crime. Documents include a scrapbook of news clippings on the case, a wanted
				poster for the fugitive suspect John Giusto, and the court transcript of Macri's
				trial.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			
			<controlaccess>
				
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110">International Ladies' Garment Workers'
					Union.</corpname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Giusto, John. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Lurye, William. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Macri, Benedict. </persname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
				</corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Women's clothing industry--United
					States.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions--Clothing workers--United
					States.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers--United States.</subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Industrial relations--United States.</subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				
				</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			
			<accessrestrict>
				
				<p>The ILGWU Records, except for publications and materials produced for
					publication, are restricted. Materials created prior to twenty years from the
					current date are open to researchers only with prior written permission from the
					Director of the Kheel Center; materials created during the past twenty-years are
					closed; the minutes of the General Executive Board are closed. For more
					information contact the Kheel Center.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<prefercite>
				
				<p>ILGWU. People v. Benedict Macri. Legal transcripts and scrapbook. 5780/170. Kheel
					Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Martin P. Catherwood
					Library, Cornell University.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<relatedmaterial>
			
			<p>5780. IGLWU records</p>
			<p>5780/127. ILGWU. America's Next Great Designer Award. Scrapbooks</p>
			<p>5780/128. ILGWU. Women's Wear Daily. Scrapbooks</p>
			<p>5780/160. ILGWU. Scrapbooks</p>
			<p>5780/160mf. ILGWU. American Labor Party news article scrapbook. Microfilm</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		<odd type="notes">
			
			<p>"Permanent deposit"</p>
		</odd>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
					<container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle>Scrapbook: Lurye Case. </unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1949/1957" type="inclusive">1949-1957</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains news clippings pertaining to William Lurye's murder and the trial of
						Benedict Macri. May 10, 1949 - November 19, 1957.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
					<container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle>Poster: New York City Police Department, Detective Division Circular
						No. 3,</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>June 28, 1949. Wanted for Homicide: John Giusto for murder of William Lurye.
					</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
					<container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle>Report of the trial of Benedict Macri, indicted for the murder of
						William Lurye</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Court of General Sessions of the County of New York, New York, Oct. 4-29,
						1951. Typescript volume. October 4-18, 1951. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
					<container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle>Report of the trial of Benedict Macri, indicted for the murder of
						William Lurye</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Court of General Sessions of the County of New York, New York, Oct. 4-29,
						1951. Typescript volume. October 19-29, 1951. </p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>