<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
			publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06111mf::FBI Confidential
Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm.)//EN"
			>KCL06111mf</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm<date> 1938-1958</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
				<date>February 23, 2016</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>February 23, 2016</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 6111 mf</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183> <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
							>kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, September 26, 2012</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Randall Miles, February 23, 2016</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>&#169; 2016 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1938-1958</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">6111 mf</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">15 microfilm reels</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records, microfilm.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Leab, Daniel J. </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Lester, Robert. </persname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. Federal Bureau of Investigation-- Archives. </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">University Publications of America (Firm) </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects: </head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Motion picture industry--Political aspects--United States--History--Sources. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Communism--United States--1917---Sources. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Blacklisting of entertainers--United States--History--Sources.</subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Records </genreform>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Microfilm</genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>FBI Confidential Files on Communist Activity in the Entertainment Industry and FBI Surveillance Files on Hollywood on Microfilm #6111 mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<relatedmaterial>
			<head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
			<p>Related Collections:<lb/>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05898mf.html"> 5898 mf: FBI Files on Highlander Folk School on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06079mf.html"> 6079 mf: FBI Files on A. Philip Randolph on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06082mf.html"> 6082 mf: FBI Files on Sacco and Vanzetti on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06106mf.html"> 6106 mf: FBI Files on John L. Lewis on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
			</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link8">Correspondence - September 1942-March 1945.</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">1</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link9">Volume 1. </unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942/1943">1942-1943</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p> September 1942-July 1943. 307 pp.: List of radical artists, writers, actors, and musicians; Communist influence in labor unions; Harry Carlisle; Communist front organizations and activities; LATSE; films of a propaganda nature;
							Mission to Moscow; writers' unions; establishment of American Legion Union Post [Cinema Post #561]. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">1</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link10">Volume 2.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1943/1944">1943-1944</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p> July 1943-April 1944. 228 pp.: Mission to Moscow; films of a propaganda nature; Warner Brothers Pictures; Cinema Post #561; Northwest Section (Movie Industry), Los Angeles County Communist Party organization and membership list;
							Screen Writers Guild; AFL and independent unions; history of Communist infiltration; Communist front organizations; Hollywood Democratic Committee.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">1</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link11">Volume 3. </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1944 cont.-August 1944. 283 pp.: Propaganda in films; Motion Picture Labor Committee for Political Action; Northwest Section (Movie Industry), Los Angeles County Communist Party organization and membership list; history of
							Communist infiltration; Mikhail Kalatozov; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; League of American Writers; Communist and Communist-front organizations' membership subdivided into producers, directors, writers, actors and actresses,
							labor, and miscellaneous; Hollywood Democratic Committee; OWI activities; War Activities Committee-OWI film productions; Motion Picture Alliance for the Preservation of American Ideals; Cinema Post #561.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">1</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link12">Volume 4. </unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944/1945">1944-1945</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1944-March 1945. 180 pp.: History of Communist Infiltration; Communist Political Association activities; Hollywood Democratic Committee; AFL Political Action Committee activities; Cecil B. DeMille; Communist infiltration of
							RKO Radio Pictures@CIO Political Action Committee; CSU; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; strike activities; Herbert Sorrell.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link13">Correspondence - February 1945-August 1947. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">2</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link14">Volume 5. </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>February 1945-June 1945. 89 pp.: Soviet request for 35mm film; The Master Race; propaganda in films; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; Hollywood Democratic Committee; OWI activities; Council of Hollywood Guilds and Unions; strike
							activities; Herbert Sorrell; Communist Political Association; Motion Picture Alliance; screen guilds; HICCASP; CSU.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">2</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link15">Volume 6. </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1945 cont. 86 pp.: Report on Soviet influence and propaganda efforts in Hollywood. @Volume 7. June 1945 cont.-September 1945. 101 pp.: HUAC investigations; Actors' Laboratory; Motion Picture Alliance; CSU-IATSE jurisdictional
							strike; IATSE [AFL]; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; ICCASP; Warner Brothers Pictures studio riot; Herbert Sorrell. @Volume 8. November 1945-May 1947. 270 pp.: CSU jurisdictional strikes; IATSE [AFL]; AFL strike call; Helen Gahagan
							Douglas; American Youth for Democracy; Frank Sinatra; Herbert Sorrell; HUAC investigations; Tenney Committee investigations; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; HICCASP; strike activities; International Film and Radio Guild; Pale
							Robeson and the National Win-the-Peace Committee; Motion Picture Alliance; Communist political and election activities; labor violence; PCA; International Labor Organization (ILO) support of CSU; People's Educational Center. @Volume
							9. May 1947 cont.-August 1947. 127 pp. [Documents in this file are in reverse chronological order]: House Un-American Activities Committee investigations; V.J. Jerome; Henry Wallace; CSU; name checks and Communist party members;
							Eric Johnston and the Motion Picture Association; PCA, Hollywood Chapter; Motion Picture Alliance. @Volume 10. August 1947 cont. 252 pp.: Report on the history, prominent individuals, and organization of Communist infiltration.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">2</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link16">Volume 7. </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1945 cont.-September 1945. 101 pp.: HUAC investigations; Actors' Laboratory; Motion Picture Alliance; CSU- IATSE jurisdictional strike; IATSE [AFL]; Hollywood Writers Mobilization; ICCASP; Warner Brothers Pictures studio riot;
							Herbert Sorrell.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">2</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link17">Volume 8. </unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1945/1947">1945-1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1945-May 1947. 270 pp.: CSU jurisdictional strikes; IATSE [AFL]; AFL strike call; Helen Gahagan Douglas; American Youth for Democracy; Frank Sinatra; Herbert Sorrell; HUAC investigations; Tenney Committee investigations;
							Hollywood Writers Mobilization; HICCASP; strike activities; International Film and Radio Guild; Pale Robeson and the National Win-the-Peace Committee; Motion Picture Alliance; Communist political and election activities; labor
							violence; PCA; International Labor Organization (ILO) support of CSU; People's Educational Center.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">2</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link18">Volume 9. </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>May 1947 cont.-August 1947. 127 pp. [Documents in this file are in reverse chronological order]: House Un-American Activities Committee investigations; V.J. Jerome; Henry Wallace; CSU; name checks and Communist party members; Eric
							Johnston and the Motion Picture Association; PCA, Hollywood Chapter; Motion Picture Alliance.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">2</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link19">Volume 10. </unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>August 1947 cont. 252 pp.: Report on the history, prominent individuals, and organization of Communist infiltration.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">3</container>
					<unittitle id="link20">Correspondence - August 1947 cont.-January 1948. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">3</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link21">Volume 11.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>August 1947 cont.-October 1947. 271 pp.: Communist propaganda pamphlet Is Communism Un-American?; Communist industrial recruiting; Industrial Subsection, Hollywood Section, Los Angeles Communist Party; trials of studio strikers; The
							American Crime; name checks; CSU; strikes; HUAC investigations; propaganda in films; FBI policy on previewing films for propaganda content; Ronald Reagan; Eric Johnston and the Motion Picture Association; Gary Cooper.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">3</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link22">Volume 12.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1947 cont.-November 1947. 186 pp.: History of infiltration; name checks for HUAC; HUAC Washington hearings; Charles Chaplin; Senator Claude Pepper; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the
							HUAC hearings; John Garfield; Communist efforts to thwart HUAC investigations; FBI previewing of films for propaganda content; John Garfield; Paul Draper; All My Sons; Arthur Miller; PCA activities opposing the HUAC hearings; Louis
							B. Mayer.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">3</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link23">Volume 13.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1947 cont. 93 pp.: Efforts to defend subpoenaed "Unfriendly 19"; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; Edward G. Robinson; testimony before HUAC; Martin Popper.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">3</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link24">Volume 14.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1947 cont. 111 pp.: HUAC Washington hearings and "Unfriendly 19;" National Lawyers Guild; Tenney Committee hearings; Communist influence in New York motion picture industry; Bartley S. Crum; surveillance of and informant
							reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; Martin Popper; Screen Writers Guild.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">3</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link25">Volume 15.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1948">1947-1948</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1947-January 1948. 320 pp.: Committee for the First Amendment; efforts to support subpoenaed "Unfriendly 19"; surveillance of and informant reports on Hollywood persons involved in the HUAC hearings; Ira Gershwins; Max
							Lowenthal; Martin Popper and National Lawyers Guild activities; Bartley C. Crum; Eric Johnston; John Garfield; wiretaps; American Writers Association; PCA; Hollywood "purge"; reactions to the HUAC hearings; indictment of Hollywood
							"10"; International Motion Picture Committee.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">4</container>
					<unittitle id="link26">Correspondence - December 1947-April 1950. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">4</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link27">Volume 16.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1947/1948">1947-1948</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>December 1947-May 1948. 296 pp.: People's Educational Center; PCA; screen guilds; Eric Johnston and Motion Picture Producers Committee; FBI previewing of alleged propaganda films; microphone surveillance of Benjamin Margolis; Motion
							Picture Association; "Hollywood 10"; Actors' Laboratory; Committee of 1000; Lynn [Lin] Root; New York theater investigations; Freedom From Fear Committee; labor situation in Hollywood; Senator Claude Peppers; Screen Writers Guild;
							Martin Popper; Thieves' Paradise; Motion Picture Alliance; Civil Rights Congress.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">4</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link28">Volume 17.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948/1949">1948-1949</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>May 1948 cont.-January 1949. 246 pp.: Review of book Hollywood on Trial; Abe Polonsky; wiretaps; Motion Picture Association; Hollywood Section, Los Angeles Communist Party, reorganization; Hollywood ASP and Conference for Peace;
							screen guilds; Sid Benson; Screen Writers Guild; "Hollywood 10"; Dore Schary; French motion picture industry; National Americanism Commission of the American Legion; RKO Radio Pictures studios; Myron C. Fagan; Cinema Educational
							Guild; Lester Cole lawsuit against Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM); John Howard Lawson; Civil Rights Congress.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">4</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link29">Volume 18.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1949 cont.-September 1949. 192 pp.: Cinema Educational Guild; "Hollywood 10" activities; activities calling for abolition of HUAC; Anti-Censorship Committee; Conference on Cultural Freedom and Civil Liberties; New York City
							ASP; social democracy and the theater; Communist infiltration of New York theater; Lester Cole lawsuit against Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer (MGM); Motion Picture Alliance; Western Peace Conference; Hollywood ASP; Civil Rights Congress;
							Communist infiltration in the radio industry; John Howard Lawson; Dalton Trumbo; FBI reviews of films for propaganda content.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">4</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link30">Volume 19.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949/1950">1949-1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>September 1949 cont.-January 1950. 184 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; John Howard Lawson; Dalton Trumbo; Cinema Educational Guild; Myron C. Fagan; Hollywood ASP; Continental Congress for World Peace; screen guilds; Civil Rights
							Congress; Lester Cole; Communist infiltration of the radio-television industry; New York City ASP.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">4</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link31">Volume 20.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1950 cont.-April 1950. 145 pp.: Los Angeles County Communist Party; National ASP; Hollywood ASP; "Hollywood 10" activities; screen guilds; Cinema Educational Guild; Myron C. Fagan; FBI reviews of motion pictures; Cultural and
							Scientific Conference for World Peace; Communist cultural activities; John Howard Lawson; Communist infiltration of legitimate theater; Actors Equity Association; Clifford Odets; Paul Draper; Hollywood ASP on hydrogen bomb issue;
							American-Soviet Friendship Committee; Screen Writers Guild.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">5</container>
					<unittitle id="link32">Correspondence - April 1950 cont.-April 1951. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link33">Volume 21.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1950 cont.-June 1950. 79 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; "US Supreme Court and Hollywood 10"; Hollywood ASP on political issues; Herbert Biberman; Rockwell Kent; Cinema Educational Guild; Myron C. Fagan.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link34">Volume 22.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1950 cont. 58 pp.: Communist infiltration of legitimate theater; People's Drama, Inc.@ Little Theater Groups; Gene Kelly; lists of suspected and Communist theatrical personnel.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link35">Volume 23.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1950 cont.-September 1950. 125 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; Hollywood ASP support of "Hollywood 10;" Herbert K. Sorrell; Screen Writers Guild; Committee for the "Hollywood 10"; Drew Pearson allegations regarding Louis B.
							Mayer and cancellation of HUAC hearings on Hollywood in 1945-1946; National ASP support of "Hollywood 10"; reorganization of Los Angeles County Communist Party apparatus.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link36">Volume 24.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>August 1950-September 1950. 152 pp.: History of Communist infiltration; John Howard Lawson; list of suspected and Communist motion picture industry personnel; Louis B. Mayer; Harry M. Warner; Korean War issue; Hollywood ASP; Screen
							Directors Guild; Screen Writers Guild; Motion Picture Alliance; 1947 HUAC hearings; "Hollywood 10" activities.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link37">Volume 25.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>September 1950 cont.-November 1950. 152 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; Cinema Educational Guild and Myron C. Fagan; Hollywood ASP activities; Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born; Committee to Free the "Hollywood 10"
							activities; Dore Schary; Screen Directors Guild.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link38">Volume 26.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1950 cont. 58 pp.: Cultural Commission, Communisty Party, USA; labor unions; Actors Equity Association; Committee for the Negro in the Arts; People's Drama, Inc.@ FBI reviews of motion pictures; "Hollywood 10" activities;
							international motion picture affairs.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link39">Volume 27.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1950/1951">1950-1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1950 cont.-February 1951. 197 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; Cinema Educational Guild; labor unions; Communist front intellectual and entertainment groups; Committee to Free "Hollywood 10" activities; Hollywood ASP
							activities; Motion Picture Industry Council; screen guilds; anti-Communist activities in Hollywood; Korean War issue; Dore Schary; New Playwrights, Inc. People's Drama, Inc.@ An Enemy of the People; Edward Dmytryk; Los Angeles
							Committee for the Protection of Foreign Born; FBI reviews of motion pictures.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">5</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link40">Volume 28.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>February 1951 cont.-April 1951. 200 pp.: HUAC investigations and hearings; National ASP; Hollywood ASP protest activities; Herbert Biberman; Communist front intellectual and entertainment groups; Gale A. Sondergaard; Motion Picture
							Alliance and John Wayne; Cinema Educational Guild; CSU; Herbert K. Sorrell; Edward Dmytryk; Screen Writers Guild.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">6</container>
					<unittitle id="link41">Correspondence - April 1951 cont.-July 1952. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">6</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link42">Volume 29.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1951 cont.-June 1951. 218 pp.: HUAC investigations and herings; Meta Reis Rosenberg; Los Angeles County Communist Party membership; Cinema Educational Guild; National ASP's anti-HUAC activities; Motion Picture Alliance;
							American Guild of Variety Artists; informant reports; Hollywood Communists in Mexico; Myron C. Fagan. Volume 30. June 1951 cont. 56 pp.: Labor unions; National ASP activities; American Federation of Musicians, Local 802; Communist
							front intellectual and enteratinment groups; American National Theater and Academy; Huac investigations and hearings; Union Films.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">6</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link43">Volume 31.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1951 cont.-September 1951. 155 pp.: HUAC investigations and hearings; Hollywood ASP; Steve Nelson Case and the Civil Rights Congress; Herbert Biberman; John Howard Lawson; Korean War issue.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">6</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link44">Volume 32.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951/1952">1951-1952</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>September 1951 cont.-March 1952. 183 pp.: National Americanism Commission of the American Legion; list of motion pictures containing Communist or "fellow traveler" motion picture personnel; HUAC hearings; John Howard Lawson;
							Hollywood ASP activities; Negro motion picture actors and actresses; Screen Writers Guild; Screen Actors Guild; Motion Picture Alliance; American Legion support of anti-Communist activities in Hollywood; Hollywood Communist Party
							organization [John Reed Division] membership; HUAC Los Angeles Hearings witness list; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">6</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link45">Volume 34.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>March 1952 cont.-July 1952. 155 pp.: HUAC Los Angeles investigations and heraings; witness lists; anti-HUAC activities; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms; American Legion support of anti-Communist activities; Motion
							Picture Association; Paul Jarrico-RKO Radio Pictures dispute; Communist infiltration of New York theater and radio groups; Hollywood ASP activities; National Lawyers Guild, Beverly Hills Chapter; Edward G. Robinson; Hollywood ASP
							Equal Rights Conference for Negroes; Freedom Stage, Inc.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">7</container>
					<unittitle id="link46">Correspondence - June 1952-November 1958. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">7</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link47">Volume 35.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1952-August 1952. 19 pp.: Judy Holliday; Hollywood ASP activities; Hollywood chapter, Civil Rights Congress, activities.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">7</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link48">Volume 36.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952/1953">1952-1953</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>August 1952 cont.-January 1953. 115 pp.: HUAC Los Angeles hearings; Hollywood ASP protest activities; Communist infiltration of radio-television industry; interrelation of Communist cultural activities between Los Angeles and New
							York City; National ASP on Korean War; Los Angeles Committee to Secure Justice in the Rosenberg Case; Motion Picture Industry Council support of HUAC; Champions of the Bill of Rights; Citizens Committee to Preserve American
							Freedoms.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">7</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link49">Volume 37.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1953 cont.-December 1953. 159 pp.: American Legion anti-Communist activities; HUAC Los Angeles hearings; Screen Actors Guild; witness lists; Hollywood ASP activities; law suits against motion picture industry; Independent
							Productions Corporation; The Salt of the Earth; Actor's Equity Association; labor unions; National ASP; congressional investigations in entertainment industry; John Howard Lawson; Lucille Ball.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">7</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link50">Volume 38.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1955">1953-1955</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>December 1953 cont.-March 1955. 240 pp.: Hollywood ASP activities; The Salt of the Earth; labor unions; Martin Berkeley; New York ASP; Herbert Biberman; John Howard Lawson; labor situation; Citizens Committee to Perserve American
							Freedoms; activities of Nwe York City FBI office; Motion Picture Alliance; gray lists issue; informant activities; Communist infiltration of radio-television industry; National ASP; reorganization of Los Angeles Communist Party's
							Cultural Division; Writers Guild of America; Barry Storm; The General Died at Dawn.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">7</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link51">Volume 39.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>March 1955 cont.-December 1955. 152 pp.: Los Angeles Communist Party organization; Writers Guild of America; studio craft unions and screen guilds; Hollywood ASP activities; Fund for the Republic activities; New York ASP activities;
							The Salt of the Earth; Communist film reviews; list of Communists in motion picture industry; labor-studeio contract negotiations; American Legion list of Communists in motion picture industry; IATSE; HUAC hearings; Association of
							Motion Picture Producers, Inc.@ Communist ghost writer allegations; Motion Picture Alliance; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, AFL; HUAC hearings on Communist infiltration in the New York theater and
							radio-television industries.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">7</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link52">Volume 40.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1958">1956-1958</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1956-November 1958. 197 pp.: John Cromwell; Los Angeles Communist Party, Cultural Division membership; Citizens Committee to Preserve American Freedoms; Musicians Committee for Cultural Freedom; Hollywood ASP activities; HUAC
							hearings; Independent Productions Corporation; American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, AFL; HUAC hearings on Communist infiltration in the New York theater and radio-television industries; Fund for the Republic
							activities; Marilyn Monroe; Storm Center; King Brothers, Inc. cover up of Communist script writers; John Howard Lawson; blacklisting issue; Arts and Research Foundation; activities of the "Hollywood 10"</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">8</container>
					<unittitle id="link53">News clippings - January 1943-October 1947. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link54">Volume 1.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1943/1944">1943-1944</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1943-February 1944. 118 pp.: Labor union activities; Mission to Moscow; Press reviews of films; David Platt's "Film Front" column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; Motion Picture Alliance; Charles Chaplin.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link55">Volume 2.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>March 1944-December 1944. 103 pp.: David Platt's "Film Front" column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; The Negro Soldier; labor union activities; Hollywood Democratic Committee; Seventh Cross; Motion Picture Alliance;
							Screen Writers Guild; Hollywood Writers Mobilization.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link56">Volume 3.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1945-May 1945. 102 pp.: David Platt's "Film Front" column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; Screen Actors Guild; Uncle Remus; postwar educational film production; Soviet films; CSU-IATSE jurisdictional strike;
							labor violence.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link57">Volume 4.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1945-December 1945. 65 pp.: David Platt's column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; proposed HUAC investigations of motion picture industry; Motion Picture Alliance; Cecil B. DeMille; Herbert K. Sorrell and CSU
							strike activities; religious and racial intolerance in motion picture industry.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link58">Volume 4 (Only Documents Dated 1946).</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1946-December 1946. 47 pp.: David Platt's column--commentaries and revews [from Daily Worker]@United Productions; screen guilds; labor-studios wage negotiations; HUAC investigations.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link59">Volume 5.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1947-June 1947. 102 pp.: David Platt's column--commentaries and reviews [from Daily Worker]; foreign film reviews; HUAC investigations and hearings; anti-Soviet films; Robert Taylor and the Song of Russias; Adolphe Menjou;
							Eric Johnston; Screen Writers Guild.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link60">Volume 6.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>July 1947-October 1947. 117 pp.: HUAC hearings; House Labor Subcommittee investigations of unions; labor strife; Los Angeles "Town Meeting of the Air" [radio discussion program]; Charles Chaplin; Hanns Eisler; PCA anti-HUAC
							activities; "Unfriendly 19"; Jack L. Warner.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link61">Volume 7.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1947 cont. 117 pp.: Robert Taylor and Song of Russia; HUAC hearings; John Howard Lawson; Adolph Menjou; John Weber espionage investigation and Chalmers "Slick" Goodlin; Rupert Hughes; Paul V. McNutt; Committee for the First
							Amendment.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">8</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link62">Volume 8.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1947 cont. 113 pp.: Reactions to HUAC hearings; HUAC hearings; Humphrey Bogart; Paul V. McNutt and the Motion Picture Producers Association; Eric Johnston; Senator Claude Pepper; Walt Disney; "Unfriendly 19"; Committee for
							the First Amendment.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">9</container>
					<unittitle id="link63">News clippings - October 1947 cont.-March 1949. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link64">Volume 9.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1947 cont. 102 pp.: Reaction to HUAC hearings; HUAC hearings; John Howard Lawson; Eric Johnston; Dalton Trumbo; labor strikes; Roy M. Brewer; Lauren Bacall.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link65">Volume 10.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1947 cont. 81 pp.: HUAC hearings; reaction to HUAC hearings; atomic bomb spies and alleged Hollywood Communists; Emmett Lavery.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link66">Volume 11.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1947. 98 pp.: Reaction to HUAC hearings; "Hollywood 10" contempt hearings; Committee for the First Amendment; Lauren Bacall; Screen Writers Guild; House Speaker Joseph W. Martin.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link67">Volume 12.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1947 cont. 112 pp.: Reaction to HUAC hearings; RKO Radio Pictures; blacklisting allegations; Scren Actors Guild's anti-Communist policy; Eric Johnston; Twentieth Century-Fox; "Hollywood 10"; Louis B. Mayer.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link68">Volume 13.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>November 1947 cont.-December 1947. 92 pp.: Blacklisting of "Hollywood 10"; blacklisting of alleged Communists; The Iron Curtain; Hollywood AFL Film Council; screen guilds' anti-Communist policies; Humphrey Bogart; "Hollywood 10"
							activities; Eric Johnston.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link69">Volume 14.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1948-February 1948. 88 pp.: "Hollywood 10" hearings; "Hollywood 10" law suits against studios; Screen Actors Guild's non-Communist oath policy; Tenney Committee [California Senate Un-American Activities Committees] hearings;
							Eric Johnston; Edward Dmytryck; House Labor Subcommittee investigations of IATSE-CSU jurisdictional strike; Hungarian ban on US films.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link70">Volume 15.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>March 1948-May 1948. 143 pp.: "Hollywood 10" law suits against studios; legal defense of "Hollywood 10"; blacklisting issue; international film community's response to Hollywood "inquisition"; anti-Communist films; John Howard
							Lawson; "Hollywood 10" contempt trials; Dalton Trumbo; protests against The Iron Curtain.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link71">Volume 16.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>May 1948-September 1948. 79 pp.: The Iron Curtain; "Hollywood 10" contempt trials; anti-trust suit against studios on issue of blacklisting; Screen Writers Guild; press on anti-communism and the motion picture industry.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">9</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link72">Volume 17.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948/1949">1948-1949</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>October 1948-March 1949. 87 pp.: HUAC Hollywood hearings; anti-trust suit against studios on issue of blacklisting; Screen Writers Guild; "Hollywood 10" activities; blacklist issue; John Howard Lawson; "red-baiting" films and plays;
							labor disputes; "Hollywood 10" law suits against studios; Walk a Crooked Mile; Eric Johnston; anti-Semitism and racial intolerance in motion picture industry.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">10</container>
					<unittitle id="link73">News clippings - April 1949-December 1958. </unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link74">Volume 18.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1949-June 1949. 94 pp.: Anti-Communist films; Dalton Trumbo; Screen Writers Guild; racism and Home of the Brave; "Hollywood 10" anti-trust law suit against the studios; Red Menace; "Hollywood 10" activities; Albert Maltz and
							book The Journey of Simon McKeever.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link75">Volume 19.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1949/1950">1949-1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>July 1949-March 1950. 131 pp.: Anti-Communist films; Ayn Rand; racist films issue; "Hollywood Beat" column and David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; protest support for "Hollywood 10"; CSU activities; strike
							activities; "Hollywood 10" activities; Negro stereotype in films; Roberto Rossellini.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link76">Volume 20.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1950-June 1950. 89 pp.: John Howard Larson; Dalton Trumbo; New York City's Deadline for Freedom Rallies in support of "Hollywood 10"; "Hollywood 10" activities; US Supreme Court decision on "Hollywood 10" appeal; David Platt
							column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; appeal for re-hearing of "Hollywood 10"; international support of "Hollywood 10"; appeal to United Nations on behalf of "Hollywood 10"; blacklist issue.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link77">Volume 21.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>July 1950-December 1950. 76 pp.: "Hollywood 10" activities; international support of "Hollywood 10"; Harry M. Warner on Communist infiltration; Motion Picture Alliance; public support for "Hollywood 10"; David Platt column [motion
							picture and industry commentaries].</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link78">Volume 22.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>January 1951-May 1951. 144 pp.: David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; HUAC hearings; V.J. Jerome; Gale A. Sondergaard; Motion Picture Alliance; Larry Parks; Actors Equity Association; I Was A Communist For
							The FBI; Roy M. Brewer; David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries].</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link79">Volume 23.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1951/1952">1951-1952</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>June 1951-February 1952. 94 pp.: HUAC hearings; Ronald Reagan; Martin Berkeley; Hollywood ASP activities; blacklisting issue; Sidney Buchman.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link80">Volume 24.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1952/1953">1952-1953</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>March 1952-March 1953. 125 pp.: "Hollywood 10" law suit against studios; American Legion support of anti-Communist activities; Paul Jarrico; blacklisting issue; RKO Radio Pictures; Edward G. Robinson; Clifford Odets; Ronald Reagan;
							HUAC hearings; Charles Chaplin; The Salt of the Earth; lawsuits against studios alleging blacklisting; Libby Burke.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link81">Volume 25.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1953/1955">1953-1955</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1953-March 1955. 118 pp.: HUAC hearings; Screen Actors Guild; television industry; Actors Equity Association; Edward Dmytryk; David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; The Salt of the Earth; Roy M. Brewer;
							reviews of Soviet and other foreign films.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">10</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link82">Volume 26.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1955/1958">1955-1958</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>April 1955-December 1958. 63 pp.: David Platt column [motion picture and industry commentaries]; Blackboard Jungle; The Salt of the Earth; Arthur Miller; lawsuits against studios alleging blacklisting; "Hollywood 10" activities.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">11</container>
					<unittitle id="link83">Bureau File #100-138754</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link84">Enclosure to Serial 4.</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938/1940">1938-1940</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>29 pp. League of American Writers; IATSE convention proceedings</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link85">Enclosure to Serial 163.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>27 pp. List of Communist party members employed in the motion picture industry, June 11, 1947. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link86">Enclosure to Serial 157X.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>317 pp. Report entitled Communist Infiltration of Motion Picture Industry, Up to Date as of May 24, 1947. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link87">Enclosure to Serial 188.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>34 pp. IATSE convention proceedings, 1940; The Daily Worker articles on film as propaganda. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link88">Enclosure to Serial 238.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>11 pp. Statement on motion picture industry and congressional investigations. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link89">Enclosure to Serial 250.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>71 pp. July 8, 1947 report entitled Communist Infiltration of the Motion Picture Industry. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link90">Enclosure to Serial 251X.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>357 pp. Biographical sketches, highlighting Communist "connections" of witnesses appearing before HUAC in 1947. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link91">Enclosure to Serial 251X1.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>205 pp. Report entitled Summary on the Communist Infiltration into the Motion Picture Industry, October 2, 1947. </p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">11</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link92">Enclosure to Serial 360.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>16 pp. Hollywood Reporter and Variety articles regarding reaction to HUAC investigations; Hollywood ASP flyer.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">12</container>
					<unittitle id="link93">Bureau File #100-138754</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link94">Enclosure to Serial 391.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>279 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, October 20-24 and 28-30, 1947.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link95">Enclosure to Serial 455.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>25 pp.: Myron C. Fagan on Thieves' Paradise.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link96">Enclosure to Serial 464.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>5 pp.: Title page and Foreword of Gordon Kahn's book entitled Hollywood on Trial: The Story of the 10 Who Were Indicted.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link97">Enclosure to Serial 469.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>21 pp.: Transcripts of Abe Polonsky's telephone conversations of March 20, 1948.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link98">Enclosure to Serial 491.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>45 pp.: Myron C. Fagan.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link99">Enclosure to Serial 494.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>33 pp.: Investigation of the New York theater industry; New Theatre League.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link100">Enclosure to Serial 500.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>29 pp.: Cinema Educational Guild theater play entitled Mr. X.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link101">Enclosure to Serial 534.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>30 pp.: Myron C. Fagan; Catholic Stage Guild in Ireland; Gregory Peck.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link102">Enclosure to Serial 541.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>6 pp.: Title page from Myron C. Fagan's book entitled Red Treason in Hollywood.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">12</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link103">Enclosure to Serial 554.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>80 pp.: Amici curiae brief in Lawson v. U.S. and Trumbo v. U.S.@ Dalton Trumbo's pamhplet on the "Hollywood 10" entitled The Time of the Toad.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">13</container>
					<unittitle id="link104">Bureau File #100-138754</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link105">Enclosure to Serial 637.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>67 pp.: Public correspondence with US Supreme Court regarding the Eugene Dennis Contempt Case and "Hollywood 10".</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link106">Enclosure to Serial 826.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>45 pp.: Script of The Troubled Air.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link107">Enclosure to Serial 831.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>221 pp.: HUAC hearing transcripts, May 16-18, 1951; Roy M. Brewer testimony.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link108">Enclosure to Serial 834.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>20 pp.: Press articles on the alleged Communist infiltration of Hollywood.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link109">Enclosure to Serial 836.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>128 pp.: HUAC hearing transcripts, May 24, 1951 and April 24, 1951.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link110">Enclosure to Serial 839.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>113 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, April 25, 1951; Edward Dmytryk.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">13</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link111">Enclosure to Serial 1003.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p> 583 pp.: Report entitled Summary on the Communist Infiltration Into the Motion Picture Industry, July 15, 1949.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">14</container>
					<unittitle id="link112">Bureau File #100-138754</unittitle>
				</did>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">14</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link113">Enclosure to Serial 1006.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>51 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, November 12-13, 1952.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">14</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link114">Enclosure to Serial 1025.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>422 pp.: HUAC hearings transcripts, March 26-28, 30-31, and April 7-8, 1953.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">14</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link115">Enclosure to Serial 1047.</unittitle>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>99 pp.: Cinema Educational Guild pamphlet encompassing Myron C. Fagan's article entitled Red Treason on Broadway; Lucille Ball.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">14</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link116">Enclosure to Serial 1103.</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>523 pp.: Report entitled Summary on the Communist into the Motion Picture Industry (Up to Date as of December 31, 1955).</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">14</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link117">Supplemental Release Materials</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1948/1958">1948-1958</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>26 pp.: Synopses of Communist infiltration of the Motion Picture Industry by D.M. Ladd for J. Edgar Hoover; Michael Seymour Blankfort.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
				<c02 level="file">
					<did>
						<container type="reel">14</container>
						<unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
						<unittitle id="link118">Other Agency Documents Approved for Release by the FBI</unittitle>
						<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1943/1947">1943-1947</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>40 pp.: OWI review of script for Secret Service in Darkest Africa; Office of Censorship cable intercepts from USSR to the American Cinematographer in Hollywood.</p>
					</scopecontent>
				</c02>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">15</container>
					<unittitle id="link119">Guide to the Microfilm Collection</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
