<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
 <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
  <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05918mf::Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05918mf</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm<date> 1925-1955</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
    <date>August 03, 2015</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p>
      <subject>Labor</subject>
     </p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>August 03, 2015</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 </eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm<lb/></titleproper>
   <num>Collection Number: 5918 mf</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, March 27, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Randall Miles, August 03, 2015</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2015 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
   <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1925- 1955</unitdate>
   </unittitle>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">5918 mf</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">American Federation of Labor (AFL)</corpname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">19 microfilm reels</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records, minutes.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">Minutes of the Executive Council of American Federation of Labor, 1925-1955.</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
   <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
   <p>Microfilmed from the holdings of the George Meany Memorial Archives. Guide, compiled by Randolph H. Boehm, entitled: A guide to the microform edition of Minutes of the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor.</p>
  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
   <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Names: </head>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Boehm, Randolph. </persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">American Federation of Labor --History--Sources. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">American Federation of Labor. Executive Council--Archives. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">American Federation of Labor. Executive Council. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">George Meany Memorial Archives. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">University Publications of America (Firm) </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Subjects: </head>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions--United States--Political activity--History--Sources. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor movement--United States--History--20th century-- Sources.</subject>
   </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
   <accessrestrict>
    <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    <head>Cite As:</head>
    <p>Minutes of the Executive Council of AFL, Pt. 2 on Microfilm #5918 mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
   <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05527mf.html"> 5527 mf: National AFL Conventions on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
   </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">Minutes 1925-1927</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link7">0001. Meeting Minutes of February 4-11, 1925. 118 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor departments consolidation; Iron Workers dispute with Philadelphia (Pennsylvania) Athletics baseball club; Bricklayers and Plasterers jurisdiction dispute; immigration restriction quotas; Carpenters Union dual
       national organization; Child Labor Amendment; American Federation of Labor visit to President Coolidge; private detection agencies and Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania, unions; resignation of Vice President James Duncan; German Federation of Trade Unions; Mine
       Workers dispute with Locomotive Engineers; prison labor model legislation; Franklin Roosevelt; Street Railway Employees dispute with Metal Trades Department; Teamsters disputes with Railway Clerks and Street Railway Employees; Union Label Campaign;
       American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; organization drive among women office workers; organizing drive in southern states; boycotts; civilian military training.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link8">0119. Meeting Minutes of May 5-9, 1925. 60 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Recreation; Marine Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Steam Engineers; military training camps; ship subsidy bill; clerical workers, Stenographers, Book Keepers, and Accountants Union; Textile Workers Union dispute with American Thread
       Company; anti-picketing decision by Washington State Supreme Court.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link9">0179. Meeting Minutes of July 29-August 4, 1925. 106 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Conference among Machinists, Blacksmiths, and Street and Electric Railway Employees; American Federation of Labor tribute to William Jennings Bryan; Chicago garment makers unions, United Garment Workers Amalgamated Clothing Workers;
       United Mine Workers dispute with Coal River Collieries; federal restrictions on aliens; Child Labor Amendment; farmers relations with American Federation of Labor; labor banks; Railway shop crafts strike; Teamsters disputes with Railway Clerks and
       Street and Electric Railway Employees; Ladies Garment Workers Union application for prosanis (sanitary) label; workmen's compensation legislation in Massachusetts and Missouri; Mexican immigration; citizen military camps; Pan American Federation of
       Labor; strike against Pennsylvania Railroad; People's Legislative Service; Textile Workers wage reduction; organizing drive among women in industry; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link10">0285. Meeting Minutes of October 4, 10, and 16, 1925. 39 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Federal restrictions of aliens; Asian exclusion; anti-labor bills defeated in 68th Congress; Book Keepers, Stenographers, and Accountants Union dispute with Ladies Garment Workers Union; United Mine Workers dispute with Coal River
       Collieries; immigration law violation by merchant seamen; workmen's compensation legislation for longshoremen; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Fire Fighters; mothers pensions; Oil Field Workers organization; sales taxes; Equal Rights Amendment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link11">0324. Meeting Minutes of November 17-20, 1925. 106 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor opposition to conscription bill; convict labor; Fascist movement; Canadian and Mexican immigration; federal injunction bill; federal anti-labor legislation; Machinists dispute with Fire Fighters; Mexican
       Federation of Labor; Machinists agreement with Plumbers; World Court; American Federation of Labor financial and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link12">0430. Meeting Minutes of March 23-29. 1926. 126 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Actors union; Australian Labor Party; British Labor Mission to the United States; Carpenters affiliation with Wood Workers Union; Western Union suit against Chicago Building Trades; Steam Engineers disputes with Electrical Workers and
       with Marine Firemen; immigration restriction; deportation of alien seamen; delegation from Mexican Federation of Labor; organizing drive among African American workers; Watson-Parker railroad bill; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey;
       workmen's compensation legislation in District of Columbia and Massachusetts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link13">0556. Meeting Minutes of June 25-30, 1926. 95 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Bar Association endorsement of voluntarism in industrial relations; British Miners financial assistance; Fur Workers Union investigation; Machinists dispute with Street Railway Employees; workmen's compensation legislation in
       Missouri; radicalism; National Crime Commission; organizing drive among African American workers; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; Railway Labor Act; labor conditions in Russia; American Federation of Labor financial and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link14">0651. Meeting Minutes of August 24-30, 1926. 62 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: British Miners relief; Electrical Workers dispute with Railroad Signalmen; anti-union shop movement; citizens military training; employee stock ownership; voluntarism in industrial relations; Communist activities in Fur Workers Union;
       Russian labor commission; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; William B. Wilson's United States Senate candidacy; American Federation of Labor finance and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link15">0713. Meeting Minutes of October 3 and 15, 1926. 24 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile, Aircraft, and Vehicle Workers application for re-affiliation; investigation of Communist influence in Fur Workers Union; American Federation of Labor conference with Mexican and European labor representatives; Eugene Debs
       citizenship restoration; federal immigration laws; Muscle Shoals power project; night work wage differentials; farmers cooperation with labor; Sacco-Vanzetti case; Richard T. Ely lecture on taxation; Stone Cutters Union complaints about pneumatic
       hammer; yellow-dog contracts; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link16">0737. Meeting Minutes of January 11-19, 1927. 123 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing drive; Communist activity in Canadian labor movement; company unions; causes-of-crime study endorsed; American Federation of Labor Education Committee; Communist activities in Fur Workers Union; Italian
       trade union movement; Communist activity in Ladies Garment Workers Union; Mexican Federation of Labor; restriction of Mexican immigration; reorganization of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers Union; Navy Yard employees; Stone Cutters Union complaints about
       pneumatic hammer; Textile Workers strike in Passaic, New Jersey; Union Label campaign; workmen's compensation legislation in Massachusetts and Missouri; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link17">0860. Meeting Minutes of May 10-17, 1927. 116 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers protest of Volstead Act; Bricklayers and Plasterers Unions agreement; suppression of union activities in Cuba; Communists expelled from Fur Workers Union; Indiana State Federation of Labor; Japanese Workers Union; Jewelry
       Workers organizing drive; Alexander Kerensky visit; John L. Lewis visit to Executive Council; Mexican Federation of Labor; Mooney-Billings case; labor delegation to Russia; Supreme Court decision on Stone Cutters Union request of antitrust exemption;
       Workers Education Bureau convention.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link18">Minutes 1927-1929</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link19">0001. Meeting Minutes of May 10-17, 1927. 54 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Street and Electrical Railway Employees injunction case in Indianapolis, Indiana; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Pan American Commercial Conference; American Federation of Labor meeting with American Bar
       Association on federal labor legislation and court interpretations of federal antitrust law; Mexican Federation of Labor; Sacco-Vanzetti case; Canadian and Mexican immigration restrictions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link20">0055. Meeting Minutes of September 7-13, 1927. 45 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor ban on Communist delegates; Electrical Workers jurisdiction controversy with Railroad Signalmen; indebtedness of Ladies Garment Workers Union; American Federation of Labor educational motion picture.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link21">0100. Meeting Minutes of October 1 and 15, 1927. 35 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Communist activities in Los Angeles labor movement; Carpenters re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor Building Trades Department; Mine; Mill, and Smelter Workers organizing drive; restriction of aliens; legislative reform of
       antitrust law; Canadian immigration restriction; Civil War veterans pensions; organization of African American workers; farmers cooperation with the labor movement; restriction of immigrant seamen, artists, and Latin Americans; Ladies Garment Workers
       struggle with Communists; Mississippi flood catastrophe; Muscle Shoals power project and labor standards; old age pensions; pacifism denounced; Pan American Financial Conference; aid to Puerto Rico; federal government employee protections; United
       Textile Workers organizing drive in the south.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link22">0135. Meeting Minutes of November 21, 1927. 30 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor conference with President Coolidge; American Federation of Labor conference with Pennsylvania Governor Fisher; United Mine Workers strike.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link23">0165. Meeting Minutes of January 17-25, 1928. 104 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Federal anti-conspiracy bill; Shipstead anti-injunction bill; Boulder Dam project; Mexican immigration restriction; Tom Mooney case; United Mine Workers strike; Communist activity in Seattle and Los Angeles labor movements; Teamsters
       agreement with Railway Clerks; Sleeping Car Porters organization; Street and Electric Railways Union New York injunction suit; American Federation of Labor petition for modification of Volstead Act; American Federation of Labor finances and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link24">0269. Meeting Minutes of April 24-May 2, 1928. 139 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Airplane Workers organization; Automobile Workers organizing drive; Boilermakers jurisdiction dispute with Bridge and Structural Iron Workers; Electrical Workers jurisdiction dispute with Railroad Signalmen; American Federation of Labor
       legislative proposals; labor exemption from antitrust laws; anti-injunction legislation; protection for union organizing; Child Labor Amendment; convict labor; five-day workweek; workmen's compensation for District of Columbia United Mine Workers
       strike; Pocketbook Workers Union, New York, New York, charter denied; American Federation of Labor platform to political parties conventions; Sleeping Car Porters charter denied; Tobacco Workers Union controversy with R.J. Reynolds; John H. Walker,
       labor delegate to foreign countries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link25">0408. Meeting Minutes of July 31-August 7, 1928. 98 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor disaffiliation from Brookwood Labor College; Communist activity in Canton, Ohio, labor movement; indebtedness of Ladies Garment Workers Union; Leather Workers amalgamation with New York, New York, Pocket Book
       Workers; Mexican Federation of Labor; United Mine Workers strike; American Federation of Labor National Non-Partisan Political Committee report; Republican and Democratic party replies to American Federation of Labor political program; Sleeping Car
       Porters charter application; yellow-dog contracts among Seattle teachers; Tobacco Workers controversy with R.J. Reynolds; American Federation of Labor delegate to League of Nations conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link26">0506. Meeting Minutes of October 18-25, 1928. 63 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor disaffiliation from Brookwood College; expulsion of Communists from Carpenters Union; indebtedness of Ladies Garment Workers Union; Mexican labor movement; Mexican immigration restriction; Machinists
       agreement with Street Railway Employees; Sleeping Car Porters application; Textile Workers Union strike in New Bedford, Massachusetts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link27">0569. Meeting Minutes of November 18 and 25, 1928. 44 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Audit of American Federation of Labor finances; federal employees labor relations; Ladies Garment Workers; Shipstead anti-injunction bill; Mexican, Canadian, and Caribbean immigration restriction; federal farm relief bill; federal mine
       workers bills; Molders Union boycotts; narcotics addiction treatment bill; naval appropriations bill; ban on Chinese-made shingles; southern states organizing drive; yellow-dog contracts among Seattle teachers; Sleeping Car Porters charter
       application.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link28">0613. Meeting Minutes of February 18-25, 1928. 44 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anheuser-Busch Company dispute with American Federation of Labor building trades; boycott policies; Brookwood Labor College; Cigar Makers and Tobacco Workers amalgamation; convict labor legislation; American Federation of Labor
       declaration of economic principles; immigration legislation; Shipstead anti-injunction bill; Ladies Garment Workers request for bond endorsement; narcotics treatment farms; Hoover commission to investigate prohibition; American Federation of Labor
       finances and membership statistics; Sleeping Car Porters issued federal labor union charter; American Federation of Labor Unemployment Committee; unemployment insurance legislation; Equal Rights Amendment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link29">0723. Meeting Minutes of May 21-28, 1929. 134 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing drive; conscription legislation; convict labor legislation; immigration restriction policies and legislation; Ladies Garment Workers request for bargaining assistance; Hoover Commission on Law Enforcement;
       American Federation of Labor draft of anti-injunction legislation; discrimination against middle-aged workers; Mooney-Billings case; Pan American Federation of Labor; Sleeping Car Porters charter applications; unemployment programs endorsed by American
       Federation of Labor; "Progressive" faction in American Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link30">0857. Meeting Minutes of August 8-20, 1929. 102 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Increased compensation bill for Army officers and enlisted men; Cigar Makers strike, New Brunswick, New Jersey; Communist activities in Fur Workers Union; anti-injunction legislation; loans to Ladies Garment Workers Union; United Mine
       Workers finances; Mooney case; Oil Field Workers organizing drive; New Orleans Street Railway Employees strike; Textile Workers Union strike in southern states; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link31">0959. Meeting Minutes of October 6, 12, and 18, 1929. 32 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Cuba; Cigar Makers amalgamation with Tobacco Workers; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers dispute with Shell Oil Company; Automobile and Vehicle Workers organizing; immigration restriction; Mexican immigration; government employment
       conditions; coal industry legislation; forty-four-hour workweek; discrimination against older workers; southern states organizing campaign; Equal Rights Amendment; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; Textile Workers southern organizing campaign.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link32">Minutes 1930-1932</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link33">0001. Meeting Minutes of January 8-17, 1930. 103 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor organizers retirement plans; prevailing wages in government contracts; Catholic unions in Quebec, Canada; convict labor; American Federation of Labor conference with President Hoover; United Mine Workers
       internal politics; Pan American Federation of Labor; southern states organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link34">0104. Meeting Minutes of May 5-12, 1930. 152 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Bridge and Structural Iron Workers dispute with Tarrett Brothers Company; injunction relief legislation; coal industry legislation; Mexican immigration restriction; conscription legislation; convict labor; Filipino immigration
       restriction; Longshoremen's compensation; forty-four-hour work week; unemployment policies; United Mine Workers internal politics; unemployment at Navy Yards; Judge John J. Parker Supreme Court nomination; Owen J. Roberts Supreme Court appointment;
       Sleeping Car Porters international charter application; southern states organizing campaign; Textile Workers southern organizing; World Court; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link35">0256. Meeting Minutes of September 4-12, 1930. 127 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Dissension in Alabama State Federation of Labor; American Legion relations with American Federation of Labor; request for modification of Volstead Act; Building Trades Department policy on jurisdiction disputes; Catholic unions in
       Canada; Cigar Makers and Tobacco Workers amalgamation; American Federation of Labor involvement in congressional elections; United Mine Workers and Progressive Mine Workers; Pan American Federation of Labor; southern organizing campaign; Sugar Beet
       Workers charter application; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; Textile Workers negotiation in Danville, Virginia; unemployment insurance; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link36">0383. Meeting Minutes of October 5, 12, 18, and 21, 1930. 39 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Equal Rights Amendment; prevailing wages in government contracts; five day workweek; Sleeping Car Porters campaign to organize Pullman Company; southern organizing campaign; unemployment insurance; women's auxiliaries in American
       Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link37">0422. Meeting Minutes of January 13-23, 1931. 180 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor Building Trades Department relations with Carpenters Union; Catholic unions in Quebec; convict labor; Hod Carriers jurisdiction dispute with Marble Polishers; prevailing wages on government contracts;
       injunction relief bills; Mexican and Canadian immigration restriction; immigration restriction; five-day workweek; Navy Yards unemployment; workmen's compensation; military training in public schools; railroad consolidations; Sleeping Car Porters;
       southern organizing campaign; Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; Textile Workers strike in Danville, Virginia; Volstead Act modification; women's auxiliaries in American Federation of Labor; World Court; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link38">0602. Meeting Minutes of May 5-13, 1931. 115 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Workers education; Hod Carriers jurisdiction dispute with Marble Polishers; United Mine Workers internal politics; old age pension model legislation; industrial conditions in Puerto Rico; Railroad Trainmen re-affiliation; wage
       reductions; war mobilization of labor legislation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link39">0717. Meeting Minutes of August 6-19, 1931. 142 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Boulder Dam labor conditions; repression of labor unions in Cuba; Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Firemen; model injunction relief bill; Mooney case; National Civic Federation; old age pension bill; Pan American Federation of Labor;
       Teamsters dispute with Railway Clerks; United Textile Workers strike at Paterson, New Jersey, silk mills; unemployment insurance; wage reductions opposed by the American Federation of Labor; World Court; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link40">0859. Meeting Minutes of October 4 and 16, 1931. 23 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Convict labor; five-day workweek; immigration restriction; motion picture industry, directly affiliated unions; bill on illegal immigrant seamen; unemployment policies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link41">0882. Meeting Minutes of February 2-12, 1932. 136 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Legion relations with American Federation of Labor; political parties national conventions; federal employee unions; injunction relief legislation; Machinists dispute with Street Railway Employees; United Mine Workers strike in
       Harlan County, Kentucky; Mooney-Billings case; motion picture industry and union recognition; old age security bill; prevailing wage rate on government contracts; United States Supreme Court appointments; industrial preparedness war legislation; Chicago
       World's Fair; American Federation of Labor financial and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link42">Minutes 1932-1935</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link43">0001. Meeting Minutes of July 12-22, 1932. 120 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Bridge and Structural Iron Workers internal corruption charges; cotton legislation breach of labor standards; Federal Employees Union charter application; five-day workweek; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Carpenters; eight-hour day
       in motion picture industry; American Federation of Labor nonpartisan political action committee; American Federation of Labor proposals to national party conventions; racketeering in labor unions; American Federation of Labor charges against Steam
       Engineers; Theatrical Stage Employees charges against Motion Picture Operators; unemployment conference; unemployment policies; unemployment insurance; women's auxiliaries in the American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link44">0121. Meeting Minutes of October 18-27, 1932. 93 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Carpenters agreement with Machinists; Communist conference stumps American Federation of Labor convention; child labor; convict labor; five-day workweek; immigration restriction; injunction relief legislation; Kellogg-Briand Pact; old
       age security legislation; Pan American Federation of Labor; depression relief principles; unemployment; unemployment insurance; unemployment policies; Volstead Act modification; workmen's compensation; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics; American Federation of Government Employees; American Federation of Labor requests unemployment conference with Herbert Hoover; railroad workers pension legislation; Theatrical Stage Employees and Motion Picture Machine Operators
       protection against dual unionism.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link45">0214. Meeting Minutes of November 20 and December 3, 1932. 34 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Convict labor; Sleeping Car Porters injunction fight; shorter workday and workweek legislation; Daniel Tobin candidacy for secretary of labor; women and children in industry; bill to prohibit federal purchase of sweatshop products;
       women's auxiliaries in American Federation of Labor; workmen's compensation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link46">0248. Meeting Minutes of April 20-May 2, 1933. 114 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers jurisdiction dispute with Engineers and Teamsters; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers corruption case; Chain Store Employees organization drive; Commercial Telegraphers organizing drive among postal employees; five-day
       workweek; six-hour day legislation; Nazi treatment of German trade unions; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association charter application; National Association of Master Mechanics and Foremen of Navy Yards charter application; American Federation of Labor
       opposition to minimum wage legislation; Federated Motion Picture Studio Crafts recognition battle; naval appropriations; railroad legislation; Executive Council visit to President Roosevelt; recognition of Russia; Sleeping Car Porters injunction case;
       women's auxiliaries.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link47">0362. Meeting Minutes of September 6-15, 1933. 96 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor organizing campaign in federal labor unions; Federal Bankruptcy Act; Firemen and Oilers jurisdiction award over Brewery Firemen; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Carpenters Union; Executive Council visit
       with President Roosevelt; six-hour day legislation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link48">0458. Meeting Minutes of October 1, 8, and 11, 1933. 36 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Amalgamated Clothing Workers charter issued; nationalization of banks; Communist interference with American Federation of Labor convention; resolution on Father Charles E. Coughlin; policies regarding federal labor unions; Panama Canal
       Commission; National Recovery Act; discrimination against older workers; organizing drive among African Americans.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link49">0494. Meeting Minutes of January 23-February 1934. 118 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters, Engineers, and Firemen; cigar making industry code; company unions amendment to Section 7-A National Recovery Act; resolution on Father Charles E. Coughlin; Fur Workers representation
       dispute; Ladies Garment Workers jurisdiction dispute with Textile Workers; unemployment relief in New York, New York; Steel Workers protest against Weirton Steel Company; Theatrical Stage Employees; jurisdiction over motion picture machine operators;
       unemployment insurance; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link50">0612. Meeting Minutes of May 2-11, 1934. 104 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor organizing drive; Automobile Workers organizing campaign; Firemen dispute with Engineers; Garment Workers jurisdiction dispute with Textile Workers; paper industry organizing campaign; resolution on George W.
       Perkins; Wagner-Connery Labor Disputes Act; women's auxiliaries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link51">0716. Meeting Minutes of August 6-17, 1934. 81 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers Federal Labor Unions; Sleeping Car Porters charter application; women's auxiliaries; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link52">0797. Meeting Minutes of September 28-October 14, 1934. 121 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; appeals of Carpenters, Bricklayers, and Electrical Workers to Building Trades Department; Agricultural and Cannery Workers Union reduction in dues; anti-union laws; Boulder Dam labor conditions;
       company unions; convict labor; employment agencies; Federal Emergency Relief Administration employment requirements; labor standards on government contracts; Federal Housing Act; immigration law modification; African American organizers; racketeering
       resolution; rubber workers unemployment; Sleeping Car Porters application; thirty-hour workweek; Timber Workers organizing; Textile Workers strike.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link53">0918. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 14, 1935. 116 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing drive; Blacksmiths protest American Federation of Labor organizing infringements; Firemen jurisdiction dispute with engineers; Gas Workers charter application; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers protest
       Anaconda Company agreement with Metal Trades Department; Carpenters jurisdiction over Saw Mill and Timber Workers; Textile Workers program; Tobacco Trades Council petition regarding codes; American Federation of Labor finances and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link54">Minutes 1935-1936</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link55">0001. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 14, 1935 (continued). 226 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Executive Council meeting with Colonel Daniel McCormack, Commissioner of Immigration and Naturalization; radicalism in the labor movement; Automobile Workers organizing drive; Blacksmiths protest American Federation of Labor organizing
       infringements; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades controversy; Child Labor Amendment; Fascist movement activities in United States; Sidney Hillman and National Recovery Administration administration; immigration legislation
       amendments; International Labor Office; prevailing wages in federal relief employment; Marine Shipbuilders charter application; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers protest Anaconda Company agreement with Metal Trades Department; Amalgamated Clothing
       Workers; Executive Council meeting with President Roosevelt; Radio Workers charter application; Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction dispute with Sleeping Car Conductors; Steel Workers organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link56">0227. Meeting Minutes of April 30-May 7, 1935. 189 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organization; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Service Employees jurisdictional applications; Catholic University of America chair in social economics; Father Charles E. Coughlin invites American
       Federation of Labor to participate in National Union for Social Justice; Firemen and Oilers dispute with Textile Workers; Dubinsky report on Firemen and Oilers dispute with Textile Workers; Dubinsky report on International Labor Office; industrial
       organization in mass production industries; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers protest Metal Trades Department agreement with Anaconda Company; Molders amalgamation with Foundry Workers; American Federation of Labor conference with President Roosevelt;
       Rubber Workers charter application; Steel Workers insurgent movement; Wagner labor disputes bill; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link57">0416. Meeting Minutes of June 6-7, 1935. 47 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades Department, internal controversy; Father Charles E. Coughlin communication; Supreme Court decision invalidating National Recovery Act; Robert F. Wagner meeting with Executive
       Council.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link58">0463. Meeting Minutes of August 5-16, 1935. 128 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades Department, internal controversy; anti-Communist amendment to American Federation of Labor convention; injunction relief laws; Child Labor Amendment; industrial organization in mass
       production industries; National Labor Relations Board; National Recovery Act invalidation; unemployment relief; National Youth Administration; International Labor Office; racketeering investigation in New York; Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction;
       American Federation of Labor Special Committee on Colored Workers; Social Security Board; Theatrical Stage Employees jurisdiction extension; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link59">0591. Meeting Minutes of October 5-6, 12, and 20-21, 1935. 150 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organization; American Federation of Labor resolution regarding Communists; Thomas E. Dewey racketeering investigation; American Federation of Labor resolution on injunctions; labor and depression relief legislation;
       anti-lynching bill; Communist activity in Minneapolis labor movement; Mooney case expenses; Special Committee Report on Negro Workers; organizing drive among African Americans; Scottsboro case; organizing drive in southern states; Steel Workers
       organizing drive; American Federation of Labor legislative activities; Seattle, Washington, Labor Council suspension of Brewery Workers; American Federation of Teachers investigation; National Youth Administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link60">0741. Meeting Minutes of January 15-29, 1936. 238 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organization; International Labor Office; British Trades Union Congress; Child Labor Amendment; Congress of Industrial Organizations; amendment to United States Constitution to limit judicial review of legislation;
       Arkansas Tenant Farmers organization; immigration legislation; Iron and Steel Workers organization; American Federation of Labor resolution on Kohler Company; resignation of John L. Lewis from Executive Council; Metal Trades Department dispute with Oil
       Field Workers; organization of Lumber Workers; American Federation of Labor critical report on National Civic Federation; Radio Workers charter application denied; Rubber Workers constitution; Sleeping Car Porters charter; Tampa, Florida, floggings of
       labor organizers reported by Norman Thomas; women's auxiliaries; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link61">Minutes 1936</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link62">0001. Meeting Minutes of May 5-20, 1936. 297 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Sheet Metal Workers jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; Automobile Workers organization; Brewery Workers dispute with Seattle Central Labor Union; civil service qualifications; Congress of Industrial Organizations; convict labor
       legislation; Flat Glass Workers jurisdiction; American Federation of Labor opposition to Frazier-Lemke Act; International Federation of Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor Legal Defense Department; American Federation of Labor legislative
       program; Pan American Federation of Labor; Social Security Act administration; Steel Workers organizing campaign; American Federation of Teachers; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; unemployment immigration restriction;
       injunction relief to supplement National Labor Relations Act; subversive activities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link63">0298. Meeting Minutes of July 8-15, 1936. 272 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Building Service Employees jurisdiction extension; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Metal Trades Department charges against Congress of Industrial Organizations; Ladies Garment Workers affiliation with Congress of Industrial
       Organizations; Mooney-Billings Defense Fund; Seamen's International Union and Pacific Coast maritime dispute; Textile Workers affiliation with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor suspension of Congress of Industrial
       Organizations unions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link64">0570. Meeting Minutes of August 3-5, 1936. 84 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Congress of Industrial Organizations; Electrical Workers charges against Congress of Industrial Organizations; Hatters, Cap, and Millinery Workers relationship to Congress of Industrial Organizations; International Typographical Union
       relationship with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen jurisdiction expansion; Metal Trades Department charges against Congress of Industrial Organizations; Printing Trades dispute with Lithographers; American
       Federation of Labor suspension of Congress of Industrial Organizations unions; Wisconsin Federation of Labor resolution regarding Congress of Industrial Organizations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link65">0654. Meeting Minutes of October 8-21, 1936. 233 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Newspaper Guild strike at Seattle Post- Intelligencer; Amalgamated Clothing Workers disputes with United Garment Workers; Cloth Hat, Cap, and Millinery Workers resolution on Congress of Industrial Organizations; Machinists
       resolution on Congress of Industrial Organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities in Toledo, Ohio; Dubinsky resignation as vice president of American Federation of Labor; Building Service Employees jurisdiction expansion; American
       Federation of Labor relations with Federal Labor Unions; Automobile Workers and American Federation of Labor; convict labor; civil service; health insurance; housing; European labor; National Labor Relations Board; Pan American Federation of Labor;
       public education; Puerto Rico; depression relief; Social Security Act; Steel Workers organizing campaign; unemployment; American Federation of Teachers; technological changes; Hutcheson resignation as vice president of American Federation of Labor;
       Indiana State Federation of Labor endorsement of Farmer-Labor Party; International Federation of Trade Unions; International Typographical Union relations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Lithographers dispute with Printing Trades Unions;
       United States Supreme Court decision on National Recovery Administration; American Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees charter; Walsh-Healey minimum wage bill; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link66">0887. Meeting Minutes of November 14-15 and 28-29, 1936. 64 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Butte, Montana, Central Labor Union charter application; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Brewery Workers resolution on Congress of Industrial Organizations; company unions; convict labor; housing; immigration legislation;
       International Federation of Trade Unions; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association; motion picture industry labor agreement; American Newspaper Guild trike in Seattle; Puerto Rico and Wagner Labor Relations Act; depression relief qualifications; labor
       espionage; limitation of power of United States Supreme Court; vigilante violence; Walsh-Healey minimum wage bill; Filipino exclusion; seamen's legislation; occupational disease; workmen's compensation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link67">Minutes 1937-1938</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link68">0001. Meeting Minutes of February 8-19, 1937. 247 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Agricultural, Packing House, and Cannery Workers union; Butte, Montana, Central Labor Union application; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations relations with Central Labor Unions; Communist activities
       in labor movement; Gallup, Mexico, Miners situation; General Motors strike; federal (Guffey) coal bill; Hotel and Restaurant Workers jurisdiction expansion; General Hugh S. Johnson attack on American Federation of Labor; Machinists dispute with Tobacco
       Workers; Masters, Mates, and Pilots dispute with Longshoremen; Meat Cutters and Butchers Workmen jurisdiction expansion; Metal Trades Department hearing on Congress of Industrial Organizations activities; minimum wage legislation; motion picture
       industry agreement; African American labor organizers; Ladies Pocketbook and Novelty Workers charters; white collar workers organization; Works Progress Administration workers organization; Seamen's International Union insurgent challenge; United States
       Supreme Court president reorganization plan; Teamsters jurisdictional expansion; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link69">0248. Meeting Minutes of April 19-22, 1937. 51 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Congress of Industrial Organizations; Cleveland Federation of Labor; report on Congress of Industrial Organizations; Georgia Federation of Labor resolution on American Federation of Labor and Congress of Industrial Organizations;
       Massachusetts Federation of Labor organizing drive; minimum wage legislation; International Textile conference.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link70">0299. Meeting Minutes of May 23 and 26-30, 1937. 156 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Agricultural, Packing House, and Cannery Workers charter application; Aluminum Workers affiliation with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Chicago Federation of Labor; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Georgia Federation of Labor
       relations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor Marine Trades Department; Progressive Miners charter application; Street and Electric Railway Employees dispute with Transit Workers Union in New York, New York;
       International Typographical Union relations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; Teamsters jurisdiction extension to warehousemen; Welders charter application denied; Pacific Coast Longshoremen dispute with Teamsters over warehousemen; American
       Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link71">0455. Meeting Minutes of August 21-September 2, 1937. 216 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brewery Workers suit against American Federation of Labor and Teamsters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Constitutional amendments; Building Service Employees jurisdiction extension; exclusion of alien workers; age discrimination;
       injunction relief legislation; child labor; Congress of Industrial Organizations; convict labor; hours of work for women and minors; housing legislation; industrial homework; anti-lynching bill; Progressive Miners Union; Pan American Federation of
       Labor; Puerto Rico Free Federation of Workingmen; Railroad Employees Retirement Law; sit-down strikes; social security; wages and hours legislation; International Federation of Trade Unions; International Labor Office; Congress of Industrial
       Organizations organization in lumber industry; maritime organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations activity in Minneapolis Central Labor Union; Quarry Workers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters, and Hod Carriers and Engineers; Seamen's
       International Union reorganization; West Virginia State Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link72">0671. Meeting Minutes of October 3-4, 9, and 13-16, 1937. 109 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p> Major Topics: Building Service employees jurisdiction dispute with Hotel and Restaurant Employees; cannery industry organizing campaign; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities in northwest lumber industry and Pacific Coast maritime industry;
       American Federation of Labor "peace conference" with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor Defense Fund; Federal Labor Unions tax reductions and suspensions; housing; anti-lynching bill; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers
       charter application; National Labor Relations Board; African American organizers; old age pensions; Progressive Miners charter application; Puerto Rico political situation; wages and hours legislation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link73">0780. Meeting Minutes of December 3-4, 1937. 18 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Marine Engineers Beneficial Association jurisdiction dispute with Operating Engineers; wages and hours legislation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link74">0798. Meeting Minutes of January 24-February 8, 1938. 263 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor tax assessments; Blacksmiths jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; Building Service Employees dispute with Hotel and Restaurant Employees; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers dispute with Teamsters and
       Engineers; report on Congress of Industrial Organizations; organizing drive ta Ford Motor Company; Wagner Housing Bill provision for prevailing wage rates; Japanese aggression in China; wages and hours legislation; Building Trades agreement with
       Maintenance of Way Employees; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers charter revocation; Progressive Miners of America; United Mine Workers charter revocation; social security legislation; unemployment; American Federation of Labor finances and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link75">Minutes 1938-1939</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link76">0001. Meeting Minutes of April 25-May 5, 1938. 211 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Public works and appropriations bills; Bakery and Confectioner Workers jurisdiction expansion; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Trades dispute in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania; Congress of Industrial Organizations in Canadian
       Trades and Labor Congress; Seattle labor movement; wages and hours legislation; National Labor Relations Board decisions; Painters and Decorators jurisdiction expansion; Pan American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link77">0212. Meeting Minutes of August 22-September 2, 1938. 217 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Auto Workers charters; Building and Construction Trades Department agreement with Carpenters; Congress of Industrial Organizations; Congress of Industrial Organizations status in Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; joint American
       Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Labor Day proceedings; Dies Committee investigations; American Federation of Labor organizing drive among industrial workers; housing; Hod Carriers dispute with Quarry Workers; Hotel and
       Restaurant Employees dispute with Building Service Employees; report on International Federation of Trade Unions; Machinists dispute with Sheet Metal Workers; Marine Engineers Beneficial Association; Progressive Miners Union organizing drive; National
       Labor Relations Act, survey of decisions and administration; Packinghouse workers organizing drive; Sailors Union of the Pacific; Seamen organizing drive; Street and Electric Railway Employees jurisdiction disputes; Upholsterers jurisdiction disputes;
       wages and hours legislation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link78">0429. Meeting Minutes of October 2, 4, 8, 12, and 14, 1938. 71 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations reconciliation proposals; Congress of Industrial Organizations representation in Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Upholsterers Union jurisdiction disputes; Metal Trades
       Department organizing among shipyard workers; Seafarers International Union charter; International Seamen's Union charter revocation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link79">0500. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 14, 1939. 420 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Actors jurisdiction extension; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress appeal for assistance; Oregon anti-labor law; National Youth Administration apprentice training; Associated Farmers anti-labor activities;
       Automobile Workers organization; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; boycott of German-made goods; Building Service Employees dispute and agreement with Hotel and Restaurant Employees; Congress of Industrial Organizations dissociated from Canadian
       Trades and Labor Congress; Carpenters Union jurisdiction disputes; Congress of Industrial Organizations-American Federation of Labor peace negotiations; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities in Butte, Montana; Dies Committee; American
       Federation of Labor Housing Committee; National Labor Relations Board appointments; Labor's Non-Partisan League; National Labor Relations Act amendments; refugee legislation; wages and hours act (Walsh-Healey Fair Labor Standards Act); seniority rights
       of African American railroad maids; African American voting rights in the south; African American membership in American Federation of Labor; Longshoremen dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; labor relations in Mexico; Progressive Mine Workers of
       America; National Youth Administration and national defense; neon sign industry jurisdiction; Pan American Federation of Labor; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction expansion; Seafarers International Union report; State, County, and
       Municipal Employees jurisdiction; Teamsters dispute with Brewery Workers in Detroit; Textile Workers of America re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Fort Wayne, Indiana,
       Housing Plan.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link80">0920. Meeting Minutes of March 22-23, 1939. 45 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations pace negotiations; Associated Farmers; Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers; United Mine Workers; Oil Field, Gas Well, and Refinery Workers; Western Federation of Miners;
       Textile Workers of America; Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America; Automobile Workers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link81">Minutes 1939-1940</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link82">0001. Meeting Minutes of May 10-19, 1939. 180 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Actors jurisdiction extension; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Automobile Workers jurisdiction; Balfour Declaration on Palestine; Brewery Workers dispute with
       Teamsters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Operating Engineers jurisdiction matters; Laborers jurisdiction dispute with Operating Engineers; Longshoremen's Dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; American Federation of Labor Maritime Department
       proposed; Progressive Miners Union of America; Street and Electric Railway Employees dispute with Teamsters over Bus Operators organizing; American Federation of Labor organizing report; Pan American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor
       finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link83">0181. Meeting Minutes of August 7-18, 1939. 258 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Actors and Artists of America jurisdiction dispute with American Federation of Actors and Theatrical Stage Employees; Congress of Industrial Organizations activities; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial
       Organizations peace negotiations; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress dissociation from Congress of Industrial Organizations; Carpenters jurisdiction disputes; Japanese aggression in China; American Federation of Labor legislative program; Longshoremen's
       dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Molders Union dispute with Stove Mounters Union and Foundry Workers Union; discrimination against African Americans by American Federation of Labor unions; Upholsterers dispute with Carpenters; women's
       auxiliaries representation in State Federations of Labor; prevailing wages in Works Progress Administration work; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Summary of Legal Activities of American Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link84">0439. Meeting Minutes of October 1, 9, and 14-15, 1939. 96 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Injunction case in New Orleans; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; Carpenters jurisdiction dispute with Machinists over Millwrights; resolution for judicial recall; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; discrimination
       against African American workers by American Federation of Labor unions; National Labor Relations Act amendments; Oregon anti-labor law; Upholsterers agreement with Painters disapproved; Textile Workers organizing campaign; Upholsterers dispute with
       Carpenters; federal labor unions for warehousemen; Works Progress Administration working condition; Works Progress Administration Minneapolis strike and prevailing wage controversy; anti-Communist resolutions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link85">0535. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 9, 1940. 206 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Oregon antilabor law; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Building Service Employees jurisdiction expansion; United States Department of Justice
       indictments of Building Trades unions for antitrust violations; Painters Union agreement with Stove Mounters; proposed federal health security legislation; Conference on War Mobilization of Industry; United States Housing Authority; National Labor
       Relations Act amendments; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; indictments of striking Works Progress Administration workers in Minneapolis; Newspaper Guild in Chicago; Labor's Non-Partisan League; Westbrook Pegler attacks on American
       Federation of Labor leaders; picketing rights; Sleeping Car Porters jurisdiction expansion; American Federation of Labor Committee on Taxation; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link86">0741. Meeting Minutes of May 13-21, 1940. 162 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor building; American Federationist business; British Trades Union Congress; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; Circus, Carnival, Fairs, and Rodeo International Union charter application and request for
       assistance; Immigration Service transfer from Labor to Justice Department; American Federation of Labor planks to political parties conventions; injunction relief legislation and antitrust relief legislation; housing; immigration; Ladies Garment Workers
       reaffiliation with American Federation of Labor; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Machinists jurisdiction disputes; war mobilization of industry; Tobacco Workers International Union internal controversy; Virginia State Federation
       of Labor; indictments of Minneapolis Works Progress Administration Strikers; finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link87">0903. Meeting Minutes of September 30-October 10, 1940. 122 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Theatrical Agents and Managers Union jurisdiction extension; Southern Tenant Farmers Union charter application; Building and Construction Trades Department disputes with Machinists; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; Brotherhood of
       Railway Clerks jurisdiction matters; conscription exemption from union taxes; Congress of Industrial Organizations-American Federation of Labor peace negotiations; Workers Education Bureau; social security; American Federation of Labor opposition to
       appointment of Sidney Hillman to National Defense Commission; Longshoremen's dispute with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; National Labor Relations Act amendments; nonpartisan political policies; presidential campaign; American Federation of Labor policies
       on suspension of international unions; Virginia State Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link88">Minutes 1940-1942</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link89">0001. Meeting Minutes of September 30-October 10, 1940 (continued). 84 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Building and Construction Trades Department disputes with State, County, and Municipal Employees; postwar economic planning; workers education; application of antitrust to labor unions; American Federation of Labor organizing drives;
       American Federation of Labor policies on suspension of international unions; proposed American Federation of Labor libel suit against Westbrook Pegler; labor racketeering; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link90">0085. Meeting Minutes of November 17-29, 1940. 28 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor legal fees; American Federation of Labor policies on suspension of international unions; Stove Mounters and Molders protests.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link91">0113. Meeting Minutes of February 10-20, 1941. 202 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Alien migration to the United States; Oregon anti- labor law; protest application of antitrust law to labor unions by Thurman Arnold; Automobile Workers organizing; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; opposition to youth replacement of
       adult Civilian Conservation Corps workers; American Federation of Labor anti-Communist resolution; collective bargaining in national defense industries; Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor; Operating Engineers jurisdiction dispute with
       Teamsters; Grain Processors application for charter application; antistrike and compulsory arbitration legislation; compulsory work legislation; Longshoremen settlement with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; Montgomery Ward unfair labor practices case;
       racketeering charges in Painters Union; Pan American Federation of Labor rehabilitation; Pegler libel suit; Sleeping Car Porters legislation regarding conductors; shipbuilding industry; wage rates in defense construction; American Federation of Labor
       finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link92">0315. Meeting Minutes of May 19-28, 1941. 159 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Variety Actors Betterment committee and American Federation of Actors; American Federation of Labor opposition to antistrike legislation; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Conductors; Carpenters
       dispute with Machinists; Ice Pullers jurisdiction dispute among Teamsters, Operating Engineers and Firemen, and Oilers; Kohler Company strike; Machinists strike at San Francisco shipyards; racketeering in Painters Union; American Federation of Labor per
       capita taxes; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link93">0474. Meeting Minutes of August 4-13, 1941. 107 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Automobile Workers organizing conflict with Machinists at Allis Chalmers Company; Boiler Makers agreement with Plumbers; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; anti-labor legislation; Communist activity in American Federation of Teachers;
       housing; application of antitrust law to unions; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; postwar reconstruction; labor standards in public contracts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link94">0581. Meeting Minutes of October 5, 14, and 17, 1941. 36 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Alaskan defense workers; anti-labor legislation; Brewery Workers dispute with Teamsters; embargo of Japan; migrant labor; investigation of Minneapolis Central Labor Union; National Labor Relations Board.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link95">0617. Meeting Minutes of December 16 and 18, 1941. 21 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anti-labor legislation, Smith Bill; President's Conference of Employers and Employees in War Production Industries.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link96">0638. Meeting Minutes of January 12-17, 1942. 130 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; anti-labor legislation; Civilian Conservation Corps merger with National Youth Association; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; American Federation of
       Labor purchase of Defense Bonds; Distillery Workers dispute with Seagram Company; Machinists dispute with Building Trades Department and Carpenters over Tennessee Valley Authority; office employees unions organization; price controls; American
       Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; War Labor Board established.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link97">0768. Meeting Minutes of May 13-22, 1942. 141 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Anglo-Soviet-American Trade Union committee proposed; Boys Town, Nebraska; William H. Davis, chair of War Labor Board, anti-union attitude; Engineers
       dispute with Machinists and Building Trades Department; application of antitrust to labor unions; anti-labor legislation; charges of bias against National Labor Relations Board; Pan American Labor Conference; prison labor in war production; wage
       stabilization; War Bond salary deduction.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link98">Minutes 1942-1944</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link99">0001. Meeting Minutes of May 13-22, 1942 (continued). 36 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Special Report on American Federation of Labor; Present Financial Status.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link100">0037. Meeting Minutes of August 4-13, 1942. 143 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; arbitration; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; collective bargaining in defense industries; labor relations in
       United States Navy; anti-labor legislation; antiracketeering legislation; Dies Committee; housing; application of anti-trust to labor unions; maritime labor legislation; Nationality Act; War Manpower Commission; subversive activities; women and children
       in war production; War Production Board; strikes, communication from Under Secretary of War Robert Patterson; wartime wage policies; war prisoners relief; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link101">0180. Meeting Minutes of October 4-6 and 15, 1942. 47 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee, inclusion of Congress of Industrial Organizations and Railroad Brotherhoods; anti-labor legislation in California, "Hot Cargo" legislation; Machinists disputes with Carpenters and Buildings and
       Construction Department; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People telegram to American Federation of Labor regarding African American workers; Anglo-Soviet Trades Union Council; collective bargaining in war industries; housing for war
       workers; immigration; anti-trust; maritime legislation; National War Labor Board; wages and benefits of government employees; Executive Order on overtime pay.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link102">0227. Meeting Minutes of January 18-27, 1943. 200 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Absenteeism in war industries; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; American Federation of Labor representation on government boards and committees in war production; Anglo-American-Soviet
       trade Union Association; Anglo-American trade Union Committee; anti-labor legislation; anti-closed shop litigation in Florida; housing for war workers; inter-American affairs; Kaiser Shipbuilding case; Los Angeles Central Labor Council; Pan American
       Federation of Labor; wage and price stabilization; Works Progress Administration liquidated; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link103">0427. Meeting Minutes of May 17-22, 1943. 141 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Carpenters over aircraft plants; anti-labor legislation, Smith-Connally bill, anti-trust; Kaiser shipyards case;
       investigation of Los Angeles Central Labor Council; United Mine Workers application for re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; National Labor Relations Board ad Kaiser shipyard case; National War Labor Board; no-strike pledge; Oil Refinery
       Workers jurisdiction; report on American Federation of Labor legal Cases; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link104">0568. Meeting Minutes of August 9-16, 1943. 135 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; proposed repeal of Chinese Exclusion Act; cigarettes for servicemen campaign; European relief, aid to underground movements; American Federation of Labor legal report; anti-trust; Machinists
       withdrawal from American Federation of Labor; National Labor Relations Board; National War Labor Board; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace negotiations; price controls and rationing; United Mine Workers
       re-affiliation; United Nations Relief Committee; American Legion Labor Posts; prisoners of war used for war labor; Connally-Smith Act threat to no-strike pledge; American Federation of Labor political activities; Progressive Miners of America
       re-affiliation with United Mine Workers; Women's Trade Union League; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link105">0703. Meeting Minutes of October 3, 5-6, 13, and 15, 1943. 48 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Brotherhood of Railway Car Men jurisdiction; Los Angeles Central Labor Union; Machinists reinstatement in American Federation of Labor; United Mine Workers re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link106">0751. Meeting Minutes of January 17-27, 1944. 236 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anti-labor legislation in general and in Florida; Chemical Workers charter application; book on closed shop; centralization of United States Department of Labor; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists; American Federation of Labor
       Housing Committee Report; Bernardo Ibanez, Chilean Labor delegation; International Federation of Trade Unions; International Labor Office; Progressive Mine Workers of America protest United Mine Workers re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor;
       National Labor Relations Board amendment to authority; American Federation of Labor opposition to National Service Act; National War Labor Board powers protested; American Federation of Labor legal actions report; American Federation of Labor political
       activity; prisoners of war labor; postwar economic planning; Paul Robeson membership in Congress of Industrial Organizations; Eleanor Roosevelt; soldiers voting rights legislation; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link107">Minutes 1944-1945</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link108">0001. Meeting Minutes of January 17-27, 1944 (continued). 34 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topic: International Council of Office Employees Unions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link109">0035. Meeting Minutes of May 1-9, 1944. 179 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations political collaboration disapproved; anti-labor legislation; Brotherhood of Railway Clerks jurisdiction matters; Operating Engineers bargaining agency in oil refineries
       and jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; George-Murray bill on war contracts; America Federation of Labor Housing Committee; immigration and nationalization of Indians; labor conscription; United Mine Workers re-affiliation with American Federation of
       Labor; Montgomery Ward labor dispute; National War Labor Board; discrimination against African American workers; American Federation of Labor political platforms sent to major parties; Railway Clerks controversy with Railroad Telegraphers; Philadelphia
       Transportation Workers; Conference of Office Employees Unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link110">0214. Meeting Minutes of August 21-29, 1944. 111 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: British Trades Union Congress; Chemical Workers charter application; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists; American Federation of Labor litigation; Fair Labor Standards Act; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial
       Organizations peace negotiations; Ladies Handbag and Novelty Workers controversy; American Federation of Labor Housing Committee; American Federation of Labor representative visit to Italy; Office Employees charter application; American Federation of
       Labor litigation against anti-labor laws; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link111">0325. Meeting Minutes of November 19, 22, 28, and December 1, 1944. 46 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: British Trades Union Congress; National War Labor Board; Confederation of Workers of Latin America; Machinists dispute with Operating Engineers; United Mine Workers re-affiliation; World Trade Union Conference.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link112">0371. Meeting Minutes of February 5-15, 1945. 171 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anti-labor laws in Florida; Cannery Workers jurisdiction dispute with Teamsters over warehousemen; Central Labor Unions as collective bargaining agencies; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations peace
       initiative; Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor organizing; Operating Engineers dispute with Machinists; Federal Labor Unions; International Federation of trade Unions; discrimination against Japanese Americans; American Federation of Labor
       litigation; federal aid to education bill; work-or-fight bill; universal military training; Progressive Mine Workers of America protest re-affiliation of United Mine Workers; United Nations San Francisco convention; veterans aid; white-only democratic
       primary elections; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link113">0542. Meeting Minutes of April 30-May 8, 1945. 164 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor collaboration with Congress of Industrial Organizations in Canada; Aluminum Workers charter application; World trade Union Conference; Code of Principles for Labor and Management by American Federation of
       Labor; Congress of Industrial Organizations; and Chamber of Commerce; Congress of Industrial Organizations influence on postwar planning; Grain Processors charter application; American Federation of Labor meeting with farmers' organizations; amendments
       to National Labor Relations Act suggested by Metal Trades Department; African Americans relationship to American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor organizing policies; Theatrical Stage Employees dispute with Painters; postwar
       reconversion program; Executive Council meeting with President Truman; United Nations Conference in San Francisco; American Federation of Labor proposed amendments to Dumbarton Oaks Proposals; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor
       finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link114">0706. Meeting Minutes of August 6-14, 1945. 175 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Associated Actors and Artist; Code of Principles of American Federation of Labor, United States Chamber of Commerce, and Congress of Industrial Organizations; Aluminum Workers charter application; veterans seniority issues; Building
       Trades Department disputes with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; Canadian Seamen's Union; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Car Men, Railway, and Shop Crafts Brotherhoods; strike and jurisdiction controversy among Hollywood
       studio unions; Communist activity in southern California; Federal Industrial Relations Act; Hod Carriers dispute with Building Trades Department; American Federation of Labor litigation against state anti-labor legislation; amendments to National Labor
       Relations Act; organizing of women in industry; National Labor Relations Board; no-strike pledge discontinued; World Trade Union Conference; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link115">0881. Meeting Minutes of October 15-124, 1945. 100 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; anti- labor legislation in Massachusetts; British Trades Union Congress; Hollywood studio unions jurisdiction dispute between Carpenters, Painters, and Theatrical Stage Employees; withdrawal of
       Montreal, Canada, Trades and Labor Council; jurisdiction controversy between Operating Engineers and Firemen and Oilers in Louisville, Kentucky, strike; Farmers Cooperative meeting with American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor foreign
       policy statement; Ladies Handbag and Novelty Workers jurisdiction dispute; Mexican immigration; Government Employees Council formed; housing legislation; American Federation of Labor statements of housing, taxes, wages, and wage and price controls;
       Teamsters protest National Labor Relations Board ruling on California Cannery Workers jurisdiction to Congress of Industrial Organizations; World Trade Union Congress; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link116">Minutes 1945-1957</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link117">0001. Meeting Minutes of October 15-24, 1945 (continued). 62 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anglo-American Trade Union Committee; British Trades Union Congress; jurisdiction controversy between Operating Engineers and Firemen and Oilers in Louisville, Kentucky, hotel strike; Farmers Cooperative meeting with American Federation
       of Labor; Ladies Handbag and Novelty Workers jurisdiction dispute; Labor-Management Conference; League for Human Rights; jurisdiction controversy in Hollywood studios between Painters, Carpenters, and Theatrical Stage Employees; American Federation of
       Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link118">0063. Meeting Minutes of January 21-31, 1946. 202 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: United Nations; Air Force adequacy; Brewery and Soft Drink Workers re-affiliation; Hollywood studios strike and jurisdiction dispute among Operating Engineers, Carpenters, and Theatrical Stage Employees; federal labor legislation; Cuban
       labor situation; federal aid to education; jurisdiction dispute between Operating Engineers and Firemen and Oilers in Louisville, Kentucky, hotels; conditions in Germany; housing shortage; inflation and price controls; Latin American labor movement;
       anti-labor law in Florida; John L. Lewis elected vice president; Machinists jurisdiction controversies; Progressive Mine Workers of America oppose United Mine Workers re-affiliation; Japan and Philippines organization of labor unions; postwar
       reconversion of employment policies; American Federation of Labor resolution on Spain; State, County, and Municipal Employees competition with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor statements on federal labor legislation;
       housing in Germany; inflation; postwar reconversion; Spain and taxation; World Federation of Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; super-seniority litigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link119">0265. Meeting Minutes of May 15-22, 1946. 133 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor Financial Committee Report; federal anti-labor legislation, Case bill; Automobile Workers loan refinance and jurisdiction competition with Machinists; Brewery and Soft Drink Workers re-affiliation; Carpenters
       protest decision in Hollywood studio jurisdiction dispute; Teamsters activities in California; Cannery Workers on Pacific Coast protest National Labor Relations Board ruling; Communist activities in southern California; trade unions in Germany;
       Government Employees Council; United Mine Workers Health and Welfare Fund; Building Service Employees dispute with Hod Carriers and Laborers in Hollywood Studio jurisdiction; United States Senate investigation of industrial unrest; Latin American labor
       movements; Maritime Trades Council; Machinists affiliation status; Maritime Trades Council proposed; southern states organizing campaign; Pan American Labor Movement; union label application to grain products; Wisconsin State Federation of Labor
       competition with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link120">0398. Meeting Minutes of August 12-20, 1946. 184 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor Financial Committee Report; Hollywood studios jurisdiction settlement; Cannery Workers in California; Commercial Telegraphers jurisdiction extension and dispute with Communications Workers; Operating
       Engineers dispute with Machinists policies for Central Labor Unions and State Federations of Labor; federal aid to education; housing legislation; formation of Maritime Trades Council; Machinists dissociation from American Federation of Labor; National
       Farm Labor Union jurisdiction request; price controls; farmers cooperatives; Auto Workers jurisdiction over Farm Implement Manufacturers; labor conditions in Germany; American Federation of Labor housing program; International Labor Organization;
       Musicians Union opposition to Lea Bill amending Federal Communications Act; Minneapolis Central Labor Union and Congress of Industrial Organizations; Memphis Central Labor Union and Teamsters Union; southern states organizing campaign; United Textile
       Workers of America; American Federation of Labor membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link121">0582. Meeting Minutes of October 6 and 18, 1946. 40 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Alaska organizing efforts among Seafarers and Mine Workers; right-to-work legislation in Nebraska; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; southern organizing campaign; Germany; Hollywood studios jurisdiction controversy; American Federation
       of State, County, and Municipal Employees jurisdiction extensions to nurses; reinstatement of Railroad Signalmen; Railroad Brotherhoods; United Nations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link122">0622. Meeting Minutes of January 29-February 5, 1947. 145 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; Watch Workers Union charter application; anti-labor legislation; American Federation of Labor mission to Argentina; Metal Trades unions complaints
       about Automobile Workers Union; British Trades Union Congress; International Labor Office; agricultural workers wage ceiling; Firemen and Oilers merger negotiations with Operating Engineers; Auto Workers jurisdiction request over Farm Implement Workers;
       American Federation of Labor mission to Germany; American Federation of Labor Housing Committee report; Hollywood studio jurisdiction dispute between Carpenters and Theatrical and Stage Employees; American Federation of Labor jurisdiction policies in
       amusement industry; Moscow Peace Conference; salaries of American Federation of Labor organizers; slave labor; southern organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor resolution on Spain; American Federation of Labor statement on universal military
       training; right-to-work law in Nebraska; United Nations Security Council; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link123">0767. Meeting Minutes of April 21-25, 1947. 104 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Anti-labor legislation (Taft-Hartley Bill); Hollywood studio unions jurisdiction dispute; Metal Trades dispute with Automobile Workers; Firemen and Oiler merger with Operating Engineers; Carpenters dispute with Theatrical Stage Employees
       in Hollywood; Latin American labor movement; Machinists re-affiliation; southern organizing campaign; American Federation of Labor financial report and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link124">0871. Meeting Minutes of September 8-13, 1947. 141 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; American Federation of Labor policy against collaboration with Congress of Industrial Organizations; anti-labor legislation (Taft-Hartley Act);
       Canadian labor movement; Carpenters dispute with Theatrical Stage Employees over Hollywood jurisdiction; British Trades Union Congress; Germany conditions; inflation and price controls; report on Japan; non-communist affidavits; Brotherhood of Sleeping
       Car Porters dispute with Railway shop Craft Unions; Railroad Brotherhoods opposition to Taft-Hartley legislation; United Nations children's aid; women's commission.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link125">Minutes 1948-1950</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link126">0001. Meeting Minutes of January 26-February 3, 1948. 165 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor cooperation with Congress of Industrial Organizations against Taft-Hartley; American Federation of Labor litigation; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; anti-communism; southern organizing campaign; slave
       labor; American Heritage Foundation; Hollywood jurisdiction controversy; inflation and price control; jurisdiction dispute machinery; Labor's League for Political Education; American Federation of Labor-sponsored labor-management legislation; Latin
       American Confederation of Labor; equal pay of women; Fair Employment Practices bill; Marshall Plan; Minneapolis Central Labor Union collaboration with Congress of Industrial Organizations; National Farm Labor Union; contract with American Federation of
       Labor counsel Joseph Padway; Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Railroad Shop Craft Unions; migrant labor; Taft-Hartley Act; universal military training; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link127">0166. Meeting Minutes of May 10-14, 1948. 132 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor consultants to United Nations; Building and Construction Trades Department dispute with Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers Union; Chinese Federation of Labor;
       Department of Federal Labor Unions proposed; American Federation of Labor representation in European Recovery (Marshall) Plan; Grain Millers petition for charter; Jewelry Workers protest charter to Watch Workers; Inter-American Confederation of Labor;
       American Federation of Labor litigation; labor planks in political party platforms; Progressive Mine Workers of America; Sleeping Car Porters dispute with Railway Shop Crafts; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; American
       Federation of Labor International Labor Relations Department Report.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link128">0298. Meeting Minutes of August 23-27, 1948. 105 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor nonpartisan political policy in 1948 elections; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction problems; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; Chemical Workers jurisdiction problems; American
       Federation of Labor representation on Marshall Plan; Defense Fund to defend unions against anti-labor laws; American Federation of Labor activities in Hawaii; Machinists dispute with Teamsters and Retail Clerks in strike at Boeing Corporation, Seattle;
       American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link129">0403. Meeting Minutes of November 13-15, 19, and 23, 1948. 59 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor attitude toward Taft-Hartley Act; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress dispute with Railway Clerks; Cigar Makers merger with Tobacco Workers; American Federation of Labor organizing in Hawaii; Labor's League
       for Political Education; Seafarers International Union organizing on west coast; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers Union; American Federation of Labor legislative agenda.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link130">0462. Meeting Minutes of January 31-February 8, 1949. 167 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Amendments to National Labor Act; housing; World Federation of Trade Unions; American Federation of Labor statement on social justice; international affairs; Panama; repeal of Taft-Hartley Act; Building and Construction Trades Department
       jurisdiction matters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress relations with American Federation of Labor; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers jurisdiction matters; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; Congress of Industrial Organizations proposal for
       conference with American Federation of Labor and Railroad Brotherhoods; Communications Workers of America possible affiliation discussed; federal aid to education; labor in Hawaii; Hotel and Restaurant Employees Union organization in Miami, Florida;
       American Federation of Labor legislation agenda; Thomas amendments to National Labor Act; equal pay for women; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link131">0629. Meeting Minutes of May 16-20, 1949. 174 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity report; Air Line Pilots Association charter protested by Flight Engineers; Aluminum Workers charter application; United States foreign policy toward China; Bridge
       and Structural Iron Workers jurisdiction matters; Building and Construction trades Department jurisdiction matters; Carpenters dispute with Upholstery Workers; American Federation of Labor organization in Alaska; policies toward Federal Labor Unions;
       rent control; Workers Education Bureau; Hawaiian labor situation report; American Federation of Labor litigation report; repeal of Taft-Hartley Act; National Security Program; American Federation of Labor organization campaign; social security; Textile
       Workers of America jurisdiction matters; American Federation of Labor consultants to United Nations; World Federation of Free Democratic Unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link132">0803. Meeting Minutes of August 15-19, 1949. 136 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Aluminum Workers charter application; Bridge and Structural Iron Workers jurisdiction matters; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction matters; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress suspension of Seamen's Union; federal aid
       to education; Federal Labor Unions, strike benefits; labor situation in Hawaii; American Federation of Labor legislative program; Machinists re- affiliation with American Federation of Labor; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
       request for financial assistance; Seafarers International Union charter application; Marine Engineers charter application; Textile Workers of America jurisdiction matters; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link133">0939. Meeting Minutes of October 2, 5, and 11, 1949. 46 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations noncooperation in political matters; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction matters; Carpenters dispute with Upholsterers; age discrimination; government
       employees; Hawaii organizing drive; Israel labor movement; Labor's League for Political Education; Maintenance of Way Employees jurisdiction matters.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link134">0985. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 7, 1950. 105 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity; American Federation of Labor financial obligations to International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; displaced persons; Grain Millers dispute with Building and
       Construction Trades Department; housing; American Federation of Labor litigation report; Machinists re-affiliation negotiations; national defense; American Federation of Labor position on Point-Four Program; American Federation of Labor statement on
       genocide; public housing; repeal of Taft-Hartley Act; social security legislation; State, County, and Municipal Employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link135">Minutes 1950-1952</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link136">0001. Meeting Minutes of January 30-February 7, 1950 (continued). 25 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; report of American Federation of Labor Committee on Social Security.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link137">0026. Meeting Minutes of May 8-11, 1950. 108 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Building and Construction Trades Department complaint about raiding by United Mine Workers District 50; Carpenters-Upholsterers; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations political cooperation; American Federation
       of Labor litigation; Machinists re-affiliation with American Federation of Labor; State, County, and Municipal Employees in Pennsylvania and Montana; American Federation of Labor study on pension and welfare funds; fair labor standards in Puerto Rico;
       National Labor Relations Board reorganization; age discrimination; United States foreign policy; Federal Labor Union strike benefits; sugar Act of 1948; Swedish labor movement, invitation to American Federation of Labor delegation; white collar workers;
       Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link138">0134. Meeting Minutes of August 8-11, 1950. 84 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity committee and political cooperation; Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction dispute with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; national wage
       and price controls and rationing; Machinists re-affiliation; State, County, and Municipal Employees Union in Montana; printing trades unions dispute with Pulp, Sulphite, and Paper Mill Workers; Schumann Plan for joint French-German control of steel and
       coal; Workers Education Bureau; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link139">0218. Meeting Minutes of September 17 and 24, 1950. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organization unity negotiations; Arizona State Federation of Labor on Central Arizona Project; British Trades Union Congress; social security legislation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link140">0237. Meeting Minutes of January 22-29, 1951. 116 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; Florida citrus workers strike; New York State Defense Emergency Act; Hawaiian labor movement; Labor's League for Political Education; National Security
       Training Act of 1950; American Federation of Labor organizing activities; American Federation of Labor message to Russian people; Saint Lawrence Seaway Project; American Federation of Labor policy on strike benefits; amendments to Taft-Hartley Act;
       universal military training; Virginia right to work legislation; International Ladies Garment Workers Union dispute with New York Central Labor Union; American Federation of Labor litigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link141">0353. Meeting Minutes of May 14-18, 1951. 132 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor legislative program; report on American Federation of Labor finances; American Federation of Labor litigation; baseball players organization; Blacksmiths amalgamation with Boilermakers; Building and
       Construction trades Department jurisdiction dispute with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; National Farm Labor Union; Defense Housing Program; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; Leather Workers amalgamation with Butcher
       Workmen; Machinists jurisdiction dispute and raiding charges; wartime economic controls, wages, prices, and rationing; Saint Lawrence Seaway Project; amendments to Taft-Hartley Act; Veterans Preference Act; American Federation of Labor finances and
       membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link142">0485. Meeting Minutes of August 7-10, 1951. 79 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor withdrawal from unity negotiations with Congress of Industrial Organizations; American Federation of Labor finances studied; Canadian Trades and Labor Congress; agricultural organizations hostility toward
       organized labor; Building and Construction Trades Department dispute with Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees; National Farm Labor Union organization of dairy farmers; Soviet aggression in Europe; International Labor Organization; Federal Labor
       Unions strike benefits; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; Spanish fascism; National Labor Relations Board unfavorable decisions on Taft-Hartley; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link143">0564. Meeting Minutes of September 16, 23, and 25, 1951. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Textile Workers jurisdiction dispute with Hosiery Workers; non-Communist affidavits signed by Executive Council members; United Labor Policy Committee.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link144">0583. Meeting Minutes of January 28-February 5, 1952. 146 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Inflation; colonial undeveloped countries; Japan; American Federation of Labor litigation; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; Australian Council of Trade Unions; Building and
       Construction Trades Department dispute with Maintenance of Way Employees; Compulsory Military Training legislation; Communist-dominated labor unions; National Farm Labor Union; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; American Federation of
       Labor endorsement of Israeli bonds; Japanese Peace Treaty; Korea; National Labor Relations Board cases involving Machinists and Carpenters; American Federation of Labor cooperation with Mexican labor movement; mining disasters legislation; moral
       rearmament; American Federation of Labor organizing program; Longshoremen dispute with Teamsters and Printing Pressmen; racial violence in Florida; social security; subversive activities; Taft-Hartley repeal efforts; wage stabilization; American
       Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; federal tax policy.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link145">0729. Meeting Minutes of May 19-22, 1952. 137 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor legislative agenda; anti-labor bills; wage and price controls; displaced persons legislation; amendments to National Labor Relations Act; Saint Lawrence Seaway Project; National Agricultural Workers Union;
       Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction disputes; National Labor Relations Board cases involving Carpenters and Machinists; wage and price controls; National Council of Government Employees; International Confederation of free Trade
       Unions; American Federation of Labor report on immigration and naturalization; National Defense Program; Taft-Hartley amendments; social security benefit liberalization; moral rearmament; Puerto Rican constitution and labor movement; racketeering in
       labor unions; American Federation of Labor finances and membership; Teamsters jurisdiction disputes with Plumbers and Printing Pressmen; Texas State Federation of Labor; Ohio State Federation of Labor on labor unity; Federal Wage Stabilization
       Board.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link146">0866. Meeting Minutes of August 11-15, 1952. 93 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: United Automobile Workers of America; building and Construction Trades Department report; Carpenters dispute with Machinists; inflation and cost of living; GI Bill of Rights for Veterans of Korean War; Native Americans employment;
       Jewelry Workers charter controversy; racketeering among New York Longshoremen; American Federation of Labor organizing program in Michigan; political party conventions; Puerto Rico labor movement; women's auxiliaries; American Federation of Labor
       finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link147">0959. Meeting Minutes of September 14, 22, and 24, 1952. 46 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction dispute with Chemical Workers; presidential endorsements by American Federation of Labor; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity proposal by John
       L. Lewis; Justice Department ruling on television producers rights to motion picture productions; Puerto Rico labor movement; non-communist affidavits signed by American Federation of Labor Executive Council in compliance with Taft-Hartley Act;
       television; Textile Workers of America financial investigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">15</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link148">1005. Meeting Minutes of November 25, 1952. 17 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; death of William Green; election of George Meany as president of American Federation of Labor; election of William Schnitzler as secretary-treasurer of
       American Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link149">Minutes 1953-1955</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link150">0001. Meeting Minutes of February 2-9, 1953. 141 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; American Federation of Labor litigation; International Automobile Workers Union charter controversy; American Federation of Labor Civil Rights
       Department established; racketeering among New York Longshoremen; moral rearmament movement; Justice Department ruling on motion picture industry condemned; Postal Workers; Puerto Rico; assistance to Democrats in Congress; American Federation of Labor
       public relations program; Seafarers International Union dispute with Canadian Seamen's Union; anti-Semitism in Soviet Russia; Taft-Hartley Act amendments; United Textile Workers of America; undulant fever as an occupational disease; American Federation
       of Labor Report on Wages and Economic Stability; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link151">0142. Meeting Minutes of May 20-25, 1953. 153 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations Unity Committee; American Federation of Labor organization; International Union of United Automobile Workers charter controversy; Building Service Employees dispute with
       Federation of State, County, and Municipal Employees; National Association for the Advancement of Colored People financial appeal to American Federation of Labor; investigation of Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor; Marine Engineers Beneficial
       Association merger with Masters, Mates, and Pilots; British Trades Union Congress; Gas Workers Federal Labor Union jurisdiction dispute with Building Trades Unions; National Council of Government Employees protest contracts to private industry;
       International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; racketeering in New York Longshoremen's Unions; Machinists jurisdiction dispute with Building and Construction Trades Department; Brotherhood of Maintenance of Way Employees jurisdiction dispute with
       building and Construction Trades Department; American Federation of Labor no-raiding agreement with Congress of Industrial Organizations; housing and rent control; union security in Railroad Labor Unions; Taft-Hartley Act amendments; American Federation
       of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link152">0295. Meeting Minutes of august 10-14, 1953. 136 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: International Union of United Automobile Workers charter revoked; Building and Construction Trades Department report on jurisdiction disputes; Carpenters opposition to no-raiding agreement with Congress of Industrial Organizations;
       factionalism in Detroit and Wayne County Federation of Labor; relief fund for East Berlin workers; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; New York Longshoremen's racketeering; International Longshoremen's Association abolition of "shape-up"
       system; State, County, and Municipal Employees jurisdiction dispute with Building and Construction Trades Department; Teamsters organization of New York, New York, taxi drivers; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link153">0431. Meeting Minutes of September 20-21, 23, 26, and October 14, 1953. 53 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major topics: Building and Construction Trades Department jurisdiction disputes recommendations; Building Service Employees dispute with State, county, and Municipal Employees; International Longshoremen's Association charter revocation; American
       Federation of Labor-congress of Industrial Organizations unity negotiations; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations no-raiding agreement; Puerto Rico organizing campaign.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link154">0484. Meeting Minutes of February 1-9, 1954. 129 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations unity conference; Airline Pilots Association jurisdiction dispute with Machinists; Bricker Amendment; Equal Rights Amendment; Hatters strike in Norwalk, Connecticut;
       housing; International Confederation of Free Trade Unions; Italian labor movement; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations no- raiding agreement; congressional hearings on labor racketeering; Mexican migrant agricultural
       workers; Spanish fascism; German economic situation; National Labor Relations Board; Russia; Taft-Hartley Act amendments; Postal Employees; social security; American Federation of Labor litigation; union health and welfare funds; American Federation of
       Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link155">0610. Meeting Minutes of May 13 and 17-19, 1954. 129 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor litigation; American Federation of Labor constitution recodification; Railway Clerks dispute with Teamsters; unemployment and national economic outlook; housing policy; racial integration, American Federation
       of Labor statement on Brown versus Board of Education decision; Indochina; Israel; American Federation of Labor jurisdiction dispute plan; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; Sugar Workers charter application and dispute
       with Teamsters.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link156">0739. Meeting Minutes of August 9-12, 1954. 64 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American federation of Labor policy on internal disputes; Beet Sugar Workers charter application; American Federation of Labor statement on communism; Marine Engineers jurisdiction dispute with Seafarers International Union over Masters,
       Mates, and Pilots; Federal Labor Unions policies; Airline Pilots Association dispute with flight Engineers; International Longshoremen's Association; racial discrimination in employment in the South; National Urban League; American Federation of Labor
       finances; American Federation of Labor condemnation of 83rd Congress.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link157">0803. Meeting Minutes of September 19, 24, and 27, 1954. 31 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Associated Actors and Artists of America dispute with American Federation of Musicians; Marine Engineers dispute with Seafarers International Union; organization of Los Angeles "News" Company; Teamsters jurisdiction over Sugar workers
       investigated.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link158">0834. Meeting Minutes of December 15, 1954. 32 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: Amalgamated Meat Cutters merger with Fur and Leather Workers; Handbags and Novelty Workers merger with Butcher Workmen; American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger agreement.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link159">0866. Meeting Minutes of February 1-10, 1955. 128 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger agreement; American Federation of Labor litigation; Berlin, Germany, workers revolt; American Federation of Labor defense of Davis-Bacon Act; Building Service
       Employees International Union; Defense Mobilization manpower policies; Operating Engineers organization in metal mining industry; federal aid to education; Fur and Leather Workers merger with Amalgamated Meat Cutters; union health and welfare plans;
       American Federation of Labor policy on internal disputes; International Labor Relations Committee on Europe, Latin America, and Moscow-Peking; Taft-Hartley revision; organization of metal mining and smelting industry; Post Office Employees merger with
       Building Service Employees; American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics; National Labor Relations Board rulings on Taft-Hartley.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">16</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link160">0994. Meeting Minutes of May 2-4, 1955. 70 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution and merger plans; foreign policy toward Europe and Asia; Teamsters request for jurisdiction over Longshoremen; Amalgamated Meat Cutters merger with Fur and
       Leather Workers; Fair Labor Standards Act revision.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link161">Minutes 1955 and Executive Council Vote Books 1925-1929</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link162">0001. Meeting Minutes of May 2-4, 1955 (continued). 22 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topic: American Federation of Labor finances and membership statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link163">0023. Meeting Minutes of August 8-12, 1955. 121 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution; Building Service Employees suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; Electrical Workers suggestion on American
       Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; Flint Glass Workers jurisdiction dispute with glass Bottle Blowers over fabrication of fiberglass; Fur and Leather Workers merger with Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen; Israel-United
       States mutual security agreement; Metal Trades Department suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; American Federation of Labor statement on Soviet Union; Sleeping Car Porters suggestions on American
       Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; International Typographical Union suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; American Federation of Labor finances and membership
       statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link164">0144. Meeting Minutes of October 24-26 and November 3, 1955. 94 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American Federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations constitution; Air Line Pilots Association jurisdiction dispute with flight Engineers; Flight Engineers strike at United Air Lines; world peace; Fur and Leather Workers
       objection to merger with Meat Cutters and Butcher Workmen; Italy admission to United Nations; Laundry Workers International Union health and welfare fund; Independent Longshoremen agreement with Teamsters.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link165">0238. Meeting Minutes of November 30 and December 1, 1955. 36 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Major Topics: American federation of Labor- Congress of Industrial Organizations Constitutional Convention and merger agreement; Flight Engineers controversy with Air Line Pilots Association; Handbag and Novelty Workers dispute with Meat Cutters and
       Butcher Workmen; Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters suggestions on American Federation of Labor-Congress of Industrial Organizations merger; death of Daniel Tobin.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link166">0274. Executive Council Vote Books. January 1925-December 1925. 188 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link167">0462. Executive Council Vote Books. January 1926-August 1926. 200 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link168">0662. Executive Council Vote Books. September 1926-January 1927. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1926/1927">1926-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link169">0674. Executive Council Vote Books. February 1927-August 1927. 173 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">17</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link170">0847. Executive Council Vote Books. August 1927-July 1929. 219 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1927/1929">1927-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link171">Executive Council Vote Books 1929-1935</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">18</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link172">0001. Executive Council Vote Books. July 1929-February 1931. 213 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1929/1931">1929-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">18</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link173">0214. Executive Council Vote Books. February 1931-April 1933. 262 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1931/1933">1931-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">18</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link174">0476. Executive Council Vote Books. April 1933-September 1935. 257 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933/1935">1933-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="reel">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link175">Executive Council Vote Books 1935-1954</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">19</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link176">0001. Executive Council Vote Books. September 1935-April 1938. 358 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935/1938">1935-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">19</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link177">0359. Executive Council Vote Books. April 1938-December 1944. 337 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938/1944">1938-1944</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container type="reel">19</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link178">0696. Executive Council Vote Book. November 1944-September 1954. 290 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1944/1954">1944-1954</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>