<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-057::ILGWU Local 22 Education Department Records.)//EN">KCL05780-057</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Local 22 Education Department Records</titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Local 22 Education Department Records</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>June 13, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>June 13,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240223">02/23/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Local 22 Education Department Records</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780/057</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
                        Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, October 07, 2008</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Randall Miles, June 13, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">ILGWU Local 22 Education
                Department Records, 
            </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1930-1979</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/057</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU). Local 22</corpname>;
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">2 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Clippings, correspondence, newsletters,
                photographs, speeches.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">The records of the Education Department of Local 22 consist
                of correspondence, newspaper clippings, newsletters, programs, photographs, and
                speeches documenting the activities of the Department from the 1930s to the 1970s.
                In addition to documentating the Department's activities, there is material on the
                local's political involvement with the Liberal Party of New York State and some
                items about aid to the Republican cause during the Spanish Civil War. There are also
                some materials dealing with international labor cooperation, civil rights, and
                communism in the U.S. Correspondents include Joseph Mazur and Saby
                Nehama.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>2 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>The Education Department of Local 22 was developed to further the educational and
                cultural development of the Local's membership. It routinely sponsored lectures and
                courses on a variety of labor and other topics; it also offered musical and dramatic
                performances on a regular basis, either for or featuring its membership. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Local 22 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as
                the Dressmakers' Union, was chartered in December 1920 and based in New York City.
                The dress industry formed its own Joint Board in 1921 composed of Local 22
                Dressmakers, Local 25 Waistmakers, Local 58 Waist Buttonhole Makers, Local 60 Waist
                and Dress Pressers, Local 66 Bonnaz Embroidery Workers, Local 89 Italian Waist and
                Dressmakers, and the waist and dress branch of Cutters' Local 10. A general work
                stoppage in February 1923 in the dress industry won the union a 40 hour week and 10
                percent wage increase, as well as a large gain of new members. During the summer of
                1923, after years of discussion and deliberation, the two dress locals, Local 23 and
                22 were consolidated. The dressmakers from Local 23 transferred to Local 22 and
                subsequently Local 22 joined the New York Cloakmakers' Joint Board. Soon, the Dress
                and Waist Joint Board became unnecessary and was dissolved. Local 25 Waistmakers
                were left without an affiliated organization and in October 1924 merged with the
                Dressmakers' Union, Local 22. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>By the end of 1926, the Communists had gained control of the dress organization in
                New York City and the union barely existed. In February 4, 1930, 25,000 dressmakers
                walked out of the shops. The strike was called to reorganize dressmakers and finally
                abolish the Communist influence in the industry. On April 8, 1930 the General
                Executive Board decided to separate the dressmakers from the Cloakmakers' Joint
                Board. In 1931, Charles Zimmerman formed a committee to rebuild Local 22. He was
                elected to executive board of Local 22 in 1932, and elected manager-secretary in
                1933. Another walkout in all dress shops, both union and non-union on August 16,
                1933 brought the dress industry to a halt. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Zimmerman left Local 22 in 1958 to become manager of the Dress Joint Board. Israel
                Breslow succeeded him as manager of Local 22 from 1958 until his retirement in 1975.
                By 1975, the New York Dress Joint Board completed restructuring of affiliate locals,
                and Locals 60-60A, 159, and 38 were merged into existing Locals 22 and 89. Local 22
                gained jurisdiction over all dressmakers in Manhattan. In the 1980s, more locals
                were dissolved and members transferred to Local 22, but by 1984, Local 22 saw
                restructuring as well. Changes in the garment industry necessitated the dissolution
                of the Joint Board and Local 22 into the new Local 89-22-1.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>The records of the Education Department of Local 22 are made up of correspondence,
                newspaper clippings, newsletters, programs, photographs and speeches documenting the
                activities of the department from the 1930s to the 1970s. The newsletters, pamphlets
                and brochures detail the multitude of events and activities organized by the
                Education Department. The calendars in the collection show with daily listings, and
                illustrate the wide range of offerings with recreation such as concerts and gym
                classes, tap dancing and art workshops, and education with classes in English,
                citizenship, public speaking, trade unionism, social labor and legislation. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Education Department held dances and festivals, often specific to the many ethnic
                groups in the union, and organized excursions such as boat cruises, outings to Unity
                House, trips to Puerto Rico, and a tour of Spain, North Africa and Portugal. There
                are also records of Club 22, which was comprised of the women members of Local 22.
                Club 22 planned activities such as dances and holiday parties, and brought in
                speakers and held lectures. The collection contains programs, fliers and
                correspondence detailing the events put on by the club for each calendar year. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Within the local there was the Dressmakers Liberal Party Club formed in reaction to
                the passage of the Taft-Hartley bill to organize dressmakers for effective action on
                the political field. The group held meetings to discuss campaigns, candidates, and
                current politics that could affect dressmakers, and the records include membership
                lists, correspondence, and information about meetings. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The second series of the collection contains the correspondence of Saby Nehama.
                Nehama was the secretary of the Dressmakers Liberal Party, a Business Agent for
                Local 22, and worked in the Education Department.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Mazur, Joseph. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Nehama, Saby. </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    Local 22 (New York, N.Y.).Education Dept. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Liberal Party of New York State. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil rights--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Communism--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">International labor activities. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions and education--New York (State)--New
                    York. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Working class--Education--New York (State)--New
                    York. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">New York (State)--Politics and
                    government--1865-1950. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">New York (State)--Politics and government--1951-
                    . </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">Spain--History-- Civil War, 1936-1939. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>ILGWU Local 22 Education Department Records #5780/057. Kheel Center for
                    Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            
            <p>Related Collections:
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-014.html">
                    5780/014: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-014p.html">
                    5780/014 P: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Photographs</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-015.html">
                    5780/015: ILGWU Local 22 Records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-036.html">
                    5780/036: ILGWU Local 22 Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-057p.html">
                    5780/057 P: ILGWU Local 22 Education Department Photographs</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-067.html">
                    5780/067: ILGWU Local 22 Israel Breslow Papers</extref>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <arrangement>
            
            <p>
                <emph render="bold"><ref actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple" show="replace" target="link8">Series I: Subject Files, 1930-1973</ref></emph>
            </p>
            <p>
                <emph render="bold"><ref actuate="onrequest" linktype="simple" show="replace" target="link42">Series II: Saby Nehama Correspondence,
                    1949-1969</ref></emph>
            </p>
        </arrangement>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Series Series I: Subject Files, 1930-1973</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link9">Civil Rights</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1963">1963</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Robert Kennedy letter w. enclosed report on the progress in the field of
                            civil rights.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
                        <unittitle id="link10">Club 22</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1948/1957" type="inclusive">1948-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Announcements, programs, printed material and related correspondence.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
                        <unittitle id="link11">Club 22</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1958/1963" type="inclusive">1958-1963</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
                        <unittitle id="link12">Club 22</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1962">1962</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Includes undated material.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
                        <unittitle id="link13">Communism, U.S.A.</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1946/1951" type="inclusive">1946-1951</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
                        <unittitle id="link14">Contributions</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1948/1973" type="inclusive">1948-1973</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
                        <unittitle id="link15">Convention</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Newspaper clippings.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
                        <unittitle id="link16">The Dressmaker</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1962/1963" type="inclusive">1962-1963</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
                        <unittitle id="link17">Economic Cooperation Administration</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1948/1950" type="inclusive">1948-1950</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Incl. text of conversation between James B. Carey (CIO) and Giuseppe Di
                            Vittorio (Italian Confederation of Labor).</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
                        <unittitle id="link18">Education Department</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1933/1979" type="inclusive">1933-1979</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Announcements and programs.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link19">Education Department. Live and Let Learn.</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Local newsletter.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
                        <unittitle id="link20">Education Department</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1961/1971" type="inclusive">1961-1971</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Report 1962. Financial data, 1961,1971.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
                        <unittitle id="link21">Entertainment</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1936/1957" type="inclusive">1936-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
                        <unittitle id="link22">Excursions, Outings, Trips. [folder 1 of
                            4]</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1968" type="inclusive">1949-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
                        <unittitle id="link23">Excursions, Outings, Trips. [folder 2 of
                            4]</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1968" type="inclusive">1949-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
                        <unittitle id="link24">Excursions, Outings, Trips. [folder 3 of
                            4]</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1968" type="inclusive">1949-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
                        <unittitle id="link25">Excursions, Outings, Trips. [folder 4 of
                            4]</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1968" type="inclusive">1949-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
                        <unittitle id="link26">Excursions, Outings, Trips</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1966" type="inclusive">1950-1966</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Wilson Line Contracts.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
                        <unittitle id="link27">Is Economy Wealth? The Dressmakers' Struggle With the
                            I.L.G.W.U. (1920's) by Grace Palladino.</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1975">1975</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Thesis for B.A. Mount Holyoke College, South Hadley, Mass. 1975, 116
                            pp.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link28">Lena's Boy a play in three acts by Luby
                            Miller</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
                        <unittitle id="link29">Politics</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1952/1971" type="inclusive">1952-1971</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>General.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
                        <unittitle id="link30">Politics. Dressmakers Liberal Party Club. [folder 1
                            of 2]</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1947/1960" type="inclusive">1947-1960</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Call to meetings.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
                        <unittitle id="link31">Politics. Dressmakers Liberal Party Club. [folder 2
                            of 2]</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1947/1960" type="inclusive">1947-1960</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Call to meetings.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
                        <unittitle id="link32">Politics. Dressmakers Liberal Party Club.</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1961/1970" type="inclusive">1961-1970</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>District lists</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
                        <unittitle id="link33">Politics. Dressmakers Liberal Party Club.</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1951/1963" type="inclusive">1951-1963</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Membership lists</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link34">Politics. Dressmakers Liberal Party Club and Liberal
                            Party material</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1948/1961" type="inclusive">1948-1961</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
                        <unittitle id="link35">Politics. Liberal Party (and Dressmakers Liberal
                            Party Club)</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1965/1974" type="inclusive">1965-1974</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
                        <unittitle id="link36">Resolutions</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1934/1959" type="inclusive">1934-1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
                        <unittitle id="link37">Seminar (Local 22)</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1964">1964</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Croton-on-Hudson. June 1964.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
                        <unittitle id="link38">Spain</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Trade Union Relief for Spain.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
                        <unittitle id="link39">Spanish Dressmakers (Local 22)</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Incl. Left-wing material during the 1930's.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
                        <unittitle id="link40">Speeches</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1950/1959" type="inclusive">1950-1959</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
                        <unittitle id="link41">Taft-Hartley Act</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1957" type="inclusive">1949-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle id="link42">Series Series II: Saby Nehama Correspondence,
                        1949-1969</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
                        <unittitle id="link43">Bartoli, Jose (artist in Mexico)</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1949/1968" type="inclusive">1949-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
                        <unittitle id="link44">Calera, Marie (business agent)</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1954/1957" type="inclusive">1954-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>9/1/54-7/3/57. Correspondence during leave of absence in Spain &amp;amp;
                            Mexico.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
                        <unittitle id="link45">Inter-American Federation of Textile Garment and
                            Leather Workers Union</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1962/1969" type="inclusive">1962-1969</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Corres. w. trade unions in Central &amp;amp; South America.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
                        <unittitle id="link46">Spain</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1937/1952" type="inclusive">1937-1952</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Letters from Spanish Republican militiamen who came to U.S. for aid.
                            Subsequent letters from these visitors.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
                        <unittitle id="link47">United States Department of Labor, Bureau of Internal
                            Affairs</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1955/1968" type="inclusive">1955-1968</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link48">Images digitized from the collection.</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link49">Text digitized from the collection.</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>