<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780mf::ILGWU Robert Lazar's Guide to the Records on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05780mf</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Robert Lazar's Guide to the Records on
                        Microfilm<date> </date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Robert Lazar's Guide to the Records on
                    Microfilm</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>June 26, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>June 26,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Robert Lazar's Guide to the Records on
                Microfilm<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780 mf</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, June 26, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Randall Miles, June 26, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">ILGWU Robert Lazar's Guide to the
                Records on Microfilm, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1984</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780 mf</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>;<lb/>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator"> Lazar, Robert</persname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1 microfilm reel</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Microfilm, records (documents).</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection includes records and papers by union locals
                and officers of the ILGWU: <lb/> Local 10 (Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters
                Union); David Dubinsky (President) Papers; Louis Stulberg (General Secretary
                Treasurer) Papers; Frederick F. Umhey (Exectutive Secretary) Papers; Morris Sigman
                (President) Papers; Benjamin Schlesinger (President) Papers; Local 10 Records
                (Managers Correspondence); Local 9 (Cloak &amp; Suit Finishers Union)
                (Managers Correspondence); Local 22 Zimmerman, Charles S. - Dressmakers' Union
                Records; ILGWWU General Executive Board Minutes; New York Cloak Joint Board Records;
                Local 22 Records; Luigi Antonini (General Secretary, Italian Dressmakers' Union
                Local 89) Papers; Local 40 (Beltmakers' Union) Records; Upper South Dept. Baltimore
                Joint Board; Local 48 (Italian Cloakmakers Union) Records, Local 72, 192 - Toronto
                Cloak Joint Board Records, Locals 14, 68, 83, 92, 94; Chicago Joint Board Records;
                Joint Board Dress &amp; Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York;
                Cleveland Joint Board Records; Education Department Records (Fannia M. Cohn,
                Executive Secretary); Gus Tyler (Assistant President) Records; Local 105 Records;
                Local 155 Records; Boston Joint Board Records; Research Department - Collection
                Document; Southeast Region Records; Union Health Center Records; Miscellaneous;
                International Relations Department (henoch Mendelsund, Director) Records; San
                Francisco Joint Board Records. <lb/> A negative copy is available upon
                request.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.11 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <p>This collection includes records and papers by union locals and officers of the
                ILGWU: </p>
            <p>Local 10 (Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters Union); David Dubinsky (President)
                Papers; Louis Stulberg (General Secretary Treasurer) Papers; Frederick F. Umhey
                (Exectutive Secretary) Papers; Morris Sigman (President) Papers; Benjamin
                Schlesinger (President) Papers; Local 10 Records (Managers Correspondence); Local 9
                (Cloak &amp; Suit Finishers Union) (Managers Correspondence); Local 22
                Zimmerman, Charles S. - Dressmakers' Union Records; ILGWWU General Executive Board
                Minutes; New York Cloak Joint Board Records; Local 22 Records; Luigi Antonini
                (General Secretary, Italian Dressmakers' Union Local 89) Papers; Local 40
                (Beltmakers' Union) Records; Upper South Dept. Baltimore Joint Board; Local 48
                (Italian Cloakmakers Union) Records, Local 72, 192 - Toronto Cloak Joint Board
                Records, Locals 14, 68, 83, 92, 94; Chicago Joint Board Records; Joint Board Dress
                &amp; Waistmakers' Union of Greater New York; Cleveland Joint Board Records;
                Education Department Records (Fannia M. Cohn, Executive Secretary); Gus Tyler
                (Assistant President) Records; Local 105 Records; Local 155 Records; Boston Joint
                Board Records; Research Department - Collection Document; Southeast Region Records;
                Union Health Center Records; Miscellaneous; International Relations Department
                (henoch Mendelsund, Director) Records; San Francisco Joint Board Records. </p>
            <p>A negative copy is available upon request.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Lazar, Robert. </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers x Labor unions z United States.
                </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <p>ILGWU Robert Lazar''s Guide to the Records on Microfilm #5780 mf. Kheel Center
                    for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Robert Lazar's original 1984 guide to the ILGWU
                        collection</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>