<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
            publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06036-008::Newman,
Pauline M. Autobiography..)//EN"
            >KCL06036-008</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Newman, Pauline M. Autobiography.<date>
                    1969-1969</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Newman, Pauline M. Autobiography.</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>January 10, 2013</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kathryn Dowgiewicz,
                    <date>January 10, 2013</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Newman, Pauline M. Autobiography.<lb/></titleproper>
            <num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc484">Collection Number: 6036/008</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, January 10, 2013</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2013 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Newman, Pauline M. Autobiography.,
                    <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1969-1969</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">6036/008</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Newman, Pauline M.</persname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">.2 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence,
                photographs.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection consists of a manuscript of Pauline Newman's
                autobiography.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
            <p>Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities
                in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership
                size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American
                organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment
                industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members
                through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities,
                cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form
                the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a4" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
            <p>Pauline Newman was born in Lithuania around 1890 and came to the United States in
                1901 with her mother and sisters after the death of her father. Shortly after her
                arrival, she went to work to help support her family. After working in various
                factories, Newman became employed at the Triangle Shirtwaist Co. factory. Newman was
                involved in the 1909 Shirtwaist Makers' Strike and following the strike, became the
                first woman organizer for the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union,
                traveling through the Midwest and Northeast. By the time of the 1911 Triangle Fire,
                she was no longer employed at the factory, but many of her former coworkers perished
                in the fire and Newman marked the anniversary of the tragedy every year. In 1914,
                she served on the Joint Board of Sanitary Control in New York City, which was a
                combined trade union and manufacturers' unit designed to establish standards for
                maintaining sanitary conditions in the shops. From 1918 to her retirement, Newman
                was the director of education for the Union Health Center. As health educator, she
                arranged for lectures and programs, created an innovative preventive health care
                program, and served as a liaison between the medical staff and the local unions.
                Newman often spoke on behalf of workers' health care before city, state and federal
                government panels. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Additionally, Newman was a member and officer of numerous labor and civic
                organizations, including the Women's Trade Union League, United Nations Commission
                on the Status of Women, the advisory committee of the U.S. Department of Labor's
                Women's Bureau, the New York State Commission on enforcing equal pay law, and the
                New York State Department of Labor's Minimum Wage Board. She died in 1986 at the age
                of 96.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
            <p>The collection consists of Pauline Newman's autobiography in the form of a letter
                addressed to Michael and Hugh in which she recounts stories and details of her life
                while she is on board a ship heading to Switzerland to attend a meeting of the
                International Labor Organization. In her recollections, Newman begins with her
                childhood and village life in Lithuania and discusses immigrating to the U.S. after
                the death of her father in 1901. She vividly details the difficult trip across the
                Atlantic and the conditions for new immigrants upon arrival in New York. Newman
                writes about her early employment experiences in various factories before ultimately
                finding work in the garment industry. Of particular interest are the passages in
                which she describes her employment at the Triangle Shirtwaist Company, including the
                inhuman working conditions in the factory, the long hours, and the little pay.
                Newman also spends time discussing her activities outside the ILGWU, including her
                involvement in the Socialist Party and the Socialist Literary Society. She provides
                a first-hand account of the Shirtwaist Makers' Strike of 1909 and her subsequent
                work with the ILGWU, including her organizing trips and assignments across the
                country.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Newman, Pauline. </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> UNITE HERE (Organization) </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile
                    Employees. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655"> Autobiography</genreform>
            </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>Newman, Pauline M. Autobiography. #6036/008. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU
                    records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-060.html"> 5780/060:
                    ILGWU. Union Health Center records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-171.html"> 5780/171:
                    ILGWU. Union Health Center publications</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link6">Letters to Michael and Hugh from P.M. Newman</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
