<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05445::Teachers Union of the City of New York Records.)//EN">KCL05445</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Teachers Union of the City of New York Records<date>
                        1920-1942</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Teachers Union of the City of New York
                    Records</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 13, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 13,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Teachers Union of the City of New York
                Records<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5445</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, August 02, 2005</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Teachers Union of the City of New
                York Records, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1920-1942</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5445</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Teachers Union of the City of New
                    York</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">4.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents).</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Organization with a long history of radical involvement.
                Substantial materials on the Lusk Commission, teachers dismissals for unpopular
                political views during the 1950's, etc.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
            <p>The Teacher's Union, Local 5, was organized in 1916 as an affiliate of the American
                Federation of Teachers, (A.F. of L.) by Henry R. Linville, Abraham Lefkowitz and a
                few other pioneering teachers in New York City. </p>
            <p>Perhaps the most significant contribution of the T.U. during those early years was
                its fight on behalf of civil liberties, an area in which it would later become a
                formidable combatant. Its principal target was the repeal of the Lusk laws, statutes
                which allowed for the revocation of a teacher's license "if he is not of good moral
                character -- or if by act or utterance he shows that he will not support the
                constitution of the State or of the United States of America." </p>
            <p>During the 1920's the T.U. continued its fight for increased salaries commensurate
                with the higher cost of living, reduced classroom size, tenure for teachers,
                improvements in the pension system, and increased state aid education.
                Unfortunately, the results rarely met the organization's expectations. </p>
            <p>About 1925, organized political factions began appearing within the T.U.'s ranks.
                After 1929, two such groups were dominant in their opposition to the majority
                organization: the "Rank and File" group which represented the official Communist
                Party of America, and the "Progressive" group which represented a faction within the
                Communist movement opposed to the official party. </p>
            <p>The leadership of Local 5 soon realized that it was helpless in the factional battle
                that ensued because of an overly liberal constitution, which had been designed to
                insure the rights of all minority groups whatever their objectives. In an attempt to
                rid its house of revolutionary elements, on October 27, 1932, at a large membership
                meeting, a Committee of Five was selected to try five members of the Rank and File
                group and one member of the Progressive group on the charge of disruptive conduct. </p>
            <p>John Dewey, chairman, delivered the unanimous report of the Committee on April 29,
                1933 before a Membership meeting of approximately 800. As was anticipated, the
                Committee reported that the primary cause of the intolerable strife within the
                Teachers' Union was due to the existence and activity of the two Communist organized
                factions. With the support of both the Executive Board and the Delegate Assembly,
                the local petitioned the national office to investigate the local and sought to have
                the local's old charter revoked so that a new local might be formed without the
                Communist element. </p>
            <p>In May 1935, the national office sent an investigating committee composed of its
                president, secretary-treasurer and its Washington representative. The Committee's
                finding was that the local union "was 'helpless' and 'completely at the mercy of a
                small obstructionist group in the local', and that the obstructionist's group was
                itself 'not free to formulate its own policies but was subject to a political force
                which is itself fundamentally opposed to basic principles for which the union
                attends.'" </p>
            <p>Despite this report of the investigating committee, a request by the administration
                of the Teachers Union to reorganize the local was turned down at the A.F.T. National
                Convention in August 1935 by a vote of 100 to 79. As a result, October 1, 1935,
                Henry R. Linville and Abraham Lefkowitz led eight hundred dissatisfied members out
                of the Teachers Union and into the newly formed independent Teachers Guild. Also
                among the seceding members were all the officers (with the exception of one) and a
                majority of the Executive Board. </p>
            <p>In 1936, the Executive Council of the American Federation of Labor, as a result of
                testimony taken before a sub-committee in Washington, recommended to the American
                Federation of Teachers that it revoke the charter issued to Teachers Union Local 5.
                The A.F.T., however, did not see fit to abide by this recommendation. </p>
            <p>On March 15, 1938 the Greater New York Central Trades and Labor Council suspended the
                Teachers Union from membership in its organization. Also in March, Teachers Union,
                Local 5 was expelled from the Joint Committee of Teachers Organizations of New York
                City. </p>
            <p>Again in 1941, the subject of Local 5's charter revocation came up before the
                American Federation of Teachers. However, this time the Executive Council
                recommended (with one dissenting vote) revocation and their action was
                overwhelmingly endorsed by the delegates at the Conventions in August 1941, at
                Detroit. After having its charter revoked, the Teachers Unions continued as Local
                555 of the United Public Workers of the Congress of Industrial Organizations. The
                C.I.O. in February 1950 expelled the United Public Workers due to its alleged
                Communist domination. The Teachers Union, however, continued its association with
                the U.P.W. until it withdrew in February 1952. </p>
            <p>Finally, in 1964, at the suggestion of Rose Russell, one of the T.U.'s guiding
                lights, the annual convention dissolved the T.U. with the recommendation that its
                members unite with the other forces in the New York City Teacher's Movement. On June
                20, prior to the 1941 Convention, the Teachers Guild accepted the offer of a charter
                and was reunited with the American Federation of Teachers. Although it retained its
                name of the Teachers Guild, it was now designated Local 2, AFT. </p>
            <p>The Teachers Guild during this period increased in both size and strength. In March,
                1960, the Teachers Guild merged with the CATU (Committee of Action Through Unity) to
                form the United Federation of Teachers. Under the auspices of the New York City
                Labor Department and empowered by the Board of Education, a representation election
                was scheduled and held on December 15, 1961. The results were overwhelmingly in
                favor of the U.F.T. (Local 2, AFT) and so the following August the Board of
                Education and the U.F.T. entered into their first collective bargaining
                relationship.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Teachers' Union of the City of New York </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">American Federation of Teachers. Local 5 (New
                    York, N.Y.) </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects: </head>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Teachers' unions -- New York (State) -- New York. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Teachers' -- New York (State) -- New York. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions and communism -- New York (State) --
                    New York. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil rights -- New York (State) -- New York. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>Teachers Union of the City of New York Records #5445. Kheel Center for
                    Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05015.html"> 5015:
                    Teachers Union of the City of New York Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05015av.html"> 5015 AV:
                    Teachers Union of the City of New York Audio- Visual Materials</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05015mf.html"> 5015 mf:
                    Teachers Union of the City of New York Executive Board Minutes on
                    Microfilm</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05015mb.html"> 5015 MB:
                    Teachers Union of the City of New York SCMWA Local 555 Anne Grant Pin
                    Memorabilia</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05927.html"> 5927:
                    Teachers Union of the City of New York Additional Records</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1-4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Academic Freedom</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1921/1938">1921-1938</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">5-7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Academic Freedom Resolution</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938/1939">1938-1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Academic Freedom Case</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">9-11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Academic Freedom Democracy in Schools -
                        Questionnaire</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">12-13</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Academic Freedom The Signpost, etc.</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link13">Academic Freedom Committee</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930/1939">1930-1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">2-3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">Academic Freedom Committee, American Civil Liberties
                        Union</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1920/1935">1920-1935</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">4-5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link15">Academic Freedom Committee, Anti-Hearst
                        Campaign</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1935/1937">1935-1937</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link16">Academic Freedom Committee, Anti-War
                        Symposium</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link17">Academic Freedom Committee, Anti-War
                        Telegrams</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1941">1940-1941</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">8-13</container>
                    <unittitle id="link18">Academic Freedom Committee, Ives Loyalty Oath</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930/1936">1930-1936</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">14</container>
                    <unittitle id="link19">Academic Freedom Committee, Program for
                        Democracy</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1938/1939">1938-1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">15</container>
                    <unittitle id="link20">Academic Freedom Committee, Dr. Bertrand
                        Russell</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">3</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link21">Child Resignation - Counts</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">3</container>
                    <container type="folder">2-10</container>
                    <unittitle id="link22">Convention-American Federation of Teachers</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">3</container>
                    <container type="folder">11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link23">Dies Committee</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1939/1940">1939-1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link24">Case file</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1926/1929">1926-1929</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link25">Case file</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1922/1926">1922-1926</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link26">Labor Defense Council</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link27">Legal Aid and Grievance</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1934/1938">1934-1938</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link28">Legal Suits vs Board of Education</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936/1937">1936-1937</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <container type="folder">6-11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link29">Lusk Laws</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1920/1924">1920-1924</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">5</container>
                    <container type="folder">1-5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link30">Case file</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">5</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link31">Minutes of Teachers Union</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">5</container>
                    <container type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link32">Case files</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">5</container>
                    <container type="folder">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link33">Monroe High School - Case</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933/1934">1933-1934</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">5</container>
                    <container type="folder">9</container>
                    <unittitle id="link34">Case file</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">6</container>
                    <container type="folder">1-11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link35">Case file</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1942">1940-1942</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">7</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link36">Referendum on War Resolutions</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">7</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link37">Released Time-Religious Instruction</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1923/1940">1923-1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">7</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link38">Releases</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1936/1941">1936-1941</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">7</container>
                    <container type="folder">4-12</container>
                    <unittitle id="link39">Revocation</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">7</container>
                    <container type="folder">13</container>
                    <unittitle id="link40">Revocation - AFT vs Local 5</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">8</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link41">Special Committee on Left-Wing Activities</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">8</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link42">Statement of Police</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">8</container>
                    <container type="folder">3-4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link43">Teachers League for Academic Freedom</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">8</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link44">Witch Hunting Legislative Committee</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">8</container>
                    <container type="folder">6-7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link45">Zysman, Dale - Case</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1941/1942">1941-1942</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">9</container>
                    <container type="folder">All</container>
                    <unittitle id="link46">Miscellaneous</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>