<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
 <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
  <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06174-018::NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files..)//EN">KCL06174-018</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files.<date> 1988-2011</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files.</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
    <date>November 06, 2014</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>November 06, 2014</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files.</titleproper>
   <num>Collection Number: 6174/018</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, September 15, 2011</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Randall Miles, November 06, 2014</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2014 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   
   <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files., 1988-2011</unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1988-2011</unitdate>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">6174/018</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)</corpname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Neira, Maria</persname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">5.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">As vice president of New York State United Teachers, Maria Neira oversees the union's initiatives on educational policy and is NYSUT's frontline advocate to the New York State Board of Regents and the State Education Department.
    At her direction, the NYSUT Education &amp;amp; Learning Trust, the union's professional development arm, has strengthened and expanded educational opportunities for teachers and other school staff. 
     Neira was appointed by President Obama to serve on the President's Advisory Commission on Educational Excellence for Hispanics. She also serves on the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute Advisory Council. She is a member of the National Board for
    Professional Teaching Standards and the founding publisher of Educator's Voice. 
     An AFT vice president, she also serves as a vice president of the New York State AFL-CIO Executive Council and as a member of the Board of Directors of the AFL-CIO's Workforce Development Institute. She is a member of the New York State Workforce
    Investment Board, the Greater Capital Region United Way Board of Directors, Capital District's 100 Hispanic Women, the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement and the National Association of Latino Elected Officials Education Fund. She directs NYSUT's
    fundraising as a statewide flagship sponsor for American Cancer Society programs, including the Making Strides Against Breast Cancer annual walks in which union volunteers have raised millions for the cause. She has served on many state committees,
    including the governor's Children's Cabinet Advisory Board and the State Committee of Practitioners, and is a member of several other professional organizations. 
     Neira is a recipient of the Ellis Island Medal of Honor from the National Ethnic Coalition of Organizations, the Educational Leadership Award of the National Puerto Rican Day Parade and the YMCA Northeast New York Woman of Achievement Award. She has
    been honored by the United Federation of Teachers Hispanic Affairs Committee, the Hispanic Latino Cultural Center, Long Island Latino Teachers Association, the Schenectady Hispanic Heritage Committee and the Girl Scouts of Northeastern New York. 
     She previously served as assistant to the president on education issues for the United Federation of Teachers, NYSUT's affiliate in New York City public schools, where she directed a wide range of education initiatives and helped develop strategic
    plans for education reform. She also served as director of the UFT's Special Educator Support Program. Neira began her teaching career in New York City in 1977 and was a fourth-grade bilingual teacher at the Bilingual Bicultural Mini School in Manhattan. 
     Neira holds a B.A. and an M.S. from Hunter College of the City University of New York.</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  <physdesc><extent>5.5 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   
   <p>New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with
    the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the
    AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO. </p>
   <p>In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY. </p>
   <p>NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to
    ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations. </p>
   <p>While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for
    teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions. </p>
   <p>NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   
   <p>As vice president of New York State United Teachers, Maria Neira oversees the union's initiatives on educational policy and is NYSUT's frontline advocate to the New York State Board of Regents and the State Education Department. At her direction, the
    NYSUT Education &amp;amp; Learning Trust, the union's professional development arm, has strengthened and expanded educational opportunities for teachers and other school staff. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira was appointed by President Obama to serve on the President's Advisory Commission on Educational Excellence for Hispanics. She also serves on the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute Advisory Council. She is a member of the National Board for
    Professional Teaching Standards and the founding publisher of Educator's Voice. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>An AFT vice president, she also serves as a vice president of the New York State AFL-CIO Executive Council and as a member of the Board of Directors of the AFL-CIO's Workforce Development Institute. She is a member of the New York State Workforce
    Investment Board, the Greater Capital Region United Way Board of Directors, Capital District's 100 Hispanic Women, the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement and the National Association of Latino Elected Officials Education Fund. She directs NYSUT's
    fundraising as a statewide flagship sponsor for American Cancer Society programs, including the Making Strides Against Breast Cancer annual walks in which union volunteers have raised millions for the cause. She has served on many state committees,
    including the governor's Children's Cabinet Advisory Board and the State Committee of Practitioners, and is a member of several other professional organizations. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira is a recipient of the Ellis Island Medal of Honor from the National Ethnic Coalition of Organizations, the Educational Leadership Award of the National Puerto Rican Day Parade and the YMCA Northeast New York Woman of Achievement Award. She has been
    honored by the United Federation of Teachers Hispanic Affairs Committee, the Hispanic Latino Cultural Center, Long Island Latino Teachers Association, the Schenectady Hispanic Heritage Committee and the Girl Scouts of Northeastern New York. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira previously served as assistant to the president on education issues for the United Federation of Teachers, NYSUT's affiliate in New York City public schools, where she directed a wide range of education initiatives and helped develop strategic
    plans for education reform. She also served as director of the UFT's Special Educator Support Program. Neira began her teaching career in New York City in 1977 and was a fourth-grade bilingual teacher at the Bilingual Bicultural Mini School in Manhattan. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira holds a B.A. and an M.S. from Hunter College of the City University of New York.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
   
   <p>Covers 2006-2010, with a few folders 1988-1991. In addition to records of NYSUT's Division of Research and Educational Services, which fell under the purview of the First Vice President, the files document the activities of Maria Neira more generally, in
    her role as a member of the NYSUT Board of Directors, Executive Committee, Cabinet, Officers' Committee, Administrative Committee, NYSUT Policy Council, National Board for Professional Teaching Standards, and the Education and Learning Trust. Meeting
    agendas and minutes of these entities are heavily featured, as well as speeches and reports prepared by Neira. Minutes and materials of NYSUT's political action arm, VOTE/COPE, and its lobbying group, the Committee of 100, are also included. Topics cover
    closing the academic achievement gap, credit recovery (attempts to allow students who missed class to make up course credit online, in order to graduate), charter schools, vocational training and other programs for non-college-bound students, and the state
    response to federal programs under presidents G. W. Bush and Obama, No Child Left Behind and Race to the Top, respectively.</p>
  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
   
   <controlaccess>
    
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Neira, M. (Maria) </persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers. Archives </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Teachers' union, New York (State) </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   
   <accessrestrict>
    
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    
    <p>NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files. #6174/018. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   
   <p>Related Collections:
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-003.html"> 6174/003: NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services Files.</extref>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-016.html"> 6174/016: NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files.</extref> All other 6174 collections </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">100 Hispanic Women Gala</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/30/09 at 6:30PM in Franklin Plaza. List of guests by table; cover memo to Gala Committee with facilitative details</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link7">100 Hispanic Women Gala Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tuesday, August 18, 2009. Program for second annual gala; committee agenda; list of sponsorship levels; correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link8">100 Hispanic Women Third Annual Membership Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Saturday, April 18, 2009. Agenda for third annual membership meeting; mission statement and list of board of directors; membership application; committee description of Capital District Chapter; April 2009 issue of Latino New York</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link9">100 HW Annual Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/18/09 at 9:00AM in NYSUT HQ. Drafts 1 and 2 of agenda for annual membership meeting; flyer for annual meeting; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link10">100 HW Leadership Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>7/23/08 at 6:00PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Memos with list of committee members, meeting agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link11">100 Hispanic Invoice for 2008 Gala</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invoice from NYSUT for printing</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link12">100 Hispanic Annual Membership Mtg.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/7/08. Outline of presentation; outline of presentation re Capital District Chapter; memos; CD disk re annual meeting; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link13">100 Hispanic Women Capital District Inc. Membership</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Membership application from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link14">100 Hispanic Women Strategic Planning Forum Guidelines</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Strategic Planning Forum agendas; Strategic Planning Forum Priorities; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link15">NYSUT BOCES Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/11/09 at 10:30AM in NYSUT. Publication re NYS Boards of Cooperative Education (BOCES); brochure; draft discussion paper, "Draft Framework for a New York State High School Exiting Credential," December 11, 2009; agenda for NYSUT BOCES Committee
      meeting; list of NYSUT committee responsibilities</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link16">BOCES</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/24/09 at 1:00PM in Conference Room A. Agenda for NYSUT/BOCES District Superintendent Committee meeting; handwritten note re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link17">BOCES Teachers Association Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/18/09 at 5:30PM in Western NY NYSUT Office. Text of remarks by NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to ED 3 meeting; newspaper clipping re Regents effort to improve teaching; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link18">BOCES</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/11/09 at 3:00PM at Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Handwritten notes from meeting; list of contact information for 2008- 2011 BOCES Statewide Planning Committee</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link19">BOCES</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/27/09. Agenda for NYSUT/BOCES District Superintendent Committee</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link20">BOCES Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/04/08 at Empire State Plaza. List of participants; letter reminding NYSUT officers of plans to lobby members of state legislature; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link21">BOCES Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/10/10 at 10:30AM in NYSUT Conference Center. BOCES Statewide Planning Committee agenda; Report on Special Education (cost containment proposals); draft program for 38th annual NYSUT Conference for BOCES Leadership, October 22-23; list of BOCES local
      presidents by ED</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link22">BOCES District Superintendent Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/27/09 at 12:30PM in Executive Conf. Rm 2. NYSUT/BOCES District Superintendent Committee agenda; list of meeting dates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link23">Capital Region BOCES Collaboration Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/19/08 at 9AM. Facilitative correspondence re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link24">Children's Cabinet Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summary of meeting of Governor's Children's Cabinet Advisory Board, August 15, 2007; communication to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira requesting submission of Appointments Questionnaire for possible appointment to advisory committee, with attached NYS
      Police Application for Confidential Background Investigation; list of Children's Cabinet Advisory Board Members; biographical sketches of members; work group agenda re quality early learning programs, October 30; focus group reports re child care quality
      rating system; draft standards; materials re quality rating system; press release from Executive Chamber, "Governor Spitzer Encourages Child Health Plus Enrollment to Insure New York's Children," August 9, 2007; report by advisory board, "A Description
      of New York State Early Learning Programs," August 15; Executive Order establishing the Governor's Children's Cabinet; brochure by National Center for Children in Poverty, Columbia University, "Promoting Effective Early Learning: What Every Policymaker
      and Educator Should Know," January 2007; document, "Universal Coverage for Children: Framing the Problem for Children's Cabinet," comparing Medicaid with Child Health Plus; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link25">BOCES Pre-Conference Workshop</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/3/08 at 3PM in Gideon Putnam Resort, Saratoga, Springs NY. Flyer announcing BOCES Pre-Conference Workshop re disability awareness</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link26">Oswego Boces</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Reprint request forms and photographs; note of thanks to Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link27">BOCES: The Tech Valley Consortium</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Publication, "Connecting the P-16 Educational System &amp;amp; 21st Century Business Environment," with cover note to Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link28">Children's Cabinet Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/3/09 at 10:30am. Descriptions and goals of Early Childhood Advisory Council workgroup, Subcommittee on Children with Incarcerated Parents, Subcommittee on Child Welfare/Juvenile Justice; New York Times editorials decrying conditions at juvenile
      detention facilities; policy briefs by New York State Afterschool Network (NYSCAN)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link29">Children's Cabinet Advisory</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/09/09 at 10:30AM in Blue Room, State Capitol. Notice of cancellation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link30">Tax Cap</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/07/08 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm 2. Memos re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link31">Stimulus Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/27/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link32">Healthcare Talking Points</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Talking points on health care, November 7, 2009; press release, "House Passage of Affordable Health Care Is a Victory for All Americans: Statement of Randi Weingarten, President, American Federation of Teachers," November 7, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link33">Education Finance Research Consortium</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/31/08 at 8:30AM in State Museum. Invitation to attend presentation, "Three Reports on K-12 Education in New York State," re property taxes, financial management in charter schools, and variations in teacher contracts</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link34">Property Tax Commission</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/15/08 at 9:15AM in Dick's Office. Memo re meeting to discuss NYSUT's role in Property Tax Commission</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link35">The New York State Education Department 2008-2009 Regents Budget Proposal</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008/2009" type="inclusive">2008-2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed document, 2008-2009 Regents Budget Proposal</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link36">Children's Advisory Board</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/04/09 at 10:30AM in State Capitol, Blue Room. Agenda; summary of February 26 meeting; briefing for June 4 meeting, focusing on disconnected youth; Progress Report on the Recommendations from the People First Forums, August 2008, re delivery of
      mental health/ developmental disabilities/alcohol abuse treatment services</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link37">Children's Cabinet Advisory</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/26/09 at 10:30AM in Blue Room, State Capitol. Agenda; Presentations by the Subcommittee of the Workgroup on Disconnected Youth, February 26; Preliminary Recommendations to Address the Needs of Children with Incarcerated Parents; Progress Report,
      Local Implementation of Children's Health Insurance Enrollment Efforts Work Group; list of members of Advisory Board to be appointed to the Early Childhood Advisory Council</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link38">Children's Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>7/31/08 at 10:30AM in Blue Room of the Capitol. Memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link39">Children's Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>July 31, 2008 at 10:30-2:30pm in Blue Room, 2nd Fl Capitol. Agenda; Project Brief for Early Childhood Comprehensive Systems Planning Initiative; talking points re tax cap; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link40">Children's Cabinet Advisory Bd.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/8/08 at 10:30am in State Capitol, Blue Rm. Universal Pre-K (UPK) Implementation Work Group Report to the Advisory Board, May 8; Early Learning Financing Work Group Report to the Advisory Board, May 8; response to recommendations; budget
      highlights</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link41">Children's Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/01/08 at 10:30AM in ESP Concourse Level, Meeting Rm. 6. Meeting notice</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link42">Children's Cabinet Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Filled-in appointments questionnaire, authorization for disclosure of protected health information, and application for confidential police background check for NYSUT vice president Maria Neira for appointment to the Children's Cabinet Advisory
      Committee; Excerpts from the NYS Public Officers Law and other laws and regulation related to Ethics in State Government, from the NYS Ethics Commission; Neira resume;</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link43">Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to Maria Neira from Federation of Protestant Welfare Agencies, urging Children's Cabinet to support proposed legislation to aid disconnected youth, December 18, 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link44">Children's Cabinet: Teenage Births, Outcomes for Teen Parents and their Children</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008/2009" type="inclusive">2008-2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 2008 report by Schuyler Center for Analysis and Advocacy, send to Maria Neira in her role as a member of the Children's Cabinet Advisory Board</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link45">Children's Cabinet Quality Stars NY</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program for 30th Anniversary Celebration for Center for Women in Government and Civil Society, September 25, 2008; meeting summary for Quality Stars NY webinar; description of Quality Stars NY, a program of the NYS Office of Children and Family
      Services</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link46">Committee of 100 NYSUT</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 23-24, 2009. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use
      after meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, SUNY, CUNY, retirement, health and safety)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link47">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/15-16/10. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after
      meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, SUNY, CUNY, retirement, health care, charter schools); flyer re teachers centers; letter to legislators in
      advance of lobby day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link48">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/11/10. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after
      meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, SUNY, CUNY, retirement, health and safety); projected school district job losses, updated May 10, 2010</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link49">NYSUT Committee of 100 Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/03/09 at 10AM in Albany, NY. Agenda for extraordinary meeting of Committee of 100/lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance
      Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; issues briefing sheet</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link50">Committee of 100 Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 2-3, 2009. Testimony to the Senate Finance Committee on the proposed 2009-10 Executive Budget, prepared by Professional Staff Congress/CUNY, January 15, 2009; agenda for higher education lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members
      of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after meetings with individual legislators; flyer, Invest in Higher Education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link51">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/12-13/08. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after
      meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, SUNY, CUNY, retirement, health and safety)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link52">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/17-18/08. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after
      meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, SUNY, CUNY), opposition to tax cap</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link53">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/17/08 in Desmond. Agenda for Political Action Committee meeting and lobby day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link54">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/07-08/07 at 8PM in Desmond Hotel. NYSUT Research Department Contract Language for Peer Review and or Portfolio (actual contract language from various locals); State Education Department Regents Priority Proposal: Adding to the Prospective Pool of
      Qualified Teachers: Re-Employing Retired Public Employees as Teachers in Hard-to-Staff Schools; working drafts of growth models; materials re tenure decisions; handwritten notes from meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link55">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/11-12/09. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets for use after
      meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, higher education, health and safety issues, labor and retirement)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link56">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/11-12/09 in Desmond Hotel. Agenda for lobby day; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Assembly and Senate Education Committee, Higher Education Committee, Ways and Means Committee, Finance Committee, with office numbers; note sheets
      for use after meetings with individual legislators; list of members of NYSUT Legislative Department; briefing sheets re issues of importance to NYSUT (K-12, higher education, health and safety issues, labor and retirement, social justice)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link57">Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute 2008 Sponsorship Options</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Informational brochure</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link58">Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/7-10/08 in DC. AFT memo re institute's Public Policy Conference; materials re annual gala</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link59">Contract for Excellence Update Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/10/08 at 2:30pm in Hilton, NYC. Discussion paper for Regents, "Proposed Revisions to the Regulations of the Commissioner Relating to Contracts for Excellence," February 5; memo from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to locals re Contract for
      Excellence update and meeting, March 11</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link60">Anne Schiano Meeting: They will meet after the Regents</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/13/09.Memos re meeting date; paper by Justin Minkel, 2997 Arkansas Teacher of the Year, "Reflections on Education Policy Related to English Learners"; draft chart, "Performance Indicators with Benchmarks Integrating ESL Performance Indicators into
      the ELA/ESL Revised Standards"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link61">ELA/ESL Standards Review Panel</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/26-27/2008. Agenda for June 26-27 meeting of the ELA/ESL Standards Review Panel</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link62">ELA/ESL Standards</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/24/08. Draft document, "Educating English Language Learners: What the Research Does -- and Does Not -- Tell Us"; agenda for Regents Learning Standards Review Initiative Public Forum on the Review of the ELA/ESL Standards</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link63">ELA/ESL Panel</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Panel recommendations and researchers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link64">ELA/ESL Learning Standards DRAFT Versions</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Presentation outline of Regents Standards Review Initiative at Board of Regents meeting, December 15, 2008; Partnership for the 21st Century Skills Review of NYS Standard English Language Arts K-12, January 22, 2009; draft reading performance
      indicators for pre-kindergarten, grade 5, and grade 9</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link65">ESL Reseachers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Individual biographies of ESL researchers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link66">Spanish/Hispanic/Latino Quotations</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/5/08. Quotations on leadership and the Latino experience</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link67">Hispanic Participation in Technology Careers Summit</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/5-6/08. Report prepared for summit, "A Matter of Trust: Ten Key Insights from Recent Public Opinion Research on Attitudes about Education Among Hispanic Parents, Students, and Young Adults"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link68">Hispanic Federation: Reform Agenda</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report, "Confronting the Latino Academic Achievement Gap: A Reform Agenda"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link69">Janella Hinds Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/05/09 at 2PM. Report of the NYSUT High School Initiatives Task Force on Improving Graduation Rates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link70">Credit Recovery</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/06/08 at 1PM in SED, NYC. NYSUT Talking Points on Credit Recovery, the practice of allowing students to make up for lack of classroom attendance, sometimes through online courses, in order to improve school district graduation rates; article from
      New York Times, April 11, 2008; reports/marketing materials by online learning companies</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">66</container>
     <unittitle id="link71">NYSUT High School Initiative Task Force on Improving Graduation Rates</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for task force meeting, October 15; draft report; articles; related materials; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">67</container>
     <unittitle id="link72">High School Initiative Task Force</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/22/08 at 10AM in NYSUT HQ. Memos; agenda for NEA Leadership Forum</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">68</container>
     <unittitle id="link73">High School Initiatives Task Force</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/14/08 at 10AM in NYSUT HQ. Agenda; handwritten outline of problem; presentation, "NYS High School Graduation and Dropout Rates: Looking at Low Performing Students"; recommendations; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">69</container>
     <unittitle id="link74">High School Initiatives Task Force - Maria</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/14/08. Agenda; timeline; list of members; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">70</container>
     <unittitle id="link75">NYSUT HS Initiatives Task Force</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/8/08. Summary by Fact Finders, "2008 NYSUT HS Initiatives Student and Parent Study"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">71</container>
     <unittitle id="link76">Task Force on High School Initiatives</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Charge to the task force; background re establishment of task force; list of members; reports of the first vice president (Maria Neira), updating on high school initiative, prepared for the NYSUT Board of Directors</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">72</container>
     <unittitle id="link77">FAIR: Legislative Analysis</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>The DREAM Act (Development, Relief, and Education for Alien Minors Act of 2007) legislative analysis by Federation for American Immigration Reform</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">73</container>
     <unittitle id="link78">NYSUT Local Action Project Carmel Teacher's Association</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2011">2011</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tarrytown regional office, local presidents' conference; newsletter; list of LAP events; presentation summary re LAP; memorabilia</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">74</container>
     <unittitle id="link79">NYSUT Local Action Project</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>7/22/10. Presentation materials, "Defining Excellence in Our Professions," NYSUT Local Action Project, July 22, 2010</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">75</container>
     <unittitle id="link80">LAP: The Gideon Putnam</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/21-24/09. At-a-glance agenda for Local Action Project Conference; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">76</container>
     <unittitle id="link81">LAP Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/30/08 at 2PM in Conf. Rm. C. List of local funding requests, September 12; LAP budget forms from locals</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">77</container>
     <unittitle id="link82">LAP Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>7/21-25/08 in Fort Henry, Lake George. NYSUT vice president Maria Neira welcome and opening remarks</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">78</container>
     <unittitle id="link83">LAP Applications</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/29/08 at 11:30AM in Maria's Office. LAP applications from locals</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">79</container>
     <unittitle id="link84">LAP Summer Planning Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summary of participant feedback; evaluation report; thank-you letter to Niera from Association of Career and Technical Education Administrators for use of facility</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">80</container>
     <unittitle id="link85">Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference Planning Mtg.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/10/09 at 1:30PM in Exec. Rm. 1. Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference Planning Committee minutes, April 24; conference tentative schedule (pre-Representative Assembly); planning committee agenda; summary and results of 2009 Local
      Presidents Conference Survey</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">81</container>
     <unittitle id="link86">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/06-07/09 in Washington, DC. Registration form for Maria Neira; talking points for Finance Committee telephone call meeting; agenda for NBPTS Board of Directors meeting; highlights of development activities; financial update; report of nominating
      committee; minutes of meeting of Executive Committee via conference call, October 20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">82</container>
     <unittitle id="link87">NBPTS</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/15-18/09 in Atlanta, GA. Attendance list for Board of Directors meeting; CDs; publicity materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">83</container>
     <unittitle id="link88">NBPTS: Conflict of Interest Policy</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2011">2011</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Director disclosure statement for Maria Neira; Code of Ethics; Conflict of Interest Policy; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">84</container>
     <unittitle id="link89">NBPTS Code of Ethics</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Code of Ethics; related memo; statement by Maria Neira, "Vote. Get Involved. Make a Difference."</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">85</container>
     <unittitle id="link90">NBPTS</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/28/06. Investment guidelines, June 2003; issues of Education Week; list of committees; fact sheet, "About National Board Certification"; newspaper clippings; Executive Committee meeting agenda, February 28, 2007; minutes of October 13, 2006,
      meeting; talking points re Harris and Sass research re effects of NBPTS-certified teachers on student achievement</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link91">NBPTS Board of Directors Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/27-28/09. Tabbed materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link92">NBPTS Board of Directors Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/04-05/08. Tabbed materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link93">NBPTS Executive Committee Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/20/09 at 4:30PM. Minutes of Executive Committee meeting of May 20, 2009; agenda for October 20 conference call; outline, "Draft Mid-Year Cuts Campaign"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link94">NBPTS Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/20/09 at 4PM in Maria's office. Minutes of Executive Committee meeting of March 27, 2009; nomination form for James A. Kelly Award for First Lady Michelle Obama; nomination for Kelly Award for Education Secretary Arne Duncan; nomination for Arthur
      Wise; list of nominees; description of James A. Kelly Award</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link95">NBPTS: President/CEO Performance Assessment</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Performance Planning and Assessment Program materials; memo; schedule</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link96">Performance Goals for President/CEO of NBPTS</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Timeline; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link97">NBPTS Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/22/08 at 5PM in Maria's office. Agenda for Executive Committee conference call, August 14; minutes of April 3 meeting; second quarter financial review; performance progress report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link98">NBPTS Exec. Comm. Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/14/08 at 4PM. Agenda for August 14 conference call; president/CEO performance goals; progress report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link99">NBPTS Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/04-05/08 at 10AM TBD. Tabbed materials re president/CEO Performance Planning and Assessment Program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link100">NBPTS Executive Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/3/08 TBD. Tentative agenda; memos; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link101">NBPTS Finance Committee Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/21/09 at 6:00pm. Agenda; talking points; memos; minutes of September 23 meeting; confidential detailed memo re approval of 2010 general and administrative budget, October 16</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link102">NBPTS Finance Committee Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/23/09 at 6:00PM. Agenda; talking points; minutes of August 24 meeting; financial review</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link103">NBPTS Finance Committee Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/24/09 at 6:00PM. Agenda; talking points; minutes of July 2 meeting; financial review</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link104">NBPTS: Financial Committee Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/21/09 at 6:00PM. Agenda; talking points; minutes of March 27 meeting; financial review</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link105">NBPTS: Financial Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/27-28/09 in Arlington, VA. Agenda for Finance Committee meeting of March 27; agenda for Executive Committee meeting of March 27; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of November 7, 2008; minutes of Finance Committee meeting of March 3, 2009; memo
      re office space lease; Report of Finance Committee: 2008 Financial Results and 2009 Comprehensive Budget; memo re leadership competencies assessment for president/CEO</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link106">NBPTS: Financial Committee Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/03/09 at 5:30PM. Talking points for meeting; agenda; minutes of February 11 meeting; confidential detailed memo re 2008 estimated results of financial operations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link107">NBPTS: Financial Committee Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/11/09 at 5:30PM. Agenda; talking points; confidential financial overview</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link108">John Zimmerman Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/12/08 at 9AM in Dick's office. Letter to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, congratulating her on her election as chair of NBPTS Finance Committee, November 12, 2008; AFT financial statements</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link109">NBPTS</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/04/08 at 12:30PM in Maria's office. Financial report, December 31, 2007; Federal Awards Supplemental Information, December 31, 2007; September 2008 financial review; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link110">NBPTS Conference and Exhibition</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/15-18/09 in Atlanta, Georgia. Conference program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link111">National Board Certification Program</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Greater Capital Region Teacher Center folder with informational brochures and fact sheets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link112">NYS &amp;amp; NBPTS</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>July 7, 2008, at Exec. 2. Bullet points</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link113">NBPTS</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/16/08 at 3PM in SED. Draft meeting agenda, "Taking Inventory and Moving Forward: National Board Certification in NYS"; related memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link114">AFT NBPTS Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/12/08 at 5PM. Notes from planning meeting 3, "In Pursuit of Excellence: Celebrating the Accomplished Teacher," January 11, 2007; memo and outline of discussion questions for conference call</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link115">NBPTS/Albert Shanker Grant</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chart of contracts with National Board Certification incentives</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link116">NBPTS Ballot: James A. Kelly Award</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Ballot from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira in her role as member of the Board of Directors of National Board for Professional Teaching Standards; letter to Board of Directors recommending that the James A. Kelly Award for Advancing Accomplished
      Teaching go to Gov. Roy E. Barnes and Dr. Linda Darling-Hammond</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link117">NBPTS Incumbent Director's Consent-to-Questionnaire Form</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Blank and filled-in forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link118">NBPTS Incumbent Director's Consent-to-Serve Questionnaire</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Filled-in form by Maria Neira; instruction to Neira re how to fill out form, including draft responses; blank forms; Report of 2007 Nominating Committee</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link119">NBPTS President/CEO Leadership Competencies Assessment Executive Committee Summary</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Performance plan and related confidential materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link120">NBPTS Executive Committee Meeting Materials</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/28/07 in Arlington, VA. Agenda; minutes of December 8, 2006, meeting of working group; 2006 Financial Results of Operations; 2003-2006 Selected Progress Indicators; brochure, "Making the Commitment to Accomplished Teaching: Q and A for 2007 National
      Board Certification"; fact sheet, "About National Board Certification"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link121">NCLB (No Child Left Behind) Task Force Webcast</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 14, 2009 at 2:00-4:30. Agenda; AFT position papers, "Investing in a Well-Qualified Teacher in Every Classroom," "Community Schools," "Focus on High-Achieving Low-Income Students," other issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link122">Conf. Call NCLB Task Force Web Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/8/09. Facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link123">Alternative Proposal to NCLB</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/22/08 with Lunch at Hilton, Chevy Chase Run (Terrace Level). NCLB Task Force meeting agenda, April 17-18, 2008; statement by Randi Weingarten, president, United Federation of Teachers, to the Association for a Better New York, "Accountability in New
      York City's Public Schools," March 13, 2008; highlights of the proposed accountability reports; list of NCLB Task Force members; related documents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link124">NCLB Task Force</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/22/08 at 12:15-1:45PM. Memo from executive vice president Antonia Cortese, inviting task force members to attend meeting with AFT vice president Randi Weingarten to develop alternatives to No Child Left Behind accountability proposals</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link125">AFT NCLB Task Force</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/17-18/08 in Washington, DC. Overview of the Academic Performance Index; questions for discussion of the Elementary Index; related documents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link126">NCLB (No Child Left Behind)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by the Commission on No Child Left Behind, "Beyond NCLB: Fulfilling the Promise to Our Nation's Children," 2007; report by the National Middle School Association, "Success in the Middle: A Policymaker's Guide to Achieving Quality Middle Level
      Education," 2006; other reports and article reprints</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link127">NCLB</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft report by the Commission on No Child Left Behind, "Beyond NCLB: Fulfilling the Promise to Our Nation's Children"; Rand Corporation report, "The Role of Districts in Fostering Instructional Improvement: Lessons from Three Urban Districts Partnered
      with the Institute for Learning," 2005: AFT report, "NCLB: Let's Get It Right," n.d.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link128">NCLB PowerPoint</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/19-20/07. Presentation at NYSUT Board of Directors meeting; document, "Landmark Agreement for Pension Benefits and School-Wide Bonuses Brings Professional Gains to NYC Public School Educators"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link129">NCLB Task Force Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/14/07 at 2PM in Video Conf. Room. Call for meeting of the No Child Left Behind Task Force</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link130">NCLB Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/06/06 at 10:30AM in Maria's Office. Presentation by Maria Neira to the NYS Association of Black and Puerto Rican Legislators re Campaign for Fiscal Equity, "Can CFE Close the Achievement Gap?" February 18, 2006; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link131">Proposal of NCLB Video</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to Door Knob Films LLC, expressing support for documentary project, "No Teacher Left Behind," referencing $10,000 grant from NYSUT to assist in production, June 24, 2008; copy of check; proposal for video
      documentary and request for support, with budget, April 5, 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link132">NCLB Growth Model Proposal in Rochester</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from Kenmore Teachers Association to State Education Department</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link133">Miller/Mckeon ESEA Title 1 Draft Bill</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from Maria Neira to NYSUT officers re NYSUT position on Miller/McKeon draft of reauthorization of Title I of the No Child Left Behind Act</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link134">Gillibrand: NCLB</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT document, "NCLB: Time for a Change: Recommendations to the United States Congress," March 12, 2007</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link135">NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/18/09 at 11:30AM in Sheraton NY Hotel. Minutes of meeting of June 16, 2009; letter to Maria Neira re December 18 meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link136">NYS AFL-CIO Workforce Development Inst. Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/23/09 at 2:30PM. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link137">NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/16/09 at 12:30PM in Crowne Plaza. Agenda; secretary-treasurer's report; NYS AFL-CIO Budget Analysis for the period July 1, 2008, through March 31, 2009; minutes of December 19, 2008, Executive Council meeting; 2009-2010 Proposed Budget; press
      advisory, "Join New Yorkers In Support of Their Union Brother's (sic) and Sisters And the Workers of Puerto Rico!" with attached materials, June 15, 2009; brochure re labor law at Fordham Law School; related materials; memo re Senate introduction of 9/11
      Health Compensation Fund, June 16, 2009; flyer for national health care reform rally and lobby day, June 28; NYS AFL-CIO Document Retention Policy; Conflict of Interest Policy; Whistleblower Protection Policy; Community Outreach Department Report;
      Executive Summary, Young Unionists' Conference, May 7-9, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link138">NYS AFL-CIO/NYC Central Labor Council Executive Board</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/22/08 at 12:30PM in Sheraton NY Hotel. Publication by the Fiscal Policy Institute, "The State of Working New York 2007: Encouraging Recent Gains but Troubling Long-Term Trends"; presentation, "With the end of Wall Street as we knew It, what lies
      ahead? New York's economic and fiscal challenges"; report, "New York's Rising Unemployment: The Other Crisis in Albany"; NYS AFL-CIO document, "Labor 2008: Targeted Races," tracking canvassing activity; flyer invitation to NYS AFL-CIO breakfast in honor
      of Attorney General Andrew Cuomo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link139">NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/04/08 at 11:30AM in Grand Hyatt, NYC. Draft AFT concept paper, Innovation Fund, September 2, 2008; agenda; conference call meeting minutes, August 26, 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link140">NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/17/08 at 11:30AM in Albany, New York. Agenda; meeting minutes of December 7, 2007; NYS AFL-CIO Budget Analysis; 2008-2009 Proposed Budget; Secretary-Treasurer's Report; NYS AFL-CIO Investment Policy; Resolution 2, submitted by AFL-CIO Executive
      Council, "A Diverse Movement Calls for Diverse Leadership," 2005; charts of targeted NY Congressional Districts; flyers for receptions for political candidates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link141">NYS AFL-CIO Exec. Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/17/08 at 11:30AM in Albany Crowne Plaza. Minutes of meeting; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link142">Workforce Development Institute Board Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/11/08 at 10:00AM in the Troy Office. Agenda for Board of Directors meeting; draft employee manual; program reports; Executive Director's Report; financial statements; publications of photographs and stories by workers and families of UAW Local 465
      and others, "Unseen America New York State"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link143">NYS AFL-CIO Rally</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/8/07 at 10AM in NYC. Invitation to Maria Neira to Labor Day rally in support of proposed federal legislation for medical monitoring and treatment for 9/11 first responders and other workers whose long-term health was affected by the attack</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link144">NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/10/07 in Sheraton, New York. Agenda; report on the BALCONY (Business and Labor Coalition of New York) Universal Health Care Forum, "Affordable Health Care for New York Prescriptions for a Health State"; projected budget</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link145">Peer Review &amp;amp; PSPB</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/04/09 at 2PM in Maria's Office. Agenda; evaluation sheets; thank-you letters to seminar panelists</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link146">Peer Review Conf. for Local Leaders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/5/08 at 9AM in Auditorium. Agenda; bio of Antonia Cortese; suggested questions for panel presentation; presentation bullet points; resolution adopted by AFT, Peer Assistance and Review for New Teachers: Taking Charge of Our Profession; issue of AFT
      American Educator, fall 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link147">NYSUT Peer Review Seminar</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/05/08. Agenda; seminar materials; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link148">Web Meeting - Draft Resolution on Peer Asst. and Review</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/17/08. Draft and revised resolutions re peer assistance and review; related memo; instructions for web meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link149">Peer Assistance and Review</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Comments on draft resolution from Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link150">Senate Democratic Hispanic Task Force Forum</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/24/08 at 3PM in Senate Russell Office. Talking points for legislative visits; invitation to Maria Neira from Senators Ken Salazar and Richard Menendez, co-chairs of Senate Democratic Hispanic Task Force, to attend forum with Latino labor union
      leaders re concerns of working families; handwritten notes; materials on the Employee Free Choice Act; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link151">Somos El Futuro Debrief</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/30/08 at 10AM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link152">2009 Somos Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 2-5, 2009. Memo re logistics of maintaining a NYSUT presence at the Somos conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link153">NBPTS Executive Committee Conference Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/15/09. Agenda; minutes of November 6, 2009, meeting; National Board of Professional Teaching Standards Accomplished Principal Standards</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link154">Somos El Futuro</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 25-27, 2008 at the Egg, Albany, NY. Talking points for Maria Neira; NYSUT bullet points, "Fulfilling America's Promise: Improving Educational Opportunities for Hispanic Children," April 25; booklet for luncheon awards program; agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link155">Somos El Futuro</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Caucus Weekend 2008 &amp;amp; Somos El Futuro Conferences memorandum</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link156">Somos El Futuro Puerto Rico</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program for 2nd Annual Latino Upstate Summit, October 17, 2008; memo to Maria Neira re Somos Conference held in Puerto Rico, with agenda and registration form</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link157">21st Annual Somos El Futuro Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>On 04/25-27/08 in Albany, New York. Program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link158">Somos El Futuro 20th Annual Legislative Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/27-30/07. Preliminary agenda; Awards Luncheon Program; NYSUT Guide to Special Education brochures in English and Spanish; AFT brochures, Pathways to Success, in English and Spanish; NYSUT flyer in English and Spanish</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link159">Race To The Top (RTTT)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Race to the Top Program Executive Summary, U.S. Department of Education, November 2009; full funding guidelines for publication in the Federal Register; Race to the Top Program Preamble and Major Changes; Race to the Top Application for Initial
      Funding</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link160">RTTT</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/15/09. NYSUT Comments Regarding the Report on Improving the Preparation, Recruitment, and Retention of Urban Educators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link161">Race to the Top</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/19/09. Education Initiatives agenda; draft, Education Initiatives: Next Steps for NYSUT; presentation bullet points</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link162">RTTT Applications: TN, DE, LA, MA and FL</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Comparative narratives</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link163">RTTT: Weingarten AFT News Release</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Statement by Randi Weingarten, president, American Federation of Teachers, on "Race to the Top" Grant Awards, March 29, 2010; note about New York losing RTTT grant, NYSUT position</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link164">NYS AFL-CIO Annual Labor Celebration</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/18/08 at Sheraton NY Hotel. Invitation to NYS AFL-CIO Annual Labor Celebration</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link165">NYS AFL-CIO Annual Labor Celebration</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/17/09 at 6:00-9:00PM at Sheraton NY Hotel. Letter inviting NYSUT vice president Maria Neira; invitation to gala</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link166">AFL-CIO Workforce Development Institute</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/28/09. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link167">NYS AFL-CIO Conflict of Interest Policy</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Policy document, with cover letter; signed statement by Maria Neira, agreeing to policy</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link168">NYS AFL-CIO: NYC Airport (Delta Airlines)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to Maria Neira, describing anti-union efforts by Delta Airlines; open letter to Delta CEO from Neira, "An Appeal for Fairness at Delta Airlines"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link169">Task Force on Creating Pathways for New York's Youth</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Meeting agenda, May 24, 1991; outline of issues; notes for NYSUT president Tom Hobart</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link170">Career Pathways Subcommittee Meetings</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda, June 26, 1991; list of subcommittee assignments; reports from advisory councils from other states; report, New York State Job Training: Workforce Preparation Evaluation Program Plan; testimony by National Alliance of Business before the House
      Ways and Means Committee re "Education and Human Resource Factors Affecting U.S. International Competitiveness," June 5, 1991</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link171">Career Pathways Meeting [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Wednesday, August 28 at 11:00AM in Syracuse Regional Office. Memo re meeting; U.S. Department of Labor Secretary's Commission on Achieving Necessary Skills report, "What Work Requires of Schools: A SCANS Report for America 2000," June 1991; brochure
      version; executive summary of U.S. General Accounting Office report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link172">Career Pathways Meeting [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Wednesday, August 28 at 11:00AM at Syracuse Regional Office. Agenda for meeting of Standards and Inclusion Subcommittee, June 26; plans from Virginia and Wisconsin for improving workforce preparation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link173">Characteristics of Ideal Learning Environments</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Document</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link174">Youth Apprenticeship, American Style: A Strategy for Expanding School and Career Opportunities</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 7, 1990. Report of a conference by Consortium on Youth Apprenticeship</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link175">New York State Job Training Partnership Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Publication, "A Statement of Policy on Youth Employment Investments in New York State"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link176">The ASVAB Workbook - Exploring Careers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1989">1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Exploring Careers: The ASVAB (Armed Services Vocational Aptitude Battery) Workbook</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link177">National Center on Education and the Economy - America's Choice: High Skills or Low Wages!</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>The Report of The Commission on the Skills of the American Workforce</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link178">Education and Human Services Consortium - Structuring Interagency Partnerships to Connect Children and Families with Comprehensive Services</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Joint publication of the Education and Human Services Consortium</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link179">U.S General Accounting Office - Training Strategies: Preparing Noncollege Youth for Employment in the U.S and Foreign Countries</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 1990. U.S. General Accounting Office Report to Congressional Requesters</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link180">At Risk: A Nation and Its Youth-The National Youth Employment and Training Conference</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYS Department of Labor (?) publication</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link181">New York State Job Training Partnership Council-Creating a Vision: The Workforce Preparation System Of the Future</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Publication</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link182">State Education Department-Education Statistics New York State</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 1991. Booklet prepared especially for members of the legislature</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link183">New York State Job Training Partnership Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990/1991" type="inclusive">1990-1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NY State Education Department Basic and Expanded Basic Skills: Scales for Validation Study, July 1990; fact sheet from the White House, "America 2000: The President's Education Strategy," April 18, 1991; Statement of Senator Edward M. Kennedy at the
      Executive Session on S. 2, "The Strengthening Education for American Families Act"; Report to the Board of Regents on Career Preparation Validation Study; article, "Preparing a World-Class Work Force," Vocational Education Journal, May 1991; Pathways for
      New York State's Youth, showing charts for enrollment and graduation activity, 1985-89, comparison of percentage of public and private school graduates entering institutions of higher learning</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link184">Career Pathways Task Force</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 31. Notice of meeting; Proposal by the Rochester School-to-Work Transition Initiative, October 28, 1991; Cornell University publication, "Creating Apprenticeship Opportunities for Youth: A Progress Report from the Youth Apprenticeship
      Demonstration Project in Broome County, NY," September 1991; brochure, "The University at Albany: A $4 Billion Engine for Economic Growth 1990-1999"; Statement of Senator Edward M. Kennedy at the Introduction of "The High Skills, Competitive Workforce
      Act of 1991," October 1; Cornell publication, "Adapting German Apprenticeship to New York State: Report on a Symposium Convened by S. H. Hamilton," June 7, 1990; Outline of Proposed Recommendations and Recommendation Options of the Task Force on Creating
      Career Pathways for New York's Youth; updates by subcommittees; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link185">Task Force on Creating Career Pathways [folder 1 of 3]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Monday, October 7 at 10:30AM in Room 5-B, SED. Monthly Labor Review article, "Shared Training: Lessons from Germany," March 1991; draft task force reports</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link186">Task Force on Creating Career Pathways [folder 2 of 3]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Monday, October 7 at 10:30AM in Room 5-B, SED. Meeting materials, including draft report, proposed recommendations, and cover letter</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link187">Task Force on Creating Career Pathways [folder 3 of 3]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Monday, October 7 at 10:30AM in Room 5-B, SED. Proposed recommendations and options; other documents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link188">Administrative Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/20/09 at 12 Noon in Auditorium. NYSUT document, "Managing a Harassment-Free and Respectful Workplace"; training program evaluation forms; memo calling meeting, noting training topic</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link189">Administrative Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/09/09 at 1:00PM. Agenda; presentation bullet points re Obama's Pre-K-Higher Education agenda; AFT presentation points, "The View from the States"; presentation, "Expanding the Promise of Education in America," White House Domestic Policy Council</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link190">Administrative Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/27/09 at 1:00PM. Memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link191">Administrative Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/24/08 at 10:00AM. Keynote Speech by NYSUT Vice President Maria Neira to the Capital Region Human Resources Association Diversity Gala, October 16, 2008; handwritten notes; training materials on trust and self-evaluation for integrity</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link192">Administrative Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/10/08 at 1PM in Auditorium. Agenda; AFT presentation bullet points, "From Members to Unionists: Connecting with NYSUT's Next Generation"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link193">Administrative Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/11/08 at 1PM in Auditorium. Agenda; discussion group notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link194">Administrative Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/30/08 at 11PM in NYSUT Auditorium. Agenda; article from WorkingUSA: The Journal of Labor and Society, "A Strategic Choice Framework for Union Decision Making," March 2005; presentation bullet points, "Strategic Choice and Building Union Capacity";
      handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link195">Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/04/09 at 1PM in Conf. Rm B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; press releases: from Department of Labor, "Statement by U.S. Secretary Hilda L. Solis on reports detailing international child labor and forced labor," and from National Labor Committee, "Retail Giant
      Flouts Recommendation of Centers for Disease Control: Wal-Mart's Sick Leave Policy Risks Spreading Swine Flu," November 3, 2009; definition of NYSUT's Social Justice Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link196">Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/18/09 at 1:00PM. Agenda; Report of Vice President Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link197">Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/14/08 at 1:30PM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link198">Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/4/08 at 1PM in Conf. Rm A&amp;amp;B. Agenda; radio script by Shorr Johnson Magnus Strategic Media opposing proposed property tax cap; related communications plan; draft of letter to state legislators; Code of Ethics Frameworks for NYSUT Local
      Leaders, Benefit Fund Trustees and Their Employees Provided by NYSUT Member Benefits Trust; confidential memorandum from NYSUT general counsel James Sandner re ethics issues raised by association with Harris, Conway and Donovan, June 3, 2008; New York
      Times editorial re property tax cap; press release from National Education Association (NEA) recommending endorsement of Barack Obama for president, June 3, 2008; NYSUT Briefing Bulletin, "Summary of the Report of the Commission on Property Tax Relief,"
      June 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link199">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/04-05/09 at Headquarters. Draft discussion paper, "NYSUT's Principles for Leading Excellence in Higher Education"; consolidated financial statements, draft as of September 1, 2009; report of vice president Neira; report of general counsel;
      resolution in support of reconsideration of marriage equality bill; issues briefing papers; Report of the NYSUT High School Initiatives Task Force on Improving Graduation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link200">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/25-26/09. Presentation for Board of Directors, "NYSUT Redistricting Background and Resolutions"; Representative Assembly materials (tentative program, deadlines); financial statements for NYSUT Building Corporation as of July 31, 2009; Report of the
      Executive Director; NYSUT Member Benefits Trust and Corporation Report; Conflict of Interest Policy for NYSUT Officials and Employees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link201">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>7/23/09 at Saratoga Hilton Hotel. Agenda; minutes of Board of Directors meeting of April 1, 2009; minutes of Executive Committee meetings of June 4 and May 12, 2009; reports of officers; NYSUT Building Corporation financial statements as of May 31,
      2009; Building Corporation membership meeting minutes of July 23, 2009; memo re proposed building purchase, July 23, 2009; requests for affiliation; presentation points re redistricting; NYSUYT Constitution and Bylaws, effective 2009-2010; Implementation
      of Actions by the 2009 NYSUT Representative Assembly, April 2-4, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link202">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/23/09 at 9AM in Saratoga Hilton. Report of vice president Maria Neira, focusing on the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act and the Race to the Top; biography of Regent Chancellor Merryl Tisch; handwritten notes; NSYUT presentation points, "Using
      the Power of LAP (local action project) to Improve/Enhance Achievement"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link203">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/27-28/09. Update from State Education Department on the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act of 2009 (ARRA); report of vice president Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link204">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/27/09-2/28/09. Agenda; minutes of meeting of December 12-13, 2008; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of January 15, 2009; legislative report; officers reports; publication, Educator's Voice, NYSUT's journal of best practices in education, spring
      2009; NYSUT Building Corporation financial statements; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link205">Workforce Development Institute Board of Directors Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/28/09. Agenda; employee manual (draft), effective April 1, 2008; executive director's report; program reports; status of contracts</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link206">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/12-13/08. Agenda; 2009 NYSUT Representative Assembly Committee Nominations, revised as of December 12, 2008; presentation of dues proposal; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of October 24, 2008; proposed amendments to NYSUT Constitution and
      bylaws; officers reports</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link207">NYSUT Board of Directors Retreat Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/29/08 at 3PM in Kathleen's Office. Report of Committee to Review Responsibilities of Board Members; excerpt from NYSUT Policy Manual re Board of Directors</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link208">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/12-13/08. Agenda; 2008-09 NYSUT Budget; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of August 13, 2008; officers reports; NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations NYS Assembly, U.S. Congress; press releases opposing tax cap, cuts to higher ed</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link209">New Board of Dir. Orientation</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/11/08 at 9AM at Headquarters. Agenda; presentation materials; 2005-2006 Local Leaders' Guide, by NYSUT Research and Educational Services; Information Bulletin; Briefing Bulletin re special education requirements, January 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link210">NYSUT Board of Directors Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August 2008. Minutes of Board of Directors meetings of April 9 and 12, 2008; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of June 5, 2008; Report of the Executive Director; other officers' reports; position papers by NYSUT committees; proposed 2008-2011
      committee recommendations; Implementation of Actions by the 2008 NYSUT Representative Assembly; survey results compiled by Task Force on the Roles and Responsibilities of Board Members</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link211">NYSUT Board of Directors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/29/08 at 4PM in Auditorium. Agenda; officers' reports, including report of the general counsel; financial statements; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of February 29; materials re Community Service Award winners</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link212">Committee Appointments</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005/2008" type="inclusive">2005-2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Committee nomination forms; memo to Board of Directors from NYSUT president Richard Iannuzzi re committee appointments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link213">NYSUT Board of Directors Mail Ballots</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2011">2011</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos and ballots re bullying, suicides, and harassment statement, endorsement in Attorney General primary, endorsement of state senate candidate</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link214">08-09 Budget</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008/2009" type="inclusive">2008-2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed NYSUT budget for Cabinet presentation, May 7, 2008; salary adjustment schedules for management/confidential compensation; narrative document, "Compensation for the President of NYSUT," recommending large increase; confidential memo re Research
      and Educational Services staffing budget, March 27, 2008; memo from director of finance and administration expressing concern re continuing large overages in charitable giving, lack of oversight</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link215">Budget Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 12, 2006 at 3:30PM at Chuck's Office. Schedule for management/ confidential salary proposals, 2006; memo to officers re 2006-2007 NYSUT budget, April 5, 2006; list of Research and Educational Services staffing, dates of hire</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link216">Cabinet Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/02/09 at 12 Noon. Meeting agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link217">Cabinet Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/21/09 at 12:30PM in Executive Conf. Rm 1. Meeting agenda; draft text for radio ad; draft outline for mid-year cuts campaign; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link218">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/09/09 at 12:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda; questionnaires for officers; NYSUT Education and Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting agenda for September 9, minutes of April 15 and June 2 meetings, proposed budget, and related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link219">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/17/09 at 12:30PM. Agenda; materials re charter schools</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link220">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/6/09 at 12:30PM. Cabinet meeting and Officers' meeting agendas; memo from director of finance and administration re CUNY Professional Staff Congress request for increased financial support; highlights of 2009 school nurse survey; list of charitable
      contributions of over $5,000 for the period September 1, 2008, to April 30, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link221">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/15/09 at 11:30AM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda; CSEA dues structure</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link222">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/25/09 at 12:30PM. Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link223">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/4/09 at 12:30PM. Agenda for Cabinet meeting; agenda for Representative Assembly; delegate bulletin for Representative Assembly; draft list of invited speakers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link224">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/6/09 at 12:30PM. Agenda; NYSUT talking points re governor's 2009-2010 budget; tentative Representative Assembly program; NYSUT Regents' Report Card</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link225">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/2/08 at 12:30PM. Agenda; memo re regional office responses to the economic crisis, December 3, 2008; NYSUT consolidated statements of operating expenses for the years ended August 31, 2008 and 2007; statement of financial position as of August 31,
      2008; NYSUT membership comparison as of October 31, 2008 vs Fiscal Year end 2008, by regional office; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link226">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/1/08 at 12:30PM. Agenda for Cabinet meeting; agenda for Board of Trustees meeting; status of regional office projects as of October 1, 2008; minutes of the Board of Trustees of the NYSUT Education and Learning Trust, March 18 and May 16; projected
      Education and Learning Trust budget; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link227">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/11/08 at 11:00AM. Agenda; Executive Committee resolution re Establishment of the New York State United Teachers Nonqualified (Management/ Confidential) Employees' Retirement Plan, September 11, 2008; draft Leader Access proposal, re levels of secure
      access to NYSUT web site;</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link228">Cabinet Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/11/08 at 12:15PM in Video Conference Room. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link229">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>08/04/08 at 1PM in Executive Conf. Rm 1. Article from New York State School Boards Association newsletter, On Board, re testing; article in New York Sun re testing; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link230">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/07/08 at 12PM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link231">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 1, 2008 at 11:30-1:00PM. Agenda; NYSUT Solidarity Fund application</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link232">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/18/08 at 10AM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda for Cabinet meeting; agenda for NYSUT Education and Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting, March 18; memo re check disbursement approvals; request for financial support for new Cornell ILR Extension
      course (denied)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link233">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/26/08 at 12:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda; draft memo re liaisons to the Board of Regents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link234">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/16/08 at 12:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda; resolutions submitted for consideration at the Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link235">Cabinet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/3/08 at 12:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Agenda; document by Center on Budget and Policy Priorities, The Problem with Property Tax Caps; map of election districts and school districts in NYS; preliminary draft, Amendment to the Rules of the Board of
      Regents and the Regulations of the Commissioner of Education re tenure</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link236">CWA Bargaining Agreement: Contract</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005/2008" type="inclusive">2005-2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT and Communication Workers of America Local 1141 Collective Bargaining Agreement, January 1, 2005-December 31, 2008; cover letter to NYSUT officers from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link237">Duty Descriptions for Titles Established Effective Jan 1, 2007</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from NYSUT executive director Pauline Kinsella to CWA president and staff representative, referencing job duties for titles established by collective bargaining agreement, April 4, 2007</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link238">Speaking Engagement ELT-SRP Summer Training Program</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2011">2011</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/27/11 at 11:00AM in Desmond, Albany. Speech by NYSUT vice president Maria Neira; hand-notated draft; agenda for SRP (school-related personnel) training schedule</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link239">ELT Meeting: Yankowski</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/25/08 at 4PM in Maria's Office. Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link240">ELT Budget Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>08/23/10 at 1PM in Maria's Office. Education and Learning Trust statement of financial activities</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link241">ELT Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/08/10 at 11AM in Maria's Office. Survey results and analysis</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link242">NYSUT ELT: Conflict of Interest Policy and Whistleblowers Policies</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2010">2010</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/03/10. Ballots by Maria Neira approving resolutions re whistleblower and conflict of interest policies; description of policies</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link243">NYSUT ELT Board of Trustees Meeting [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/02/09 in NYSUT HQ. Agenda; minutes of meeting of Education and Learning Trust Board of Trustees of September 9, 2009; course descriptions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link244">NYSUT ELT Board of Trustees Meeting [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/02/09 in NYSUT HQ. Course descriptions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link245">ELT: Fiscal Agent</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/17/09. Memo recommending that Education and Learning Trust be designated as the fiscal agent for the statewide Teacher Centers meetings to comply with new federal payment policy under the American Recovery and Reinvestment Act (ARRA)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link246">ELT Minutes</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/09/09. Minutes of special meetings of the Board of Trustees of the NYSUT Education and Learning Trust, April 15 and June 2 (minutes approved 09/09/09)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link247">ELT Summer Training</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>07/20/09 at Gideon Putnam. Summer training agenda; Maria Neira talking points; presentation outline, NYSUT's Position on Reform; facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link248">Proposed ELT Instructors</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of proposed instructors; cover memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link249">ELT New Course Proposal Meeting (Immediately After R&amp;amp;E Managers Meeting)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/13/09. Board of Trustees meeting agenda; course outlines re cyber-bullying, cultural proficiency, autism spectrum disorders, other topics</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link250">NYSUT ELT Report</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/08-01/09. Report; financial (activities) statement</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link251">ELT Regional Coordinators Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/3/08 at 6PM in Hilton Garden Inn. Agenda for Regional Coordinators' meeting; regional reports for Utica/Rome, Capital District/northern New York, Southern Tier, Suffolk, NYC, Syracuse region, and western NY</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link252">ELT Minutes</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/01/08. Minutes of Board of Trustees meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link253">ELT Budget</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/1/08. Agenda of Board of Trustees meeting; minutes of March 18 and May 26 meetings; projected budget for 2008-09</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link254">ELT Regional Coordinators' Minutes</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Friday, October 3, 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link255">Mark of Excellence Award Video Taping</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/11/08 at 4PM in Cotton Hill Studio, Colonie, NY. Outline of questions re marketing campaign; facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link256">Education and Learning Trust Progress</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/22/08. Presentation bullet points</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link257">ELT Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/08/08 at 1:30PM in Maria's Office. Scenarios; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link258">ELT Promotional Video</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/30/08 at 10:30AM in Exec. Conf. Rm 1. Video script</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link259">Capital District TC - NBCT</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/5/07 at 4PM in Maria's Office. Memo re teacher leadership; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link260">ELT Regional Report</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Sept. 2007. Regional reports from western NY, Hudson Valley, Nassau, Suffolk, Southern Tier, Capital District/northern NY; Utica/Rome, Syracuse</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link261">ELT Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/15/07 at 3PM in Conf. Rm. 3. Agenda; memo re brochure mailing</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link262">Interim Report on the Trust Self Study</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Professional development needs assessment survey; memo re interim report on the ELT self study; bullet points from meeting with regional staff in Cooperstown</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link263">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/17/09 at 1PM. Officers reports; NYSUT Dual Credit Task Force Final Report; letter from Maria Neira to Education Commissioner David Steiner re Race to the Top grant application, November 2, 2009; State Education Department discussion item,
      Transforming Teaching and Ensuring an Equitable Distribution of Qualified Teachers in NYS, November 10</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link264">NYSUT Exec Committee Ballot</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2011">2011</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Ballot by Maria Neira supporting NYSUT endorsement of Kathy Hochul (D) in special election in 26th Congressional District</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link265">Executive Committee Meeting, Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>November 17, 2009. Agenda; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of October 22; officers reports; NYSUT Dual Credit Task Force Final Report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link266">NYSUT Exec. Committee Meeting: Web-cam from Elmhurst</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/22/09 at 2PM. Report of NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to the Executive Committee; NYSUT testimony to the Assembly Standing Committee on Ways and Means on the Estimated Budget Deficit for the 2009-2010 state fiscal year, October 21, 2009; research
      brief, National Education Association Visiting Scholars Series, "A Time of Peril for Education," Diane Ravitch, New York University</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link267">NYSUT Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/05/09 at 4:15PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Memo re recommendation to endorse moderate Dede Scozzafava (R) in special election in the 23rd Congressional District</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link268">Executive Committee Meeting, Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>September 25, 2009. NYSUT Building Corporation Board of Directors meeting agenda; Conflict of Interest Policy for NYSUT Officials and Employees; draft NYSUT redistricting plan</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link269">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/25/09 at 1PM. Agenda; Board of Directors meeting agenda; minutes of Board of Directors meeting of July 23; NYSUT Building Corporation membership meeting agenda, September 25; report of vice president Maria Neira; newspaper clippings; NYSUT
      redistricting plan; memo re PSC/UUP concerns; New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link270">Executive Committee, Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>7/23/09. Agenda; Member Benefits Trust 403(b) Endorsement Survey summary and results; memo re proposed building purchase; NYSUT Building Corporation Board of Directors meeting agenda, July 23</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link271">Executive Committee, Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/4/09. Agenda; minutes of Executive Committee meeting of May 12; officers' reports; NYSUT and NYSUT Building Corporation financial statements as of April 30, 2009; requests for affiliation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link272">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/4/09 at 1:00PM. Agenda; report of vice president Maria Neira; NYSUT 2009-2010 Budget for Executive Committee, June 4, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link273">NYSUT Exec. Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/12/09 at 12 Noon in Desmond. Agenda; officers' reports; NYSUT member benefits report; preliminary analysis of President Obama's FY 2010 budget proposal; document, "Race to the Top: Promising State Models"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link274">Exec. Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/24/09 at 8:30AM in Desmond Hotel, Fort Orange Room. Agenda; report of vice president Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">66</container>
     <unittitle id="link275">Executive Committee Meeting, Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/24/09. Agenda; 2009 Proposed Constitutional and Bylaw Amendments (for 37th Representative Assembly); requests for affiliation; memo to the Business and Labor Coalition of New York from the Gotham Research Group re the Fair Share Tax Concept: An
      Overview of Survey Findings, March 23</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">67</container>
     <unittitle id="link276">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/27/09 at 1:00PM. Oral report of vice president Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">68</container>
     <unittitle id="link277">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/15/09 at 2:00PM. Agenda; officers' reports; financial statements; requests for affiliation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">69</container>
     <unittitle id="link278">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/12/08 at 1:00PM. Minutes; dues proposal; memo re CUNY master plan 2004-2008; briefing re differentiated accountability and growth models; report of vice president Maria Neira; statement for Maria Neira re status of Sandy Feldman Award and grant
      applications, noting lack of candidates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">70</container>
     <unittitle id="link279">Executive Committee Meeting, Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/18/08. Report of the Executive Director to the Executive Committee; requests for affiliation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">71</container>
     <unittitle id="link280">NYSUT Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/18/08 at 2PM Webcast. Agenda; minutes of October 24 meeting; report of vice president Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">72</container>
     <unittitle id="link281">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/26/08 at 4PM Conference Call. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">73</container>
     <unittitle id="link282">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/11/08 at 1:00PM. Agenda; resolution establishing NYSUT Nonqualified Employees' Retirement Plan (managerial/confidential); Representative Assembly proposed deadlines; reports of officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">74</container>
     <unittitle id="link283">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/13/08 at 1:00PM. NYSUT position papers re virtual learning, improving access and support for students with disabilities in technical education, and improving the state's assessment system; report of vice president Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">75</container>
     <unittitle id="link284">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/5/08 at 1PM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; minutes of meeting of May 13; NYSUT 2008-09 Budget, prepared by Office of Secretary-Treasurer for Executive Committee meeting; legislative update; officers' reports; financial statements</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">76</container>
     <unittitle id="link285">Executive Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/13/08 at 3PM Webcast. Agenda; officers' reports; report of general counsel</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">77</container>
     <unittitle id="link286">RA Set Design</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/09/09 at 3PM. Seating plan for Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">78</container>
     <unittitle id="link287">RA Theme Meeting: Immediately Following the NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>08/31/09. Revised list of 2010 RA proposed themes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">79</container>
     <unittitle id="link288">RA Speech Practice</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/18/09 at 3:30PM in NYSUT Auditorium. Fifth draft of prepared remarks for Maria Neira at Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">80</container>
     <unittitle id="link289">Maria's RA Speech/Background Materials</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Prepared remarks for NYSUT 37th Annual Representative Assembly, sixth draft</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">81</container>
     <unittitle id="link290">RA Speech</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/17/09 Conf. Call. Report by Center for American Progress, "From Qualifications to Results: Promoting Teacher Effectiveness through Federal Policy," January 2009; report by Economic Policy Institute, "Education Accountability Policy in the New
      Administration"; first draft of remarks of vice president Maria Neira to 37th NYSUT Representative Assembly, February 9, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">82</container>
     <unittitle id="link291">RA Video Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/07/09 at 4:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Agreement with Gracey Communications Group, Inc., for video production services for Representative Assembly 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">83</container>
     <unittitle id="link292">RA Reporter</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Daily newsletter from Representative Assembly though April 4, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">84</container>
     <unittitle id="link293">Widmeyer Conf. Call</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/28/09 at 3:30PM in Maria's Office. Maria Neira's RA speech outline and commentary on draft from Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">85</container>
     <unittitle id="link294">RA Report</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 7-13, 2008. Schedule of events; list of invitees (guest speakers); media summary with newspaper clippings of coverage</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">86</container>
     <unittitle id="link295">RA Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/19/08 at 2PM in NYSUT Auditorium. Program; facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">87</container>
     <unittitle id="link296">Gracey Video Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/11/07 at 1PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">88</container>
     <unittitle id="link297">RA Program Planning</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/21/07 at 12:00PM in Dick's Office. Tentative program; tentative schedule for pre-RA local leaders and Retire Council conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">89</container>
     <unittitle id="link298">RA Speech Meeting and Teach New York/Vouchers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/1/06 at 2-4PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1 and 4-5pm in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">90</container>
     <unittitle id="link299">RA Site Visit</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/06/06 at 11-3PM in Washington DC. Memo re agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">91</container>
     <unittitle id="link300">NYSUT RA</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>RA Reporter daily proceedings, noting unification of NYSUT and NEA/NY, endorsement of Hillary Clinton for re-election to U.S. Senate; list of Community Service Awards nominees; program and agenda for pre-RA local and retiree council presidents
      conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">92</container>
     <unittitle id="link301">RA</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2008 NYSUT Representative Assembly "Convention Call" and pre-NYSUT RA Local &amp;amp; Retiree Council Presidents Conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link302">NYSUT RA 2008 Representative Assembly</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 10-12, 2008. Tabbed scripts for general sessions for Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link303">NYSUT 35th Annual Representative Assembly [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/26-28/07, 2007 Black Book. Agenda and tabbed script for RA general sessions 1-2; report of the Resolutions Committee, session 1</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link304">NYSUT 35th Annual Representative Assembly [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/26-28/07, 2007 Black Book. Tabbed script for RA general sessions 3-5</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link305">GLSEN: RA in DC</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Gay, Lesbian and Straight Education Network internship job description</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link306">RA, Rochester: GLSEN</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>RA Reporter daily proceeding newsletters; brochure, "Dealing with Legal Matters Surrounding Students' Sexual Orientation and Gender Identity"; brochure, "What can you do about anti-LGBT bias in America's k-12 schools?"; materials re table assignment
      for GLSEN at Representative Assembly; list of chapters; GLSEN newsletter, Respect, September 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link307">NY Teacher: Going Forward</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/01/09 at 4PM in Dick's Office. Memo confirming meeting to discuss the future of New York Teacher newsletter</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link308">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/09/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for November 26 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link309">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/26/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for November 12 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link310">New NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/26/09 at 1PM in Dick's Office. List of possible new titles for New York Teacher; design timeline</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link311">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/13/09 at 11AM in Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for October 29 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link312">NY Teacher</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/14/09 at 11AM in Executive Conference Room 2. Story list for October 1 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link313">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/01/09 at 1PM in NYC. Articles from New York Times re Newsweek downsizing to fit smaller audience</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link314">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/01/09. Story list for June 18 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link315">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/18/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for June 4 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link316">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/20/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for May 7 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link317">New York Teacher Revisioning and Future Planning</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/25/09 at 3:30PM in Dick's Office. Document re rationale for revising New York Teacher; timeline for revisioning</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link318">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/2/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for March 19 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link319">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/17/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Issue of January 22, 2009, New York Teacher; story list for March 5 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link320">NY Teacher</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/16/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Story list for February 5 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link321">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/5/09 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for January 22 issue; memo re poll questions on school issues; handwritten letter to Maria Neira from teacher, thanking her for posters of the late Robert F. Kennedy; letter to the editor of Albany Times
      Union from Albany Public School Teachers' Association president re school aid formula</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link322">NY Teacher Planning Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/01/08 at 4PM in Dick's Office. Editorial planning calendar for several months; memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link323">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/17/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for December 11 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link324">NY Teacher</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/06/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for October 23 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link325">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/22/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for October 9 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link326">NY Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/8/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Story list for September 25 issue; press release, "Governor Patterson Announces Hearings Statewide on Property Tax Relief"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link327">Communications</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/13/08 at 4PM in Maria's Office. Memo re meeting with Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link328">New York Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/19/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conference Rm. 2. Story list for June 5 issue</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link329">NY Teacher Redesign Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/16/09 at 2PM in Dick's Office. Communications Department two-year savings and reinvestment plan; justification for revisioning (downsizing) New York Teacher; timeline; 2009-2010 issues and deadlines</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link330">New York Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/10/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conference Rm. 2. Story list for March 27</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link331">New York Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/25/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conference Rm. 2. Story list for March 13; NYSUT at-large directors Regents represented; 2008 Contract for Excellence Summary and Survey, Newburgh Enlarged City School District</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link332">New York Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/28/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conference Rm. 2. Story list for February 14</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link333">New York Teacher Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/14/08 at 11AM in Exec. Conference Rm. 2. Story list for January 31</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link334">New York Teacher Stories</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008/2009" type="inclusive">2008-2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printouts of articles from various issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link335">Officers' Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/21/09 at 1PM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; internal summary of NYSUT's Position on Charter Schools; NYSUT Action Steps; profiles of approved charter schools; NYSUT affiliated charter schools; Race to the Top Update; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link336">Officers' Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/19/09 at 12:30PM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link337">Officers' Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/08/09 at 1PM in Conf. Rm. B7C. Agenda; NYSUT 2009-1020 Budget Advocacy, outlining talking points re state budget; list of NYSUT compensation expenses; press release, "Governor Patterson Presents Economic Recovery Agenda to President-Elect Obama,"
      December 29, 2008</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link338">Officers' Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/07/08 at 2PM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; Local and Retiree Council Presidents post-conference survey summary and results</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link339">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/8/09 at 9:30AM. Discussion paper for Board of Regents re Transforming Teaching and Ensuring an Equitable Distribution of Qualified Teachers in New York State, November 10, 2009; description of framework and objectives of the New York Opportunity to
      Learn Summit 2010; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link340">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/02/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda for Officers' meeting; agenda for Cabinet meeting; financial statements; document, "Renaming New York Teacher: Summary and Survey Results," December 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link341">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/20/09 at 10AM in Dick's Office. Agenda; confidential outline of Regents/State Education Department proposal for Race to the Top</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link342">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/14/08 at 11:30AM in Conf. Rm. D. Agenda; draft letter to Chancellor Robert Bennett from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, urging Regents to seek significant increases in state aid to schools</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link343">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/02/08 at 4PM in Dick's Office. Agenda; NYSUT Policy Prohibiting Harassment; 2009 Segal Health Plan Cost Trend Survey</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link344">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/9/09 at 9:30AM. Memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link345">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/17/09 at 11:00AM. Agenda; NYSUT Harassment-Free Workplace Policy (adding predisposing genetic characteristics and gender identity or expression); memo re local presidents election results; letter from NYSUT president Dick Ianuzzi to president of
      Professional Staff Congress (NYSUT's staff union) re relationship, noting "insurmountable" differences, June 16</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link346">Officers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/20/09 at 9:30AM. Solicitation guidelines</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link347">Officers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/06/09 at 11AM in Dick's Office. Discussion topics for meeting with the Commissioner; proposal for charitable contribution administration from the secretary-treasurer, noting consistent spending over budget, April 15</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link348">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/15/09 at 10AM in Dick's Office. Agenda; agenda for Cabinet meeting; financial statements; draft program for NYSUT Local Action Project; draft program for NYSUT New Local Presidents Conference; memo re NAACP Centennial Convention; New York Post
      article about teacher salary hikes and other changes made by NYC Mayor Bloomberg and his chancellor, Joel Klein</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link349">Officers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/25/09 at 11:00AM. Agenda; United University Professions list of direct funding costs; news clipping re counterdemonstrators at Buffalo memorial service visited upon by three-person itinerant hate group; program for Local and Retiree Council
      Presidents Conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link350">Officers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/4/09 at 11:00AM. Agendas for Officers' and Cabinet meetings; letter from president of Buffalo Teachers Federation to NYSUT president Dick Ianuzzi complaining about unresponsive legal services, February 26</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link351">Meeting with Dick</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/27/09 at 10AM. Memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link352">Mini Officers Retreat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/12/09 at 9AM in Fort Orange's Club. Facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link353">Dinner with Officers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/5/09. Poll questions with arguments for and against on school-related issues; memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link354">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/2/08 at 10AM. Agenda; memo from NYSUT executive director Pauline Kinsella to NYSUT president Dick Ianuzzi re collective bargaining issues in the current and anticipated economic climate, November 19; presentation to Board of Directors meeting,
      "Impact of the Economy on the State Budget"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link355">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/19/08. Memo re cancellation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link356">Officers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/04/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; lists of Administrative Committee, NYSUT Advisory Committee, and Cabinet members; memo re Solidarity Grant recommendations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link357">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/11/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; program for ULTA (United Teachers of Los Angeles) Leadership Conference 2008; recommendations from Personnel Committee</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link358">Officers' Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/07/08 at 11AM in Dick's Office. Agenda; Solidarity Fund grant applications</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link359">NYSUT Policy Council-Maria Neira</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/7/09. Agenda; presentation bullet points, "Taking Charge of Our Professions"; document, Core Standards for Reading, Writing, and Speaking and Listening; draft document re college and career readiness standards for mathematics</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link360">Policy Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/10/08 at 10:30AM in NYSUT HQ. Presentation points re 2008 Fiscal Crisis; State Education Department policy papers for decision, Submission of a Differentiated Accountability Model to the U.S. Department of Education, and Proposed Interim Growth
      Model for Title I Accountability; draft NYSUT High School Initiatives Task Force Strategies and Action Items for Improving Graduation Rates; attendance sheet for Policy Council meeting; list of Policy Council members for 2008-2011</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link361">Policy Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/04/08 at 10AM in NYSUT HQ. Agenda; meeting attendance sheet; list of policy discussion groups; notes from November 8, 2007, meeting; draft NYSUT Briefing Bulletin re changes in tenure determination; Briefing Bulletins re 2008-09 Executive
      (governor's) Budget for Pre-K-12 and Higher Education; list of 2005-2008 Policy Council members; policy discussion paper re career and technical education; State Education Department discussion paper re Implementation of New Law on Teacher Tenure
      Determinations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link362">Policy Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/8/07 TBD. Facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link363">Barry Kaufmann</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Poughkeepsie Public School Teachers' Association president's resignation letter, coinciding with retirement as teacher</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link364">NYSUT Policy Council Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/8/07 at 10-3PM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; NYSUT Policy Council Draft Discussion Paper, "Use of Peer Review in Making Tenure Determinations"; draft NYSUT Action Plan: Tenure Determinations; list of Policy Council members, 2005-08; draft
      resolution for Representative Assembly opposing merit pay for performance; draft resolution re Medicaid reimbursement for special education services</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link365">Plattsburgh Regional Office Open House</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/25/07 at 3PM. Letter to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira from Plattsburgh regional staff director inviting her to open house for new facility; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link366">Elmsford Regional Office Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/27/06 at 10:00AM. Elmsford and NYC Regional Office staff meeting agenda; memo to regional staff directors re health benefits update; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">66</container>
     <unittitle id="link367">Research and Educational Services Dept. Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/18/09 at 9AM in Conf. Room B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; final draft of speech, "States Will Lead the Way Toward Reform: National Governors Association"; NYSUT's Framework for Action on Teacher Quality; document re teacher quality and effectiveness</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">67</container>
     <unittitle id="link368">Research and Educational Services Planning Session</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/5/09. List of schools in need of improvement under Title I, with cover press release from State Education Department, September 3, 2004; memo from NYSUT director of field operations to NYSUT officers re public employee strikes in New York (text of
      Taylor Law), September 19, 2005; summary of Division of Research and Educational Services Planning Conference, April 28-29, 2005; speech by Maria Neira at Representative Assembly, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">68</container>
     <unittitle id="link369">Research and Educational Services Dept. Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/9/08 at 9AM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. List of small groups discussing "Charting Our Course"; discussion group work sheets; list of NYSUT's organizational frameworks; outline of staff meeting theme, "Staying Ahead of the Curve"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">69</container>
     <unittitle id="link370">Research and Educational Services Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/18/08 at 9:00AM in Conf. Rm. B&amp;amp;C. Agenda; document, 2007-08 Review of Major Issues and Events; questions for table discussion on collaboration; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">70</container>
     <unittitle id="link371">Resarch &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs. Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/29/06 at 9:00AM in NYSUT Auditorium. Agenda, including discussion item re assimilating NEA staff and review of unification rationale; highlights of June 29 meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">71</container>
     <unittitle id="link372">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/13/06 at 9:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda for managers' meeting; talking points for NYSUT president Dick Ianuzzi and vice president Maria Neira re Representative Assembly resolutions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">72</container>
     <unittitle id="link373">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/06/06 at 9AM. Staff meeting agenda; reprint of article from December 8, 2005, New York Teacher, "Combating the Achievement Gap" ; special report by the Education Trust, "The Funding Gap 2005: Low-Income and Minority Students Shortchanged by Most
      States"; campaign trifold brochure (apparent retirement gag), "Yagielski for Congress in 06"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">73</container>
     <unittitle id="link374">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs. Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/06/06 at 9:00AM in Conf. Room B&amp;amp;C. Staff meeting agenda; reprint of article from December 8, 2005, New York Teacher, "Combating the Achievement Gap" ; special report by the Education Trust, "The Funding Gap 2005: Low-Income and Minority
      Students Shortchanged by Most States"; campaign trifold brochure (apparent retirement gag), "Yagielski for Congress in 06"; brochure, "NYSUT presents Literacy and Math Institutes," February 11, 2006; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">74</container>
     <unittitle id="link375">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/05/05 at 12:30PM in Chuck's Office. Managers' meeting agenda; document, EMSC Deputy Commissioner Search</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">75</container>
     <unittitle id="link376">Research and Educational Services Holiday Parties</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Holiday party invitation from the Neiras; guest list; replies</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">76</container>
     <unittitle id="link377">NYSUT Research &amp;amp; Educational Services Staff Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/20/07 Agenda; 2007 Report of the Vice President; clippings of articles by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">77</container>
     <unittitle id="link378">Research and Educational Services Managers Retreat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>08/26/09 at Sargo's, Saratoga Springs. Discussion materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">78</container>
     <unittitle id="link379">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/21/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda; memo from Maria Neira to NYSUT Board of Directors re expiration of terms of members of Board of Regents, possible candidates, December 18</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">79</container>
     <unittitle id="link380">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/11/09 at 4PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; revised draft report of NYSUT Task Force on Improving Graduation Rates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">80</container>
     <unittitle id="link381">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/23/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">81</container>
     <unittitle id="link382">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/8/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">82</container>
     <unittitle id="link383">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/05/09 at 10:30AM in Chuck's Office. Memo from Maria Neira to Chuck Santelli re meeting to review work</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">83</container>
     <unittitle id="link384">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/21/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda; draft report, "Contracting for Teacher Quality: Annual Professional Performance and Contract Language"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">84</container>
     <unittitle id="link385">R &amp;amp; E Managers &amp;amp; PSA</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>09/11/09 at 3:15PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">85</container>
     <unittitle id="link386">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/8/09 at 2:00PM. Agenda; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">86</container>
     <unittitle id="link387">R &amp;amp; E Managers Retreat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>08/26/09 at 10AM in Sargo's at Saratoga National, Crystal Room. Agenda; draft discussion item re next steps for NYSUT for Race to the Top; outline for Southern Tier Summer Leadership Conference; response by State Education Department to U.S. Department
      of Education request for comments re Race to the Top, August 24, 2009</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">87</container>
     <unittitle id="link388">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/08/09 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; NYSERDA (New York State Energy Research and Development Authority)/NYSUT Partnership Proposal; presentation outline re federal and state efforts at education reform</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">88</container>
     <unittitle id="link389">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/21/09 at 3PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; recommendations from the Regents Project Management Group; materials for New Local Presidents' Conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">89</container>
     <unittitle id="link390">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/11/09 at 10AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT New Staff Orientation; NYSUT capital expenditures budget for 2009-10; budget for Office of the First Vice President</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">90</container>
     <unittitle id="link391">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/27/09 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; materials for QuEST conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">91</container>
     <unittitle id="link392">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/13/09 at 9:30AM. Agenda; agenda for Transforming Assessment and Accountability Systems: A Working Forum for State Partners</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">92</container>
     <unittitle id="link393">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/23/09 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; memo re request for PSC (Professional Staff Congress/CUNY) funding</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">93</container>
     <unittitle id="link394">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/09/09 at 3:00AM in Chuck's Office. Draft program for NYSUT Local Action Project; agenda and list of attendees at 2009 Local Presidents Conference; planning meeting agenda; timetable; flyer</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">94</container>
     <unittitle id="link395">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/11/09 in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting; questions for roundtable discussion on the economy and state aid; letter to Kerry Kennedy from NYSUT president Dick Ianuzzi re Speak Up Speak Out social justice agenda
      partnership between NYSUT and Robert F. Kennedy Memorial</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">95</container>
     <unittitle id="link396">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/13/09 at 3:00PM. Agenda; draft questions for NYSUT 2009 NEA Accountability Grant; materials re teacher certification</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">96</container>
     <unittitle id="link397">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/24/08 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; presentation outline re Federal Policy Agenda: State Input on NEA's Blue Book</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">97</container>
     <unittitle id="link398">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/11/08 at 10AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; memo from State Education Department re guidance on record keeping and reporting the required professional development completed by teachers and teaching assistants; NYSUT Information Bulletin re the
      professional development requirement for certification</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">98</container>
     <unittitle id="link399">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/27/08 at 2:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">99</container>
     <unittitle id="link400">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/14/08 at 3:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; memos re credit recovery (allowing students to graduate by taking online courses to make up for missed class time), importing thousands of foreign teachers to make up for teacher shortage</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">100</container>
     <unittitle id="link401">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/29/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; summary of May 29-30, 2008, meeting with BOCES representatives, State Education Department staff, and others; growth model forums survey questions; New York Post article re credit recovery for graduation by online
      coursework</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">101</container>
     <unittitle id="link402">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/9/08 at 9AM. Agenda; NYSUT Position Paper on Recommendations for Improving New York State's Assessment System; flyer and description of education summit re closing the achievement gap in Title I schools</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">102</container>
     <unittitle id="link403">R &amp;amp; E Managers Retreat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/3/08 at 10AM in Sargo's. Agenda; retreat materials; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">103</container>
     <unittitle id="link404">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/25/08 at 3PM. Agenda; list of committee nominations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">104</container>
     <unittitle id="link405">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/9/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; draft outline of Governor's Dropout Summit; presentation to NYSUT by James Viola, executive director, NYS Education Department, June 5, 2008; memo recommending against proposed legislation requiring school districts to enforce
      a disciplinary action against students regardless of whether the offending behavior occurred in a different district</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">105</container>
     <unittitle id="link406">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/29/08. Agenda; handwritten notes; memo re Peer Assistance and Review contract language</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">106</container>
     <unittitle id="link407">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/12/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; agenda for statewide conference by Capital Region BOCES, "Ready, Set, Grow: School Improvement through Value-Added Analysis"; draft agenda for NYSUT Local Action Project Summer Planning Conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">107</container>
     <unittitle id="link408">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/25/08. Agenda; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">108</container>
     <unittitle id="link409">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/18/08 at 3PM. Agenda; materials for Representative Assembly, including list of invitees; list of pre-RA attendees for Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference; report to the Board of Regents, "Charter Schools: overview of the formation process
      and impact in small cities"; discussion and action items for Regents meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">109</container>
     <unittitle id="link410">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/25/08 at 1PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">110</container>
     <unittitle id="link411">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>02/08/08 at 2:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; draft report by NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, "2008 Physical Education Compliance Survey and Summary"; text of budget bill in Senate and Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link412">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/26/08 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; outline of speech by Maria Neira re teachers and teacher quality</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link413">R &amp;amp; E Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/22/08 at 10:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting; 2008 needs assessment survey by bargaining unit leaders; 2008 Newburgh Enlarged City School District Contract for Excellence Survey</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link414">Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/7/08 at 9:30AM. Agenda; State Education Department progress report on implementation of Chapter 57 of the Laws of 2007</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link415">R &amp;amp; E Managers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/18/07 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; downloaded articles, including Local Presidents' Online Reference Guide; draft letter to the editor to be signed by Board of Regents, NYSUT, and NYS Council of School Superintendents re addressing teacher
      shortage by allowing retired certified teachers to return to work without diminishing their retirement benefits</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link416">R &amp;amp; E Managers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/21/07 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; report by Council of Chief State School Officers, "Recommendations to Reauthorize the Elementary and Secondary Education Act"; Policy Council presentation, "Focus on Accountability"; agenda and list of
      Policy Council attendees at March 28 meeting; letter from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira to Education Commissioner Richard Mills re testing program for grades 3-8, November 13, 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link417">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>06/27/06 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; document, "NYSUT Research Department: What We Do, What We Need"; employment (salary) histories for individual NYSUT staff (CWA or PSA)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link418">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/25/06 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Draft language of an SES Rewards and Incentive Policy</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link419">L &amp;amp; RCPC Debriefing</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/24/06 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 1. Local and Retiree Council Presidents Conference agenda; evaluation form summaries for various conference events</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link420">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/15/06 at 9:30AM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting; confidential (for managers only) NYSUT promotional recommendations guidelines; related materials; list of Research and Educational Services staffing</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link421">Research &amp;amp; Ed. Svcs. Managers Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>01/25/06 at 2:30PM in Chuck's Office. Agenda; agenda for 2006 Pre-RA Local and Retirees Council Presidents Conference, January 27; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting, February 8; NYSUT-NEA Unification Q and A; resolutions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link422">Maria Neira NYSUT Statewide Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/06/08. Agenda for NYSUT Statewide Committee meeting; comments for review by Maria Neira re possible NYSUT position on modifications to regulations allowing make-up course credit (credit recovery) and independent study, December 3; list of Research
      and Educational Services committees, 2008-2011; newsletter, Connect-ability, on disabilities awareness, prepared by and for students, 2007, with message from Maria Neira; NYSUT position paper on improving access, support, and employability for students
      with disabilities, August 2008; guidance paper on virtual learning in New York State; Recommendations of NYSUT's Committee on Education Technology; end-of-term reports for the NYSUT Educational Services committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link423">Subject Area Committee Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/1-3/08 at 7PM in Desmond. Facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link424">End of Term Reports</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005/2008" type="inclusive">2005-2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Reports by NYSUT Educational Services committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link425">VOTE COPE</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/28/09 at 3:30PM in Executive Conference Room 2. Revised proposed agenda; financial statements; minutes of March 11 and May 5, 2009, meetings; financial report; resolutions authorizing expenditures; memos re VOTE COPE's tax status; memo re new draft
      regulations prohibiting gifts of more than nominal value, including meals and beverages, to public officials, January 30; conflict of interest and whistleblower policy; tax return documents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link426">VOTE/COPE Questionnaire 2008 Fiscal Year</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/28/09. Disclosure form for Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link427">VOTE COPE</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>05/05/09 at 3:30PM in Executive Conf. Rm. 2. Confidential memo re change in IRS regulations affecting VOTE COPE's tax status; confidential presentation points re tax exempt functions of NYSUT and VOTE/COPE; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link428">VOTE COPE Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2009">2009</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>04/29/09 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Facilitative memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link429">VOTE COPE Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>10/2/08 at 3PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Proposed agenda; financial report; resolutions authorizing expenditures; list of Local Assistance Rebates; minutes of January 22, 2008, meeting; draft minutes of October 2, 2008, meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link430">VOTE COPE</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/2/08. Facilitative memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link431">VOTE COPE</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>03/11/08 at 3:30PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Proposed agenda; minutes of October 2, 2008, meeting, including resolutions authorizing expenditures; VOTE/COPE flow chart for cash flow; financial report; facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link432">Vote Cope</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2008">2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/22/08 at 2PM in Exec. Conf. Rm. 2. Proposed agenda; minutes of August 14, 2007, meeting, including resolutions authorizing expenditures; list of Local Assistance Rebates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>