<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
			publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06064p::Philione Fried
Collection of Sidney and Bessie Abramowitz Hillman Photographs.)//EN"
			>KCL06064p.xml</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Philione Fried Collection of Sidney and Bessie Abramowitz Hillman Photographs<date> 1946-1956</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Fried, Philione Collection of Sidney and Bessie Abramowitz Hillman Photographs</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
				<date>October 28, 2015</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>October 28, 2015</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Philione Fried Collection of Sidney and Bessie Abramowitz Hillman Photographs<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 6064 P</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183> <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
							>kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, June 05, 2013</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Randall Miles, October 28, 2015</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>&#169; 2015 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Philione Fried Collection of Sidney and Bessie Abramowitz Hillman Photographs, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC
245$f">1946-1956</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">6064 P</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Fried, Philoine</persname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1.8 linear ft.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Photographs.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a4" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
			<p>Sidney Hillman (March 23, 1887-July 10, 1946) was an American labor leader. He was head of the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America and instrumental in the creation of the Congress of Industrial Organizations. He encouraged labor's support of
				Franklin Delano Roosevelt and the Democratic Party. </p>
			<p>Sidney Hillman was born in Lithuania, he emigrated to America in 1907. He landed in New York City, and after finding a poor job market, he moved on to Chicago, where the job market was better. He found work in the garment industry as an
				apprentice. </p>
			<p>In 1910 due to a citywide strike of 45,000 garment workers against the company Hart Schaffner &amp; Marx, the Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America was formed, because the garment workers were so unhappy with the agreement the United
				Garment Workers had come up with. </p>
			<p>Hillman became Chief Clerk within the International Ladie's Garment Workers' Union in early 1914. The union workers that formed Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America started contacting Hillman and wanted him to take over as President, the most
				persuasive letter came from Bessie Abramowitz, who was one of the original leaders of the Chicago strike, and also Hillman's fiance. He accepted the offer and left the ILG the next year. </p>
			<p>Sidney and Bessie married in 1916, and had two daughters. </p>
			<p>Hillman's leadership encouraged the "constructive cooperation" between employers in the industry to impose industry wide working standards, which would take wages and hours out of the dispute equation. Hillman worked to get companies to use
				arbitration to settle disputes. </p>
			<p>The Great Depression of 19291939 strengthened Hillman's belief in the importance of a strong partnership between government and labor. He was named to the Labor Advisory Board of the National Recovery Administration in 1933 and to the National
				Industrial Recovery Board in 1934. One of his closest advisers helped Sen. Robert Wagner draft the historic labor legislation that became the National Labor Relations Act. And Hillman himself worked closely with Secretary of Labor Frances
				Perkins to draft a comprehensive wage and hours bill that eventually became the Fair Labor Standards Act. </p>
			<p>Hillman helped create the Committee for Industrial Organization in 1935. In 1937, Hillman pulled ACWA (which had re-affiliated with the AFL in 1933) out of the AFL, joining John L. Lewis and others to found the Congress of Industrial
				Organizations (CIO). Elected first vice president of the CIO in 1937, Hillman headed up its Textile Workers Organizing Committee and its Department Store Workers Organizing Committee. </p>
			<p>The Textile Workers Union of America came to life in 1939, with more than 100,000 members, and that led directly to the creation of the Retail, Wholesale and Department Store Workers Union of America. </p>
			<p>In both World War I and World War II, Hillman used the influence of the federal government to advance labor's social goals and its organizing needs. He was a strong supporter of Roosevelt and campaigned for him in both elections. At times
				leaving the labor industry wondering if he was leaving the labor movement behind. </p>
			<p>The Sydney Hillman Foundation established in his honor, gives annual awards to journalists and writers for work that supoorts social justice and progressive public policy. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Bessie Abramowitz (May 15, 1889-December 23, 1970) </p>
			<p>Bessie Abramowitz Hillman devoted her life to unions, organizing her first strike at fifteen, announcing her engagement on a picket line, and continuing her fight for workers' rights untill her death. </p>
			<p>Bessie immigrated to America alone at fifteen and started work sewing buttons in a garment factory while attending night school at Hull House, run by suffragette Jane Addams. Abramowitz organized workers for the Women's Trade Union League all
				along the East Coast, and then went on to become education director of the Laundry Workers Joint Board in 1937. Through Laundry Workers, she became involved in civil rights issues, serving with the CIO and AFL-CIO. She also worked with the
				Child Welfare Committee of New York, the Defense Advisory Commission on Women in the Services, and President Kennedy's Commission on the Status of Women, among many others. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Sidney and Bessie's daughters Sally and Philoine and grandchildren, help to carry on their legacy to this day.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Fried, Philione </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hillman, Bessie Abramowitz </persname>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hillman, Sidney, 1887-1946 </persname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects: </head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor leaders </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Photographs.</genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Philione Fried Collection of Sidney and Bessie Abramowitz Hillman Photographs #6064 P. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link6">Photos of Sidney and Bessie Hillman</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>8 photographs</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link7">Photos - Sidney Hillman, Rich Berc, William Green, John L. Lewis</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>3 photographs</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle id="link8">Photo Album contents</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>71 photographs, some text</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link9">Sidney Hillman Photo Album</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>30 photographs, photocopies of the photos, some text</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link10">Photo album contents</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>59 photographs - photo album cover was unique, so it was kept and is stored in box under the photos</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link11">Amalgamated Clothing Workers 40th Anniv., 19th Biennial Convention - 1954</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>34 photographs - Album cover included</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link12">Amalgamated Life Ins. Company - Meeting Program - 1946</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle id="link13">20th Biennial Convention - Amalgamated Clothing Workers - 1956</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>52 photographs</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle id="link14">Photo Album contents</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>40 photographs</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">3</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle id="link15">Sidney Hillman Photo Album</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>9 photographs</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">4</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link16">Oversize photograph of David Dubinsky</unittitle>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>1 photograph</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
