<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" standalone="no"?>
	 
<ead>
   <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
      <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05204-002::The Green rising)//EN">KCL05204-002.xml</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Southern Tenant Farmers Union. The Green
			 Rising, 1901-1977.</titleproper>
            <titleproper type="sort">Southern Tenant Farmers Union. The Green
			 Rising, 1901-1977.</titleproper>
            <author>Compiled by University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill.
			 Library. Southern Historical Collection.</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
			 Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
            <date>December 2, 2002</date>
         </publicationstmt>
         <notestmt>
            <note audience="internal">
               <p> 
				
                  <subject>labor</subject>
               </p>
            </note>
         </notestmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>Finding aid encoded by Casey S. Westerman 
		  <date>December 2, 2002</date>
         </creation>
      </profiledesc>
      <revisiondesc>
         <change encodinganalog="583">
            <date normal="2007-05-29">2007-05-29</date>
            <item>converted from EAD 1.0 to EAD 2002 </item>
         </change>
      </revisiondesc>
   </eadheader>
   <frontmatter>
      <titlepage>
         <titleproper>Guide to the Southern Tenant Farmers Union. The Green
		  Rising, <lb/>1910-1977</titleproper>
         <num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc1993">Collection Number: 5204B</num>
         <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
		  Cornell University Library </publisher>
         <list type="deflist">
            <defitem>
               <label>Contact Information:</label>
               <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
				Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell
				University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/> 
				<extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
				<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref> </item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Compiled by:</label>
               <item>University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill. Library. Southern
				Historical Collection.</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>Date completed:</label>
               <item>1978</item>
            </defitem>
            <defitem>
               <label>EAD encoding:</label>
               <item>Casey S. Westerman, December 2, 2002</item>
            </defitem>
         </list>
         <date>© 2002 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
		  Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
      </titlepage>
   </frontmatter>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
         <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="245$a">Southern Tenant Farmers
		  Union. The Green Rising, 
		  <unitdate encodinganalog="245$f">1910-1977. </unitdate>
         </unittitle>
         <unitid label="Collection Number:">5204B</unitid>
         <origination label="Creator:">Souther Tenant Farmers Union.</origination>
         <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="300">17 microfilm
		  reels.</physdesc>
         <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Microfilm.</physdesc>
         <repository label="Repository:"> 
		  
            <corpname>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
			 Cornell University Library </corpname>
         </repository>
         <abstract label="Abstract:">Consists of the papers of four men active in
		  the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union: Harry Leland Mitchell, a founding member
		  and first executive secretary of the union; Thomas H. Gibbins; Clyde L.
		  Johnson, an organizer for the Southern Organizing Committee of the Farmers'
		  Union and various other trade unions; and David S. Burgess, a minister active
		  in organizing migrant workers. The collections contain correspondence, subject
		  files, printed matter, manuscripts, autobiographies, oral histories, newspapers
		  and newsletters, sermons, and reports which document each individual's
		  career.</abstract>
         <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="041" langcode="eng">English</language>
         </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist encodinganalog="545">
         <p>The Southern Tenant Farmers' Union (STFU), a multi-racial union of
		  sharecroppers, tenant farmers and small landowners, was founded in Arkansas in
		  1934 by a group of socialists. Its operations extended throughout the South,
		  the Southwest, and California and came to include migrant farm workers, cannery
		  workers, rice and sugar mill workers and fishermen.</p>
         <p>Harry Leland Mitchell was a founding member and first executive
		  secretary of the Southern Tenant Farmers' Union from 1934 to 1939. During this
		  time, he was also an officer of the Socialist Party of Arkansas. After serving
		  as a consultant and special assistant to the National Youth Administration and
		  as an organizer for the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union, Mitchell
		  was re-elected secretary of the STFU from 1941 to 1944 and served as president
		  of its successor, the National Farm Labor Union. During the 1950's, Mitchell
		  served on Dept. of Labor Committees and participated in various international
		  labor activities, as well as helping to form the AFL-CIO's Agricultural
		  Workers' Organizing Committee. During the 1960's, Mitchell continued to
		  organize southern agricultural workers, as well as rice and sugar mill workers
		  and fishermen. He also helped to found the Southern Mutual Help Association,
		  Inc. of Louisiana (1969) and the Southern Rural Welfare Association (1971).</p>
         <p>Thomas H. Gibbins was employed for many years by Western Union
		  Telegraph Company and other concerns in Kansas City. In the early 1930's, he
		  turned to farming and continued in that occupation until drought conditions
		  forced him to move to California, where he held various jobs. From 1950 until
		  1965, he served as caretaker at the Children's Home Society of California.</p>
         <p>During the Depression, Clyde L. Johnson was an activist in the
		  National Student League. In Georgia, he organized unemployed and WPA workers,
		  as well as farmers. As a member of the Communist Party, Johnson organized
		  workers in the steel and coal industries of Alabama. In 1935, he became
		  secretary of the Alabama Share Croppers Union and later served on the Southern
		  Organizing Committee of the National Farmers' Union. He also held various posts
		  in the United Cannery, Agricultural, Packing and Allied Workers of America, the
		  Oil Workers Organizing Committee, the Newspaper Guild, the United Electrical
		  Workers, and the United Brotherhood of Carpenters and Joiners. Since 1966, he
		  has worked as a consultant and writer on labor.</p>
         <p>During the 1940's, David S. Burgess served as Minister to Agricultural
		  Labor for the United Church of Christ and worked with the Southern Tenant
		  Farmers' Union among agricultural migrants, tenant farmers and small farmers in
		  the South. In 1947, Burgess worked as an organizer for the Textile Workers'
		  Union of America. In 1949, he became southern representative for the CIO
		  Political Action Committee and, during the 1950's, served as executive
		  secretary of the Georgia CIO Council. From 1955 to 1960, Burgess was the
		  American labor attache in India. In the 1960's and '70's, he held various
		  administrative posts in the Peace Corps and UNICEF.</p>
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent encodinganalog="520">
         <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
         <p>Consists of the papers of four men active in the Southern Tenant
		  Farmers' Union: Harry Leland Mitchell, a founding member and first executive
		  secretary of the union; Thomas H. Gibbins; Clyde L. Johnson, an organizer for
		  the Southern Organizing Committee of the Farmers' Union and various other trade
		  unions; and David S. Burgess, a minister active in organizing migrant workers.
		  The collections contain correspondence, subject files, printed matter,
		  manuscripts, autobiographies, oral histories, newspapers and newsletters,
		  sermons, and reports which document each individual's career.</p>
      </scopecontent>
      <controlaccess>
         <head id="a7">SUBJECTS</head>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Names: </head>
            <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Burgess, David S.,
			 1917-</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Gibbins, Thomas H.,
			 1897-</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Johnson, Clyde L.,
			 1908-</persname>
            <persname encodinganalog="600" role="subject">Mitchell, H. L. (Harry
			 Leland), 1906-</persname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Alabama Share Croppers'
			 Union.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">American Newspaper
			 Guild.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Louisiana Farmers'
			 Union.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Oil Workers'
			 International Union.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Share Croppers'
			 Union.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">Southern Tenant Farmers'
			 Union.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">United Brotherhood of
			 Carpenters and Joiners of America. Local 550 (Oakland, Calif.)</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">United Cannery,
			 Agricultural, Packing, and Allied Workers of America.</corpname>
            <corpname encodinganalog="610" role="subject">United Electrical, Radio
			 and Machine Workers of America. Local 610 (Pittsburgh, Pa.)</corpname>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Subjects:</head>
            <subject encodinganalog="650">Church and labor--United
			 States.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="650">Migrant agricultural laborers--United
			 States.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="650">Migrant labor--United States.</subject>
            <subject encodinganalog="650">Sharecropping.</subject>
         </controlaccess>
         <controlaccess>
            <head>Form and Genre Terms:</head>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655">Autobiographies.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655">Photographs.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655">Sermons.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655">Speeches.</genreform>
            <genreform encodinganalog="655">Oral histories.</genreform>
         </controlaccess>
      </controlaccess>
      <descgrp type="admininfo">
         <head id="a8">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
         <accessrestrict encodinganalog="505$a">
            <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
            <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please
			 contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
         </accessrestrict>
         <userestrict>
            <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
            <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center
			 Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
         </userestrict>
         <prefercite>
            <head>Cite As:</head>
            <p>Southern Tenant Farmers Union. The Green Rising, 1901-1977. 5204B.
			 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
			 University Library. </p>
         </prefercite>
      </descgrp>
   </archdesc>
</ead>