<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
            publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-049p::ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn
Photographs.)//EN"
            >KCL05780-049p.xml</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn Photographs<date>
                        1916-1935</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn
                    Photographs</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>April 08, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>April 08,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn
                Photographs<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780/049 P</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
                            >kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center"
                            >http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, December 02, 2010</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, April 08, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>&#169; 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">ILGWU Education Department, Fannia
                Cohn Photographs, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1916-1935</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/049 P</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Cohn, Fannia M. (Fannia
                    Mary)</persname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Photographs .</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Collection consists of photographs pulled from the Fannia
                Cohn papers. Photographs include portraits of Cohn, as well as document activities
                of Local 66, trips to Unity House, Triangle Factory fire commemoration, and other
                union activities.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>, <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="rus">Russian</language>, <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="yid">Yiddish</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a4" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
            <p>Fannia Cohn, garment worker, labor organizer and educator, </p>
            <p> and officer, International Ladies' Garment Workers' </p>
            <p> Union. Fannia Cohn was born in Minsk in the late 1880s </p>
            <p> (there is disagreement as to the exact year). She </p>
            <p> emigrated to the U.S. in 1904 and began working in a New </p>
            <p> York garment factory in 1905. She joined the ILGWU in </p>
            <p> 1909 and quickly emerged as a skilled leader and </p>
            <p> organizer. She was the first woman vice-president of the </p>
            <p> ILGWU and in 1918 became Executive Secretary of the </p>
            <p> Education Department, a position she held until her </p>
            <p> retirement in 1961. She played a significant role in </p>
            <p> worker education and was a co-founder of both the </p>
            <p> Workers' Education Bureau and the Brookwood Labor </p>
            <p> College. She died in 1962 in New York City.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
            <p>Local union's of the ILGWU established and maintained robust, ambitious educational
                departments early on in the international's history. As these groups grew in size
                and scope, the international office sought to coordinate and centralize educational
                programming for the union's members, culminating in the formation of the Educational
                Department in 1918. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The department's programming included courses at the Workers' University at the
                Washington Irving High School in New York City, lectures at Unity Centers and Unity
                Houses in the northeastern United States, and other events. The educational
                offerings of the International's Education Department were varied, as had been the
                education departments of the local unions, and included not only classes in labor
                studies but also courses in languages, music, and the arts. The ILGWU's 1937 musical
                "Pins and Needles" exemplified the diversity of the union's programs. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Directors of the Education Department, especially Fannia Cohn and Mark Starr, wrote
                extensively on the ILGWU's programs and worker education in general. Longtime
                director Gus Tyler not only directed the department, but also served as the ILGWU's
                on-staff scholar. In later years, the Education Department went beyond collaborating
                with other education organizations and arranging in-house programs to also
                supporting post-secondary education for union members and their families.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
            <p>The Education Department records document activities across the entire period of the
                department's existence, with the bulk of the records covering the 1970s and 1990s.
                It contains papers from directors of the Education Department: Fannia Cohn, Mark
                Starr, Gus Tyler, and Kitty Krupat. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The earliest documentation of the department's work is found in the Fannia Cohn
                papers (5780/049, 5780/049 P); these contain correspondence, subject files,
                speeches, photographs, and printed material from her work as director of the
                Educational Department. A microfilm copy of the Fannia Cohn papers held at the New
                York Public Library (5998 mf) complements the Kheel Center's holdings. Documentation
                of the work of another longtime leader of the Education Department, Mark Starr, is
                contained in these records (5780/166, 5780/166 PUBS), as well as in a related
                collection from Starr on worker education programs (5243). </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Documentation of the work of Gus Tyler, who led the merged Education and Political
                Department after Mark Starr's retirement in 1960, is also contained in the ILGWU
                records (5780/052, 5780/088, 5780/096). Tyler's papers are complemented by those of
                Assistant Director Jasper Peyton (5780/086) and Special Projects Coordinator Beverly
                Shulman (5780/106). These collections contain routine correspondence and memoranda,
                reports, materials relating to training institutes, seminars, and conferences, and
                printed material. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The papers of Kitty Krupat, who was serving as Education Director at the time of the
                ILGWU/ACTWU merger in 1995, constitute the entirety of Education Department records
                from the 1990s. They include correspondence, memoranda, reports, and financial
                records relating to the ILGWU's independent and collaborative education projects,
                including the Worker-Family Education Program, the Joint Union-University Committee
                on Labor Education, and the Consortium for Worker Education, as well as numerous
                trainings, conferences, and seminars. Also included in the files are materials from
                local unions and regional departments of the ILGWU, files on the Internationals'
                conventions, and reports to the General Executive Board. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Fannia Cohn papers (5780/049) contain correspondence, subject files, speeches,
                articles, photographs, and programs from Fannia Cohn's term as Executive Secretary
                of the ILGWU Education Department. The materials in Series I are primarily letters
                between Cohn and various individuals pertaining to trade union matters in general
                and the ILGWU in particular. Included in the series are programs for lectures,
                concerts, museum visits and tours of New York City that were offered to ILGWU
                members and others as part of the Education Department's activities. Series II
                consists of bulletins, articles, lectures and course outlines. Most of these
                materials were written by Cohn herself or were prepared under her direction for use
                at the union's Unity Centers and at the Workers' University. A number of articles
                are by Mark Starr. There are also lectures by Charles A. Beard; Robert Brure;
                Babette Deutsch; Paul H. Douglas; Harry Laidler; A.J. Muste; Grace Scribner;
                Alexander Trachtenberg; Carl Van Doren; and Theresa Wolfson, among others.
                Significant individuals represented in the collection include David Dubinsky, Samuel
                Gompers, Morris Sigman ,Rose Pesotta, and H.G. Wells. Organizations include the
                Education Department of the ILGWU, the Brookwood Labor College, the AFL, Pioneer
                Youth of America, the Rand School of Social Science, and Unity House.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Bereowitz, Edith </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Bosel, Mary </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Bosel, Sadie </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Calderon, Abe </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Cohn, Fannia M.(Fannia Mary), 1885- </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Curbelo, Carmen </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982 </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Frati, Lucy </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Fried, Lazar </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Gidda, Sam </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Goff, Mary </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Kadison, Harry </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Karlowski, Ann </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Kula, Anna </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Leonotti, Jimmy </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Liberti, Frank </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Lubin, Gertrude </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Miller, Ruth </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Pesotta, Rose, 1896- </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Provenzale, Catherine </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Provenzale, Christine </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Rivera, Ambaro </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Rosenfelt, Ada </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Rossi, David </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Rothberg, Clara </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Sosnovsky, Anna </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Starr, Mark </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Vengen, Frances </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Weiss, Bessie </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Wertis, David </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Wolfson, Theresa, 1897-1972 </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">American Federation of Labor. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    Educational Dept. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects: </head>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions--Officials and employees. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor movement. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC  650">Labor movement--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions and education--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Working class-- Education--United States.
                </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Photographs. </genreform>
            </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn Photographs #5780/049 P. Kheel Center for
                    Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780:
                    ILGWU records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-106.html">
                    5780/106: ILGWU Education Department, Beverly Shulman Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-138.html">
                    5780/138: ILGWU Education Department, Kitty Krupat Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-166.html">
                    5780/166: ILGWU Education Department Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-166pubs.html">
                    5780/166 PUBS: ILGWU Education Department Publications</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-086.html">
                    5780/086: ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-049.html">
                    5780/049: ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-049mf.html">
                    5780/049 mf: ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn Papers on
                    Microfilm</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Cohn, Fannia. General, ca. 1910s-mid1930s.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1916/1934">1916-1934</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: Niagara Falls "ILGWU Convention Special," 1934; Fairfield,
                        Connecticut, 1934; Bermuda 1924; A.F. of L. Convention, 1916; and
                        unspecified.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Cohn, Fannia. Portraits, ca. 1920s-1930s</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: Formal portraits of Fannia Cohn, some on postcards, from Unity
                        House and her time as Executive Secretary of the ILGWU Educational
                        Department</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Local 66</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: Local 66 excursion to Bear Mountain (1935) Fannia Cohn on the Local
                        66 Excursion (S.S. Colvert?) (1935)</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Summer Schools and Camps, ca. 1926-1935 (majority
                        1935)</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1926/1935">1926-1935</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: Individuals, groups and activities at Bryn Mawr Summer School (Mt.
                        Ivy, Pomona, New York), the Brookwood (Summer) Institute/Session (Katonah,
                        New York); Commonwealth College; unnamed “affiliated school”; “P.Y. Camp,”
                        1931; Local 89 students, 1935. Identified individuals include: Fannia Cohn,
                        Dr. Theresa Wolfson; Christine Provenzale; Brookwood Commencement, graduates
                        including 2 from Puerto Rico: Ruth Miller, Rebecca Goldberg, Anna Kula,
                        Edith Bereowitz, Anna Sosnovsky, Fannia M. Cohn, Mary Goff, Ambaro Rivera,
                        Frances Vengen, Carmen Curbelo, Mark Starr, Abe Calderon.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Triangle Fire Commemoration, unspecified
                        dates</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Commemoration of Triangle Fire victims including ILGWU Committee members
                        laying wreaths, gravestones (of Sarah Cooper, age 16; Rosie Mehl, age 15,
                        and Isi Rosen, age 17</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link13">Union Activities. General</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1930/1935">1930-1935</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: Waterbury [Materbury?] Strike, 1935; two female ILGWU strikers Feb.
                        14, 1935 with signs “Strike at Osgood and Sons” and “We Want Recognition of
                        our Union;” Marion Memorial meeting, Oct. 1930; graphic of marchers with
                        ILGWU banner, and images portraying education and healthcare, partial bottom
                        reads: “…Pioneers in Bringing Education, Recreation, Art and Medical Science
                        to the Service of Labor;” and women beneath an “ILGWU Educational
                        Department” sign, ca. 1930s. Identified individuals include Fannia Cohn, Ann
                        Karlowski, Helen [?] Reed, Rose Pesotta, Clara Rothberg, Theresa Wolfson and
                        Dr. Igo [?] Goldstone probably at Brookwood ca. 1930s</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">Unity House</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1924/1935">1924-1935</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: Fannia Cohn; ILGWU Training For Trade Union Activity Institute;
                        ILGWU Education Department; and union Locals 1, 32, 35, and 143 members.
                        Educational Department Unity House Institute including Out-Of-Town students
                        (1935); training for Trade Union Activity/Institute(1935); sports and
                        recreation including boating, basketball, theatrical productions and hiking;
                        ILGWU Players; art exhibition and lecture on “Appreciation of Art” (1935);
                        Pine Grove - Unity House (1934). People include: Fannia Cohn; David
                        Dubinsky; Frank Liberti; A. Ostrofsky; Bessie Weiss; Jimmy Leonotti; Molly
                        Mottola/Matolla; Mamie Troccoli; Lucy Frati; Sam Gidda; Sadie Basel/Bosel;
                        Mary Bosel; Lazar Fried; David Rossi; Harry Kadison; Gertrude Lubin;
                        Nathalie Opatowsky; Sarah Shapiro; Rose Wertis; Ada Rosenfelt; Christine
                        Provenzale; Catherine Provenzale; Gertrude Lubin; Paul Degribetzer[?]; Harry
                        Kadison; and others.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link15">Miscellaneous. ca. 1900-1930s.</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Includes: perhaps baby, childhood, and youth photos; signed photo of an
                        infant and toddler (“Jan. 1931 A Happy New Year to you Fannia dear - from
                        Teddy Peggy Pooky”); Photograph postcard of middle-aged and elder gentleman;
                        Postcard with Russian and Hebrew typeface mother and baby; young man; and
                        with who might be Fannia or a relative; two women holding a child; Christmas
                        note with two children, addressed to Fannia from Evelyn (1931); Fannia with
                        a young child; young boy. Postcard of Robert Smillie; Postcard - one man and
                        two women at work outdoors.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link16">Images digitized from the collection.</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
