<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05374::New York State Joint Legislative Committee Hearing Transcripts.)//EN">KCL05374</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the New York State Joint Legislative Committee Hearing Transcripts<date> 1928</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">New York State Joint Legislative Committee Hearing Transcripts</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
				<date>March 30, 2015</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 30, 2015</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the New York State Joint Legislative Committee Hearing Transcripts<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 5374</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183> <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
							>kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, November 25, 2013</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, March 30, 2015</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>&#169; 2015 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">New York State Joint Legislative Committee Hearing Transcripts, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1928</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5374</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">New York State Joint Legislative Committee</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.3 linear ft.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Transcripts.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Transcript of the hearings of the New York State Legislature Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions from July, September, and October of 1928.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
			<p>A joint legislative committee was established by a concurrent resolution in both houses of the New York State Legislature to inquire into manufacturing and labor conditions was established on February 25, 1926. Senator James C Truman was named
				chairman and Henry D. Sayer served as counsel and executive secretary of the committee. </p>
			<p>The committee held hearings on the operations of the State Department of Labor, the Bureau of Workmen's Compensation, the State Placement Service and the efforts of state and New York City officials to regulate private employment agencies. </p>
			<p>On January 23, 1928 Governor Alfred E. Smith appointed Lindsay Rogers, Professor of Public Law and Government at Columbia University the thirty-third Moreland Commissioner to investigate the operations of the State Department of Labor and the
				Bureau of Workmen's Compensation Insurance. It was Governor Smith's opinion that the Joint Committee was being used by the Republican Legislature in an attempt to discredit a Democratic governor. </p>
			<p>The Moreland Act of 1907 was an attempt by the proponents of good government to prevent special interests from influencing public policy. The act gave the Governor power to investigate the activities and administration of any department, bureau
				or division of the state. Although the funds were appropriated by the Legislature, disbursement was to be at the direction of the governor, who was given all the power possible under the Constitution to institute and carry out such inquiries as
				he deemed important. </p>
			<p>When the Legislature learned of Roger's appointment it asserted that Governor Smith sought to "white wash" his Administration of these departments and extended the life of its Committee to March 12, 1928 and later to March 1, 1929. A split
				between Senate Assembly Republicans, however, also produced a resolution instructing the Committee to cooperate with the Moreland Commissioner. </p>
			<p>Rogers presented his report on the first and fifteenth of June,1928. The Chairman of the Committee, James C. Truman asserted in an open letter on the twenty-seventh that Rogers gave the impression that all was well in the Department of Labor,
				although he had found as much mismanagement as the Legislative Committee. Rogers was invited to appear before the Committee to discuss the activities of the Department and his suggestions for reform. Rogers submitted his final report on
				December 1, 1928. </p>
			<p>In the meantime, on May 28, 1928, the Supreme Court of the United States decided in the case of Rebnik vs. McBride (277 U. S. 350) that, while the state had the power to license and regulate the business of an employment agent, it was not
				affected with a public interest so as to allow the state to fix charges for the service.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>This collection consists of a transcript of the hearings of the New York State Legislature Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions from July, September, and October of 1928. Hearings were held on July 10 and 31; September
				11 and 12; and October 9, 10, 23, and 24, 1928. 1,000 pages (numbered 4,686 to 5,686) plus indices of witnesses, typescript, carbon.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York (State). Legislature. Joint Legislative Committee on Industrial and Labor Conditions </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects: </head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Industrial relations -- New York (State) </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Records</genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>New York State Joint Legislative Committee Hearing Transcripts #5374. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link6">Transcript of hearings</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
