<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
  <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
    scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
    <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
      publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06036-027::The Gentle
Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and Labor Organizer by Elaine Leeder..)//EN"
      >KCL06036-027</eadid>
    <filedesc>
      <titlestmt>
        <titleproper>Guide to the The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and Labor Organizer by
          Elaine Leeder.<date> 1985-1985</date></titleproper>
        <titleproper type="sort">The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and Labor Organizer by
          Elaine Leeder.</titleproper>
        <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
      </titlestmt>
      <publicationstmt>
        <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
          Library</publisher>
        <date>January 10, 2013</date>
      </publicationstmt>
      <notestmt>
        <note audience="internal">
          <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
        </note>
      </notestmt>
    </filedesc>
    <profiledesc>
      <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kathryn Dowgiewicz, <date>January
          10, 2013</date></creation>
    </profiledesc>
  </eadheader>
  <frontmatter>
    <titlepage>
      <titleproper>Guide to the The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and Labor Organizer by
        Elaine Leeder.<lb/></titleproper>
      <num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc455">Collection Number: 6036/027</num>
      <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
        Library </publisher>
      <list type="deflist">
        <defitem>
          <label>Contact Information:</label>
          <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P.
            Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/>
            (607) 255-3183<lb/>
            <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
          </item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>Compiled by:</label>
          <item>Kheel Staff, January 10, 2013</item>
        </defitem>
        <defitem>
          <label>EAD encoding:</label>
          <item>Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013</item>
        </defitem>
      </list>
      <date>© 2013 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
        Library </date>
    </titlepage>
  </frontmatter>
  <archdesc level="collection">
    <did>
      <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
      <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta,
        Anarchist and Labor Organizer by Elaine Leeder., <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1985-
          1985</unitdate>
      </unittitle>
      <unitid label="Collection Number:">6036/027</unitid>
      <origination label="Creator:">
        <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Leeder, Elaine</persname>
      </origination>
      <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.333333333333333 linear ft.</physdesc>
      <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence,
        photographs.</physdesc>
      <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
        Cornell University Library </repository>
      <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection consists of Elaine Leeder's Ph.D. dissertation for
        Cornell University, 1985, about anarchist, labor organizer, and ILGWU member Rose
        Pesotta.</abstract>
      <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041"
          langcode="eng">English</language>
      </langmaterial>
    </did>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
      <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
      <p>Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the
        northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political
        influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by
        mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to
        improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining
        agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational
        opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing
        and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile
        Employees (UNITE).</p>
    </bioghist>
    <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
      <head id="a4" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
      <p>Born Rachelle Peisoty on November 20, 1896, Rose Pesotta was the second oldest of ten
        children. Pesotta grew up in the Ukraine where her parents owned and operated a small shop,
        and the family lived comfortably in a Jewish orthodox household. Education was important,
        and Pesotta was proficient in four languages. From 1909 to 1912, she attended Rosalia
        Davidoff's private girls' school. While her father was a member of the Bund and
        self-proclaimed political activist, he forbade any revolutionary and radical discussions in
        the home out of fear of persecution, yet older sister Esther introduced Pesotta to radical
        political ideas. After being betrothed without her knowledge to a neighborhood boy, Pesotta
        decided she wanted to immigrate to the United States to join Esther and her husband. At the
        age of seventeen and after many struggles with her family, she was finally allowed to leave
        and Pesotta and her grandmother arrived in New York. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>Pesotta stayed with Esther who was working in the needle trades. She soon joined her sister
        as a seamstress making shirtwaists, while teaching herself English. The conditions in the
        factories prompted Pesotta to join the Waistmakers Local 25 of the ILGWU in 1914. Pesotta
        was active early in the union, picketing, attending the union's education classes, and
        taking trips to Unity House. In 1917 with employment scarce in the garment industry, Pesotta
        briefly trained to become a nurse. She resumed her work in a garment factory and became
        fully invested in the Russian Revolution. In 1920, she became a member of the executive
        board of Local 22 and was a dynamic spokesperson in her shop. Pesotta attended the Bryn Mawr
        Institute for women workers during the summer of 1922 and subsequently attended other labor
        colleges including the Brookwood Labor College and the Wisconsin Summer School, gaining
        writing, speaking, and negotiating skills. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>In 1920, her father was killed during an anti-Semitic raid in his village and during this
        period she also suffered the loss of her fianc, Theodore Kushnarev, when he was deported.
        Throughout the difficulties, Pesotta continued with her work for the ILGWU and began her
        career of anarchist writing and organizing. While in Boston for a union meeting in 1922,
        Pesotta became involved in the Sacco and Vanzetti case. Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti
        were Italian immigrants active in the anarchist movement who were arrested and convicted of
        murder during an armed robbery in 1920. Pesotta met both Sacco and Vanzetti while they were
        in jail and continued to correspond and visit them until the end. She was sympathetic to
        their plight and volunteered at the defense offices and attended court proceedings. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>By September 1933, Pesotta was now a paid staff member of the union and was sent to Los
        Angeles to organize dressmakers. Her exceptional work on the west coast and the advancements
        made through her organizing efforts led to her election of vice president of the ILGWU in
        1934. She traveled to cities across the country to help with organizing efforts and strikes,
        and Pesotta became involved with the UAW during the Flint Sit-Down Strike in 1937. In 1942
        after some disagreements and opposition with a difficult to organize shop in Los Angeles,
        and tensions with the board and David Dubinsky, Pesotta resigned and resumed sewing in a New
        York dress shop. At the 25th convention in 1944, Pesotta resigned as vice president on the
        executive board of the ILGWU. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>It was when Pesotta returned to work as a sewing machine operator that she began to write
        her autobiography, "Bread Upon the Waters," published in 1945. Though not endorsed by the
        ILGWU, the book was successful and had multiple printings and was translated into different
        languages. Her new found fame led to new opportunities, including a job with the
        Anti-Defamation League. In 1946, Pesotta participated at a summer school for the Workers
        Education Association in Norway at the invitation of the secretary of the Norwegian Labor
        Party. During the trip, she also traveled to Sweden and Poland and was deeply affected by
        the conditions of post- war Poland. She soon resigned from the ADL and in January 1949,
        began a position with the American Trade Union Council for the Histadrut as Midwest regional
        director. In between the various jobs or travels, Pesotta always returned to working in the
        garment industry. During her time in the factories, she continued to write manuscripts,
        including the 1957 self-published "Days of Our Lives" about her childhood in Russia. Pesotta
        died on December 4, 1965.</p>
    </bioghist>
    <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
      <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
      <p>"The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and Labor Organizer" is a dissertation
        presented to the faculty of the Graduate School of Cornell University by Elaine Leeder in
        partial fulfillment of the requirements for the degree of doctor of philosophy in June 1985.
        Leeder later published the book now titled "The Gentle General: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and
        Labor Organizer" in 1993. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>The dissertation discusses the conditions in the small Jewish villages, shtetls, of Russia
        in the late 19th century and provides background information on Pesotta's childhood, and the
        early events and education that began her rebellion and radical thinking that led to her
        eventual departure to the United States. Jewish life for new immigrants in New York City is
        examined in relation to Pesotta, as well as an overview of the hierarchy of the workers in
        the garment industry and the sexual discrimination in the shops where she now found herself
        employed. Pesotta continued her quest for education, became active in the shops, and
        asserted her interest in radicalism and anarchism. The author provides a detailed discussion
        of anarchist ideology and an extensive history of the anarchist movement in the United
        States in Chapter Two. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>Pesotta became involved with the Nicola Sacco and Bartolomeo Vanzetti case and Chapter
        Three details her involvement with the case and the individuals she met on the defense
        committee including Albert Martin (born Frank Lopez) whom she would later briefly marry.
        Pesotta not only volunteered at the defense offices, but also visited Sacco and Vanzetti in
        jail, attended court proceedings, and corresponded often, and the case and outcome had a
        profound effect on her. The dissertation examines the shifting focus in labor to organizing
        large numbers of women during the Depression, contradictory to continued workplace
        discrimination and segregation and the absence of women from leadership roles in unions.
        Pesotta continued her union activities, including, striking, picketing, and establishing
        educational and recreational programs while making significant advancements in organizing
        dress shops on the west coast. Recounted are her achievements and feelings towards her
        election to office within the union, working with David Dubinsky, the organizing missions
        that required travel from city to city and her work with other unions and industries. Also
        detailed are the complications that arose and the opposition with Dubinsky and the executive
        board that ultimately led to Pesotta's resignation. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>In the chapter devoted to Pesotta's political work, related is her involvement with the
        "Road to Freedom" (monthly anarchist journal), the International Anarchist Group that met in
        New York City, and her friendship and work with Emma Goldman, who became her mentor and
        inspirational leader. Pesotta became engaged in many political causes, anarchist work, and
        civic organizations, and her philosophy and ideology regarding anarchism and her beliefs are
        outlined. The remainder of the biography discusses Pesotta's family, friends and various
        relationships, as well as the trajectory of her later career, her travels, and success as an
        author. </p>
      <p> </p>
      <p>Additional material on Rose Pesotta including primary documents and personal collections
        includes the Rose Pesotta Papers at the New York Public Library, the John Nicholas Beffel
        Collection at the Walter P. Reuther Library, which contains Pesotta's reports, chapters and
        manuscript drafts in which she collaborated with Beffel, and the Rose Pesotta Papers,
        1919-1961 (5928) at the Kheel Center, Cornell University.</p>
    </scopecontent>
    <controlaccess>
      <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Names: </head>
        <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Pesotta, Rose, -- 1896- </persname>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Subjects: </head>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Labor unions -- United States -- Officials and employees
          -- Biography. </subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Women anarchists -- United States -- Biography. </subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Labor movement -- United States -- History -- 20th
          century. </subject>
        <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- History.
        </subject>
      </controlaccess>
      <controlaccess>
        <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
        <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655"> Dissertations</genreform>
      </controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
    <descgrp>
      <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
      <accessrestrict>
        <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
        <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference
          archivist for access to these materials.</p>
      </accessrestrict>
      <userestrict>
        <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
        <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and
          Procedures for Document Use.</p>
      </userestrict>
      <prefercite>
        <head>Cite As:</head>
        <p>The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist and Labor Organizer by Elaine Leeder.
          #6036/027. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
          University Library.</p>
      </prefercite>
    </descgrp>
    <relatedmaterial>
      <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
      <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
        <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU
          records</extref><lb/>
        <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05928.html"> 5928: Pesotta, Rose.
          Papers. Elaine Leeder, Collector.</extref><lb/>
      </p>
    </relatedmaterial>
    <dsc type="in-depth">
      <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <unittitle id="link6">Box also contains 6036/024.</unittitle>
        </did>
      </c01>
      <c01 level="file">
        <did>
          <container type="box">1</container>
          <container type="folder">1</container>
          <unittitle id="link7">"The Gentle Warrior: Rose Pesotta, Anarchist, and Labor
            Organizer"</unittitle>
          <unitdate normal="1985">1985</unitdate>
        </did>
      </c01>
    </dsc>
  </archdesc>
</ead>
