<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-014mf::ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05780-014mf</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers on
                        Microfilm<date> </date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers on
                    Microfilm</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>June 13, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>June 13,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers on
                Microfilm<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780/014 mf</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, June 13, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Randall Miles, June 13, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">ILGWU Local 22, Charles S.
                Zimmerman Papers on Microfilm, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1933-1954</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/014 mf</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Zimmerman, Charles S.</persname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> ILGWU Local 22</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">8 microfilm reels</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Reports, microfilms.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Primarily correspondence, reports, minutes, newspaper
                clippings, and broadsides dealing with his activities as a leader in Local 22 (in
                Series I), as well as his other union and political activities (in Series II). Among
                the most significant material in the collection is correspondence documenting
                Zimmerman's activities with the Communist Party in the U.S. and its various factions
                and splinter groups, as well as other political organizations and
                figures.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.89 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <p>Charles Sasha Zimmerman was born in Russia in 1897. He arrived in the United States
                in 1913 and soon found work in garment shops. His career with the ILGWU began in
                1916 when he went to work in a waist shop and joined Local 25. By 1925, Zimmerman
                was a member of the Executive Board for Dressmakers' Local 22. Throughout the 1920s,
                Zimmerman was an active member of the Communist Party, an affiliation that cost him
                his leadership positions within the union in 1925. He was involved with the bitter
                Communist infighting, and though he initially belonged to the Communist Party, he
                soon saw that they subverted the strike of 1926 for its own purposes which nearly
                decimated the ILGWU. With other members now opposed to Communism, Zimmerman worked
                to rid the Communist influence from the union and help reorganize the dress industry
                with his reinstatement in 1931. Even after his reinstatement in the ILGWU, he
                maintained close ties with the anti-Stalinist Lovestonites of the Communist Party. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Zimmerman was elected manager of Local 22 in 1933, and the next year became a vice
                president of the ILGWU. He became general manager of the New York Dress Joint Board
                and the Dressmakers' Joint Council in 1958. Zimmerman was involved with civil
                rights, social welfare and international labor organizations throughout his career.
                He was a trustee of the National Urban League, chairman of the Jewish Labor
                Committee's National Trade Union Council for Human Rights, and a member of New York
                City's first Human Rights Commission. Zimmerman helped found the Inter-American
                Federation of Textile and Garment Workers in 1966 and served as a U.S.
                representative to the International Textile, Garment and Leather Workers Federation.
                In 1969, Zimmerman was elected president of the Jewish Labor Committee and named to
                the Civil Rights and Social Security committees of the AFL-CIO. He resigned as a
                union vice president and general manager of the Dress Joint Council and New York
                Dress Joint Board in 1972. Zimmerman died in 1983.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <p> Local 22 of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), also known as
                the Dressmakers' Union, was chartered in December 1920 and based in New York, New
                York.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <p>The Charles Zimmerman papers consist primarily of correspondence, reports, minutes,
                newspaper clippings, and broadsides dealing with his activities as a leader in Local
                22 (in Series I), as well as his other union and political activities (in Series
                II). b Among the most significant material in the collection is correspondence
                documenting Zimmerman's activities with the Communist Party in the U.S. and its
                various factions and splinter groups, as well as other political organizations and
                figures. Correspondents include Jay Lovestone and William Z. Foster; there is also
                considerable material dealing with the Communist Party of the U.S.A. and the
                "Majority Group," or Lovestone faction. Other political parties represented include
                the American Labor Party, the Liberal Party (New York State), and the Socialist
                Party. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The remainder of the materials covers union affairs, both within and outside of the
                ILGWU, from the 1920s to the 1950s, as well as labor issues in general. There is a
                good deal of information on civil rights and African-American employees from the
                1930s to the 1950s. Other subjects include anti-fascism and anti-Nazism; strikes and
                other labor disputes in the U.S. and Canada; union elections; and worker education. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Significant organizations represented in the Zimmerman collection include the AFL and
                CIO (before and after the merger); the Fur and Leather Workers' Union; the Jewish
                Labor Committee; joint boards and locals of the ILGWU, especially Local 22 in New
                York; the League for Industrial Democracy; the NAACP; the National Urban League; the
                Workmen's Circle; and the Works Progress Administration. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Notable individuals represented include: Luigi Antonini; Irving Brown; David
                Dubinsky, Julius Hochman; Fiorello LaGuardia; Tom Mooney; Rose Pesotta; Adam Clayton
                Powell; Jackie Robinson; Norman Thomas; and Roy Wilkins.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Brown, Irving, 1911- </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Foster, William Z., 1881-1961. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hochman, Julius, 1892-1970. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">La Guardia, Fiorello H.(Fiorello Henry),
                    1882-1947. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Lovestone, Jay. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Mooney, Thomas J., 1882-1942. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Pesotta, Rose, 1896- </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Powell, Adam Clayton, 1908-1972. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Robinson, Jackie, 1919-1972. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Wilkins, Roy, 1901-1981. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Zimmerman, Charles S., 1896-1983. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">AFL-CIO. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">American Federation of Labor. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">American Jewish Congress. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Communist Party of the U.S.A. (Majority Group) </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Communist Party of the United States of America. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Congress of Industrial Organizations (U.S.) </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">International Fur and Leather Workers Union of
                    the United States and Canada. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    --Management. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    Local 22 (New York, N.Y.) </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    Local 22 (New York, N.Y.)--Management. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Jewish Labor Committee (U.S.) </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">League for Industrial Democracy. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Liberal Party of New York State. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">National Association for the Advancement of
                    Colored People. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">National Urban League. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Socialist Party (U.S.) </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">United States. Works Progress Administration. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Workmen's Circle/Arbeter Ring. </persname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">African Americans--Employment. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Anti-fascist movements. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Anti-Nazi movement. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil rights--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers--Labor unions--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Communists--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Communism--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor disputes--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor disputes--Canada. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions and communism--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions--Officials and employees. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor union locals. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Strikes and lockouts--United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Strikes and lockouts--Canada. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Working class--Education--United States.
                </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">New York (State)--Politics and government--20th
                    century. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">United States--Politics and government--20th
                    century. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <p>ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers on Microfilm #5780/014 mf. Kheel
                    Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
                    Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-014.html">
                    5780/014: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-014p.html">
                    5780/014 P: ILGWU Local 22, Charles S. Zimmerman Photographs</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Local 22 files - General Union Activities: 1933-1945;
                        Youth Releases; Politics; Printed Matters; Resolutions; Art; Leaflets;
                        Printed Material; Sports; General</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Local 22 files - General Union Act;
                        General-Herberg</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Local 22 files - Keep America out of the war committee,
                        1938, 1939, 1941; American league against war and Fascism, 1934, 1935, 1936;
                        American league for peace and democracy, 1936-1939; Spain, 1936-1939 --
                        North American committee, 1937; Trade Union relief for Spain, 1937; Spanish
                        relief pledges; Red Cross Trade Union Committee; Medical Bureau; Gen files;
                        Trade Union relief for Spain; Medical Bureau for Spain,
                        1939-1940…</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Local 22 files - Spain, 1938; War Relief Fund, 1943;
                        Greater N.Y. Fund, 1943-1945; National War Fund, 1943; American War
                        Community Services; N.Y. Labor Chest; League for Human Rights; N.Y. Labor
                        Chest (Add); United China Relief</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Local 22 files - United China Relief; Russian War Relief;
                        Allied War Relief; American Red Cross; British War Relief; British-Russian
                        War Fund; Russian War Relief; N.Y. Labor Chest; War Agencies, 1942-1943;
                        Treasury Dept.; Blood Donors Campaign; Hitler-Stalin Pact; War Loans; War
                        Bods, 1943-1944 and some not dated; American Labor Party, 1936.</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link13">Local 22 files - American Labor Party, 1937-1944; Liberal
                        Party, 1944-1947</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">Local 22 files - A.D.A. 1950 to 1956; Jewish Labor
                        Committee (General), 1939 to 1954</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="reel">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link15">Local 22 files - Jewish Labor Committee (Correspondence),
                        1939 to 1954; Labor Reports (American), 1946 to 1954; Labor Reports
                        (Canada), 1947, 1948; Committees: Improved Human Relations, Combat
                        intolerance, Combat Anti-Semitism, Minority Discrimination</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>