<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../styles/style.xsl"?>
<!DOCTYPE ead PUBLIC "+//ISBN 1-931666-00-8//DTD ead.dtd (Encoded Archival Description (EAD) Version 2002)//EN" "../dtds/ead.dtd">
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
            publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05619oh::ACWA Oral History Project Records.)//EN"
            >KCL05619oh.xml</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ACWA Oral History Project Records<date>
                    1990</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ACWA Oral History Project Records</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 21, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 21,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ACWA Oral History Project Records<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5619 OH</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
                            >kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center"
                            >http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, February 01, 2012</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 21, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>&#169; 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">ACWA Oral History Project Records,
                    <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1990</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5619 OH</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Amalgamated Clothing Workers of
                    America (ACWA)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1.6 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Oral histories (document genres).</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Interviews by Gail Malgreen with ACWA leaders. Releases
                signed and included from each interviewee. Interviews with Henry Dropkin, Murray H.
                Finley, Scott Hoyman, and Peter Swoboda.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">ACWA/ACTWU ORGANIZATIONAL
                HISTORY</head>
            <p>The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing
                workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a
                breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in
                the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which
                advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft
                organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had
                come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart,
                Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's
                advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an
                arbitration system to settle disputes. </p>
            <p>Members flocked to the new union. Around 50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the
                ACWA counted about 170,000 members. Initially composed mostly of immigrants of
                Jewish European descent with Socialist leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members
                of a great number of nationalities and diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment
                unions, most workers and many members were women, but the leadership was
                predominantly male, a situation that did not change for many decades. Early on the
                union adopted a centralized administrative structure combined with industrial
                unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having precedence over those of locals. </p>
            <p>Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its early immigrant socialist members,
                the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter issues and adopted a distinctive form
                of social unionism that was largely absent in the American labor movement. Starting
                in the 1920s, it provided educational opportunities and recreational facilities for
                its members, as well as services such as an insurance plan, banks offering personal
                loans at low interest rates, low-cost housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and
                even union-owned restaurants. </p>
            <p>Sidney Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important
                officer in its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in
                Chicago to the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant
                strides in securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the
                same time it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the
                widespread adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx.
                Hillman paid close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and
                marketing. In order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the
                union conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to
                the official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued
                within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management. </p>
            <p>Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs and
                political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for
                Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although
                many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially
                endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were
                firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became
                prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D.
                Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National
                Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's
                Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of
                Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the
                war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union,
                which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable. </p>
            <p>During the post World War II period the union faced a number of significant
                challenges. Membership continued to grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the
                union's political influence and visibility in national affairs declined. In their
                never ending pursuit of lower production costs, many firms relocated to the South,
                forcing the union to engage in large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began
                to appear of changes that would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic
                apparel industry and, ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign
                imports of cheap clothing goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed
                in the following two decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a
                steady decline. Union efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and
                extensive lobbying in Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged
                with the Textile Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile
                Workers Union. Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the
                Farah boycott and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the
                union's existence continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed
                in the late 1970s and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap
                labor abroad. By 1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies'
                Garment Workers' Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of
                Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new
                life in a troubled union.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
            <p>The Amalgamated Clothing Workers of America, the most significant union representing
                workers in the men's clothing industry, was founded in New York City in 1914 as a
                breakaway movement from the United Garment Workers. Radical and immigrant workers in
                the tailors' and cutters' locals were the core of the seceding group, which
                advocated industrial unionism and economic strikes in opposition to the UGW's craft
                organization, which they saw as conservative and timid. Their diverging views had
                come to the fore during the historic 1910 dispute at the Chicago firm Hart,
                Schaffner, and Marx. The opposition called the strike against the UGW leadership's
                advice, and reached a path-breaking agreement with management that established an
                arbitration system to settle disputes. Members flocked to the new union. Around
                50,000 strong at its founding, by 1920 the ACWA counted about 170,000 members.
                Initially composed mostly of immigrants of Jewish European descent with Socialist
                leanings, the ACWA quickly welcomed members of a great number of nationalities and
                diverse backgrounds. Like in other garment unions, most workers and many members
                were women, but the leadership was predominantly male, a situation that did not
                change for many decades. Early on the union adopted a centralized administrative
                structure combined with industrial unionism, with the joint boards' by-laws having
                precedence over those of locals. Espousing a philosophy perhaps brought over by its
                early immigrant socialist members, the Amalgamated went beyond bread and butter
                issues and adopted a distinctive form of social unionism that was largely absent in
                the American labor movement. Starting in the 1920s, it provided educational
                opportunities and recreational facilities for its members, as well as services such
                as an insurance plan, banks offering personal loans at low interest rates, low-cost
                housing cooperatives, medical clinics, and even union-owned restaurants. Sidney
                Hillman was the first president of the new union and the most important officer in
                its history. He applied his experience as bargaining representative in Chicago to
                the whole industry. Under his leadership the union made significant strides in
                securing better wages and working conditions for its members, and at the same time
                it consolidated gains and provided stability to the industry through the widespread
                adoption of the arbitration system tested at Hart, Schaffner, and Marx. Hillman paid
                close attention to industry issues, such as production, pricing, and marketing. In
                order to help management meet the competition of non-union firms, the union
                conducted studies of efficiency, work methods, and factory costs. Letters to the
                official publication of the union, Advance, document the controversy that ensued
                within the union over what was perceived to be collaboration with management.
                Hillman also understood the importance of labor's involvement in national affairs
                and political action. In the 1920s the ACWA sent delegates to the Conference for
                Progressive Political Action and to the Farmer-labor party conventions. Although
                many members and officers were Socialists, the union stopped short of officially
                endorsing the party. Communist attempts at gaining influence within the union were
                firmly curbed. Hillman's participation in national affairs and politics became
                prominent during the New Deal, when he became a close advisor to Franklin D.
                Roosevelt on labor and economic issues. He also served on the board of the National
                Recovery Administration. Later, during World War II, he helped establish the Labor's
                Non Partisan League. He was also named associate director of the Office of
                Production Management, which assisted in mobilizing the nation's resources for the
                war effort. Hillman's prestige perhaps reflected the healthy condition of his union,
                which by the end of the conflict was strong and stable. During the post World War II
                period the union faced a number of significant challenges. Membership continued to
                grow (peaking at 395,000 in 1968), but the union's political influence and
                visibility in national affairs declined. In their never ending pursuit of lower
                production costs, many firms relocated to the South, forcing the union to engage in
                large organizing efforts. Simultaneously, signs began to appear of changes that
                would lead to the almost complete demise of the domestic apparel industry and,
                ultimately, to the erosion of union membership. Foreign imports of cheap clothing
                goods steadily grew in the 1950s and 1960s, and mushroomed in the following two
                decades, plunging employment in the apparel sector into a steady decline. Union
                efforts to stem the tide included Buy American campaigns and extensive lobbying in
                Congress, but they were to no avail. In 1976, the ACWA merged with the Textile
                Workers of America to become the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union.
                Despite successful and much publicized nationwide actions such as the Farah boycott
                and the J.P. Stevens corporate campaign, the woes threatening the union's existence
                continued unabated. The fate of the domestic industry was sealed in the late 1970s
                and the 1980s by the flight of firms chasing tax breaks and cheap labor abroad. By
                1995, when ACTWU voted to merge with the International Ladies' Garment Workers'
                Union, their combined membership was 350,000. The new Union of Needletrades,
                Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE!) seemed poised to infuse new life in a
                troubled union.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
            <p>Interviews by Gail Malgreen with ACWA leaders. Releases signed and included from each
                interviewee. Interviews with Henry Dropkin, Murray H. Finley, Scott Hoyman, and
                Peter Swoboda.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union. </corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Dropkin, Henry. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Finley, Murray H. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hoyman, Scott. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Malgreen, Gail. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Swoboda, Peter. </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union.
                </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Oral histories (document genres)</genreform>
            </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>ACWA Oral History Project Records #5619 OH. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619.html"> 5619: ACWA
                    Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619av.html"> 5619 AV:
                    ACTWU Audio-Visual Materials</extref><lb/>

                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619c-smb.html"> 5619
                    C-S MB: ACTWU President Jack Sheinkman Additional Books, Memorabilia, and
                    Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619f.html"> 5619 F:
                    ACTWU Motion Picture Films</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619g.html"> 5619 G:
                    ACTWU Graphics</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619mb.html"> 5619 MB:
                    ACTWU Memorabilia Collection</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619mf.html"> 5619 mf:
                    ACWA Records Parts 1-3 on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619p.html"> 5619 P:
                    ACTWU Photographs</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619pubs.html"> 5619
                    PUBS: ACTWU Publications</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-001.html">
                    5619/001: ACTWU Collective Bargaining Agreements</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-002.html">
                    5619/002: ACWA Education Department Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-003.html">
                    5619/003: ACWA Sidney Hillman Scrapbooks</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-004.html">
                    5619/004: ACTWU President Jacob Sheinkman Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-004fiche.html">
                    5619/004 fiche: ACTWU President Jacob Sheinkman Speeches on Microfiche</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-005.html">
                    5619/005: ACWA Bessie Hillman Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-006.html">
                    5619/006: ACTWU Executive Vice-President's Office Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-007.html">
                    5619/007: ACTWU Organizing Department Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-008.html">
                    5619/008: ACWA Rieve-Pollock Foundation Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-009.html">
                    5619/009: ACTWU Operations Department Sidney Hillman Awards Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-010.html">
                    5619/010: ACWA Jacob Potofsky files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-011.html">
                    5619/011: ACTWU Southern Regional Joint Board Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-012.html">
                    5619/012: ACTWU Company Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-013.html">
                    5619/013: ACTWU Research Department Correspondence Chronological Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-014.html">
                    5619/014: ACWA Local 169 Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-015.html">
                    5619/015: ACTWU Department of Occupational Safety and Health Files</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Dropkin, H. (ACTWU)</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>transcript</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Finley, M.</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>transcript</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Hoyman, S.</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>transcript</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Swoboda, P.</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>transcript</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Murray Finley Interview - 5/12/1990 : Session
                        1</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">2</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link13">Murray Finley Interview - 5/12/1990 : Session
                            1</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">Murray Finley Interview - 5/12/1990 : Session
                        1</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">3</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link15">Murray Finley Interview - 5/12/1990 : Session 1 -
                            tape 2</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link16"> Murray Finley Interview - 5/21/1990 : Session
                        2</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">4</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link17">Murray Finley Interview - 5/21/1990 : Session
                            2</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link18"> Murray Finley Interview - 5/21/1990 : Session
                        2</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">5</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link19">Murray Finley Interview - 5/21/1990 : Session 2 -
                            tape 2</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link20">Peter Swoboda Interview - 8/16/1990 : Session
                        1</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">6</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link21">Peter Swoboda Interview - 8/16/1990 : Session
                            1</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link22">Peter Swoboda Interview - 8/22/1990 : Session
                        2</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">7</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link23">Peter Swoboda Interview - 8/22/1990 : Session
                            2</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link24">Peter Swoboda Interview - 8/22/1990 : Session
                        2</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">8</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link25">Peter Swoboda Interview - 8/22/1990 : Session 2 -
                            tape 2</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">9</container>
                    <unittitle id="link26">Scott Hoyman Interview - 1/27-1/28/1990</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">9</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link27">Scott Hoyman Interview - 1/27-1/28/1990</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">10</container>
                    <unittitle id="link28">Scott Hoyman Interview - 1/27-1/28/1990</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">10</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link29">Scott Hoyman Interview - 1/27-1/28/1990 - tape
                            2</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link30">Scott Hoyman Interview - 1/27-1/28/1990</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">11</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link31">Scott Hoyman Interview - 1/27-1/28/1990 - tape
                            3</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
