<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
 <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
  <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-046p::ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs.)//EN">KCL05780-046p</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs<date> 1940-1978</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
    <date>January 14, 2014</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kathryn Dowgiewicz, <date>January 14, 2014</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 </eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs<lb/></titleproper>
   <num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc1308">Collection Number: 5780/046 P</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, July 06, 2010</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 14, 2014</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2014 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1940-1978</unitdate>
   </unittitle>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/046 P</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Los Angeles Joint Board</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union</corpname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">2 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Photographs.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">Consists of photographs transferred from the records of the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board. Photographs include ILGWU members, officers, and events.</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  <physdesc><extent>2 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <p>Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <p>The first local in Los Angeles was founded in March 1907, and due to its low membership, existed for only three months. Approximately three years later (1910-1911), Local 52 was chartered and by 1920 had changed its name to the Cloak, Suit, Skirt, and Reefer Makers' Union of Los Angeles to reflect the broad range of manufacturing within the ladies' garment industry. During the union's struggle with Communism among the membership in the 1920s, the ILGWU General Executive Board (GEB) revoked Local 52's charter in November 1928, alleging Communist corruption and planned secession. The Los Angeles union had to be reorganized, and a new Local 65 was formed with former members who had remained loyal to the ILGWU and the GEB. In 1933, Rose Pesotta was sent to Los Angeles to begin a large scale organization drive. During 1933, both Cutters' Local 84 and Dressmakers' Local 96 were formed. While the strike in October 1933 was ineffective and gains were limited, the strike did prove the
    successful organizing of Latina dressmakers. At the beginning of 1934, the Los Angeles Joint Board was formed with representatives of Locals 65, 84 and 96. Early board members included H. Rubinstein (manager), L. Pine (chairman), Axelrod (vice chairman), and Paul Berg (secretary). Later that year, Pressers' Local 97 was chartered. As union membership increased, the garment workers began making substantial gains during contract negotiations. Advances were made in wages, hours and holidays. The cloak industry became a closed shop and the sector almost 100% unionized. A new local, 236, was chartered in 1936. During this time, the dressmakers underwent another strike, and Isidore Lutsky was the manager of the Joint Board. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p> In 1940, the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board separated from the Dress Joint Board. George Wishnak served as the manager of the Dress Joint Board, and Louis Pine managed the Cloak Joint Board from 1941 until his death in 1946. New production in the sportswear industries necessitated the chartering of Local 266 (sportswear and cotton dress workers). By 1947, Los Angeles became the first in the manufacture of sportswear and second to New York in cloak production. Joseph Springer led the Cloak Joint Board from 1946-1950. The Cloak Joint Board was primarily composed of Operators and Finishers Local 65, Cutters Local 65, and Pressers Local 97. The Dress Joint Board was composed of the large Dressmakers' Local 96 and the cutters and pressers in the dress trade of 84 and 97. These Joint Boards represented much of the skilled workers in the garment industry in Los Angeles, and sights were set on organizing the tens of thousands of unskilled workers. Again, the activities of Communist
    members within the union began to bring conflict on the west coast, and in 1949, a Special Committee of the ILGWU placed the Cloak Joint Board under the direction of Morris Bagno, and the Dress Joint Board under the supervision of Margaret Di Maggio, to use special powers to remove the remaining Communist influence. In October 1950, Isidore Stenzor took over management of the Cloak Joint Board, a position he would hold until 1970. The ILGWU Health Center for Los Angeles was established in 1951, offering a wide range of service. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p> The Cloak Joint Board moved to new headquarters in 1955, but the 1950s also saw a shift in production towards sportswear, as membership for Local 266 continued to increase and soon surpass the Operators Local 55 in numbers. In 1955, the ILGWU GEB recommended the merger of the two non-cloak industries, and in September 1955, the Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board was created with manager John Ulene. Ulene retired in January 1968 after 50 years of service with the ILGWU. He had been elected head of the Sportswear Joint Council then managed the combined Dress and Sportswear Joint Board from 1955-1968. Sam Schwartz, the director of organizing for the Joint Board, succeeded Ulene as manager for the Dress and Sportswear Joint Board. With decline in membership and a contraction of the union over the next decades, by December 1970, the Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board and the Cloak Joint Board merged to form the new Los Angeles Joint Board. Stenzor, who had been
    manger of the Cloak Board since 1950 resigned, and Cornelius Wall, the Western States Region Director, became the manager for the new Joint Board.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
   <p>The collection contains the photographic record of the Joint Board of Los Angeles. The images help illustrate the activities of the Joint Board and the locals and include photographs of parades, meetings, and banquets. In terms of membership, there are images of delegates at conventions, officers and managers of the Joint Board, new officers being installed at dinners, board of director luncheons, and group shots of members and factory shots of workers. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>There is a large amount of photographs centered around health care, including the City of Hope and Cesar Chavez and the Mobile Health Unit. Of particular interest are the images from the Union Health Center opening in 1951, with photos showing the new facilities, the services offered, and doctors, nurses and patients. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Political images include contract signings, the 1964 and 1972 election campaigns, and rallies against imports in the 1970s. Both David Dubinsky's, and later Louis Stulberg's, visit to Los Angeles are documented. Also, there is much on the union label, including a 1954 union label fashion show, union label clothing from 1960, and Mrs. Brown, wife of then California Governor Pat Brown, sewing in the first union label in California in March 1959.</p>
  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Antonini, Luigi, 1883-1968. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Balducci, Sally. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Bradley, Thomas. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Brown, Jerry. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Chaiken, Sol. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Chavez, Cesar, 1927-1993. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Dubinsky, David, 1892-1982. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Feinberg, Basil. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Gluckner, Herta. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Humphrey, Hubert H., 1911-1978. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Johnson, Lyndon B., 1908-1973. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Knight, Goodwin, 1896-1970. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Langer, Hyman. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Otto, Sam. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Rosales, Marie. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Shapiro, Leon. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Stenzor, Isidor. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Stulberg, Louis, 1901-1977. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Ulene, John. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Wanamaker, Maurice. </persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Union Health Center. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. -- Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board (Los Angeles, (Calif.)). </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Women's clothing industry -- United States. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Women's clothing industry -- California -- Los Angeles. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- United States. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- California -- Los Angeles. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers -- United States. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers -- California -- Los Angeles. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Industrial relations -- California -- Los Angeles. </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   <accessrestrict>
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    <p>ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board photographs #5780/046 P. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU records</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-046.html"> 5780/046: ILGWU. Los Angeles Joint Board records</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-115.html"> 5780/115: ILGWU. Western States Region records</extref><lb/>
   </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1950">1940-1950</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Cloak Joint Board; Labor Day Parade, 1947; ILGWU parade float; LA strikes 1949; Furriers Day 1940.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link7">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1950">1940-1950</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>ILGWU Golden Jubilee Convention, Atlantic City, NJ, 1950; Los Angeles 1950.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link8">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1940/1950">1940-1950</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Los Angeles 1950- pairs of men passing along documents; City of Hope- Duarte, California, 1950.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link9">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Signing Cloak Contract- Isidor Stenzor, Hyman Langer, Basil Feinberg; Opening of the Union Health Center; Outing of the ILGWU members to the City of Hope; Luncheon attended by Board of Directors of Manufacturers Association and David Dubinsky; NLRB Election, voter lines; David Dubinsky with three patients (Marie Rosales, Herta Gluckner, and Sally Balducci) the City of Hope, standing in front of the ILGWU Hillquit Memorial Hospital at opening; David Dubinsky visits research lab at City of Hope.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link10">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>David Dubinsky visit with patient Joseph Michaels at the City of Hope; David Dubinsky around the City of Hope, multiple images; Luigi Antonini in City of Hope; David Dubinsky at AFL Convention in San Francisco; NLRB Election; Isidor Stenzor at City of Hope, California; Signing contract with Style Trends, October 19, 1951; Allocation Dinner.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link11">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Health care patients in Duarte; Outdoor view, ILGWU Hillquit Memorial Hospital; Speakers at the Allocation Dinner.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link12">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Speakers at Allocation Dinner; ILGWU delegates to AFL State Convention at San Diego; Visit of David Dubinsky and ILGWU Officers to City of Hope; ILG delegates to AFL Convention in San Francisco.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link13">Union Health Center Los Angeles, Opening.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Reception; Filing; Waiting room; Examination rooms; Pharmacy; Internal medicine; Electrocardiograph; Laboratory; Weighing; Ear, nose, and throat; Eye; Physiotherapy; Radiology.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link14">Union Health Center Los Angeles, Opening.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Patients receiving services, waiting in line at Union Health Center; CYO children's group at Union Health Center.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link15">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Officers of the Dress Joint Board at the ILGWU 28th Convention; David Dubinsky visits patients at City of Hope; Vice President Otto, Sam and Manager Isidor Stenzor with member of the Association of Contractors; Pacific Region Recovery Board Conference held in Ambassador Hotel in Los Angeles; Cloak Joint Board delegates at California State Convention at the AFL, Santa Barbara.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link16">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outing of the ILGWU Shop Chairmen, City of Hope; State Convention at the AFL, Santa Barbara; Visiting shops in Los Angeles; Lawn Fair.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link17">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outing of the ILGWU Shop Chairmen, City of Hope; ILGWU Library; Installation of Cloak Joint Board at City of Hope Chapter; Local 85 Executive Board sponsoring refugee children; Mobile X-ray unit in front of Health Center.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link18">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>General membership meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board, Locals- Embassy Hall; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Installation,; Manager Isidor Stenzor, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Signing of the new contract between Los Angeles Joint Cloak Board and Coat and Suit Manufacturers Association; Convention, CJB delegation.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link19">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Elections; General membership meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; General membership meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board, Locals- Embassy Hall.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link20">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Cloak Joint Board at Catholic Labor Institute Dinner, Los Angeles; National Conference of Christians and Jews; Pacific Coast Region Delegation, 28th Convention; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Installation; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Elections.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link21">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Los Angeles Sportswear Joint Council Installation Dance; Vice President Sam Otto and John Ulene at Dance; Ratification of Contract of Cloak Joint Board; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Elections.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link22">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Los Angeles Sportswear Council at a convention; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Installation; Dress Joint Board; Los Angeles Sportswear Joint Council Installation Dance; Executive Board of the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Combine Executive Board, Joint Board and Dress Sportswear District Council; Election of Executive Committee; Officers of the Dress Sportswear Council.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link23">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Union Label Show, National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Board; Governor Goodwin J. Knight and ILG Models at the Union Label Show; Argentine delegation visiting Oscar Strauss Plant; Jogs, Inc., Special refund to workers; Retiree celebration, Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board; Welcome for delegates, Sacramento Typographical Union No. 46 and Women's Auxiliary No. 120.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link24">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Isidor Stenzor and others making a $1,000 contribution to NAACP; Visits to City of Hope; Los Angeles Labor "Ovt" conference; City of Hope Lawn Fair; Delegates of Cloak Joint Board to California State AFL Convention held in Santa Barbara. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff 19</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link25">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Los Angeles Labor Ovt, September 1954; Christmas dinner of Jogs shop; Signing of special agreement, Leon Shapiro and Isidor Stenzor; Local 483 Installation; Contract signed with Dumas; Secretary of Labor Mitchell and President David Dubinsky visiting the Deanna Dee shop; Speakers addressing the Cloak Joint Board mass meeting, celebrating the opening of the Los Angeles Coat and Suit Industry Retirement Fund. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff 20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link26">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Cloak Joint Board mass-meeting to celebrate the opening of the Los Angeles Coat and Suit Industry Retirement Fund, held in the Embassy Auditorium; First Cloak retirees; Cloak Joint Board opening of new building; Luigi Antonini and David Dubinsky and other speakers addressing mass-meeting. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff21</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link27">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Celebration of the opening of the new Cloak Joint Board building; Ribbon-cutting, speakers, outside view of building (illustration). Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff22</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link28">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Celebration Party at Los Angeles Cloak firm; Local 84 Dinner; Celebration of the opening of the new Cloak Joint Board building; California State AFL Convention held in San Diego; Allocations; Recovery Board Conference. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1. ff23</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link29">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Assorted shop and dinner scenes; Outside view of Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board Building. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff24</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link30">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Local 55 election; Officers of Local 512; Executive Board and business agent of Local 97; Election Committee of Locals 58 and 84; Installation of Locals 58, 84, 97, and 512; California State American Federation of Labor Convention in Long Beach; ILGWU Convention in Atlantic City. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1. ff25</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link31">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Cutters' Local 84, Executive Board; Voting, Cloak Joint Board. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff26</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link32">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Local 55 election, tabulating votes. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff27</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link33">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Official signing of the 1957-1960 Cloak agreement; 70th Birthday and retirement banquet, Louis Babitz; Local 84 Banquet; Local 58 Executive Board; Retirement Fund celebration meeting; City of Hope, ILGWU Library; Town Fair. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff 28</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link34">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Retirement Fund celebration meeting; Signing of contract; Town Fair outing; Los Angeles Recovery Board Dinner; signing of 1057-1960 Cloak Agreement; Sid Colene Retirement celebration. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff29</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link35">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Retirement Fund celebration meeting; Union delegation of Argentine at Local 58 meeting; California State American Federation of Labor Convention in Oakland; Local 58 Executive Board; Sid Colene retirement celebration; Signing of contract with California State Employment Department; James Roosevelt, Congressman, at ILG political rally. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1 ff30</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link36">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Women's Campaign rally against "Right-to-Work" amendment; General meeting of the retirees of the coat and suit industry. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff31</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link37">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Political Mass Rally; Entertainment at Installation of Officers of Cloakmakers Golden Club; Vice President Samuel Otto, Manager Isidor Stenzor and Local 84 Retirees; Local 512 honoring 512 honoring Carter as Mother of the Year; Women's Campaign rally against "Right-to-Work" amendment. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff32</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link38">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Installation of Officers of Cloakmakers Golden Club; Political Mass Rally. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff33</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link39">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Installation of Local 55 Executive Board, Los Angeles Cloak Locals; Joint installation. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff34</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link40">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Jewish Labor Committee Conference; Installation; Installation of Local 58, 84, 97, 483, 497, 512 Executive Boards. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff35</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link41">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1959">1959</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>30th Convention, ILGWU, Miami Beach, Florida; Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board, ILGWU, Installation of Officers and Executive Board Members; Isidor Stenzor, Manager, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Union label Show; Argentine delegation at Oscar Straus shop; California Labor Federation Convention, San Diego, California; Jewish Labor Committee Conference. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 1, ff36</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link42">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Signing of first Los Angeles Cloak designers contract; Contribution to NAACP; Contribution to C.S.O. in Los Angeles; Los Angeles Cloak Golden Club; Japanese delegation; Organization of the Five Wardens. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff1</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link43">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Retirees helping in election campaign; Los Angeles Union Label Show; California Federation of Labor Convention, Sacramento, California; Indian labor delegation; Japanese labor delegation. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff2</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link44">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Union Label Distribution; "New Horizons" Label Show; mandolin Group; Signing of Los Angeles Cloak Contract; Mailing of political rally; Dumas signing. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff3</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link45">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961/1962">1961-1962</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>ILG Educational Director Aileen Hernandez, Fashion Show; Local 58 "Mother of the Year"; Town Fair Booth; Donation to NAACP; Jack Bloom shop. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff4</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link46">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961/1962">1961-1962</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>31st Convention, ILGWU, Atlantic City, NJ; Political rally. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff5</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link47">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961/1962">1961-1962</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Installation of Cloak Joint Board Officers and Executive Boards. Collection re- boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff6</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link48">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1961/1962">1961-1962</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>31st Convention, ILGWU, Atlantic City, NJ; Local 97 Executive Board; Golden Age Club; Installation of Locals. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff7</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link49">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963/1964">1963-1964</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Severance Paychecks, Baldwin Park shop, Fashion Show workers; Testimonial Dinner for Isidor Stenzor, presentation of trophy. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff8</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link50">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963/1964">1963-1964</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Testimonial Dinner for Isidor Stenzor. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff9</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link51">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963/1964">1963-1964</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tot Lines, Inc. Strike; Joint Board Negotiating Committee of Renewal of Contract-; General membership meeting; Local 97 30th Anniversary; President David Dubinsky visiting Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff10</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link52">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1963/1964">1963-1964</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>J.B. election rally; J.B. Installation; English and citizenship class, Chinatown; Baldwin Park shop, getting severance checks; award given by the California Home for the Aged at Reseda. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, f11</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link53">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965/1967">1965-1967</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>J.B. Installation; American Red Cross Award; Local 58 Executive Committee; President Dubinsky and General Secretary-Treasury Stulberg visiting Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, f12</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link54">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965/1967">1965-1967</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>National Board of Coat and Suit Industry Conference, Miami Beach; David Dubinsky speaking to crowd of delegates; Isidor Stenzor and Sam Otto, Miami Beach; Farewell, Bon Voyage for Mr. and Mrs. Isidor Stenzor. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff13</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link55">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965/1967">1965-1967</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Farewell, Bon Voyage send-off for Mr. and Mrs. Isidor Stenzor. Collection re- boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff14</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link56">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1965/1967">1965-1967</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Farewell, Bon Voyage send-off for Mr. and Mrs. Isidor Stenzor; Local 55 celebrating the retirement of Maurice Wanamaker; California State AFL-CIO Convention in San Diego; Joint Board and Asian Negotiation Committee for renewal of contract; Workers of Vanguard fashions of California, contributed to Israel Emergency Fund; Shop meeting, Chinatown, San Francisco; Negotiation Committees of the Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board; Flu shots with Dr. Igloe; Lou Tabok with Sam Otto; Cutters strike, Geno of California. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff15</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link57">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1970">1968-1970</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>John Ulene retirement party, Los Angeles; Joint installation of all elected joint board and local officers. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff16</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link58">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1970">1968-1970</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Joint installation of all elected joint board and local officers; Hubert Humphrey campaign rally; G.E.B. members visiting Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff17</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link59">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1970">1968-1970</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Joint Campaign meeting, Los Angeles Cloak Joint Board and Los Angeles Dress and Sportswear Joint Board; Thomas Bradley, candidate for Mayor, speaking; Testimonial dinner for Sam Otto on his retirement. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff18</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link60">California</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1968/1970">1968-1970</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>John Ulene retirement party, Los Angeles. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff19</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link61">AFL-CIO Convention</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1975">1975</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>ILGWU delegates, San Francisco Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link62">Jerry Brown for Governor Campaign</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff21</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link63">Chavez, Cesar: Presentation of the United Farm Workers Flag</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1974">1974</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff22</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link64">Chic Lingerie Strike</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff23</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link65">Cranston for Controller in Governor Edmund "Pat" Brown Campaign</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff24</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link66">Funny Borex Retirement Party</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff25</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link67">Hubert Humphrey</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1972">1972</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Mrs. Humphrey during Mr. Humphrey's campaign Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff26</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link68">ILGWU Mobile Health Unit presentation with Cesar Chavez</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff27</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link69">Imports Rally</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1972">1972</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff28</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link70">Lyndon B. Johnson for President Campaign</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff29</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link71">Judy Bond Strike</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1969">1969</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff30</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link72">Lou-Gene Strike</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff31</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link73">Otto- Vice President Sam Otto Retirement Party</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff32</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link74">President Sol Chaiken and wife at 75th Anniversary of the ILGWU in Los Angeles</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1975">1975</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff33</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link75">President Louis Stulberg and members of the G.E.B. Committee visiting Los Angeles</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1971">1971</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 1971 Collection re- boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff34</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link76">President Louis Stulberg visiting Los Angeles</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1976">1976</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff35</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link77">Roosevelt for Governor, Los Angeles, CA</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff36</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link78">Tabak, Inc. Strike, Lock-out</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1968 Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff37</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link79">Tunney for U.S. Senator Campaign</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff38</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link80">Union Label. First union label in California; Union label fashion show</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff39</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link81">Vice President Glenn Clay visiting Los Angeles during the Coat and Suit negotiations</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1972">1972</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff40</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link82">Western States Region Seminar</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1975">1975</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff41</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link83">Miscellaneous, duplicates</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1973">1973</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Vice President Wall and President Lois Stulberg; Local 482 Executive Board; Vice President Wall testimonial being congratulated by Major Bradley; California State federation, COPE Convention. Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff42</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link84">Miscellaneous.</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1978">1978</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Wedding of Southern California Davis Pleating member at Union headquarters, 1978; various conferences, dinner events, meetings- no descriptions Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff43</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link85">Miscellaneous</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>No descriptions Collection re-boxed, this was formerly box 2, ff44</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>