<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
            publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05046::U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records.)//EN"
            >KCL05046.xml</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records<date>
                        1956-1957</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 04, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p>
                        <subject>Labor</subject>
                    </p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 04,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5046</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
                            >kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center"
                            >http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, December 10, 2012</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 04, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>&#169; 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">U.S. Emergency Board No. 119
                Records, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1956-1957</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5046</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">U.S. Emergency Board</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents), proceedings, transcripts
                .</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Transcript of proceedings and exhibits of the Emergency
                Board No. 119, 1957. Wages and benefits case. General Managers' Association of New
                York vs. the International Organziation of Masters, mates and Pilots, Inc.,
                1937-1957. There are also copies of 35 exhibits which provide a picture of the wage
                structure of the railroad and marine industries and describe in detail the jobs
                performed by union members.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
            <p>Emergency Board No. 119 was created under an Executive Order of the President dated
                August 6, 1957. To the fact-finding board were appointed James J. Healy of Boston,
                an arbitrator and assistant professor of Industrial Relations at Harvard
                University's Graduate School of Business Administration; Walter R. Johnson of
                Arlington, Va; special counsel of the National Association of Attorneys General and
                former Attorney General of Nebraska, and Benjamin C. Roberts of Brooklyn, N.Y., a
                lawyer active in mediation and arbitration, Healy was appointed chairman. </p>
            <p>On November 21, 1956, the Masters, Mates and Pilots union presented the carriers with
                their demands, which Included a 35% increase in pay for captains and pilots, a 25
                cent per hour increase for mates, deckhands and other crew members (both demands to
                be retroactive August 1, 1956), double time and one-half for work performed on
                holidays, differential pay of $1.50 per day for bridge motormen and ferry wheelsmen,
                and health and welfare Insurance for employees and their families. </p>
            <p>The carriers countered by offering the MMP the 1956-1957 "pattern" established In
                negotiations with the non-operating railroads. This proved to be important in the
                Board's later decision because the MMP from 1937 through 1953, had bargained jointly
                with and had agreed to, the same settlements as the non-operating unions. More
                specifically, the carriers offered a pay increase of 10 cents an hour
                across-the-board, retroactive to November 1, 1956, with additional 7 cent hourly
                increases in November of 1957 and 1958, health and welfare benefits or equivalent
                wage increases of 2.5 cents per hour, and semi-annual cost of living adjustments of
                1 cent per hour for each one-half point change in the Consumers' Price Index, in
                return for a moratorium on contract changes for three years. </p>
            <p>Conferences between the General Managers' Association of New York Harbor Railroads
                and the Masters, Mates and Pilots Organization in December 1956, February 1957 and
                March 1957 produced no agreement. In March, the services of the National Mediation
                Board were invoked. Originally intending to strike on July 21 the union postponed
                its strike deadline at the suggestion of the Mediation Board representative to 12:01
                A.M. of August 7. </p>
            <p>On August 2 and August 7, with agreement still not in sight, the carriers obtained
                temporary restraining orders from the Federal Courts to prevent the MMP from
                striking. These were made unnecessary, however, when the President under Section 10,
                of the Railway Labor Act on the Mediation Board's report that the situation
                threatened substantially to interrupt interstate commerce to a degree such as to
                deprive a section of the country of essential transportation service, created the
                Emergency Board and halted the strike for sixty days. Nine public hearings and two
                inspection trips were held by the Emergency Board, the investigation beginning on
                August 14 and being completed on August 30. With the agreement of both parties, the
                Board was granted a two week extension in which to make its report. </p>
            <p>On September 20, the Board made public its recommendation that settlement be,
                basically, on the terms offered by the railroads. The Board recommended the 26.5
                cents "pattern" settlement of the non-operating railroad unions (10 cents per hour
                retroactive to November 1, 1956, 7 cents per hour effective November 1, 1958, and
                2.5 cents in health and welfare benefits or wages at the option of the MMP,) plus a
                cost-of-living adjustment of 1 cent an hour for each half point change in the CPI,
                double pay for designated holidays or 16 cents per day increase in basic wages
                (again at the choice of the union) and Increases to captains and pilots of $1.00 a
                day retroactive to December 21, 1956, and 50 cents a day effective November 1, 1957
                and November 1, 1958. </p>
            <p>The union, however, termed these proposals Inadequate and threatened to strike again
                at 1 A.M. of October 22, the day after the cooling-off period was to end. Masters,
                Mates and Pilots' president C.T. Atkins termed the parties still "far apart," and
                the rank-and-file backed him up by voting affirmatively in the strike vote held
                October 17. The threatened strike did take place, but lasted for only 90 minutes, as
                union and management with the aid of Federal Mediator, T.E. Schoonover, reached
                agreement at 2:30 A.M. on management's terms. </p>
            <p>Over the three-year period of the agreement, the settlement meant a daily increase of
                $4.36 in wages for captains and pilots (in addition to their then current $22.50,)
                and an increase of $2.36 per day for mates and deckhands (in addition to their
                respective $16.80 and $16.40,) plus the cost-of-living adjustments which were
                estimated at an additional 32 cents. </p>
            <p>The International Organization of Masters, Mates and Pilots was the bargaining Agent
                for 872 of the 3,231 railroad marine service employees then employed in New York
                Harbor. Although this amounted to only 27% overall, the MMP represented 90.1% of the
                captains and pilots, 59.1% of the mates and 61.8% of the deckhands. </p>
            <p>The eleven railroads represented by the General Managers' Association of New York
                were the New York Central, the New York, New Haven and Hartford, the Brooklyn
                Eastern District Terminal, the New York Dock Railway, the Bush Terminal Railroad,
                the Baltimore and Delaware, Lackawanna and Western and the Central Railroad Company
                of New Jersey. </p>
            <p>The eleven railroads conduct both ferry and towing operations as extensions of their
                railroad service. Combined, they handled in 1956 approximately 27 million tons of
                freight and had an annual gross of approximately $250,000,000, Dally business was
                estimated at $725,000 and daily-losses in perishable goods, in case of a strike, at
                $5285,000. </p>
            <p>The ferry service of the New York Central, Erie, Delaware, Lackawanna and Western and
                Jersey Central Railroads handles a total of 69,000 passengers and 4,500 motor
                vehicles a day, mainly between points in Manhattan and New Jersey.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
            <p>The collection consists of the transcript of the proceedings (9 vol.) along with the
                final report (38 pp.). There are also copies of 35 exhibits which provide a picture
                of the wage structure of the railroad and marine industries and describe in detail
                the jobs performed by union members.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">General Managers' Association of New York650 </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Organization of Masters, Mates,
                    and Pilots </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. Emergency Board No. 119. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects: </head>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Train ferries--New York (State)--New York. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Train ferries--Employees. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Merchant mariners x Labor unions z United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Arbitration, Industrial z United States x
                    Sources. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Arbitration, Industrial. Train ferries. New York
                    (N.Y.) </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Mediation and conciliation, Industrial. Train
                    ferries. New York (N.Y.) </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">New York (N.Y.). Harbor. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Strikes and lockouts. Train ferries. New York
                    (N.Y.) </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Wages. Mediation and conciliation, Industrial.
                    New York (N.Y.) </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Wages. Train ferries. New York (N.Y.)</subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Records (documents) </genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Proceedings. </genreform>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Transcripts. </genreform>
            </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>U.S. Emergency Board No. 119 Records #5046. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05006.html"> 5006: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 174 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05007.html"> 5007: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 175 Transcripts and Exhibits</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05012.html"> 5012: Saul
                    Wallen Papers</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05027.html"> 5027: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 178 Transcripts</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05030.html"> 5030: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 179 Exhibits and Related Material</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05036.html"> 5036: U.S.
                    Emergency Boards under the Railway Labor Act Reports</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05037.html"> 5037: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 81 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05038.html"> 5038: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 94 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05039.html"> 5039: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 98 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05040.html"> 5040: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 106 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05042.html"> 5042: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 111 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05043.html"> 5043: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 114 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05044.html"> 5044: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 116 Reports and Exhibits</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05045.html"> 5045: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 118 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05047.html"> 5047: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 120 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05048.html"> 5048: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 121 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05050.html"> 5050: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 124 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05051.html"> 5051: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 125 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05052.html"> 5052: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 129 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05053.html"> 5053: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 130 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05054.html"> 5054: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 133 Exhibits</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05055.html"> 5055: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 134 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05056.html"> 5056: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 135 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05057.html"> 5057: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 137 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05058.html"> 5058: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 138 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05059.html"> 5059: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 142 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05060.html"> 5060: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 145 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05061.html"> 5061: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 146 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05062.html"> 5062: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 154 Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05064.html"> 5064: U.S.
                    Emergency Board No. 169 Transcript of Proceedings and Exhibits</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05075.html"> 5075: U.S.
                    Emergency Board under the Taft Hartley Act Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05579.html"> 5579:
                    National Mediation Board Emergency Board 180, Train Crew Consists</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05934.html"> 5934:
                    Arthur Stark Papers on the President's Emergency Board #219</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Exhibits for the railroads, report, transcript</unittitle>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link9">The Parties and Issues Before the Board</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">2</container>
                        <unittitle id="link10">Standard Rates of Pay and Schedule Agreements,
                            Railroad Marine Employees - New York Harbor</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">3</container>
                        <unittitle id="link11">Classes and Number of All Railroad
                            Employees</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">4</container>
                        <unittitle id="link12">Exhibit 4 - no information listed</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">5</container>
                        <unittitle id="link13">Classes, Numbers and Representation of Railroad
                            Marine Employees</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">6</container>
                        <unittitle id="link14">New York Harbor Terminals Max</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">7</container>
                        <unittitle id="link15">Local, Joint, and Proportional Freight Tariff Naming
                            Lighterage and Terminal Regulations in New York Harbors
                            Vicinity.</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Including rates, rules, and charges for grain, live stock, and storage,
                            deliveries and handling of freight between terminals on domestic,
                            import, export, coastwise, and Intercoastal freight.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">8</container>
                        <unittitle id="link16">Tonnage and Equipment</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">9</container>
                        <unittitle id="link17">Wage and Earnings Data</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">10</container>
                        <unittitle id="link18">Casualty Data</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">11</container>
                        <unittitle id="link19">Pattern Settlements in the Railroad
                            Industry</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">12</container>
                        <unittitle id="link20">Participation of International Organizations of
                            Masters, Mates and Pilots with Other Railroad Non-operating Employees of
                            Collective Bargaining</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">13</container>
                        <unittitle id="link21">Pattern Settlements in the Railroad Industry -
                            National Agreements</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">14</container>
                        <unittitle id="link22">Number and Percent of Railroad Employees Covered by
                            1956-1957 Industry Pattern Agreements</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">15</container>
                        <unittitle id="link23">Railway Express Agency Settlements</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">16</container>
                        <unittitle id="link24">Letters from E.C. Thompson, Executive Secretary of
                            the National Mediation Board</unittitle>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>To: H.F. Wyatt of the Reading Circle; J.W. Orem of the Pennsylvania
                            Railroad; R.L. Harvey of the Baltimore and Ohio Company; and Captain
                            John M. Bishop of the International Organization of Masters, Mates, and
                            Pilots, Incorporated.</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">17</container>
                        <unittitle id="link25">United States Bureau of Labor Statistics Bulletin
                            Number 1188-17 New York, New York</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>April 1956</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">18</container>
                        <unittitle id="link26">Wage Diversity</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">19</container>
                        <unittitle id="link27">Illustrations of Uniform Wage Change for Unions
                            Within an Industry or Company</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">20</container>
                        <unittitle id="link28">Rate of Return on Net Investments as of December
                            31</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">21</container>
                        <unittitle id="link29">Annual Straight Time Potential Earnings and Average
                            Annual Earnings - New York Harbor Employees Represented by International
                            Organization of Masters, Mates, and Pilots</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">22</container>
                        <unittitle id="link30">Agreement between Marine Towing and Transportation
                            Employees' Association and National Maritime Union, United Marine
                            Division, Local 333</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1957">1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>February 1, 1957</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">23</container>
                        <unittitle id="link31">Non-Railroad Tow Boats - New York Harbor</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">24</container>
                        <unittitle id="link32">Basic Daily Rates - Deck Personnel, commercial Marine
                            Operators and Railroad Marine Service</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">25</container>
                        <unittitle id="link33">Licensing and Classification of Officers of Merchant
                            Vessels</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">26</container>
                        <unittitle id="link34">Penalty Pay for Work on Holidays</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">27</container>
                        <unittitle id="link35">Sick Leave with Pay</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">28</container>
                        <unittitle id="link36">Exhibit 28 - no information</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">29</container>
                        <unittitle id="link37">Pattern Settlements with Miscellaneous Labor
                            Organizations</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">30</container>
                        <unittitle id="link38">Pattern Settlements with Railroad Labor Organizations
                            Representing Marine Employees - New York Harbor</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">31</container>
                        <unittitle id="link39">Pattern Settlements with Railroad Labor Organizations
                            Representing Marine Employees - New York Harbor</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Supplement to Exhibit 30</p>
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">32</container>
                        <unittitle id="link40">Pattern Settlements with Railroad Organizations
                            Representing Marine Employees other than New York Harbor</unittitle>
                        <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1956/1957">1956-1957</unitdate>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">33</container>
                        <unittitle id="link41">Cost Data</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">34</container>
                        <unittitle id="link42">New York Central System - "Rules of the Operating
                            Department"</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">35</container>
                        <unittitle id="link43">Cost of Holiday Proposal Based Upon Employment in
                            1956</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">36</container>
                        <unittitle id="link44">Report to the President by the Emergency Board, 38
                            pages</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container type="box">1</container>
                        <container type="folder">37</container>
                        <unittitle id="link45">Transcripts. 9 Volumes. 1082 Pages</unittitle>
                    </did>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
