<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>

<ead>
 <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
  <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06174-005::NYSUT Legislative Department Files.)//EN">KCL06174-005.xml</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the NYSUT Legislative Department Files,<date> 1884-2005</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">NYSUT Legislative Department Files.</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by P. Leary</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
    <date>October 29, 2013</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>October 29, 2013</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 </eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the NYSUT Legislative Department Files.<lb/></titleproper>
   <num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc2572">Collection Number: 6174/005</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183> <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>P. Leary, April 23, 2012</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Randall Miles, October 29, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>&#169; 2013 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
   <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">NYSUT Legislative Department Files, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1884- 2005</unitdate>
   </unittitle>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">6174/005</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:"><corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)</corpname></origination>
   <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">15.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reports, pamphlets, correspondence.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">NYSUT ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
   <p>New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO. </p>
   <p>In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY. </p>
   <p>NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations. </p>
   <p>While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions. </p>
   <p>NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">LEGISLATIVE DEPRTMENT ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
   <p>NYSUT's Legislative Department, a relatively small unit composed of just about a dozen members, was the engine behind the political powerhouse NYSUT had become by the 1980s. Reporting to the executive vice president, the department coordinated with the Legal Department and the Division of Research and Educational Services to develop an annual Legislative Program for the union, and then to push it relentlessly though the state legislature, from finding a sponsor for it in the Assembly or Senate, until it was signed by the governor. In addition to initiating legislation, the department tracked bills proposed independently by legislators, including proposals it considered detrimental to NYSUT's interests. All bills -- typically, some 15,000 per session -- would be reviewed. Of those 15,000, the approximately 3,000 that were determined to have an impact on education or health care were tracked on a daily basis by the department's electronic monitoring system. Receiving especially
    careful scrutiny was the annual budget proposed by the governor, for its impact on state aid to public education, including higher education provided by the State University of New York (SUNY) and its community colleges, and the City University of New York (CUNY). NYSUT's affiliate, United University Professions (UUP), regularly coordinated lobbying efforts with the department on behalf of higher education funding. The Legislative Department's overall lobbying operation was carried out not only by its professional staff in one-on-one contacts with individual legislators, but by a large group of volunteers, including retirees, who comprised its Committee of 100. Appointed by local presidents throughout the state, these teachers, school bus drivers, cafeteria ladies (aka School-Related Personnel), community college local presidents, and nurses (though NYSUT's affiliate, Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals), converged on Albany at least once a year, like birds returning in
    spring, to visit their local legislators on targeted, high-priority pending legislation. </p>
   <p> In addition to state legislation, federal initiatives were also on the radar of the Legislative Department. The department knew what laws were in the congressional pipeline and who was behind them, and let them know of NYSUT's interest. The Legislative Department's purview included recommending endorsements to the NYSUT Board of Directors -- for president, Congress, and statewide down to the Assembly district level -- and then working with NYSUT's political action committee, VOTE/COPE (Committee on Political Education), to elect (or reelect) those candidates through a massive effort including phonebanks to members, specially printed campaign literature, and direct financial contributions. </p>
   <p> Areas of interest to NYSUT included not only specific funding formulas for school aid, but state taxation broadly, because it knew that any reduction in revenues could ultimately be taken out of education funding. Legislation could be as narrow as giving state retirement service credit for Korean War veterans to issues affecting all public employees, such as the permanent COLA (cost of living adjustment) for retirees and the Triborough amendment to the Taylor Law, governing contract agreements. Thus the Legislative Department maintained contacts with a wide array of organizations and was itself a resource to elected and appointed officials. Led in the 1980s and 1990s by director of legislation Ray Skuse, a former Republican member of Assembly, the department worked equally well with Republicans and Democrats. The successive NYSUT executive vice presidents to whom the department reported, Dan Sanders, Herb Magidson, and Alan Lubin, all rose from the ranks of NYSUT's affiliate in
    New York City, the United Federation of Teachers (UFT), the political proving ground headed by Albert Shanker.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
   <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
   <p>1973-2005. Majority of materials cover 1990s, some 1980s. Contents include issues briefing materials for lobbying days by Committee of 100, members of NYSUT, including retirees, who volunteered to lobby legislators in Albany; voter registration and issues flyers by VOTE/COPE (Committee on Political Education), the political action committee of NYSUT; recommendations for candidate endorsements and related background materials (research on voting records, summaries of key legislation); resolutions for consideration at the NYSUT Representative Assembly; correspondence with elected officials; draft legislation initiated by NYSUT; legislative memoranda of support or opposition to specific bills; annual NYSUT legislative programs (comprehensive package of bills of interest to K-12 public education, higher education, and health professionals); analyses of proposed executive (governor's) budgets; annual reports on legislative sessions, including bills opposed by NYSUT and not passed,
    bills passed by one chamber, vetoed, or signed into law</p>
  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
   <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Names: </head>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Magidson, Herb</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Sanders, Dan</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Shanker, Albert</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Skuse, Ray</persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers. Archives </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers, Legislative Department </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers, Political Action Committee </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers, Committee of 100 </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Subjects: </head>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Teachers' union, New York (State) </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
    <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Records</genreform>
   </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
   <accessrestrict>
    <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    <head>Cite As:</head>
    <p>NYSUT Legislative Department Files. #6174/005. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">RA 1997</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Convention Call; NYSUT Constitution, May 1993; nomination form for SRP Employee of the Year; list of committees; action items; memos re VOTE/COPE reception, Local Presidents' Conference; invitations to elected officials; draft working script for "Leaders of the PAC"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link7">RA 1997 (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Final Legislative Report, 1996; proposed constitutional amendments and resolutions; VOTE/COPE list of award-winning locals for 1996; Legislative Update (special RA report), "A Constitutional Convention in NYS?"; form letters to elected representatives re educational issues, available on NYSUT web site; minutes of NYSUT Board of Directors meeting of February 28-March 1, 1997; agenda for May 1 meeting; briefing bulletins for Board of Directors</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link8">Community College Luncheon</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 12, 1997. Letters of invitation to community college presidents; list of attendees from NYSUT and community colleges; testimony of Alan Lubin, executive vice president, NYSUT, to the Assembly Standing Committee on Higher Education, "Community Colleges: Strengthening Their Financial Support Structure," October 30; SUNY press release, "Chancellor to Submit 1998-99 State University Budget: Further Investment in Community Colleges is Central Focus of the Preposed $1.596 Billion Spending Plan"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link9">UFT/NYSUT Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 4, 1997. Memos re pension and retirement lobby day in Albany; luncheon menu and facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link10">Todd French (Constitutional Convention)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Prospectus for final report re issues surrounding 1967 constitutional convention and 1997 constitutional convention referendum; correspondence with researcher</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link11">Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 3, 1997. Invitations; list of key legislative staff; menus, invoices, and other facilitative correspondence with caterers and others</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link12">UUP Dinner Meeting- Fort Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 16, 1996. Invitation on behalf of NYSUT and United University Professions to holiday dinner meeting, noting agenda to discuss future of SUNY colleges of technology; memo re Strategic Alliance of ag and tech colleges</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link13">1996 Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Clinton campaign bumper stickers; primary election results by congressional districts, Assembly districts and senate districts; memo re campaign printing and mailing operation; memo to AFT political director, requesting campaign supplies; list of NYSUT delegates and alternates to 1996 Democratic National Convention; memos re phone bank assistance for Rep. Hinchey and other priority candidates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link14">Committee of 100-Vouchers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Lists of members of Committee of 100; expense reimbursement vouchers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link15">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/25-26/1996. Notice to members re lobby day; memo re need for follow-up with legislator re school funding formula, including notes of visit; facilitative correspondence with hotel; expense invoices</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link16">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/13-14/1996. Evaluation forms summarizing positions of legislators visited during lobby day; text of legislation in Assembly re school funding, January 24, 1995; list of 1996 participants in lobby day; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link17">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1995/1996">1995-1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence and tentative agenda for March 25-26, 1996, lobby day; lists of members of Committee of 100; list of United University Professions executive board; list of NYSUT School-Related Personnel Advisory Committee members</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link18">Community College Luncheon</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 7, 1996. List of invitees to NYSUT annual community college luncheon; letters of invitation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link19">PEC Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Sept. 29-Oct. 3, 1996. Tentative agenda and related information re Public Employee Conference annual convention</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link20">NYS AFL-CIO Meeting Concord Hotel</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>9/8-12/1996. Convention call for 28th constitutional convention, including tentative program; description of workshops</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link21">UFT Retiree Meeting Jeanne DiLorenzo</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 19, 1996. Letter from UFT Retired Teachers chapter leader DiLorenzo requesting that NYSUT officer Ray Skuse speak at meeting re legislative process in Albany, August 2, 1995</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link22">ED 12 Retirees</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 24, 1996. Note re retiree lobby day; catering evaluation form; list of members attending</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link23">Committee of 100-Bill Schultz</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Briefing booklet re education issues for Committee of 100 lobby day, March 25-26, 1996; list of members of education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link24">New Board Members Orientation</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 11, 1996. Agenda and notice to Administrative Committee</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link25">NYS AFL-CIO Legislative Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda and cover letter re theme, "America Needs a Raise"; list of NYSUT legislative department staff attending</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link26">National Conference of State Legislatures</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>St. Louis, MO July 27-31, 1996. Meeting schedule and related information</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link27">Pension Security in a Changing Environment</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 11-12, 1996. Conference brochure, "Pension Security in a Changing Environment," cosponsored by NYS and Local Retirement Systems and Government Law Center of Albany Law School; correspondence re NYSUT attendees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link28">Departmental Meetings</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re weekly meeting schedule; catering evaluation forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link29">Empire State Report Pension Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYC March 20-21, 1996. Empire State Report invitational brochure, "Public Pension Investment Policy Conference"; registration forms for NYSUT legislative staff</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link30">AFT-AFL Meetings</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 1996. Facilitative materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link31">Public Employee Conference Legislative Breakfast</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 6, 1996. Notice re NYS Public Employee Conference 19th Annual Legislative Breakfast; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link32">NYSUT Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 29, 1996. Letters of invitation; menu, invoices, and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link33">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 11-12, 1996. List of attendees; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link34">Representative Assembly</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Convention call and tentative program; tentative program for pre-RA Local Presidents' Conference; NYSUT constitution, May 1993; proposed guest list of elected officials; form letters on educational issues to be sent to elected representatives, prepared for delegates visiting Political Action Center at conference; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link35">RA Material</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report of the Resolutions Committees; special orders of business re elementary school standards, phase-out of Regents competency tests; Summary of PAC Activities (revised), December 1995-February 26, 1996; report of actions taken on constitutional amendments and resolutions; description of political action workshops; agenda for ED 12 Retiree Council Political Action Committee Training Day; invitation to VOTE/COPE reception for award-winning locals; awards program, listing locals; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link36">Committee of 100-Issues</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 11-12, 1998. Briefing book re legislative and budget proposals affecting public education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link37">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 9-10, 1998. Agenda for lobbying day; issues briefing book; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link38">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 19-20, 1997. Agenda for lobbying day; issues briefing book; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link39">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 13-14, 1996. Agenda for lobbying day; issues briefing book; booklet, "New York State Tax Cuts: Promise or Peril?"; print ads/flyers re education and tax issues; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link40">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 25-26, 1996. Agenda for lobbying day; issues briefing book; print ads/flyers re education and tax issues; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; Legislative Update by NYSUT Legislative Department; list of elected official who have endorsed "Lessons for Life"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link41">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 15-16, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; briefing papers re multi-year tax-cut proposals and other education issues; print ads/flyers re negative impact of tax cuts; NYSUT press release, "25 Percent of Teachers in NYSUT Survey Report Guns in Schools"; NYSUT Legislative Memorandum opposing multi-year tax cut</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link42">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 6-7, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; talking points on state aid to education; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Committee of 100 to Press Case for More School Aid"; briefing paper, "Truth and Consequences-What the Executive Budget Doesn't Tell You about CUNY and SUNY!"; Testimony of Alan Lubin, executive vice president, NYSUT, to the Senate Finance Committee and Assembly Ways and Means Committee on the 1995-96 Executive Budget, February 14, 1995</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link43">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1884">1884</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 9-10, 1994. Agenda for lobbying day; issues briefing book; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of labor, civil service, and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link44">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 21-22, 1994. Issues briefing book, "Seeking Support for Public Education, 1994-95"; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; list of sponsors of bill to further reduce corporate taxes; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; NYSUT Special Report, "School Decay: A Prescription for Recovery"; flyer by New York State School Boards Association calling for changes in 3020-a disciplinary process</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link45">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 17-18, 1993. Agenda for lobbying day; briefing book on pension, retirement and labor issues; background sheet re COLA: pension supplementation; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of labor, civil service, and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link46">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 22-23, 1993. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; print ads/flyers re flawed tax system; report by American Economic Group, Inc., for NYSUT, "New York's 16 Billion Dollar Dilemma: Consequences of our state's well-intentioned tax cuts-and a plan to solve our revenue crisis"; Testimony of Herb Magidson, executive vice president, NYSUT, to the Joint Committee of the NYS Senate Finance and Assembly Ways and Means Committees, January 26, 1993; Testimony on State Operations Budget, presented to Senate Finance Committee, Assembly Ways and Means Committee, by John M. Reilly, president, United University Professions, February 2, 1993; Statement by Dr. Irwin H. Polishook, president, Professional Staff Congress/CUNY, to the Assembly Ways and Means Committee and the Senate Finance Committee on the Executive Budget, 1993-94, for the
      City University of New York, February 2, 1993; NYSUT summary, Executive Budget Recommendations, 1993-94, SUNY and CUNY Colleges</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link47">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 18-19, 1992. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education, civil service, and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing books, Pension and Retirement Issues, Higher Education Issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link48">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 24-25, 1992. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; NYSUT press release, "Statewide Survey: Increase Support for Public Education"; Fact Finders, Inc., survey results, "NYSUT Tracking of Public Attitudes Toward Education," February 20, 1992; Testimony of Herb Magidson, executive vice president, NYSUT, to the Senate Finance Committee and Assembly Ways and Means Committee on the 1992-93 Executive Budget, February 4, 1992; letter from Magidson to state legislators re survey showing public support for increased public education funding, February 24; Testimony presented by John M. Reilly, president, United University Professions, before the Joint Hearing of the NYS Senate Finance Committee and the NYS Assembly Ways and Means Committee, January 28, 1992; Testimony presented by Dr. Irwin H. Polishook, president, Professional Staff
      Congress/CUNY, before the Joint Hearing of the NYS Assembly Ways and Means Committee and NYS Senate Finance Committee, January 28, 1992</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link49">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 13-14, 1991. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education, civil service, and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; NYSUT press release; NYSUT report, "The Impact of Executive Proposals on State Aid to Public Education 1991-92"; "1991 NYSUT Legislative Program for Pension Equity"; NYSUT Legislative Memorandum in support of early retirement incentive; print ads/flyers re state budget</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link50">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 25-26, 1991. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of new legislators; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing book, "SUNY, CUNY, and the Community Colleges State Aid 1991-92"; print ads/flyers; letter to legislators from Tom Hobart and Herb Magidson opposing cuts in education budget; editorial from Daily Gazette (Schenectady), "Cuomo's Regressive Record," February 19; Testimony of Herb Magidson, executive vice president, NYSUT, to the Senate Finance Committee and Assembly Ways and Means Committee on the 1991-92 Executive Budget, February 11, 1991; highlights of the governor's state aid proposal</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link51">Higher Education Lobby Day (folder 1)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 3-4, 1997. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing materials for legislators; related testimony by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link52">Higher Education Lobby Day (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 3-4, 1997. Room lists and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link53">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 25-26, 1996. Analysis of key findings from the 1990 census: Demographic Trends in the NY-NJ Metropolitan Region: Educational Attainment and Economic Opportunity; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; tip sheet on effective lobbying; print ads/flyers on impact of state income tax cuts on local taxes and education; related testimony by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link54">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 11-12, 1996. Analysis of key findings from the 1990 census: Demographic Trends in the NY-NJ Metropolitan Region: Educational Attainment and Economic Opportunity; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; related testimony at state legislative committee hearings by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link55">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 27-28, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing paper, "Truth and Consequences-What the Executive Budget Doesn't Tell You about CUNY and SUNY!"; related testimony at state legislative committee hearings by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link56">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 14-15, 1994. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; print ads/flyers; NYSUT Higher Education Budget Restoration Recommendations 1994-95: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges; related testimony to state legislative committee hearings by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link57">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 9-10, 1992. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; print ads/flyers; NYSUT Higher Education Budget Restoration Recommendations 1994-95: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges; report by American Economics Group, Inc., for NYSUT, "New York's 16 Billion Dilemma"; related testimony to state legislative committees by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link58">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 9-10, 1992. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing book, "SUNY, CUNY, and the Community Colleges: State Aid, 1992-93"; print ad/flyer against cuts to public colleges; NYSUT press release, "Statewide Survey: Increase Support for Public Education"; Fact Finders, Inc., survey results, "NYSUT Tracking of Public Attitudes Toward Education," February 20, 1992; related testimony to state legislative committees by NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link59">FNHP (Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals) Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 14, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of health, education and finance committees; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; newspaper clipping/flyer re Long-Term Home Health Care Program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link60">FNHP Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 10, 1993. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of health, social services, insurance, and finance committees; briefing book, "Health Care State Aid 1993-94"; text of legislation; report by American Economics Group, Inc., prepared for NYSUT, "New York's 16 Billion Dollar Dilemma"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link61">FNHP Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 4-5, 1991. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of health and finance committees; list of new legislators; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; briefing book, "Health Care State Aid 1991-92"; tip sheet on effective lobbying; print ads/flyers re state budget deficit, including copies of editorials; draft Comprehensive Report: Legislation of Interest to Higher Education and Health Care Professionals 1990</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link62">Federal Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart and executive vice president Herb Magidson to NY congressional delegation re legislative concerns; AFT and NYSUT briefing book endorsing comprehensive health care reform, supplemental appropriations; AFT newsletter, "On the Hill," with article, "AFT Supports Clinton Economic Plan," March 1993</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link63">Political Action Committee (PAC)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August 13, 1996. Political Action Committee report form; booklet, "Speak Out for Teachers: A compilation of responses to teacher bashing provided by the participants at NYSUT's 1996 Local Presidents' Conference"; flyer, "Letters to the Editor: Six Tips for Getting Published"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link64">Workshop Session III Delegate Selection Process 1995 Presidential Primaries</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to PAC coordinators re national delegate selection process; instructions on selection process for Democratic and Republican primaries; instructions for circulating and filing petitions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link65">Presidents' Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August 1994. Agenda for Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; Guidelines for Political Endorsements for NYSUT; NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations for statewide offices, NYS Senate, Assembly, U.S. Congress; description of bills used for voting records, Senate-Assembly, U.S. Congress and Senate; congressional background information; congressional voting record 1993-94; Senate background information; NYS Senate voting record, 1993 and 1994; Assembly voting record, 1993 and 1994; Assembly background information; Assembly election results</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link66">ED 12 Retirees</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 24, 1996. NYSUT's Bill to Extend the Moratorium on the Diminution of Retirees' Health Insurance; tip sheet on effective lobbying; list of members of Senate and Assembly; list of members of finance, education, and civil service committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link67">Retiree Lobbying Training</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 25-26, 1994. Agenda for retiree lobbyist training; Rogers' Pocket Directory of members of Congress, NYS Senate, and Assembly, 1994; list of members of Senate and Assembly; issues briefing sheets re retiree health insurance, pension supplementation, permanent COLA legislation; tip sheet for effective lobbying</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link68">Retiree Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 17, 1994. Briefing book on key NYSUT pension retirement bills; tip sheet on effective lobbying; memo to lobbyists</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link69">Retiree Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Briefing book re permanent COLA, retirees' health insurance, election of retiree member of Retirement Board; print ad/flyer, "Why are we punishing our retired teachers?" (re need for permanent cost of living increase); list of legislators from North Country districts; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators; memo to lobbyists</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link70">Governor's Advisory Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for meeting of Advisory Council for a New New York, October 27, 1997; list of members; notes from meeting; memo recapping meeting, plan for report to governor, focus on education in State of the State address; description of organizations participating in Advisory Council; confidential outline, "Improving the Effectiveness of the Information Infrastructure in New York State Education," project kickoff, November 12</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link71">Vacation Schedule</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link72">Agency Fee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of estimated percentages of NYSUT employee time devoted to political activities not related to terms and conditions of teacher employment; definition of "chargeable" and "nonchargeable" activities subject to potential objection by union agency fee (dues) payers; related memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link73">Luncheon- Matt Scott, Swan Club, Glen Head Landing</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>September 30, 1997. Memos re Alan Lubin's inability to attend event</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link74">Luncheon ED 5-6 Canandaigua Yacht Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 1, 1997. Retiree Council Election District i5 newsletter re luncheon</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link75">National Conference of State Legislatures</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August 6-9, 1997. Memos re attendance and cancellation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link76">NYC Republican Senators Dinner</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 26, 1997. Letters to Republican state Senators representing NYC districts re cancellation of dinner in light of majority declining NYSUT invitation; letters of invitation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link77">Weinstein Dinner</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 27, 1997. Invitation and confirmation of dinner with Assembly members</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link78">AFL-CIO Workers Compensation Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/24-26/1997. Memo from NYS AFL-CIO president Ed Cleary re meeting to plan legislative initiative to strengthen workers compensation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link79">AFT Special Conference on Vouchers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 8-10, 1997. Memo; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link80">AFT Northeast Regional Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/15-17, 1997. Agenda; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link81">New Yorkers for Fiscal Fairness</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 22, 1997. Registration form for New Yorkers for Fiscal Fairness roundtable discussion sessions on corporate welfare reform and the 1997 constitutional convention question; memo and agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link82">AFL-CIO Legislative Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 28, 1997. Conference call for annual legislative conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link83">Community College Luncheon-Fort Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 9, 1994. List of attendees from NYSUT and SUNY; list of NYSUT-affiliated community college presidents; letters of invitation to community college presidents; memo to college presidents re discussion topics</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link84">Teacher Center Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/15/1994. Memo re teacher center policy board meeting and lobbying day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link85">SUNY-UUP Dinner-Fort Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>September 9. Notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link86">FNHP Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 24, 1994. Memo re Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Steering Committee seminar and lobbying day; memo re possible effort to amend Nurse Practices Act by State Education Department</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link87">Special Act Schools-Fort Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>July 6, 1994. Memo re informational seminar for Special Act school presidents re new reimbursement rates set by State Education Department</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link88">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/21-22, 1994. List of attendees; notice of meeting in preparation for lobby day; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link89">Cuomo-Record on Education</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Bullet points on Gov. Mario Cuomo's record on education; list of education accomplishments; bullet points, the Cuomo Labor Record; comparison of Cuomo and Pataki record on taxes and support for education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link90">1994 Election</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of endorsed candidates for statewide office and by Senate and Assembly districts; memo to regional staff directors re phone banks (calls by groups of volunteers to voters on behalf of candidates), with attached tally sheets and scripts; agreement between NYSUT and NYS Democratic Committee for lease of computer equipment</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link91">Local Presidents' Endorsement Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative agenda, list of attendees, and related correspondence for Local Presidents' Conference on Endorsements</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link92">VOTE/COPE Regional Campaign Coordinators</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of candidates endorsed at the NYSUT Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; press release; list of voting records of state legislators on bills of interest to NYSUT</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link93">Presidents' Conference on Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; AFT On the Hill newsletter re preliminary voting record of 103rd Congress; list of conference attendees; list of conference attendees from UUP; list of Democratic Assembly candidates; list of Republican Senate candidates; Assembly primary list; Senate voting record on NYSUT key bills; list of candidates in legislative races from the mid-Hudson region; preliminary legislative report, 1994 session: major NYSUT program and support bills;</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link94">Budget-End of Session Food Orders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link95">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>AFT On the Hill newsletter re preliminary voting record of 103rd Congress; lists of NYSUT endorsement recommendations for U.S. Congress, NYS Senate, Assembly, and statewide officers (governor, etc.); endorsements authorized by NYSUT Board of Directors</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link96">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/9-10, 1994. List of participants; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link97">NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT endorsement recommendations for U.S. Congress, NYS Senate, Assembly, governor and other statewide offices; list of endorsements authorized by NYSUT Board of Directors; NYSUT press release, "NYSUT Endorses [Gov. Mario] Cuomo for Re-Election"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link98">UFT Spring Education Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 7, 1994 NY Hilton. Agenda; letter of invitation from United Federation of Teachers president Sandra Feldman to NYSUT director of legislation Ray Skuse</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link99">UUP Friend of SUNY</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/6/1994. Invitation to award ceremony; list of invited guests; clipping from Chronicle of Higher Education re award recipient Ernest L. Boyer, president of the Carnegie Foundation for the Advancement of Teaching</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link100">Ad Hoc Task Force on School Violence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/13/1994. Meeting agenda; resolutions on school violence; New Paltz High School Student Bill of Rights and Responsibilities: Behavior Code</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link101">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/14-15, 1994. Lists of participants; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link102">Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1/31/1994. Invitations; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link103">Federal Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 20, 1994. Invitations; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link104">Federal Legislative Reception Manny's (Kafka) Material</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Emanuel Kafka's (VOTE/COPE) materials; invitations; lists of attendees; legislative fact sheets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link105">Health Benefits Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 3, 1993. Agenda; program brochure for New York State Public Sector Coalition on Health Benefits 7th Annual Conference, "The Health Care System in America-Do We Have the Courage to Change?"; letter of invitation to Ray Skuse; description of workshop on retiree health coverage</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link106">Campaigns and Elections Seminars</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>6/11-13, 1993. Washington DC. Memo to Ray Skuse from John Costello reporting on campaigns and elections seminars, with suggestions for NYSUT</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link107">Special Act Schools</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter re new law aimed at alleviating cash flow problem at Special Act schools, with attached text of legislation; list of NYSUT locals at Special Act schools</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link108">Chapter 437 Omnibus Retirement Bill</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outline of amended sections</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link109">Pat's (Ballard) Retirement Dinner Fort Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of invited members of Senate and Assembly, governor's office; invitation; notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link110">Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 1, 1993. Printed invitation; letters of invitation to union officials, community college presidents, and others; list of invitees; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link111">Federal Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 23, 1993. Printed invitation; list of invitees; issues briefing book, AFT and NYSUT Support supplemental appropriations, reauthorization of funding, comprehensive health care reform package; AFT newsletter, On the Hill, "AFT Supports Clinton Economic Plan"; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link112">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 22-23, 1993. Tentative agenda for lobbying day and notice of pre-lobby meeting, with issues briefing; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson; list of participants; testimony by union officials at state legislative committee hearings; summary of executive budget re SUNY, CUNY, and community colleges; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link113">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/17-18, 1993. Tentative agenda; list of participants; list of retirees from Retiree E.D. Councils 1-39; revised list of UFT participants; briefing book re pension, retirement, and labor issues; list of Senate and Assembly education committee members; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link114">New Local Presidents' Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program; description of NYSUT Legislative Department; descriptive flyer re VOTE/COPE and Legislative Department activities; completed evaluation forms; notes from conference planning meeting; document, NYSUT's Major Legislative Program and Support Bills: Passed both Houses and Signed into Law as of July 15, 1993; briefing paper re BOCES reform legislation capping salary and compensation for district superintendents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link115">Retirees Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/25, 6/1, 6/8, 6/15, 6/22 1994. List of state legislators from regional areas; tip sheet on effective lobbying; bullet points on retirement issues (pension COLA, health insurance); program for training session, including role-playing as legislators deflecting issues ; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson, summarizing issues; NYSUT press release, "Teachers to Lobby Weekly for Retiree Benefits"; list of participants; facilitative correspondence; letters from individual retirees to state legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link116">AFL-CIO AFT Meetings</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 1993. Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link117">Community College Luncheon Ft. Orange</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 1, 1993. List of attendees; letters of invitation to individual community college presidents from chair of NYSUT Community College Council; 1993-94 Executive Budget Highlights: SUNY and CUNY Community Colleges</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link118">Ulster County Democratic Committee Phone Bank</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Telephone bank use agreement between NYSUT and Ulster County Democratic Committee; letter from NYSUT legislative director Ray Skuse to chair of Ulster County Democratic Committee requesting reimbursement for expenses</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link119">End of Session Food Orders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Menu; invoices</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link120">Teacher Center Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 16, 1993. Agenda; catering invoices</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link121">FNHP Ft. Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 10, 1993. List of members of Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Committee; letter re lobbying day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link122">Committee of 100 Housing</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/22-23, 1993. Housing lists for lobbying day participants</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link123">Higher Ed Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 1-2, 1993. Lists of participants; housing lists and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link124">Community College Luncheon Ft. Orange Club</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 14, 1994. Letters of invitation to individual community college presidents; list of attendees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link125">Teacher Center Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 21, 1995. List of Teacher Centers located by districts of Ways and Means and Finance Committee members; correspondence re catering</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link126">FNHP Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 14, 1995. Form letter inviting members of Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Committee to participate in lobbying day, with attached list of committee members and response form soliciting budget concerns; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link127">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/6-7, 1995. List of committee members; expense vouchers and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link128">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/15-16, 1995. Tentative agenda; suggested order of issues briefing; schedule of appointments with members of Senate and Assembly higher education committees; list of participants; memos noting successes of previous lobby day, issues for upcoming visit</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link129">Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 30, 1995. Lists of invitees and attendees; letters of invitation to local leaders of community colleges; printed invitations; facilitative correspondence with caterer</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link130">Political Action Committee (PAC) Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 27-28, 1995 Omni Hotel. Tentative agenda for Political Action Committee Conference; list of attendees; text of remarks by NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin; outline for workshop session; letters of appointment to members of Political Action Committee, with outline of responsibilities; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link131">PAC Housing</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 27-28, 1995. Housing response forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link132">Dan Feldman Breakfast</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>November 9, 1995. Flyer invitation to Assembly member Dan Feldman reception; list of invitees; letters of invitation to labor leaders</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link133">FEC (Federal Election Commission) Conference Alan Lewis</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/11-12, 1995. Invitation and program for Federal Election Commission conference on campaign finance laws for corporations and labor organizations; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link134">Retiree Training Best Western</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>4/25-26, 1994. Tentative agenda; list of attendees; letters to trainers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link135">Retiree Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of retiree lobby days scheduled for 1995; printing request forms for materials; briefing papers re supplemental pensions, retiree health insurance, multi-year tax cut proposal, tips on effective lobbying</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link136">Retiree Training</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to volunteers re success of previous year's lobbying; schedule for upcoming lobby days by region; list of volunteers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link137">Budget End of Session Food Orders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Menus; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link138">Republican Senate</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Sample telephone scripts on issues affecting education; lists of Republican state senators; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link139">Community College Luncheon</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>November 10, 1995. List of attendees; list of community college presidents; letters of invitation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link140">Public Employee Conference (PEC) Breakfast</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 7, 1995. Printed invitation; letter to affiliates urging participation in annual legislative breakfast, noting need to show unity against threat of privatization</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link141">TDA New York City Teachers' Retirement System</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Travel documents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link142">New York State Festival</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation from Gov. Pataki and NY congressional delegation to attend NYS Theatre Institute production of A Tale of Cinderella; NYS Festival fact sheet; list of donors to 1993 gift bag; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link143">PEC Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Sept. 17-20, 1995 Myrtle Beach. Agenda for NYS Public Employee Conference Annual Convention; convention call</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link144">Higher Ed Lobby Day (folder 1)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/27-28, 1995. List of participants; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link145">Higher Education Lobby Day (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/27-28, 1995. Agenda for lobbying day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; list of members of Senate and Assembly education and finance committees; briefing book, "Truth and Consequences-What the Executive Budget Doesn't Tell You about CUNY and SUNY!"; testimony of NYSUT, UUP, and PSC/CUNY officials at legislative committee hearings; reporting sheet for lobbying meetings with individual legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link146">New York's Moynihan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Press release from Moynihan Senate campaign, "Senator Moynihan and Organized Labor"; flyer with biographical information; campaign brochure; voting record on issues of importance to AFL-CIO</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link147">New Local Presidents' Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of attendees; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link148">Committee of 100 (folder 1)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/24-25, 1992. Letters to attendees re housing arrangements; housing list of participants</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link149">Committee of 100 (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/24-25, 1992. Tentative agenda; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link150">Committee of 100 Invitations</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of UFT participants; distribution list for invitations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link151">Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 3, 1992. List of invitees; printed invitations; menu and facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link152">Wantagh Retirees Meeting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/14/1992. Letter of invitation to Ray Skuse to speak to retirees, to address several process issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link153">NYS AFL-CIO Labor Recognition Dinner</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/3/1992. Program and invitation for 8th annual Labor Recognition Dinner; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link154">Yonkers Federal Workshop Arden House</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/7/1992. Memo to Ray Skuse re speaking at the Yonkers Federation of Teachers annual workshop re legislative issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link155">Belle Zeller Scholarship Award Dinner</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>11/5/1992 NYC. Invitation to Friend of CUNY award dinner</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link156">NYS AFL-CIO</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>8/30-9/3/1992. Program for 27th Constitutional Convention of NYS AFL-CIO; reservation form for NYSUT member</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link157">Committee of 100 (folder 1)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/18-19, 1992. Agenda; memo from Ray Skuse inviting community college presidents to attend lobbying day; print request forms for materials including lists of members of Senate and Assembly higher education committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link158">Committee of 100 (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/18-19, 1992. Housing reply forms and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link159">Committee of 100 (folder 3)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/18-19, 1992. Housing lists and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link160">Special Act Schools Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 4, 1992. Agenda for lobby day; letters of invitation to lobby day; list of Special Act Schools (for children with handicapping conditions) local presidents; list of state legislators representing districts with Special Act Schools; letter to deputy education commissioner re inequities in salary formulas for Special Act Schools; legislative alert to Coalition for Special Act School Districts re funding methodologies for Special Act Schools; clipping from New York Teacher, "Giving Troubled Youth a Future"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link161">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 9-10, 1992. Agenda; schedule of appointments with legislators; list of NYSUT- affiliated community colleges as of 12/21/90; letters of invitation to community college locals; list of participating UUP members; list of attendees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link162">Federal Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed invitations; list of legislators; briefing memo to reception attendees re legislative issues, including health care, vouchers, balanced budget amendment, striker replacement, with attached voting records of legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link163">Teacher Center Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 10, 1992. List of members of Senate and Assembly finance committees and associated teacher centers; text of proposed legislation; memo re suggested changes to draft legislation; memo from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese re meeting of Teacher Center Policy board members and directors; related memos; testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to the Senate Finance Committee and Assembly Ways and Means Committee on the 1992-93 Executive Budget</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link164">New Local Presidents Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program; agenda; notes from the April 17 meeting of the New Local Presidents Conference Committee; time line and notes from May 28 committee meeting; conference call and registration form</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link165">New Local Presidents Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>July 18, 1990. Agenda; conference schedule; document, "1989-90 Invisible Victories: Bills Blocked by NYSUT That Would Have Destroyed Member Rights"; minutes of May 7 and June 11 planning committee meetings; topics for round table discussions at conference; program for 1989 conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link166">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>February 25-26, 1991. Facilitative correspondence; list of invited participants</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link167">Committee of 100 Print Shop Requests</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Print requests for materials for Lobby Day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link168">Federal Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed invitations; response forms; list of invitees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link169">Higher Education Luncheon (folder 1)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/18/1991 Fort Orange Club. Letter from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to legislators, discussing higher education funding, inviting them to lunch; list of invitees; menu</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link170">Higher Education Luncheon (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>12/18/1991. Letter from United University Professions (UUP) president to NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson re suggested issues for discussion at higher education meeting; document by Professional Staff Congress of City University of New York (PSCcuny), "Reaffirming CUNY's Mission"; bullet points for SUNY and CUNY; letters from Magidson to legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link171">Higher Education Lobbying (folder 1)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/19-20, 1991. Letters of invitation to Lobby Day to local presidents of community colleges; letters re chance in date to February 25-26</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link172">Higher Education Lobbying (folder 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/19-20, 1991. Form letter of invitation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link173">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/26-27, 1990. Agenda; list of participants; letter of invitation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link174">Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed invitations; letters of invitation to local presidents of community colleges; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link175">NYSUT Legislative Reception</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2/5/1990 Corning Tower. Printed invitation; letters of invitation to community college local presidents; list of invitees; handwritten list of legislative staff; menu and other facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link176">Federal Legislative Reception Representative Assembly</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Washington, DC. Printed invitation; program brochure for Representative Assembly; thank-you letters from NYSUT president Hobart to other NYSUT officers for moderating seminars; thank-you letters to members of Congress and others for participating; letters listing members of Congress and labor officials to attend seminars and panels</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link177">Committee of 100-Vouchers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/1991. Housing lists and expense forms for Committee of 100 participants</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link178">Committee of 100-Invitations</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 13-14, 1991. Lists of retirees participating in Committee of 100 lobby day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link179">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 13-14, 1991. Lists of attendees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link180">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 13-14, 1991. NYSUT draft budget overview, "The Impact of Executive Proposals on State Aid to Public Education 1991-92"; draft, "1991 NYSUT Legislative Program for Pension Equity"; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson, discussing issues; related memos to retiree participants in Committee of 100 lobby day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link181">Committee of 100-Material for Kits</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 13-14, 1991. Print requests for ad/flyers, lists of legislators, and related materials for lobby day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link182">FNHP Lobbying</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>3/12-13, 1990. Agenda; list of participants; letter to participants; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link183">FNHP Lobbying</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 4-5, 1991. List of participants; letter to participants; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link184">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 21-22, 1990 Hilton. Tentative agenda; issues briefing book, "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity," with cover letter to participants; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson; memo to Ray Skuse suggesting improvements; reporting form for visits with legislators; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link185">Committee of 100 Retirees</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Lists of participants; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link186">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 5-6, 1990. Housing lists; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link187">Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March 5-6, 1990. Agenda; housing lists; memo re media coverage</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link188">AFT Convention</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative program; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link189">Community College Lobbying</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 29-30, 1990. Letter of invitation to lobby day from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson to community college local presidents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link190">Federal Reception and Lobbying</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>5/8-9, 1990. Tentative agenda; talking points on issues; filled-in reporting forms noting reactions of individual legislators at lobbying meetings; list of attendees; facilitative correspondence with hotel staff</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link191">UFT Steering Committee on Veterans' Pension Credit</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 12, 1990. Schedule of meetings with legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link192">Political Action Workshop-Utica</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; letter inviting NYSUT local leaders to regional workshop; letter inviting legislators to dinner; lists of attendees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link193">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 28-June 29, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail re legislative issues, including background briefing materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link194">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 5-April 27, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link195">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 3-December 14, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link196">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 27-September 30, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link197">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>October 27-November 28, 1994. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link198">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>November 13-December 22, 1992. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link199">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>June 1-November 10, 1992. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link200">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 3-May 29, 1992. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link201">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August 20-December 3, 1991. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link202">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April 24-August 20, 1991. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link203">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 3-April 23, 1991. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link204">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>November 16-December 20, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link205">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August 31-November 16, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link206">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>May 2-August 30, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link207">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 24-May 2, 1995. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link208">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link209">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>September-December. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link210">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>August-October. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link211">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>April-August. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link212">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>March-April. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link213">Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January-March. Chronological files of outgoing mail</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link214">Costello, John (1 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence of John Costello, NYSUT assistant director of legislation, re Special Act schools, retiree contributions to VOTE/COPE, plans for 1997 legislative session; summary of report by American Economics Group, commissioned by NYSUT, "Our Tax System: Flawed and Unfair," re fiscal crisis generated by 1987 state tax cut; document, "Pension Supplementation," re bills in 1994 and 1995 legislative session</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link215">Costello, John (2 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft document re BOCES issues; draft summary of campaign operations undertaken by Legislative Department; instructions for letter writing campaign in support of Mario Cuomo's re-election as governor, with sample letters; comparisons of state aid for 4201 Schools 1993-94 to 1994-95; description of 4201 issues; draft background information re health insurance for retired public and school employees; monthly VOTE/COPE coordinators report form</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link216">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence of NYSUT legislative relations coordinator Alan Lewis re legislation, reports, referred resolutions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link217">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re legislation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link218">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1989">1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re legislation, with text of amendments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link219">Lewis, Alan (1 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Compilation of legislation enacted 1973 through 1996 affecting members of NYS Teachers' Retirement System; memos re referred resolutions; documents re Federal Election Commission, union activities under federal campaign laws; memos re state regulations for lobbyists re salary and expense reporting; list of bills of interest passed in both state houses as of 11/12/96</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link220">Lewis, Alan (2 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Proposed resolutions for 1996 Representative Assembly (RA); memo re implementation of resolutions referred at 1995 RA; legislative memoranda of support for various bills; memos re state lobbying reports; highlights of retirement incentive bill</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link221">Kafka, Emanuel</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1994 VOTE/COPE Instruction Manual; Outline of Presentation of Proposed National Health Security Act to Community Groups; Benefits Comparison under Health Security Act; memo to NYSUT Board of Directors re national health care; health care reform legislative update; list of NY congressional delegation; agenda for Clinton Health Security Plan Speakers Bureau Training Session; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link222">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link223">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link224">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re campaign contribution limits and related issues; memos to the governor re pending legislation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link225">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence and text of legislation re early retirement incentive, retirement benefits; legislation passed by both state houses awaiting action by governor as of 8/14/92; bills signed as of 8/14/92; bills vetoed as of 8/14/92</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link226">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re lobbying reports, retirement issues; text of proposed amendments re workers' compensation, maternity leave, other issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link227">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re NYSUT legislative program on a range of issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link228">Martineau, Peter</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence of NYSUT assistant director of legislation Peter Martineau re political and policy aspects of higher education issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link229">Martineau, Peter</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin at state legislative committee hearings re state budget, community colleges; correspondence re mental health issues; memos from Martineau to NYSUT officers re higher education and other legislative research</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link230">Martineau, Peter</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin at state legislative committee hearings re executive budget, future of State University of New York; letter from Martineau to counsel to Gov. Pataki re reforms supported by NYSUT, August 17; letter to locals praising turnout for Clinton/Gore rally; memo to UUP president re variable tuition report, December 19</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link231">Martineau, Peter (1 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of legislation re workers' compensation, medical monitoring; memos from Martineau to NYSUT officers re media coverage of SUNY, political critique of AFT brochure on higher education, other issues; list of status of legislation at end of session, 7/20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link232">Martineau, Peter (2 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re higher education and budget issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link233">Skuse, Ray</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Document, "History of labor laws in NYS for public employees"; draft policy re local political activities, with question and answer sheet; status report on key NYSUT initiatives; text of bill re teacher resource centers, 1992; papers analyzing proposed legislation re retirement, state aid; chronological correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link234">Skuse, Ray</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1988/1989">1988-1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence including letters to local presidents re political action workshop</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link235">Skuse, Ray</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re NYC school construction and higher education capital bond issues; progress report on Dukakis presidential campaign phone calling by region, October 12; draft press release announcing endorsement of state Sen. James Donovan (R)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link236">Skuse, Ray</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Final report, 1987 Legislative Session: NYSUT Program and Support Bills Signed into Law; Random Notes re Election of Delegates to the Democratic Convention and Congressional District Coordinators; memorandum of opposition to proposed legislation allowing school districts to require fingerprinting of employees and prospective employees; chronological correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link237">Skuse, Ray</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence including draft responses to letters to the editor criticizing NYSUT endorsement process, October 10, 1986; memos re election telephone calling operation; regional high schools of excellence, 1985; analysis of civil service and pension proposals; memo re proposed New York State Voter Registration Network, meeting with District Council 37 political director Norman Adler, Bella Abzug, Democratic party officials, and legislators, May 23, 1983, with attached documents re need to target black population in NY as largest unregistered segment in U.S.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link238">Support Statements-Bills Not Carried Over from 1985-1986</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1985/1986">1985-1986</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summaries of proposed legislation and statements of support by NYSUT</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link239">Legislation (Ventura)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Proposals for retirement/pension equity, 1990-1992; 1993 Final Report on NYSUT's major legislative program and support bills; Legislative Update: Highlights of Previous NYSUT Legislative Victories, April 1993; related documents apparently stored on Ventura computer system</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link240">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of NYSUT affiliated community colleges; memo from Ballard to Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals (FNHP) leaders re NYS budget highlights, May 8, 1992; testimony of presidents of CUNY Professional Staff Congress and United University Professions (UUP) at state legislative committee hearings; documents re community college statistics, items of interest to UUP, sexual harassment criteria</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link241">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1989/1990">1989-1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft Comprehensive Report, Legislation of Interest to Higher Education and Health Care Professionals; memo from Ballard to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re SUNY community colleges and state aid data, March 15; memo re Adolescent Tobacco Act, October 5; memo from Ballard to FNHP members, summary of 1990 legislative session, September 17; highlights of SUNY and CUNY state operations budgets and related fact sheets; testimony of officers of higher education labor unions at state legislative committee hearings</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link242">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1989/1990">1989-1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Executive Budget Highlights of Health Care Proposals; Major Legislation of Interest: Higher Education and Health Care Professionals, 1989 and 1988; memo suggesting facts re SUNY community colleges for inclusion in VOTE/COPE pamphlet; tentative schedule and workshop descriptions for "Effective Unions in Community Colleges," November 3-5, 1989; memo re Legislative Department's activities for UUP, 1989-90; materials re letter-writing campaign to elected representatives; materials re lobbying day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link243">Ballard, Pat (1 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to community college local presidents re meeting to discuss lobbying for SUNY and CUNY budget requests; list of bills of interest to higher education, signed by governor, October 27; Position Statement on the Use of Laboratory Animals in Biomedical Research, prepared by UUP; memos re budget issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link244">Ballard, Pat (2 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Reports on CUNY and SUNY state aid; letters to state legislators from NYSUT and UUP officers; letters to community college presidents re budget issues; memo re lobbying day by Committee of 100</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link245">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of legislators invited to UUP legislative breakfast (lobbying), January 26; memo from Ballard to Legislative Director Ray Skuse, "Highlights of SUNY's Undergraduate Initiative," December 7; draft documents, "Governor's Initiative to Promote Teaching Excellence at the State University of New York and the City University of New York"; memo from Ballard to UUP's Legislative Committee summarizing items of interest; memo from Ballard reporting on AFT Community College Conference, October 23-25; legislative memorandum of support for SUNY state aid proposal; final reports of 1987 legislative session; other materials related to CUNY and SUNY budget issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link246">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from Ballard to NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson summarizing final report of AFT task force on future of health care, September 21; memo and notice of Assembly Committee hearing on community colleges; notes for upcoming meeting with legislators on higher education; summaries of executive budget re higher education; document, legislation of interest to higher education and health care professionals; detailed analysis of health care state aid, 1991-92, for internal use by NYSUT Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals; agenda for FNHP lobbying day, March 4-5; list of Senate and Assembly Health Committee members</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link247">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re repeal of mandatory retirement age for tenured faculty, humane animal experimentation task force recommendations, SUNY Maritime College, certification of health teachers, Monroe Community College capital construction request; final reports on governor's action on major legislation of interest to SUNY-CUNY community colleges, UUP, PSC; highlights of 1986 tax reform proposal of interest to higher education faculty</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link248">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Legislative Program and Support Bills of Interest to Community Colleges, 1983 and 1984; final reports for 1985 session; bills of interest to UUP that were signed into law, 1983 session; text of mailgram to U.S. senators Moynihan and D'Amato opposing tuition tax credit for private school enrollment, November 9, 1983; memo from Ballard (Koenig) re first impressions of executive budget proposals, January 1984; detailed analyses of state budget proposals impacting SUNY and CUNY; update of 1984 legislative session;</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link249">Ballard, Pat</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Testimony of president of United College Employees of the Fashion Institute of Technology to the NYS Assembly Committee on Higher Education and Subcommittee on Community Colleges, October 23, 1991; testimony of SUNY chancellor D. Bruce Johnstone before the committees; State of New York multi-year financial update, fiscal year 1991-92; material re VOTE/COPE; update of 1991-92 session; agenda for FNHP legislative meeting, December 6</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link250">Connolly, Kristan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of school districts by Senate district and Assembly district; budget cut impact survey (layoffs) by local; document re BOCES reform legislation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link251">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1993">1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from Costello to legislative director Ray Skuse reporting on strategy session at UFT re governance, capital improvements, school aid, violence, and pension issues, December 16, 1993; memo from Costello to Skuse discussing state aid to NYC schools, December 13, 1993; notes from meeting of Special Act school local presidents, November 30, 1993; memo re school-related personnel issues, November 12, 1993; letter to members from NYSUT president and executive vice president, opposing secession of Staten Island from NYC, October 25, 1993; letter to members urging vote for Jim Florio in New Jersey gubernatorial election, October 25; information re retirement issues; other chronological correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link252">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1991">1991</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re phone banks (rental) from Democratic State Committee, endorsement procedures, meeting of Special Act local presidents, salary issues for 4201 schools; policy papers re tax reform, teacher centers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link253">Bozzella, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1989">1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to UFT president Sandy Feldman from assistant director for NYC John Bozzella re talking points for legislative breakfast, February 1, 1988; text of proposed legislation; memorandum of support re proposed legislation to allow retired NYC police and firefighters who become teachers to opt for NYC Teachers Retirement System</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link254">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence re Assembly hearing on small (Hurd) cities and budget vote, October 16, retiree health insurance, resolutions for NYSUT Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link255">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1988/1989">1988-1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of key NYSUT program and support bills approved since August 29, 1988; memo from Costello to legislative director Ray Skuse re Hurd (small city) school aid formula and budget vote question, March 3, 1989; outline for remarks at health insurance hearing; summary of Coalition Finance Committee meeting, January 9, 1989; discussion of Yonkers Emergency Financial Control Board impact on collective bargaining, April 12, 1989; memo re 1989 Representative Assembly resolutions; draft text for VOTE/COPE brochures</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link256">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to Ray Skuse re conversations with Senate and Assembly Education Committee staff, April 6; letter to Sen. Daniel Patrick Moynihan, indicating NYSUT endorsement of candidacy, August 15; letters to member re endorsements by NYSUT Board of Directors; legislative updates, including summary of meeting re NYC legislative concerns, November 7; letter to legislators, urging substantial increase in state aid to education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link257">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Background information re Hurd (small city schools) bills of interest; memo re NYSUT's legislative goals for 1987; memos to Retirees' Organizing Committee (ROC) re Supplemental Pension Bill, health insurance, and related legislation; memo to Ray Skuse re support activities for Committee of 100 lobbying, February 26; invoices to treasurers of various candidate election committees for phone bank use; memos re Public Employee Conference legislative breakfast</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link258">Costello, John</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials re Hurd (small city) school aid; correspondence with Retirees' Organizing Committee (ROC) re pharmaceutical assistance program; other monthly legislative updates to ROC; agreement on the use of telephone bank for political calls; phone bank script; letter to members urging vote to re-elect Assembly member Nick Spano; list of names and addresses of Board of Regents; outline of legislative program for 1986; memos to NYSUT Executive Committee re 1986-87 Executive Budget, state aid proposal; UFT requests re state aid 1985-86; list of status of bills (passed Assembly only, passed Senate only, passed both), December 11, 1985; suggestions by Costello to legislative staff for amendment language to legislation re students with handicapping conditions, December 6, 1985; memos by Costello re school bus safety legislation, special education reform, revenue sharing, teacher salaries; flyers re Democratic presidential primary candidates, "Walter Mondale on the Issues," "A Closer
      Look at Hart's Record"; Assembly Republican White Paper Summary</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link259">Frantz, Ronald</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Updates on Congressional District liaison activities; evaluation of Wharton School management training program; memos re salary legislation for 4201 schools; description of VOTE/COPE award criteria; list of VOTE/COPE contributions by service center 1980-86; memo re VOTE/COPE retiree project; agenda for VOTE/COPE coordinators meeting, November 6; draft letter to local presidents urging support for VOTE/COPE; memo and information re NYS presidential primary; memo re legislation affecting Special Act schools; list of NY members of Congress, noting party affiliation and whether endorsed by NYSUT, with major locals, ED directors, and VOTE/COPE members in district; list of names and addresses of members of Political Action Committee; list of pending bills in Senate and Assembly, status, and NYSUT position; memo to Sen. Tarky Lombardi with attached language of bill re provision of psychological services in schools, urging that he reintroduce it, March 12</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link260">Frantz, Ronald</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Lists of VOTE/COPE contributions by service center; related correspondence with locals and individuals; document, "Conducting a Successful VOTE/COPE Campaign"; description of Legislative Department; memo to NYSUT legal counsel expressing concern over liability for bus drivers in proposed legislation requiring use of seat belts by students in school buses, May 21, 1986; related correspondence, December 18, 1984; list of VOTE/COPE regional coordinators, with recommendations for reappointment or replacement, January 27, 1986; background information for Special Act (institutional) schools meeting, December 4, 1984; related correspondence; list of NYSUT top priority items for 1985 legislative session, October 2, 1984; 1984 Legislative Agenda for NYSUT's SRP [school-related personnel] Members; correspondence re voter registration drive</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link261">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Final document for legislators, "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity"; NYSUT proposed legislation for supplemental retirement allowance, April 18; update on supplemental pension bills, August 18; list of bills of interest that passed both houses, August; memos re Employees' Retirement System consultant training</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link262">Lewis, Alan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1995 Bills of Interest Passed Both Houses as of July 6; memo re implementation of resolutions passed at 1995 Representative Assembly and referred to Legislative Department, August 17; materials re early retirement incentive, supplemental pensions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link263">Kafka, Emanuel</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1988/1989">1988-1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Federal Legislative Highlights, first session, 101st Congress, 1989; legislative priorities of NYSUT and AFT in the 101st Congress; Federal Legislative Report; memo from Kafka to legislative director Ray Skuse re new state legislative program items, January 18, 1989; memo re lobbying results against the comprehensive child care bill, October 11, 1989; report on congressional legislative reception, March 22, 1989</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link264">Kafka, Emanuel</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of votes by individual members of Congress on key issues; resolutions by 1988 NYSUT Representative Assembly, with draft cover letter to AFT director of legislation, urging support; memo re key AFL-CIO legislative issues in 1988, with attached voting record of NY congressional delegation; results of phone bank in Nassau and Suffolk counties re Dukakis/Bush presidential race, November 2, 1988; items included in U.S. Senate 1987-88 voting record; list of NY congressional candidates, indicating NYSUT endorsement status, November 1, 1988; list, "Items from the Republican Platform that May be Unjurious to Our Members"; memo from Kafka to Skuse, "Bills I Recommend That We Try to Achieve This Year," May 1, 1988</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link265">Kafka, Emanuel</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re AFL-CIO meeting with representatives of candidates for Democratic nomination for president, December 7, 1987; instructions for obtaining signatures for candidate designating petitions; NYSUT resolutions re federal legislation, with cover letter to AFT Director of Legislation, November 3, 1987; summary of delegate selection process for Democratic nomination; memo detailing proposed expansion of catastrophic coverage by Medicare by House Ways and Means Committee, April 23, 1987</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link266">Kafka, Emanuel</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of 1986 "Invisible Victories," harmful state legislation successfully blocked by NYSUT; Selected Items from the 1986 Tax Reform Act re Teacher Pensions; 1986 Tax Reform Act and How It Affects Teachers; voting record of Senate and House members for 1985, as reported by AFL-CIO; memo from Kafka reporting lack of cooperation by some members in response to request to make phone calls for Guy Velella special election, April 30, 1986; letters from Kafka to individual members of Congress re tax-deferred annuity retirement plans, November 6, 1985; memo from Kafka to NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese summarizing legislative accomplishments affecting BOCES, October 17, 1985; memo from Kafka re Special Education Reform Act of 1985; other memos evaluating aspects of wide range of issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link267">Hartnell, Jeff</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Lists of towns by NYS congressional, Senate, and Assembly district</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link268">Kafka, Emanuel-Clinton Health Care</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials re Clinton health care plan; list of members of NY congressional delegation, with contact information; Federal Legislative Highlights, second session, 101st Congress, 1990</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">8</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link269">Gigi Georges</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1992">1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to Ray Skuse re priority pension items for 1992 session; statement of opposition to proposed grant program that would redirect funds from public to private schools; faxed document to Skuse, UFT legislative program and support bills that have been signed into law</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link270">Ron Frantz</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Chronological correspondence file of assistant to executive vice president re phone bank operation, pre-RA planning, VOTE/COPE material preparation, status of voter registration project; notes from board/manager retreat of September 19, 1988; report of VOTE/COPE activities at 1988 Representative Assembly; RA resolutions; report on Coalition for Economic Priorities Steering Committee meeting, March 8, 1989; letter of resignation, June 6, 1989</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link271">Read File A-L</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link272">Read File M-Z</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link273">Read File A-I</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link274">Read File J-M</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link275">Read File Mc-R</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link276">Read File S-W</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link277">Read File XYZ</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link278">Read File A-E</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link279">Read File F-K</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link280">Read File L-Q</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link281">Read File R-Z</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link282">Read File A-F</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link283">Read File G-K</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link284">Read File L-N</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link285">Read File O-S</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link286">Read File T-Z</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link287">Read File A-L</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">9</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link288">Read File M-Z</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link289">Read File A-E</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link290">Read File F-L</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link291">Read File M</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link292">Read File N-Z</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link293">Read File A-L</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link294">Read File M-Z</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence, alphabetical by recipient</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link295">John Costello Chronological Files</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outgoing correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link296">Representative Assembly Box Labels</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>RA inventory sheet; instructions; labels</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link297">RA Agenda</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>To-do list; agenda; Local Presidents' Conference agenda; memos re reception for NYS congressional delegation, Executive Committee meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link298">RA Travel Assignments</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re housing and travel accommodations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link299">RA Floor Plan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Convention hall floor plan; list of key staff telephone numbers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link300">RA Invites</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to NYS elected officials, inviting them to speak</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link301">RA Print Orders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Print orders for postcards to elected representatives, and other materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link302">RA Proposed Constitution Amendments and Resolutions (1 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of resolutions and assigned departments for implementation; booklet, Implementation of Actions by the 2003 Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link303">RA Proposed Constitution Amendments and Resolutions (2 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of resolutions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link304">RA PAC Center</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Application for display space for Political Action Center at 2003 Representative Assembly; related memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link305">RA VOTE/COPE</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of locals qualifying for awards based on levels of contribution per member; letters from NYSUT secretary-treasurer Alan Lubin to VOTE/COPE members re Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link306">RA Intros and Speeches</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of speech (unattributed), "March on Albany: Find a Way"; text of introductions of speakers (Sen. Charles Schumer, Gov. Howard Dean, Sen. John Edwards, Sen. John Kerry, Sen. Hillary Rodham Clinton, Rep. Richard Gephart); draft of speech by NYSUT president Tom Hobart; video production directions; Power Point presentation printouts; CD-ROMS and diskette</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link307">RA Other</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invoice for computer giveaway; Preview newsletter for Representative Assembly; web pages announcing convention and agenda; e-mail memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link308">RA Convention Materials Mailed</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets, RA Resolutions Due to Expire in 2003; Convention Call; Local Presidents' Conference; Constitution and Bylaws effective April 2002; Delegate and Alternate Bulletin, February 19, 2003, and March 12, 2002; program; memo re delegate mailings</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link309">RA Invites</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters of invitation to elected officials to speak at convention; tentative program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link310">RA Letters</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative program; proposed deadlines and policies; letter from president Hobart to Election District directors requesting credentials committee nominations, September 5, 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link311">RA Print Orders (1 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Print orders for Kerry flyers and other materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link312">RA Print Orders (2 of 2)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of resolutions by various committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link313">RA Solidarity Event (Rally)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link314">RA VOTE/COPE</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of VOTE/COPE coordinators attending Representative Assembly; facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link315">RA PAC Center</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters from executive vice president Alan Lubin, thanking members for staffing Political Action Center; form letters for faxing to federal and state elected officials on a wide range of issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link316">RA Intros and Speeches</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of speech by Alan Lubin, "Together We Can Do Anything"; bullet points for retiree luncheon, re Medicare; Power Point presentation printouts; diskette</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link317">RA Local Presidents' Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitator's questions for workshop, Political Mobilization for 2004 Elections; text of speech by John Costello; list of staff attending workshops; materials for Local Presidents' Conference binders, re Kerry and Bush, including questions and answers re AFT endorsement of Kerry; print request orders</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link318">RA Other</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Newsletter, RA Reporter; revised RA Team meeting agenda, January 4; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link319">RA Convention Materials Mailed</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets, Convention Call, Local Presidents' Conference, Constituency Awards: Call for Nominations, 2004 Community Service Awards, Resolutions Due to Expire in 2004; NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws effective April 2003, Retiree Council Presidents' Conference; camera-ready mockup of conference logo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link320">RA Agenda Information</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Representative Assembly program; Convention Call; program for Pre-Representative Assembly Local Presidents' Conference; action items</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link321">RA Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters of invitation to elected officials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link322">RA Give-Aways</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to director of state affairs for Sen. Chuck Schumer, asking permission to use Schumer's likeness on a coin for distribution at reception at Representative Assembly, February 25; memo indicating that a fundraising raffle was illegal in NYS</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">10</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link323">RA Memos</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of Democratic officials invited to presentation of Distinguished Service Award to Hillary Clinton; recap of discussion at video planning meeting, December 10, 1998; list of responses by political leaders invited to attend Representative Assembly; memo from NYSUT Office of General Counsel re legality of raffles, February 19, 1999; memo from counsel re use of public officials' image on coins, February 19, 1999; facultative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link324">RA Floor Plan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Layout of Niagara Falls Convention Center main floor and foyer</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link325">RA-Other</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Notes for speech by Alan Lubin; checklists; newspaper clipping re First Lady Hillary Clinton and Rep. Nita Lowy, speculation on Senate run; Thursday proceedings newsletter, featuring Hillary Clinton; NYSUT Constitution, effective May 1998</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link326">RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of proposed NYSUT constitutional amendments and resolutions arranged by committee</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link327">RA Agenda Information</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative program for Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link328">RA Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart, thanking VOTE/COPE and Political Action Committee coordinators, noting gift of jacket</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link329">RA Floor Plan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Floor plan for NY Hilton convention area</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link330">RA Give-Aways</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart, thanking VOTE/COPE and Political Action Committee coordinators, noting gift of jacket</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link331">RA Invites</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters of invitation from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to elected officials to attend or speak at Representative Assembly; thank-you letters from Lubin to staff who operated Political Action Center</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link332">RA Memos</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re assignments and daily staff functions, last-minute details; daily convention summaries; delegate survey; agendas; housing information</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link333">RA Other</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative staff list; invitation list of elected officials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link334">RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Working draft, Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions; blank forms for proposed resolutions and constitutional amendments; NYSUT Constitution, effective April 1999</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link335">RA Agenda</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agendas and staff assignments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link336">RA Delegate Bulletins</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link337">RA Emails</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Staff list; correspondence re housing and transportation logistics, memorabilia, signage, and decorations, CWA staff overtime</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link338">RA Invites</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Lists of invited guests (confirmed, declined, no reply); letters of invitation to elected officials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link339">RA Letters</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Form letter soliciting volunteers for Political Action Center, with attached list; letter to Office of the State Comptroller re anticipated remarks to RA, giving background on NYSUT and current issues of concern</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link340">RA Memos</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re display space, with attached application form; memo re political action video</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link341">RA Print Orders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Print order requests for letters and postcards to elected representatives</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link342">RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Working draft, Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link343">RA VOTE/COPE Shirts</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters informing locals that they qualified for shirts, based on contributions; invoice</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link344">RA Other</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT 2001 Representative Assembly Follow-Up Survey Report; tentative program; convention floor plan</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link345">RA Agenda</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; pocket program; flyer invitation to Legislative Department staff reception; staff assignments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link346">RA Delegate Bulletins</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Saturday summary of proceedings</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link347">RA Emails</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link348">RA Floor Plan</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Hilton convention floor plans</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link349">RA Invites</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of introductions for political officials, noting contributions to education; staff writing assignments; letters of invitation to elected officials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link350">RA Letters</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Form letter soliciting volunteers for Political Action Center, with attached list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link351">RA Print Orders</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Print order requests for postcards to elected representatives re Medicare</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link352">RA Proposed Constitutional Amendments and Resolutions</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Revised constitution, with cover letter to NYSUT Board of Directors from president Tom Hobart; text of adopted and referred resolutions, organized by assigned committees for implementation; NYSUT Constitution, effective May 2001; RA Resolutions due to expire in 2002; convention call; program for Pre-RA Local Presidents' Conference; Delegate and Alternate Bulletin</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link353">RA Other</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of convention speech by Alan Lubin; text of speech for retiree luncheon; list of VOTE/COPE regional campaign coordinators; list of locals qualifying for awards based on contributions; text of introductions for political officials; memos re special event featuring entertainment by comedy troupe Capitol Steps; facilitative correspondence, noting heightened security at Hilton</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link354">15th New Local Presidents' Conference-Participants' Handbook- Monday</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Research and Educational Services Resource Guide on CD; Local Leaders' Guide 2005-2006; Participants' Handbook for 15th New Local Presidents' Conference; A Guide to Field and Legal Services; Guide to Program Services; materials for general sessions; NYSUT Mission Statement</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link355">15th New Local Presidents' Conference-Participants' Handbook-Tuesday</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws, effective April 2005; AFT 2004 Constitution and Bylaws; description of NYSUT Benefit Trust; materials for general sessions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">11</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link356">15th New Local Presidents' Conference-Participants' Handbook-Wednesday</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Making the News, Framing the Message: A NYSUT Local Leaders Guide to Handling the News Media; 2005 Legislative Program; list of members of Political Action Committee; brochure, When Everything Seems Stacked Against Us, VOTE-COPE Tips the Scales; VOTE-COPE Instruction Manual</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link357">Lubin Calendar</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 2001-November 2001</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link358">Lubin Calendar</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2001/2002">2001-2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>December 2001-December 2002</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link359">Lubin Calendar</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>January 2003-December 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link360">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link361">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link362">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link363">Vote/Cope</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link364">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Thank-you letters from Alan Lubin to individual managers for contributions to VOTE/COPE; copies of paycheck deduction authorization forms; bullet points for Board Report 3/12/99 re Report of Task Force on Minority Involvement in NYSUT and Affiliated Locals and other items</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link365">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link366">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; letter to managers advising them that payroll deduction was now available for contributions to VOTE/COPE; list of managers contributing through payroll deduction, and those not participating; VOTE/COPE financial statements; letter from NYSUT general counsel to accounting firm Buchbinder Tunick and Co.</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">12</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link367">Vote/Cope Managers' Drive</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; lists of those who contributed and had not yet contributed</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link368">Vote/Cope Managers' Campaign</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1995">1995</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; status of number contributing, noting average contribution; reminder memos; letter to Lubin from AFT political director, noting contribution to VOTE/COPE, with attached copy of check, March 1, 1996</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link369">Vote/Cope Letters</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to managers from Alan Lubin, encouraging them to donate to VOTE/COPE; reminder memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link370">Community School Board Reform Bill Draft</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of draft legislation; Assembly version</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link371">Walk Through Memo, Weingarten Memo</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1994">1994</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from Randi Weingarten to Ray Skuse summarizing Community School Board Reform legislation; walk-through memorandum with section-by-section summary of amendments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link372">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1976/1979">1976-1979</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Spiral-bound booklets for NYSUT legislative agenda, April 20, 1976, January 24, 1976, March 22, 1978, April 5, 1979</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link373">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1980/1984">1980-1984</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT legislative programs</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link374">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1977/1979">1977-1979</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Preliminary and updated NYSUT legislative programs, including bills applicable to United University Professions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">13</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link375">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1973/1977">1973-1977</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative and updated NYSUT legislative programs, including bills applicable to Professional Staff Congress of CUNY, 1977</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link376">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1987/1988">1987-1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative and final NYSUT legislative programs and related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link377">Legislative Program Original</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1987">1987</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT legislative program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link378">Legislative Material NYSUT New Local Presidents Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1984">1984</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Political Action Committee Guidelines for Political Endorsements for NYSUT; brochure explaining VOTE/COPE; Campaign '84 Instruction Booklet; suggested payroll deduction plan; 1984 Legislative Report and Previous Accomplishments; 1984 Legislative Program; position paper, "NYSUT's Triborough Legislation: Why It Is Necessary," May 1982; NYS School Boards Association press release, "Early Retirement Bill Would Worsen Teacher Shortage," June 15, 1984; text of early retirement legislation; "Invisible Victories: Bills Held by the Legislature Due to Efforts of NYSUT"; NYSUT memoranda of support or opposition</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link379">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1991/1992">1991-1992</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets, "The Impact of Executive Proposals on State Aid to Public Education 1991-92"; "1991 NYSUT Legislative Program for Pension Equity"; "Delegate Selection Process: Campaign '92"; "1992 Summary of New Legislation Affecting Education"; NYSUT 1991 Legislative Program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link380">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1991/1993">1991-1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>1991 Annual Report of the New York State Senate Standing Committee on Education; NYSUT booklet, "Delegate Selection Process: Campaign '92"; "Teacher Resource and Computer Training Centers Located in the Districts of Assembly Ways and Means Committee Members and Senate Finance Committee Members"; NYSUT Committee of 100 Pension, Retirement and Labor Issues, May 17- 18, 1993; "AFT and NYSUT Support: FY 93 Chapter 1 Supplemental Appropriations, Chapter 1 Reauthorization Issues, Comprehensive Health Care Reform Package"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link381">Legislative Programs</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1991/1993">1991-1993</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Legislative Program and Support Bills Signed into Law, 1991 and 1992; NYSUT's Major Legislative Program and Support Bills 1993 Final Report; NYSUT Committee of 100 Pension and Retirement Issues, May 18-19, 1992; NYSUT Legislative Program 1992; NYSUT 1993 Legislative Program; Personal Income Tax Reform: A NYSUT Proposal; Executive Budget Recommendations 1993-94: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges; 1993 Summary of New Legislation Affecting Education, State Education Department; Higher Education Budget Restoration Recommendations 1994-95: SUNY, CUNY, Community Colleges</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">14</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link382">Legislative Reports to Board</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1988/1990">1988-1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Legislative updates to NYSUT Board of Directors and Executive Committee re governor's state aid proposal re K-12, key bills, presidential election telephone calling update</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link383">Legislative Reports to Board</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1985/1988">1985-1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Executive vice president's reports; notes for Executive Committee meetings re governor's state of the state message, election of Regents, small city school district (Hurd) state aid, tuition tax credits, delegates to Democratic National Convention</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link384">Voter Registration Packet</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1988">1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Voter registration forms; instructions; booklet; question and answer sheet; roster of county boards of election; description of Federal Election Commission and regulations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link385">Photographs</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Black and white photos of NYSUT officials with governor Hugh Carey, Senate Majority Leader Ralph Marino, other state elected officials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link386">FNHP Lobby Days</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2000/2004">2000-2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials for Federation of Nurses and Health Professionals Lobby Day 2000: Lists of members of Assembly and state Senate, with office numbers; list of members of legislative health and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; debriefing form (reporting on results of individual visits with legislators); NYSUT/FNHP handbook, "What Every Health Care Processional Should Know"; FNHP Policy Statements on the Use of Unlicensed Assistive Personnel, on the Definition of Safe Health Care Staffing Levels, on School Nurse Staffing Levels; NYSUT/FNHP Lobby Day statements supporting Legislation to Allow Registered Nurses to Honor Non-Hospital Do Not Resuscitate Orders, and Legislation to Enact NYS Whistle Blower Protection for Health Care Workers; Memoranda in Support of various bills; cards reminding lobbyists to ask for action on specific legislation; materials for FNHP Lobby Day 2002: text of legislation; materials for 2004 re ending mandatory overtime, other legislative
      issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link387">Teacher Center Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1997/1998">1997-1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agendas for Teacher Center Lobby Day; Rogers' Pocket Directory: Your Guide to the NYS Senate, Assembly, Members of Congress, 1998 edition; testimony of NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to legislative finance committees re 1998-99 Executive Budget recommendations for education; bullet points re Teacher Centers; related materials; invoices</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link388">Retiree Lobby Days</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1997/1998">1997-1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Briefing booklet, Tier Equity and Pension Improvement Lobby Day, June 4, 1997; lists of members of Assembly and Senate; briefing book for 1998; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">15</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link389">Political Action Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Workshop agenda; booklet, "Talking about: NYSUT's Positions on the Issues: A Series of Talking Points on Topics of Concern"; local union information sheet (form)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link390">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1997/2002">1997-2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agendas; lists of members of Assembly and Senate; lists of members of finance and education committees; testimonies of NYSUT and United University Professions officials to legislative finance committee hearings; letters of invitation to community college local presidents; (missing 1999 and 2001)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link391">NYSUT Materials</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1987/1988">1987-1988</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets, "Campaign '88: November 12-14 Congressional District Liaison Conference," "Education. The State of Excellence: CUNY State Aid 1988-89," "SUNY State Aid 1988-89," "K-12 State Aid 1988-89"; legislative memoranda of support for various bills; flyers/print ads; opposition advertisements and legislative bulletins by NYS School Boards Association; letter to legislators from NYSUT executive vice president Herb Magidson</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link392">New Local Presidents' Conference</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; NYSUT briefing booklets, "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity: Long Overdue, 1990," "Major Legislation of Interest: Higher Education and Health Care Professionals, 1989," NYUST 1990 Legislative Program," "NYSUT Focus on K-12 1989," "NYSUT's Committee of 100: SUNY, CUNY, and the Community Colleges, March 5-6, 1990-91" "K-12 State Aid 1990-91"; 1990 VOTE/COPE Instruction Booklet; VOTE/COPE general brochure; NYSUT brochure encouraging registration and voting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link393">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on K-12, UFT (NYC), SUNY, CUNY, and SUNY community colleges; memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link394">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on retirement, K-12 and NYC, higher education, health care professionals, and labor; memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link395">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on K-12, UFT (NYC), SUNY, CUNY, SUNY community colleges, and health care; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; flyers, March for Public Education; assembled packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link396">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for June Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on retirement, K-12 and NYC, higher education, health care professionals, and labor; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">16</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link397">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on UFT NYC, SUNY, CUNY, and SUNY community colleges; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; reporting forms for feedback on reactions of individual legislators; assembled packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link398">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March lobby Day; briefing book re K-12, NYC budget priorities, and higher education; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; reporting forms for feedback on reactions of individual legislators</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link399">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing book K-12, NYC budget priorities, and higher education; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link400">NYSUT Committee of 100 (C100)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing book re K-12, NYC, higher education, and health care; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link401">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing book re K-12 and higher education; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link402">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1998/2001">1998-2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Briefing books for Lobby Day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link403">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1996/2000">1996-2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Briefing books for Lobby Day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link404">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for June Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; fact sheets on retirement, K-12, higher education, health care professionals, and labor; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; letter from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to state legislators; assembled packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link405">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">17</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link406">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link407">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link408">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link409">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for May Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education, governmental employees, civil service and pension, and finance committees; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link410">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate, and education and finance committees; tip sheet on effective lobbying; briefing book; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link411">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1984">1984</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for February Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; NYSUT Proposal for State Aid and Education Reform in New York State 1984-85; Tuition Tax Credit and Deduction Fact Sheet; Statement of Albert Shanker, President, United Federation of Teachers, before a Legislative Hearing of the NYS Standing Committee on Education, February 10, 1984; list of members of Committee of 100</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link412">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1985">1985</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; briefing book, "1985-86 Public Schools State Aid Proposals: NYSUT/ECB and Executive Budget"; NYSUT legislative memoranda of support or opposition; brochure by NYS Educational Conference Board, 1985 State Aid Proposal</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link413">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1986">1986</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; NYSUT legislative memoranda of support; NYSUT 1986 Legislative Program; NYSUT 1985 Legislative Report; briefing book, "Teacher Salary Aid Proposal"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link414">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1989">1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate and finance committees; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; print ads/flyers; briefing books on K-12 state aid, SUNY and CUNY; fact sheets on community colleges</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link415">Higher Education Lobby Day</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1989">1989</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for February Lobby Day; list of members of Assembly and Senate and higher education committees; reporting form for feedback on individual legislators' reactions; print ads/flyers; briefing book re SUNY and CUNY; related notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">18</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link416">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Lists of new state legislators, members of Assembly and Senate finance committees; print ads/flyers; briefing books re SUNY, CUNY, and community colleges and K-12 state aid</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">19</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link417">NYSUT Committee of 100</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1990">1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for March Lobby Day; briefing books, "Higher Education Issues," "NYSUT Program for Pension Equity: Long Overdue 1990"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">19</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link418">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets, NYSUT Endorsements, Endorsement Recommendations (NYS Assembly, U.S. Congress); memos; letter to local presidents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">19</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link419">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; NYSUT Policy on Endorsements; NYSUT booklets, "Congressional Voting Record, 2003-04," "Brief Description of Bills Used for Voting Records, U.S. Congress," "NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, U.S. Congress," "NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, NYS Senate," "NYSUT Endorsement Recommendations, NYS Assembly," "NYS Assembly Voting Record," 2003 and 2004; "NYS Assembly Background Information," "NYS Senate Voting Record" 2003 and 2004; "NYS Senate Background Information"; "NYS Assembly 2003 Veto Overrides for Public Education"; overrides by Senate; NYSUT campaign flyers for John Kerry for president</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">19</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link420">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets re endorsement recommendations for NYSUT Presidents' Conference and Executive Committee/Board of Directors for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates, voting records, descriptions of bills</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">19</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link421">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets re endorsement recommendations for NYSUT Presidents' Conference and Executive Committee/Board of Directors for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates, voting records, descriptions of bills</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">20</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link422">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets re endorsement recommendations for NYSUT Presidents' Conference and Executive Committee/Board of Directors for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates, voting records, descriptions of bills</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">20</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link423">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1998">1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets re NYSUT endorsement recommendations for congressional and Assembly candidates, voting records, descriptions of bills</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">20</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link424">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets re background information for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates (voting records, descriptions of bills)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">20</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link425">NYSUT Endorsements</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1996">1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklets re NYSUT endorsement recommendations for congressional, NYS Senate, and Assembly candidates; phone script for member survey re presidential candidate preference; phone script for calls urging support for congressional, state Senate, and Assembly candidates; "Clinton to Educate All of America" bumper sticker and button, with NYSUT logo; fact sheet comparing Dole and Clinton records; memo from Alan Lubin to regional staff directors re fall election activities; lists of Political Action Committee members who attended and who did not attend endorsement conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>
