<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
 <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
  <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05584::National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers.)//EN">KCL05584</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation
     on Black Workers<date> 1916-1943</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation
     on Black Workers</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
     Library</publisher>
    <date>June 05, 2019</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>June 05,
     2019</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation
    on Black Workers</titleproper>
   <num>Collection Number: 5584</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
    Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood
      Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
      <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, September 20, 2012</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Randall Miles, June 05, 2019</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
    University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   
   <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">National Archives and Records Service
    Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers, 1916-
     1943
   </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1916-
     1943</unitdate>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">5584</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">National Archives and Records
     Service</corpname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">15 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents).</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
    Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">These are facsimile documents gathered by Professors James Gross and
    Cletus Daniel for their esearch project on Black Workers. These records were selected from many
    others and in each case by no means represent the complete series held by the National Archives.
    Researchers wishing to pursue further study in a particular series are advised to obtain the
    relevant series number (such numbers are stamped on the back of each document) and refer to it
    when attempting to locate the series at NARS. Use of this collection is restricted to term paper
    references for Cornell undergraduates until otherwise specified.</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  <physdesc><extent>15 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
  
  <controlaccess>
   
   <controlaccess>
    
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. National Archives and Records Service.
    </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   
   <controlaccess>
    
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">African Americans -- History -- Sources </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  
  <descgrp>
   
   <accessrestrict>
    
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference
     archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and
     Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    
    <p>National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers #5584.
     Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  
  <relatedmaterial>
   
   <p>Related Collections:
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05584a.html"> 5584 A: National
     Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black
     Workers</extref>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05584mf.html"> 5584 mf: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black
     Workers on Microfilm</extref>
   </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link8">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link9">National Recovery Administration. Labor Advisory Board
       (NRA-LAB)</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes 9 page mimeo entitled, "The NRA and the Negro Worker," by Gustov Peck;
       Correspondence re request of investigation into treatment and living and labor conditions of
       farm laborers in the Sugar Belt of Louisiana; Requests for changes in codes; re reasons for
       North and South wage differentials; re question of Negro representation on Advisory Board; re
       codes for lumber and timber industry, statement (10 pages) of Negro Industrial League
       concerning the affect of Negro labor</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link10">NRA-LAB - Subject File of "Negro Displacement" -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence with Matthew F. Boyd, Assistant Labor Advisor of the Board re the
       displacement of Negroes under the NRA in various localities; 7 page mimeo "Conclusions from
       Survey in Alabama of the Effect of the Operations of the NRA Code on Negro Labor;" 6 page
       mimeo, "A Study of the Position of Negro Workers Under the National Industrial Recovery Act;"
       "The Subnormal Negro and the Subnormal Code."</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link11">NRA-LAB - Subject File - "Negro Labor" -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence with Rose Schneiderman, member, Labor Advisory Board and others re Negro
       representative to be placed on the Board; wages of Negroes in various industries;
       discrimination against Negroes in unions</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link12">NRA-LAB - "Negro Labor" -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re the displacement of Negroes due to the payment of code wages and hours;
       "Statement of the Negro Industrial League concerning the Code of Fair Competition for the
       Cotton Textile Industry"</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link13">NRA-LAB - "Regional Differentials"</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re the wage differentials between Black and white laborers</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link14">NRA-LAB - "Southern" -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re skilled and unskilled labor in the south; 3 page mimeo "Objection to
       Minimum Wage Discrimination Against Negro Workers," by General Secretary of the National
       Consumer's League</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link15">NRA-LAB</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re wage differentials (regional and racial); code definition of gin workers;
       request for exemptions under the code</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link16">NRA - General -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1943" type="inclusive">1934-1943</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>7 page mimeo "Excerpts from the Statement of John P. Davis, Given at the Hearing on
       Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair Competition on February 2, 1935;"
       Differentials-geographic; several pages of testimony re strike situation at Packard Motor
       Company because of race issue</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link17">NRA - Report -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes "Report of the Agriculture Committee of the Inter-Departmental Group Concerned
       with the Special Problem of Negroes, May 1934," 16 pages</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link18">NRA - Miscellaneous Minutes -</unittitle>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes minutes of meetings of the Inter-Departmental Group concerned with the special
       problems of Negroes, March 2, 30, 1934; b) This section contains general correspondence of
       A.R. Forbush, Chief Correspondence Division, NRA (and others) filed in alphabetical order -
       Includes appeal letters and documents for economic relief re unfair conditions</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link19">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link20">A -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from Black and white individuals, organization, American Legion, AME Church,
       Mason Telegraph, to Franklin D. Roosevelt, General Hugh Johnson and NRA requesting emergency
       relief from economic conditions, racial discrimination, displacement of Black workers due to
       minimum wage, alleged code violation, general population, coal, railroad, cotton industry,
       and requesting appointment of Blacks to NRA-LAB. Replies by Forbush and other officials in
       the agency.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link21">American Consolidated Trades Council -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1933" type="inclusive">1926-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from Chicago Colored Plumbers Protective Association, predecessor to
       American Consolidated Trades Council, a Black building trades association, to United
       Association of Journeyman Plumbers and Steam Fitters. President John Coefield, Building
       Committee Provident Hospital and Training School; President M.J. McDonough, Building Trades
       Department, AFL; Chicago Federation of Labor; Frances Perkins, Secretary of Labor seeking end
       to racial discrimination in building trades with negative results.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link22">B</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932/1935" type="inclusive">1932-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from Black clergy and the Baptist Minister's Conference of New York
       requesting FDR, General Johnson, NRA provide emergency relief from economic conditions,
       racial discrimination, displacement of Black workers due to increase minimum wage, alleged
       code violation, in general, domestics, building trades and requests for appointment of Blacks
       to the NRA-LAB.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link23">C</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence with Senator Capper of Kansas and organizations such as the Churches of
       Christ, Citizens Taxpayer's Association, Coopers Curtain's Draperies and Linens, Urban League
       and NAACP of Kansas to General Johnson, FDR and NRA for emergency relief from adverse
       economic conditions, racial discrimination, wages displacement of Back workers due to
       increase in minimum wage, alleged code violation and for appointment of Black to NRA-LAB.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link24">D</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence by worker in Charleston, S.C. regarding exploitation of white and Black
       workers by Planters Fertilizer Company through wage cuts of 35 and 50 percent despite rise of
       sale price and urging General Hugh Johnson to correct this situation; also from other
       individuals and organizations: Delta Sigma Theta Sorority, Dutchess County Department of
       Child Welfare, Dallas Negro Chamber of Commerce to FDR, General Hugh Johnson, NRA, requesting
       relief from economic conditions, displacement due to minimum wage increase, alleged codes of
       fair practices violations in steel, railroads, brick works, AFL, and for appointment of
       Blacks to LAB and Consumer Advisory Board.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link25">E</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from individuals and organizations, Urban League sponsored Emergency
       Advisory Council of Tampa, Trenton and Atlanta, relief from economic conditions, racial
       discriminations and for appointment of Black to NRA-LAB.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link26">F</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from individuals requesting relief from economic conditions; letter from
       merchant requesting investigation of unfair labor practices of planters and farmers in St.
       Mary's Parish, Louisiana for forced trade at employer owned stores, use of merchandise as
       wage substitute practice formerly used exclusively against Blacks, threatens independent
       merchants. Response as to legality of practice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link27">G</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence from individuals requesting relief from economic conditions; letter to
       General Hugh Johnson from Black steel worker and former policeman in Gary, Indiana, describes
       economic conditions, warning of communist.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link28">H-I</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1935" type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from individuals requesting relief from economic conditions; from
       organizations - Industrial Council of Los Angeles; Insurance Agents Relief Association of
       Baltimore; Interdenominational Ministerial Alliance of Kansas City and the Iroquois
       Democratic Club of Rochester.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link29">J</unittitle>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from Joint Committee for National Recovery; Baptist clergyman; Congressman
       Oscar DePriest to FDR, General Hugh Johnson, NRA for relief from economic conditions and
       protesting dismissal of Black administrator, Mabel J. Byrd and payment of veterans
       benefits.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link30">K</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from individuals and organizations including Kansas State Association of
       Colored Women requesting relief from economic conditions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link31">L</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from Laboring men's Protective Association to General Johnson and reply;
       cites racial discrimination and request for appointment of Black to NRA.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link32">M</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence requesting relief from economic conditions in fertilizer, tobacco, laundry
       and cleaning, and agricultural industries</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link33">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link34">N</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from individuals and organizations - National Association of Colored Women,
       National Council of World War Vets, Negro Industrial League, National Technical Association
       to FDR, General Johnson, NRA, citing economic conditions, racial discrimination in employment
       and wages, displacement of Black workers by whites, alleged code violations, requesting
       Federal intervention.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link35">National Association for the Advancement of Colored People
       (NAACP)</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re displacement of Negroes under NRA codes; 19 page mimeo, "NAACP, 1932,
       23rd Annual Report;" requests for exemptions; 3 page telegram to President Roosevelt from
       Wilkins re discrimination with codes; requests for appointments of Blacks to NRA-LAB</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link36">National Consumers League</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence citing Black worker displacement by whites in Atlanta, Georgia area; also
       minimum wage, discrimination, exemptions of apprenticeships and unskilled laborers from Code
       of Fair Practice; for appointment of Black to NRA-LAB.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link37">National Urban League</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence to NRA and Frances Perkins supporting uni-level wage plans for establishment
       of Emergency Advisory Councils; to Sidney Hillman, Labor Advisory Board citing racial
       discrimination, Code of Fair Competition violation by Scripto Manufacturing Company of
       Atlanta, memo from the company explaining that due to Black worker inefficiency they are to
       be paid less than white workers, also warns of possible job displacement.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link38">P</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence from individuals and Philadelphia Tribune citing economic conditions, racial
       discrimination in employment and wages displacement of Black workers, code violations,
       requesting Federal alleviation by General Johnson, NRA-LAB. (33-? Second date cut off)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link39">Pullman Company</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1933" type="inclusive">1926-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>U.S. Board of Mediation, case documents - Pullman Company vs. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car
       Porters - includes official statements; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and others,
       forms, bulletins; 15 page letter from Randolph to E.F. Carry, President, Pullman Company
       detailing history of the Brotherhood (6/9/27); broadsides, clippings</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link40">Pullman Company</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1933" type="inclusive">1926-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>U.S. Board of Mediation, case documents - Pullman Company vs. Brotherhood of Sleeping Car
       Porters - includes official statements; correspondence between A. Philip Randolph and others,
       forms, bulletins; 15 page letter from Randolph to E.F. Carry, President, Pullman Company
       detailing history of the Brotherhood (6/9/27); broadsides, clippings</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link41">R</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence regarding economic conditions, racial and marital discrimination seeking
       relief through NRA</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link42">S</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence citing racial and economic conditions, list of demands from Steel and Metal
       Workers Industrial Union and letter from Secretary NRA Compliance Board, Columbus, Georgia,
       informing General Johnson of plans by National Chamber of Commerce to establish 25% of 30%
       wage differential of Black workers by whites. Request for paid administrator and/or
       inspector.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link43">T</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1935" type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re race discrimination within the industry codes; 18 page mimeo, "Tuskegees'
       Service in National Recovery;" and routine correspondence</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link44">U</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>routine</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link45">W</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>routine correspondence re discrimination</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">3</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link46">Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re exploitation of household servants; from various YMCA organizations re
       discrimination in employment</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link47">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link48">Atlantic Coast Line</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link49">Baltimore and Ohio</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link50">Boston and Albany</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link51">Chesapeake and Ohio</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link52">Chicago Lines</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link53">Chicago Lines</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link54">Chicago Lines</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link55">Delaware, Lackawanna and Western</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link56">Erie Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link57">Illinois Central</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link58">Lehigh Valley</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>11a- Long Island Railroad (1919)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link59">Louisville and Nashville</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link60">Missouri Pacific</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link61">New York Central Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link62">Pennsylvania Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link63">Pullman Company</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link64">Richmond, Fredericksburg Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link65">Santa Fe Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>18a - Southern Pacific (1918)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link66">Southern Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link67">Union Pacific Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link68">Washington Terminal</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">4</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
      <unittitle id="link69">Western Maryland Railroad</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link70">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link71">Blue Crab Industry</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>includes reports by the NRA Division of Research and Planning on the industry;
       Correspondence and memos, petitions re minimum wage for crab packers</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link72">Construction Industry</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, re reduction of minimum wage in this industry</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link73">Cotton Industry</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, memos, reports, re classification of cotton gin workers, whether its
       industrial or agricultural</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link74">Tobacco Industry</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931/1935" type="inclusive">1931-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>104 page manuscript. "Negro Labor in the Tobacco Industry in North Carolina" by C. Tineley
       Willis, 1931; correspondence re north/south wage differentials and miscellaneous,
       1931-1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">5</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link75">Tobacco Industry</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931/1935" type="inclusive">1931-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>104 page manuscript. "Negro Labor in the Tobacco Industry in North Carolina" by C. Tineley
       Willis, 1931; correspondence re north/south wage differentials and miscellaneous,
       1931-1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link76">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link77">Auction and Loose Leaf Tobacco Warehouse Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>December 28, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link78">China Clay Producing Industry</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>December 13, 1933 (incomplete)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link79">Cigar Manufacturing Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>January 10, 1934 (Incomplete) 3a- Cinders, Ashes and Scavenger Industry, NRA (December 6
       1933)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link80">Cotton Bale Covering Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>April 23, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link81">Cotton Compress and Warehouse Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>September 25, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link82">Cotton Garment Industry, NRA/NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 9, 1934; March 9, 1934; May 9, 1935; May 17, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link83">Cotton Garment Industry, NRA/NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 9, 1934; March 9, 1934; May 9, 1935; May 17, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link84">Cotton Garment Industry, NRA/NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 9, 1934; March 9, 1934; May 9, 1935; May 17, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link85">Cotton Garment Industry, NRA/NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 9, 1934; March 9, 1934; May 9, 1935; May 17, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link86">Cotton Pickery Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>January 8, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link87">Cotton Pickery Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>March 10, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">6</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link88">Cotton Seed Oil Refining Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>December 19, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link89">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link90">Cotton Textile Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>June 29, 1933, October 9, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link91">Cotton Textile Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>June 29, 1933, October 9, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link92">Feed Manufacturing Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>December 16. 1933 3a- Fertilizer Industry, NRA (June 6 1933)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link93">Fishery Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>May 31 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link94">Fresh Fruit and Vegetable Distributive Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>January 8 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link95">Hotel and Restaurant Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>August 20, 1934 6a- Ice Industry, NRA (9/8/33)</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link96">Laundry Industry, NIRA 11/20 and 21/23</unittitle>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link97">Leaf Tobacco Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>March 21 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link98">Machined Waste Manufacturing Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>March 21, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link99">Oyster Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>May 7, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">7</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link100">Oyster Shell Crushers Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>March 9, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link101">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link102">Paper Shell Pecan Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 23, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link103">Pecan Shelling Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>November 27, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link104">Poultry (Live) Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>December 8, 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link105">Pulpwood Industry, NRA; NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>NRA: June 5, 1934 NIRA: May 22, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link106">Raw Cotton Trade Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>January 25, 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link107">Raw Peanut Milling Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 20, 1933 6a - Retail Merchandising Industry, NRA 7/2/1934 6b - Retail Solid Fuel
       Industry, NRA 11/13/33</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link108">Rubber Tire Manufacturing Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>August 20, 1934 7a - Scrap, Iron, Non Ferrous Industry, NRA 10/2/1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link109">Soap and Glycerin Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 5, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link110">Southern Rice Millers Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>September 5 and 7 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link111">Structural Clay Products Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>August 23, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link112">Taxicab Industry, NIRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>February 13 1934</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link113">Vitrified Clay Sewer Pipe Manufacturing Industry, NRA</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>October 30, 1933 12a - Waste Material Industry, NRA, October 11, 1933</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">8</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link114">Miscellaneous Hearing - NIRA - Employment Provisions in Codes of Fair
       Competition</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>February 1, 2 1935</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link115">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. Subject Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link116">Agriculture</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>United States government pamphlet on slums and housing with special emphasis on New York
       City and selected references on housing. Also speech on the Black farmer and the Agricultural
       Adjustment Act, 1936</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link117">Black Employment Problems by Specific Industries-</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1935" type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing and employment in the
       steel, automobile, and textile industries. Proposed fair competition industry code for the
       laundry and cleaning service workers. Includes statistics for Ohio and Detroit industries and
       employees divided by race</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link118">Civilian Conservation Corps - Brown, Edgar -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Requests for information about Blacks and the New Deal. Favorable information to be used to
       swing Blacks to the Democratic political party.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link119">Civilian Conservation Corps</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re Black job applicants requesting aid to secure employment in the Civilian
       Conservation Corps</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link120">Commerce, Department of - Jones, Eugene Kinckle</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Requests for information on Blacks in the New Deal</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link121">Conferences</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939/1941" type="inclusive">1939-1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re training and employment of Blacks for national defense industries in
       Saint Paul and Minneapolis. Employment problems of the Blacks in Trenton, NJ, Los Angeles;
       Wilmington, Indianapolis, Chicago, and Little Rock. Speech on the place of Blacks in the
       Employment Security Program in Illinois Speech on training needs and employment opportunity
       in the day workers and personal service fields. Proceedings of the second National Conference
       on the problems of the Blacks and Black Youth. Speech on the U.S. Employment Service and the
       Black job applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link122">Differentials - Racial and Wages -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing and employment. Reports
       on racial and wage differentials due to the fair competition industry codes of the NRA</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link123">Elevator Operators -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence concerning alleged discrimination against Black elevator operators in the
       various federal buildings in Washington, DC</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link124">Employment Security -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Proceedings of the Institute on Routine documents</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link125">Farm Credit Administration</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence concerning the Farm Credit Administration programs available to Blacks
       including emergency relief and employment. Letters from Black job applicants requesting aid
       in securing employment</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">9</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link126">Federal Security Agency - Social Security Board, Maryland</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Information about Blacks in National Defense and Industry. Alleged racial discrimination in
       Maryland. Includes statistics on industry and employees. Describes attitudes towards Black
       employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link127">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. Subject Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link128">Federal Security Agency - Social Security Board, Region Seven
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes material on national defense training and employment for Blacks in various
       industries including aircraft, automobile, chemical, communications, construction,
       electrical, iron and steel, metal and shipbuilding in the south. Discrimination against
       Blacks by labor unions and employers. Majority of documents from the Seventh Regional Labor
       Supply Committee which monitors six southern states including Alabama, Florida, Georgia,
       Mississippi, South Carolina, and Tennessee. Includes reports and statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link129">Federal Security Agency - Social Security Board, Region
       Seven</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1941/1942" type="inclusive">1941-1942</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes material on national defense training and employment for Blacks in various
       industries including aircraft, automobile, chemical, communications, construction,
       electrical, iron and steel, metal and shipbuilding in the south. Discrimination against
       Blacks by labor unions and employers. Majority of documents from the Seventh Regional Labor
       Supply Committee which monitors six southern states including Alabama, Florida, Georgia,
       Mississippi, South Carolina, and Tennessee. Includes reports and statistics.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link130">Illinois Central Railroad - Killing of Black Firemen</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1936" type="inclusive">1933-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Newspaper and magazine articles describing the murders of Black railroad firemen by white
       railroad workers who wanted their jobs. Informal paper on immigrant unskilled construction
       labor and the formation of the International Hod Carriers, Building and Common Laborers Union
       of America</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link131">Interior, Department of - Conference of Youth Leaders</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Routine documentation</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link132">Interior, Department of - Robert C. Weaver -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1937" type="inclusive">1933-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence concerning discrimination against Blacks in a Federal Emergency Relief
       Administration project in Florida and in Public Works Administration Projects at Cleveland,
       Ohio; Atlantic City, New Jersey; Savannah and Atlanta, Georgia; Columbia, South Carolina; New
       Orleans, Louisiana; and Nashville, Tennessee. Agreements concerning the staffing of Black
       workers on Public Works Administration projects. Reports on wages paid to skilled,
       semi-skilled and un-skilled Black labor on these PWA projects. Report on the Tobacco Industry
       in North Carolina.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link133">Interior, Department of - Office of Education -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Documents concerning an educational program designed as emergency relief projects for
       Blacks. News Release, "South Faces Difficult Problem Financing Schools, Committee finds," May
       11, 1934- (Findings of the committee on financial support of the National Conference on the
       Education of Blacks. Includes statistics on the funding of public schools population, per
       capita income, teachers salaries, per student spending, comparative analysis of Black and
       white schools and their students and between the south and the rest of the United States);
       information on the Public Works Administration and federal emergency relief projects
       available to Black public schools. Projects include construction, vocational training,
       vocational rehabilitation, adult education and preschool education</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link134">Interior, Department of - Office of Education - Survey Opportunities
       for Vocational education and Guidance for Blacks -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence concerning the Technical Advisory Committee for the National Survey of
       Opportunities for Vocational Education and Vocational Guidance of Blacks. Black job
       applicants requests aid to secure employment in this project.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link135">Interstate Commerce Commission</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re the formulation of rules for protection of Blacks using buses and
       trucks</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link136">Labor Department - Bureau of Labor Statistics, Luncheon
       Club</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Routine announcements</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link137">Labor Department - Children's Bureau -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1934" type="inclusive">1922-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Information on child labor, migrants, welfare and social security, services relating to
       youths, both Black and white; re Black delinquent youth not properly placed in correctional
       institution due to lack of space and racial segregation. Includes statistics on population,,
       delinquents and types of crimes committee by Black youth; Bibliography of publications by the
       Children's Bureau about working mothers and youth with specific information on Blacks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link138">Labor Department - Conciliation Service -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932/1939" type="inclusive">1932-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence alleging discrimination against Blacks in employment by private sector
       employers and labor unions in Chicago, Illinois and Indiana. Discrimination by International
       Longshoremen's Association in Texas. Alleged discrimination against Blacks on Works Progress
       Administration projects and Public Works Administration projects; Memorandum listing Black
       political, educational, and social leaders to be invited to the ceremony dedicating the new
       Labor Department Building.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">10</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link139">Labor Department - Conciliation Service - Joint Conference Committee
       of the Community Progressive Black Painters Union -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Documents re a New York Black painters labor union allege discrimination against Blacks in
       private sector employment and federal emergency relief programs. Recommendation from Lawrence
       Oxley for the Labor Department to cease relations with the Committee.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link140">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. Subject Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link141">Labor Department - Division of Labor Standards - Apprenticeship
       Training, Federal Committee on -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes statistics on Black unemployment and students in secondary schools of ten states
       receiving grand-in-aid including Alabama, Delaware, Florida, Louisiana, Massachusetts,
       Missouri, North Carolina, South Carolina, Texas, Wyoming.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link142">Labor Department - Fitzgerald, Henry J. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Routine internal administrative correspondence</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link143">Labor Department - Gompers S.J. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes statistics on salaries and staffing of Blacks in the Labor Department, United
       States Employment Service and the National Reemployment Service. Data from the Washington, DC
       Employment Service on job applicants and employee placements divided by race.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link144">Labor Department - Hinrichs, A.F. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930/1935" type="inclusive">1930-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence regarding the Labor Department's public policy concerning state conferences
       on Black employment problems; Memorandum to Lawrence A. Oxley, April 15, 1935, requesting a
       study of the decline in Black labor union membership during the depression. Author suggests
       the reason involves unemployment; Memorandum to A.F. Hinrichs, March 4, 1935, re National and
       International labor unions in the Construction Industry, affiliated and unaffiliated with the
       AFL in which discrimination against Blacks is traditional or provided for in the union
       constitution; Memorandum to A.F. Hinrichs, January 30, 1935, noting theories on depressed
       wages in the south for both Black and white employees, including bibliography; Conference
       notes re detailed position description of Lawrence Oxley's position of Chief, Division of
       Black Labor in the Labor Department; Memorandum to A.F. Hinrichs, October 3, 1934 listing
       Black government officials and national organizations concerned with educational, economic,
       professional, political and general advancement of Blacks. Suggested bibliography on the
       Black in industry; Memorandum to A.F. Hinrichs re statistics on the distribution of Black
       miners by counties in West Virginia, in 1930</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link145">Labor Department - Immigration Service -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932/1936" type="inclusive">1932-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence and petitions from Blacks alleging racial discrimination and requesting to
       be sent to Africa</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link146">Labor Department - Lubin, Isador -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re procedure on arranging state conferences concerning Black employment
       problems. Requests for travel authorization to conferences concerning Blacks where the Labor
       Department's presence might have positive political influence for the Franklin D. Roosevelt
       administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link147">Labor Department - Lubin, Isador - Weekly Progress Reports
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Detailed accounts of Lawrence Oxley's action as Chief, Division of Black Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link148">Labor Department - Perkins, Frances M. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence and pamphlets, including general facilitative office correspondence to
       Perkins, Oxley, and other officials in the Labor Department. Contains routine solicitation
       for information on Black employment and general information on Secretary of Labor and the
       Labor Department.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link149">Labor Department - Perkins, Frances M. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence, reports and pamphlets. Includes correspondence to Perkins and Oxley on
       discrimination against Blacks in employment. Statistics on Black workers and Black education.
       Reports to Perkins on the Division of Black Labor and speeches. Exchange on alleged
       discrimination against Blacks in Labor Department. Includes hostile correspondence from Black
       person relating to Black federal employees; Letter from General Counsel of International
       Association of Railroad Employees on discrimination against Blacks in the railroad industry
       and problems with railroad craft unions and their exclusive jurisdiction under the Railway
       Labor Act, August 1, 1936; Memorandum containing rationale for maintenance of staff o the
       Division of Black Labor rather than a reduction in force of the office, noting that an active
       Division may have political influence in the voting patterns of the south, June 1, 1936;
       Memorandum recommending that the Democratic National Committee be assigned the task of
       compiling information about the New Deal Administration and its impact on Black employment
       and emergency relief. Goal is to produce a publication with information favorable to Blacks
       to influence the voting pattern of the south, March 23, 1936; Memorandum-report concerning
       the first meeting of the National Negro Congress, February 14, 1936 in Chicago. Notes John P.
       Davis as founder of the organization. Describes organization's leaders as communists, March 5
       1936; Memorandum-progress report on Blacks and the New Deal. Discusses problems on barriers
       to entry in employment, job searching, and employment opportunities. Provides an economic
       analysis of the Black population. Discusses discrimination against Blacks in emergency relief
       programs by the NRA, the Public Works Administration, the Tennessee Valley Authority, the
       Civilian Conservation Corps, and related trade unions. Lists achievements of the Division of
       Black unions. Lists achievements of the Division of Black Labor, November 9, 1935; Letter
       describing activities of Georgia Teachers and Educational Association, a Black teachers'
       association. Includes a recommendation to hire a Black supervisor to the Georgia Relief
       Emergency Administration. Statistics from 1933-34 on the number of schools, comparative
       analysis on Black and white teachers and Black and white school enrollment. Goals for
       improving elementary and secondary education for Blacks in Georgia, July 19, 1935; Memorandum
       giving opinion on Title VII of proposed Economic Security Act. Discusses grant in aid for
       vocational education. Proposal of statement to be included in the Economic Security Act
       providing equal opportunity of appropriations for grant in aid to Black and white schools.
       Reviews the Second Morrill Act and the Smith-Lever Act of 1914. Statistical table on
       discrimination, January 23, 1935; Memorandum discussing circulating rumors that Labor
       Department will dismiss Black blue collar workers in favor of whites. Calls for continued
       employment, the creation of additional employment opportunities and the end of discrimination
       for Blacks, December 14, 1934; Memorandum from Lawrence Oxley quoting the 1934 American
       Federation of Labor (AFL) resolution against discrimination of Blacks, October 22, 1934;
       Memorandum discusses the staffing of Black blue collar workers in the Labor Department.
       Insofar as possible, discrimination against Blacks will be avoided, January 2, 1934; "The
       Division of Negro Labor, Department of Labor," describes activities of the Division of Black
       Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">11</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link150">Labor Department - Phillips, Karl F.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine internal administrative correspondence</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link151">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. Subject Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link152">Labor Department - U.S. Employment Service - Black White-Collar
       Employment Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Documents soliciting various state employment services for eligible Black job applicants to
       work on a Works Progress Administration project. Surveying Black white-collar employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link153">Labor Department - U.S. Employment Service - Special Reports - Arthur,
       George R. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1940" type="inclusive">1933-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Reports on the relationship between the state employment services and Black job applicants
       in Dallas, Texas; Memphis, Tennessee; Birmingham and Montgomery, Alabama; Los Angeles and San
       Francisco, California; Kansas City, Missouri; and Denver, Colorado. Alleged discrimination
       against Blacks in these areas. Analysis of occupation and characteristics of emergency relief
       recipients for Chicago, Illinois.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link154">Labor Department -Wage and Hour Division -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Documents re Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment at the Wage and
       Hour Division of the Labor Department.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link155">Miscellaneous Complaints</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928/1937" type="inclusive">1928-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Letters from Blacks complaining of discrimination in staffing and employment from various
       parts of the country.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link156">National Archives -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re Lawrence Oxley's attempts at ensuring employment Black job applicants in
       the newly created National Archives</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link157">National Recovery Administration</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Reports and correspondence concerning NRA fair competition industry codes and Lawrence
       Oxley's participation on the Labor Advisory Board ensuring against racial discrimination; "A
       Wage Differential Based on Race," re discrimination against Blacks in wages and NRA fair
       competition industry codes; "Report on Effect of NRA Codes on Blacks, March 21, 1934," re
       alleged discrimination against Black workers. Describes the application of NRA fair
       competition codes to southern industries and the resulting effects on Blacks; "The Black and
       Wage Differentials Under the Codes," describes regional and population wage differentials
       under the NRA codes with respect to Blacks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link158">National Recovery Administration - Fair Competition Industry Codes -
       Central Weaving and Spinning Company -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Appeal for exemption from the NRA Act fair competition industry codes for the textile
       industry by the Central Weaving and Spinning Company of Fayetteville, North Carolina.
       Discrimination is apparent as the company contends, Blacks are inferior employees. Includes
       newspaper articles, statistics on Black births and deaths from 1933-1936 in the United
       States.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link159">National Recovery Administration - Fair Competition Industry Codes -
       Mente and Company -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1935" type="inclusive">1933-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Appeal for exemption from the NRA Act fair competition industry code for the textile
       industry by the Mente Company of New Orleans, Louisiana and the Selma Manufacturing Company
       of Selma, Alabama. Discrimination is apparent as the companies contend that Blacks are
       inferior employees and have a low productivity rate. Statistics on Black property ownership,
       economic, educational and religious progress in North Carolina, Virginia, and Georgia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">12</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link160">National Recovery Administration - Fair Competition Industry Codes -
       Nachman, D. and Company -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Appeal for exemption from the NRA fair competition industry code for the textile industry
       by the D. Nachman and Company of Augusta, Georgia. Racial discrimination is apparent as the
       company contends Black women are inferior employees and have a low productivity rate.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link161">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. Subject Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link162">National Recovery Administration - Fair Competition Industry Codes -
       Southland Manufacturing Company</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Appeal for exemption from the NRA Fair Competition Code for the clothing industry by the
       Southland Manufacturing Company of Montgomery, Alabama. Discrimination against Blacks is
       alleged. The company contends Blacks are inferior employees and have a low productivity
       rate.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link163">National Recovery, Joint Committee on -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>"Two Years with the Joint Committee on National Recovery, 1933-35." A publicity pamphlet
       which states goals and accomplishments of the Committee and includes their progress on behalf
       of Blacks in the New Deal. Information on Black industrial workers, farm hands and farmers,
       dayworkers, emergency relief recipients and the Tennessee Valley Authority. States
       relationship between the federal government and the Committee; correspondence, memorandums,
       meeting minutes concerning the progress of Blacks under the New Deal including the National
       Youth Administration, Civilian Conservation Corps, Works Project Administration, Public Works
       Administration and Resettlement Administration. Protest against discrimination against Blacks
       within these administrations and in the AFL trade unions. Discussion of the fair competition
       industry codes of the NRA, specifically including the cotton, laundry, tobacco and mining
       industries. Information and statistics on the conditions Black day workers encounter;
       Memorandum to all member organizations of the Joint Committee February 23, 1935 discusses the
       discriminatory effects against Blacks by the implementation of the Farm Tenant Homes Act of
       1935. Provisions render discrimination against Black tenant farmers, sharecroppers and
       marginal land owners; Memorandum to Isador Lubin, October 24, 1934, re observations of an
       annual dinner for the Joint Committee. Presents administrative viewpoints on how Black
       unemployment problems are viewed and solved.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link164">National Recovery, Joint Committee on -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>"Occupational Status of the Blacks in the Iron and Steel Industry: Pittsburgh and Environs,
       May 23, 1934," by Wilson F. Alden, Pittsburgh Urban League. History and current information
       including alleged discrimination against Blacks in the Iron and Steel Industry from Alleghany
       County, Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania. Statistics on Black employees and their occupations; "An
       Analysis of the Occupational Opportunities for Blacks in Allegheny County," by Howard D.
       Gould. Report on the problems of Black employment and resulting job opportunities in
       Allegheny County, Pennsylvania. Statistics on population (1910-1930), migration, employment,
       occupations, industries employing Blacks and wages.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link165">Publications -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1941" type="inclusive">1933-1941</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Published reports on racial employment trends in national defense, black employment
       opportunities in Kentucky, employment security and the Blacks, Black youth, placement of
       Black workers by the United States Employment Service, earnings and hours of Black workers in
       independent tobacco industry, memorandums and executive orders from President Roosevelt
       condemning discrimination in defense industries. Report on the situation of Black women
       workers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link166">Public Works Administration - Agreements -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1936" type="inclusive">1935-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Agreements between Public Works Administration and the Labor Department which guaranteed
       employment to Blacks on a percentage basis for individual PWA projects. Projects are located
       in New Jersey, New York, Alabama, Ohio, Illinois, Tennessee, Kentucky and Indiana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link167">Public Works Administration - Contracts - Isador Lubin -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks on PWA projects in New York City, Kansas City, Saint
       Louis, Los Angeles, Fort Wayne, Georgetown, Greensville, Point Pleasant, Mantina, and
       Florida. Suggested clauses to be inserted in project agreements to safeguard Blacks against
       discrimination.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link168">Public Works Administration - Housing Contracts -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Suggested clauses to be inserted into PWA contracts. Chicago, Cleveland, housing project
       agreements to prevent discrimination against Black workers. Alleged discrimination against
       Blacks on these projects in Chicago. List of building and construction trade labor unions
       barring Black membership. Racial statistics on emergency relief recipient and population in
       the United States and occupations in the building and construction trade held by Blacks in
       Chicago.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link169">Resettlement Administration</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>RE alleged discrimination against Blacks in employment on a project in North Carolina.
       Information on the number and occupations of Black employees in the Resettlement
       Administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">13</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link170">Tennessee Valley Authority -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on wages paid to Black workers with the TVA. Request of Lawrence Oxley to visit
       the work sites to prevent discrimination against Blacks in staffing.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link171">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. Subject Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link172">Tennessee Valley Authority - Discrimination</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing and employment with the Tennessee Valley
       Authority.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link173">Tobacco -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing at a tobacco plant in Ohio; "The Tobacco
       Industry in North Carolina," report on the tobacco industry with statistics for major
       companies on profits, production, employees, wages, hours. Discrimination against Blacks is
       charged because of the low wage rates prescribed by the NRA in the fair competition industry
       code.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link174">Tobacco Study -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Bibliography on the tobacco industry. Questionnaire schedule used for Black and white
       employees of the tobacco industry.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link175">Transportation, Federal Coordinator of -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Black railroad workers by American Federation of Labor
       railroad unions, resulting in unemployment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link176">Unemployment Census -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on unemployment divided by race for Arizona, Delaware, and New Hampshire</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link177">Works Progress Administration - Available Housing for Research Project
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Requests for office space from Black contacts for a WPA study concerning Black white-collar
       employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link178">Works Progress Administration - Miscellaneous Correspondence
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1938" type="inclusive">1935-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing at the WPA in North Carolina, South
       Carolina, Los Angeles, California, and Texas. Job applicants requesting aid in securing
       employment in the WPA.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link179">Works Progress Administration - Black Press Digest -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Weekly report on the articles found in Black newspapers concerning the Works Progress
       Administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link180">Works Progress Administration - Savannah, Georgia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1936" type="inclusive">1934-1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing and employment with the Works Progress
       Administration projects at Savannah, Georgia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link181">Works Progress Administration - Alfred E. Smith -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing and employment with the WPA in Alabama,
       Ohio, South Carolina, Nebraska, Louisiana, Georgia, Mississippi, Texas, Virginia, Maryland,
       North Carolina, Illinois, Massachusetts, Kansas, Missouri, and Florida. Job applicants
       request aid in securing employment with this administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">14</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link182">Works Progress Administration - Workers' Education -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Bulletins from the Workers' Education Training Center, Livingstone College, Salisbury,
       North Carolina funded by the WPA. Bulletin on workers' education from the Federal Emergency
       Relief Administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link183">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service
      State Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link184">Alabama - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Letters alleging discriminations against Blacks by Birmingham, Alabama, State Employment
       Service Office. Complaint that the office is disregarding the civil service eligible lists
       for Black job applicants.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link185">Alabama - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Concerning a conference to be held with the Alabama State Employment Service on the
       problems of Black employment and racial discrimination.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link186">Alabama - Survey</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Alabama State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, 1910-1933, emergency relief recipients, occupations,
       local industry, and data on job applicants and employee placement divided by race in
       Birmingham and Alabama. Report of conference held with service concerning Black employment
       and racial discrimination. Proposal for urban renewal in Birmingham. 1934,1938.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link187">Arizona - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Newspaper article and correspondence re the opening of a Black employment service. Alleged
       discrimination against Blacks by Arizona State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link188">Arkansas - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks by Arkansas State Employment Service concerning civil
       service merit examinations and eligible lists in Little Rock.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link189">Arkansas - Survey</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Arkansas State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants, Statistics on population, 1910-1933, emergency relief recipients, occupations,
       local industry and data on job applicants and employee placements divided by race for Little
       Rock and Arkansas. Examines cotton industry, tenant farming, housing and slave labor in
       Arkansas.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link190">California - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discriminations against Blacks in staffing by the Civilian Conservation Corps,
       Shasta Dam Project, Shasta County, Tulare California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link191">California - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence re WPA funding for study of Black unemployment in California. Alleged
       discrimination against Blacks by the California State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link192">California - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report of 1935 study on white collar and skilled and professional Blacks in Los Angeles,
       County, California funded by the WPA. Includes racial statistics on population, educational
       level, extent of training and the extent to which the training affected their socio-economic
       status. Also report including racial statistics on population (1910-1935), emergency relief
       recipients, occupations, local industry and California State Employment Service data divided
       by race in Los Angeles, Oakland, and San Francisco, California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link193">Colorado - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against a Black man by Colorado State Employment Service in civil
       service merit examinations and staffing.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link194">Colorado - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients and unemployment in Colorado and
       Denver.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link195">Connecticut - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>List of members and conference report of the State Advisory Council of the Connecticut
       State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link196">Connecticut - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, 1910-1933, emergency relief recipients and occupations of Blacks
       in Hartford, New Haven and Connecticut.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link197">Delaware - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing by the Delaware State Employment
       Service</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link198">Delaware - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, 1910-1935, emergency relief recipients, unemployment and
       occupations divided by race in Wilmington and Delaware.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link199">Florida - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in civil service competitive examinations and
       employee placement opportunities by the Florida State Employment Service. Correspondence
       alleging discrimination by unions and employers against Black mechanic, farm hand, and
       shipping industry employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link200">Florida - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment with the Florida State
       Employment Service. Discrimination against Blacks at the service, where racial segregation
       exists. Reports on the improvement of treatment of Blacks in civil service merit examinations
       and employee placements.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link201">Florida - Survey</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on occupational groups of job applicants to Florida State Employment Service,
       divided by race.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link202">Georgia - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks by Atlanta, Georgia State Employment Service in civil
       service merit examinations. Alleged discrimination against Blacks in Georgia resulting in
       unemployment and poverty.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link203">Georgia - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination regarding the dismissal of Black employees from the Atlanta, Georgia
       State Employment Service. Black job applicants request aid in securing employment with the
       United States Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">15</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link204">Georgia - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Georgia State Employment service and Black job
       applicants. Racial statistics on population, 1910-1933, emergency relief recipients,
       occupations and local industry in Atlanta and Georgia. Correspondence arranging conferences
       on Black labor in Georgia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link205">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service
      State Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link206">Illinois - Metropolitan Chicago Conference on Employment Problems of
       the Negro - 1940</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Speeches to the Conference concerning Black employment in white collar, professional,
       utilities and government sectors; the place of Blacks in the Social Security Program;
       Industrial aspect and economic aspect; the Chicago Black occupational picture; Black Labor
       Symposium includes discussion of training needs and employment opportunities in meat packing,
       iron and steel, manufacturing, hotel and restaurant and construction industries. Training and
       opportunities sought for day workers and personal and custodial service. Black youth in the
       employment picture and the Black woman workers are subjects of discussion.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link207">Illinois - Chicago Conference on Occupational Status and Employment
       Opportunities for Black Workers - 1934 -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference on occupational status and to ensure employment
       opportunities for Black workers in Chicago; WPA projects correspondence with Howard D. Gould
       of the Chicago Urban League relating to a specific project - the Black Occupational
       Survey.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link208">Illinois - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1937" type="inclusive">1934-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing by the WPA</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link209">Illinois - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicants request aid in securing employment with the Illinois State Employment
       Service. Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing at the service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link210">Illinois - Proposed WPA Studies -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Proposals for three WPA studies in Cook County, Illinois, re Black employment, occupations
       and population dynamics. Projects to be sponsored by the Illinois State Employment Service
       and conducted at the University of Chicago.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link211">Illinois - Chicago - South Parkway Employment Office -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicants request aid in securing employment at the Illinois State Employment
       Service. Complaints from the service on a labor shortage of staff and racial segregation of
       offices.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link212">Illinois - Chicago - West Wacker Drive Office -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Conference re Black employment. Report on meeting with the Chicago Urban League concerning
       the progress of Black employment in the WPA which resulted in the proposal to lobby
       government officials to demand the inclusion of Black employees on projects. Advertising for
       the re-election of Black Congressman Arthur Mitchell of Chicago.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link213">Illinois - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Illinois State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients occupations, local
       industry, job applicants and employee placements in Chicago, Cook County, and Illinois.
       Questionnaire concerning employment opportunities in retail trade for Blacks. Report on
       progress of Black employment in East Saint Louis, Chicago. Complaint from South Parkway
       office concerning racial segregation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link214">Indiana - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks by the Indiana State Employment Service in the
       service's staffing. Alleged discrimination against Blacks resulting in under unemployment and
       unemployment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link215">Indiana - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicant requests aid in securing a position with the Indiana State Employment
       Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link216">Indiana - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Indiana State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and job
       applicants and employee placements from the service for Indianapolis and Indiana. Reports and
       statistics on the employment of Blacks in various Indiana Federal Emergency Relief
       Administration Housing projects. List of Black officials in the National Youth
       Administration.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link217">Kansas - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Excerpts from a PWA Inspection Report alleging discriminations against Blacks by government
       officials and labor unions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link218">Kansas- Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Racial Statistics on the occupational groups of job applicants and employee placements from
       the Kansas State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link219">Kentucky - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>alleged discrimination against Blacks. Report of wage differentials for Black and white
       employees of the Kentucky State Employment Service. Complaints by Blacks concerning living
       conditions, unemployment and poverty.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link220">Kentucky - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">1937-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference with the Kentucky State Employment Service. Black job
       applicants request aid in securing employment. Alleged dismissal of Black employee in the
       service because of local political affiliation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link221">Kentucky - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Racial statistics on population (1910-1933), emergency relief recipients, occupations,
       local industry, and job applicants and employee placements from the Kentucky State employment
       Service for Louisville and Kentucky. Correspondence arranging conferences with the service
       concerning Black employment. Reports of field trips to Louisville, Kentucky.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link222">Louisiana - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks by the Louisiana State Employment Service. Alleged
       discrimination against Blacks resulting in unemployment and poverty.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link223">Louisiana - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference with the Louisiana State Employment Service concerning
       Black employment. Discrimination against a potential Black employee of the Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link224">Louisiana - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Louisiana State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Racial statistics on population (1910-33) emergency relief recipients,
       occupation, local industry and job applicants and employee placements from the Service, for
       New Orleans and Louisiana. Report on a field trip to Louisiana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link225">Maryland - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>alleged discrimination against Blacks in private sector industry and emergency relief
       projects in Maryland.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link226">Maryland - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference with Maryland State Employment Service concerning Black
       employment, Black job applicants request aid in securing a position with the Division of
       Negro Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
      <unittitle id="link227">Maryland - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Maryland State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, occupations, wages, unemployment, and job applicants
       and employee placement from the service, divided by race. Report from the service on Black
       employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
      <unittitle id="link228">Massachusetts - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Petition from National Association for the Advancement of Colored People that public
       service corporations be prohibited from discrimination in employment on account of race.
       Report on conference with Massachusetts State Employment Service about Black employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">16</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
      <unittitle id="link229">Massachusetts - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Racial statistics on population, occupations, unemployment and job applicants and employee
       placements from the Massachusetts State Employment Service. Meeting minutes from the service
       on Black employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link230">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service
      State Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link231">Michigan - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against a Black man by Michigan State Employment Service. Complaints
       of unemployment and poverty.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link232">Michigan - Conference on Employment Problems of the Blacks - Detroit,
       1940 -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1940">1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Papers include statistics on Black population, occupations, unemployment, vocational
       education, public welfare, WPA employees. Papers report on intellectual competence, family
       relationships, crime and delinquency, health and housing.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link233">Michigan - Detroit -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">1937-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Text from radio program about employment of Blacks by Michigan State Employment Service.
       Report on conference with service relating to Black employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link234">Michigan - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1940" type="inclusive">1937-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference with Michigan State Employment Service. Blacks request
       information and aid in securing employment. Statistics on population divided by race for
       Flint, Grand Rapids, Detroit, and Michigan. Report on Black staffing problem.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link235">Michigan - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Facts regarding PWA housing projects in Detroit. Report on the relationship between the
       Michigan State Employment Service and Black job applicants. Racial statistics on population,
       emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry, unemployment and job applicants and
       employee placements for Detroit, Flint, Lansing, Grand Rapids, and Michigan. Conference
       report concerning Black employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link236">Mississippi - General correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with Mississippi State
       Employment Service. Racial statistics on emergency relief recipients, occupations and job
       applicants, and employee placements from the service, in Meridan, Jackson, and
       Mississippi.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link237">Mississippi - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients and job applicants and
       employee placements from the Mississippi State Employment Service divided by race in Jackson,
       Meridan, and Mississippi.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link238">Missouri - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing by the Missouri State Employment
       Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link239">Missouri - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1940" type="inclusive">1936-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence concerning alleged discrimination against Blacks by the Missouri State
       Employment Service. Letters from Missouri Congressman, John J. Cochran, expressing
       dissatisfaction in Lawrence Oxley's speeches which contend that discrimination exists in many
       facets of the Federal government. Statistics on job applicants and employee placements,
       divided by race, from the service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link240">Missouri - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Missouri State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics include population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry, job applicants and employee placements from the service divided by race for Saint
       Louis, Kansas City, and Missouri. Conference report concerning the service and Black
       employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link241">Nebraska - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, and occupations divided by
       race in Omaha and Nebraska.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link242">New Jersey - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicants request aid in securing employment. Charges that Black migrants are
       depressing the farmhand wages and of alleged discrimination against Blacks in the
       shipbuilding industry in New Jersey.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link243">New Jersey - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conferences with New Jersey State Employment Service concerning
       Black employment. Letters from Black job applicants requesting aid in securing
       employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link244">New Jersey - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and unemployment divided
       by race in Jersey City, Newark, Camden, and New Jersey.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link245">New York - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1940" type="inclusive">1934-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks including barriers to entry into PWA employment where
       a closed shop agreement existed and labor unions bar Blacks from membership. Political
       cartoons and comments depicting discrimination against Blacks. Black job applicants
       requesting aid in securing employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link246">New York City - Housing Authority - Harlem Family Income Survey
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Survey containing statistics on sources of income, percentage of income for rent,
       population density, composition of the family by race.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link247">New York State - Commercial and Professional Division - Josephine P.
       Holmes -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference with the New York State Employment Service concerning
       Black employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link248">New York State - Division of Placement and Unemployment Insurance -
       Fritz Kaufman -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Proposal for study of the relationship of the New York State Employment Service with
       Blacks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link249">New York State - Harlem -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1940" type="inclusive">1934-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Annual reports from the Men's Industrial Service, Youth Statistics Divisions of the New
       York State Employment Service office in Harlem. Includes statistics on job applicants and
       placements.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link250">New York State -New York World's Fair -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>United States Employment Service endeavors to secure employment for Blacks on the New York
       World's Fair projects. Requests by Black job applicants for aid in securing employment at the
       fair. Alleged discrimination against Blacks in staffing at the fair. Leaflet on the condition
       of the urban Black population.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link251">New York State - William H. Lange -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Routine correspondence</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
      <unittitle id="link252">New York State - William H. Wilkinson -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics concerning job applicants and employee placements of the New York State
       Employment Service and the National Re-Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">17</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
      <unittitle id="link253">New York State - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the New York State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry, and job applicants and employee placements from the service, divided by race for
       New York City, Buffalo, and New York.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link254">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service
      State Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link255">North Carolina - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1938" type="inclusive">1935-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Blacks by North Carolina State Employment Service and
       private sector employers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link256">North Carolina - Examination information -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Routine correspondence.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link257">North Carolina - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1940" type="inclusive">1934-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment. Pamphlet on North Carolina
       Committee on Black Affairs and a conference program for Black social workers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link258">North Carolina - Joseph R. Watts -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Black employee in the North Carolina State Employment
       Services.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link259">North Carolina - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the North Carolina State Employment Service and Black
       job applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry, WPA staffing and job applicants, and employee placements of the service divided by
       race in Asheville, Charlotte, Greensboro, Winston-Salem Durham, Raleigh and North Carolina.
       Report on field trip to the service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link260">Ohio - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Black job applicants by the Ohio State Employment
       Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link261">Ohio - The Population of Hamilton County -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935">1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Detailed report and statistics on population, race, characteristics, age, sex, employment,
       unemployment, marital status, religious affiliation, births, and deaths in Hamilton
       County.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link262">Ohio - Columbus -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference on Black employment with the Ohio State Employment
       Service, Columbus, office. Report on conference.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link263">Ohio - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment, with the Ohio State
       Employment Service. Letters from Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment.
       Newspaper article alleging discrimination against Blacks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link264">Ohio - Special Reports -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939/1940" type="inclusive">1939-1940</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Procedures for referring Black job applicants. Report on Black employment from the Ohio
       State Employment Service and the Columbus Urban League. Survey of Black employee placement
       activities. Statistics on population, divided by race in Akron, Canton, Cincinnati,
       Cleveland, Columbus, Dayton, Toledo, Youngstown, and Ohio.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link265">Ohio - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics divided by race, on population, emergency relief recipients, and job applicants
       and employee placement from the Ohio State Employment Service and the National Re-employment
       Service for Cleveland, Columbus, Cincinnati, Akron, Youngstown, and Ohio.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link266">Ohio - Cincinnati - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on conference concerning Black job applicants and employee placements with the Ohio
       State Employment Service, Cincinnati Office.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link267">Ohio - Cleveland Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Ohio State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry, and data on job applicants and employee placements from the service divided by race
       for Cleveland. Report concerning conference on Black employment with the service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link268">Oklahoma - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference with Oklahoma State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link269">Oklahoma - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local industry and on
       job applicants and employee placements from the Oklahoma State Employment Service divided by
       race for Oklahoma City, Tulsa, and Oklahoma. Report on field trip to the service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link270">Pennsylvania - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Black job applicants by the Pennsylvania State Employment
       Service. Alleged discrimination against Blacks resulting in unemployment and poverty.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link271">Pennsylvania - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938/1939" type="inclusive">1938-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with the Pennsylvania State
       Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link272">Pennsylvania - Harrisburg - Tensard DeWolf -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Routine correspondence.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link273">Pennsylvania - Pittsburgh - George W. Dorsey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with the Pennsylvania State
       Employment Service. Radio broadcast concerning Black employment by the service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">18</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link274">Pennsylvania - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Conference report of the Pennsylvania State Employment Service concerning Black employment.
       Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, and unemployment.
       Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and unemployment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link275">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley. State Employment Service
      State Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link276">Rhode Island -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1939">1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Fourth Annual Report of the Rhode Island Unemployment Compensation Board to the Governor
       for transmission to the General Assembly.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link277">South Carolina - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference concerning Black employment with the south Carolina
       State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link278">South Carolina - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, job applicants, and
       employee placements divided by race in Charleston, Columbia, Greenville, Spartanburg, and
       South Carolina.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link279">Tennessee - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Alleged discrimination against Black person complaining of violence, unemployment, and
       poverty.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link280">Tennessee - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1937" type="inclusive">1936-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Tennessee State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry and job applicants and employee placements from the Service, divided by race for
       Nashville and Tennessee.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link281">Texas - Centennial -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence concerning an exhibit by the Labor Department which portrays American
       workers including Blacks at the Texas Centennial.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link282">Texas - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Answer to a complaint of discrimination against Blacks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link283">Texas - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference on Black employment with the Texas State Employment
       Service. Alleged racial discrimination in staffing by the Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link284">Texas - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1939" type="inclusive">1936-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the Texas State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry, and job applicants and employee placements from the Service divided by race for
       Texas. Report on field trip to the Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link285">Virginia - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence alleging discrimination against Blacks by the Virginia State Employment
       Service in civil service competitive examinations. Black job applicants requesting aid in
       securing employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link286">Virginia - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging conference on Black employment with the Virginia State Employment
       Service. Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link287">Virginia - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1939" type="inclusive">1937-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations and job applicants and
       employee placements from the Virginia State Employment Service divided by race for Richmond
       and Virginia. Editorial describing discrimination against Blacks under the New Deal.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link288">Washington, DC - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Letters protesting replacement of incompetent B lack worker with unsympathetic white worker
       at the Washington, DC Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link289">Washington, DC - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Conference on the problems of vocational and secondary schools.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link290">Washington, DC - Board of Public Welfare -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Correspondence arranging meeting with the Board of Public Welfare to discuss Black
       problems.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link291">Washington, DC - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1938" type="inclusive">1937-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes racial statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations,
       unemployment, job applicants and employee placements from the Washington, DC employment
       service. Report on the relationship between the service and Black job applicants.
       Discrimination against a Black employee at the Service is alleged.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link292">Virginia - Complaints -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1938">1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Replies to letters alleging discrimination against Blacks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link293">West Virginia - General Correspondence -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Black job applicants requesting aid in securing employment. Discrimination against Blacks
       in staffing at the West Virginia State Employment Service.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">19</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link294">West Virginia - Survey -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936/1938" type="inclusive">1936-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Report on the relationship between the West Virginia State Employment Service and Black job
       applicants. Statistics on population, emergency relief recipients, occupations, local
       industry, unemployment, and on job applicants and employee placements from the service
       divided by race for Charlestown and West Virginia. Paper on Black families concerning
       composition, children and employability.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link295">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley Files. Employment Service,
      Information and Job Applicants Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link296">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link297">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link298">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link299">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link300">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link301">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link302">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link303">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link304">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link305">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link306">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link307">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link308">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link309">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link310">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link311">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link312">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link313">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link314">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link315">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link316">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
      <unittitle id="link317">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">20</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
      <unittitle id="link318">A-Y</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1939" type="inclusive">1934-1939</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence requesting statistical data, pamphlets, department
       bulletins, bibliographies, and studies re Black labor. Filed alphabetically by
       correspondent.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link319">U.S. Department of Labor. Lawrence A. Oxley Files. Employment Service,
      Information and Job Applicants Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link320">A-Y (Section II)</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes routine correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link321">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link322">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link323">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link324">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link325">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link326">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link327">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link328">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link329">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link330">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link331">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link332">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link333">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link334">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link335">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link336">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link337">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">21</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link338">A-Y Section II</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1938" type="inclusive">1934-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence and completed application forms of job applicants. Filed
       alphabetically by applicant.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link339">Karl F. Phillips. Commissioner of Conciliation. Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link340">Andrews, R. McCants - Durham, NC attorney, invites Phillips to various
       functions.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link341">Beckett, Bishop W.W. - Mississippi - Requests DOL aid for
       project</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link342">Beckwith, Frank R. - Indiana, Director of Negro Welfare, requests of
       Phillips for job</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1932" type="inclusive">1929-1932</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link343">Branch, Joel P. - Cleveland - Hand-written report on labor situation
       for Blacks.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link344">Bruce, Phillip A. - University of Virginia, send Phillips monograph on
       northward migration of Blacks.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924">1924</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link345">Bruseaux, Sheridan A. - Chicago, Principal Keystone National Detective
       Agency, Incorporated, requests information on employment situation for Blacks all over United
       States.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1928" type="inclusive">1925-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link346">Burton, James D. - Georgia, Interstate Secretary for Alabama and
       Tennessee, Commission on Interracial Cooperation, requesting information on miners
       wages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link347">Campbell, Charles C. - Michigan, Lansing, Special Industrial Agent for
       DOL, requests information farming, migration of Blacks.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1926" type="inclusive">1924-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link348">Chisum, Melvin J. - DC Field Secretary, National Negro Press
       Association, thanking Phillips for getting friend a job.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link349">Clark, John L. - Pittsburgh, Printer, request Phillips aid to guard
       against discrimination by International Typographical Union - Phillips suggests taking matter
       up with Charles Howard, International President.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link350">Cobb, Robert S. - Jefferson City, Missouri, Executive Secretary of
       Negro Industrial Commission requests Phillips aid in finding job.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link351">Commerce Department - compilation of statistics on persons in jail by
       race.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link352">D.C. and New York - one female requests Phillips to get $15 due her
       for work as cook, 1 other requests help in clothing trades and general
       correspondence.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927/1930" type="inclusive">1927-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link353">Copeland, M.L. - Kentucky, routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link354">Cotton Picking Machine - Department of Labor, news release about new
       machine; requests for information from many farmers.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link355">Crabmeat Pickers - Maryland, pickers go on strike since their wages
       dropped from 35 cents to 25 cents.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link356">Davidson, Lucy E. - DC, letter to Kerwin thanking him for recommending
       that she be allowed to keep her job.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link357">DePriest, Honorable Oscar - D.C., Congressman, calls non-partisan
       conference on Blacks; correspondence re Brotherhood of Railway Trainmen dispute.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1931" type="inclusive">1929-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link358">Dining Car Waiters - Lemus, Rienzi B., ask for same hours and benefits
       as other railroad union members.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link359">Elks (Wilson) D.C., request Secretary Davis to send them U United
       States Health representative as speaker.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link360">Employment - Howard University, bricklayers discriminated against in
       wages; United States confidential reports on Black unemployment</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1928" type="inclusive">1926- 1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
      <unittitle id="link361">Employment Service Plan - Indiana, Phillips successful in helping
       employ Black man; letter from another describing Black emancipation.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931/1932" type="inclusive">1931- 1932</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">23</container>
      <unittitle id="link362">Employment Service - Special - requests to Phillips for aid in finding
       jobs.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">24</container>
      <unittitle id="link363">Ernst, Senator R.P. - Kentucky, routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">25</container>
      <unittitle id="link364">Fite, Hadley G. - Indiana, trying to keep Bureau for Blacks
       open.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1927" type="inclusive">1925-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">26</container>
      <unittitle id="link365">Francis, Rothschild - Virgin Islands, Administrator seeks information
       from Phillips; news article on prevailing wage.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">27</container>
      <unittitle id="link366">Froe, Arthur G. - D.C., recorder of deeds, requests Phillips for
       information to send to friends re Blacks.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">28</container>
      <unittitle id="link367">Furr, Arthur F. - D.C., requests Phillips to help him get a
       job.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">29</container>
      <unittitle id="link368">Goens, Walter W. - New York, requests Phillips aid in getting
       certified as a doctor and finding employment.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">30</container>
      <unittitle id="link369">Governorship - Pennsylvania, Phillips acts as Secretary Labor Davis'
       campaign manager of Black vote.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1930" type="inclusive">1929-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">31</container>
      <unittitle id="link370">Harris, Professor Abram - Request for information on Black
       migration.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">32</container>
      <unittitle id="link371">Hale, W.J. Request for Georgia Douglas to speak at a conference in
       Tennessee.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">33</container>
      <unittitle id="link372">Hall, Seabron F. - Detroit, letter of friendship and
       reply.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">34</container>
      <unittitle id="link373">Harris, George W. Request for job, report on Black labor statistics,
       Peoria, Illinois.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1927" type="inclusive">1925-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">35</container>
      <unittitle id="link374">Haynes, George E. Executive Secretary of Interracial Conference asks
       Davis to participate and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">36</container>
      <unittitle id="link375">Henning, E.J., New York - requests aid in finding employment for a
       friend.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">37</container>
      <unittitle id="link376">Henry, Judge Edward - Answer from Phillips to request for Labor
       Department's aid with conciliation.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924">1924</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">38</container>
      <unittitle id="link377">Hert, Alvin F. (Mrs.) Republican National Committee requests Phillips
       aid in finding a job for wife of late Phil Brown.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924">1924</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">39</container>
      <unittitle id="link378">Hill, Honorable T. Edwards - West Virginia, Director of Negro Welfare
       and Statistics, aids Phillips with reports, requests job with Phillips.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">40</container>
      <unittitle id="link379">Howard, Honorable Perry W. - Requests Phillips help in naturalizing
       immigrants.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928/1930" type="inclusive">1928-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">41</container>
      <unittitle id="link380">Howard Theatre Dispute - Dispute on Howard Theatre's musician
       dispute.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">42</container>
      <unittitle id="link381">Immigration - Princeton University, 82 page report on immigration from
       Latin America and West Indies to America.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">43</container>
      <unittitle id="link382">Indiana - Cases - Dynes, Commissioner in Indiana, sends friends to
       Phillips for employment; talks about political situation.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930/1931" type="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">44</container>
      <unittitle id="link383">Industrial Trends - Black migration, social adjustments, employment
       problems, attitudes.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1929" type="inclusive">1926-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">45</container>
      <unittitle id="link384">Johnson, Charles S., Research Director for National Interracial
       Conference asks Phillips for studies on Blacks to secure accurate picture of current Black
       living.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">46</container>
      <unittitle id="link385">Johnson, J.R. - Black from Texas requests Phillips aid in finding
       information on building and loan associations.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">47</container>
      <unittitle id="link386">Johnson, Sol - Commissioner of Immigration at Ellis
       Island.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">48</container>
      <unittitle id="link387">Jones, Eugene Kinckle - Executive Secretary of national Urban League,
       re favors and recommendations.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1926" type="inclusive">1924-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">49</container>
      <unittitle id="link388">Jones, Francis I. - Director General, United States Employment
       Service, request for information re employment.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">50</container>
      <unittitle id="link389">Jones, Scipio - Masonic Order, noted Black lawyer and judge asks
       Phillips help in raising funds for needy youth and the elderly.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925- 1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">51</container>
      <unittitle id="link390">Lewis, Morris - Chicago, Commissioner of Conciliation, routine
       correspondence</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1930" type="inclusive">1924-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">52</container>
      <unittitle id="link391">Mailing List - routine</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">53</container>
      <unittitle id="link392">McCracken, Fred D. - personal friend of Phillips, requests aid in
       establishment of job.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1928" type="inclusive">1925-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">54</container>
      <unittitle id="link393">McDougald, G.E. (Mrs.) - Harlem Vocational Guidance Committee, joint
       report with DOL.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">55</container>
      <unittitle id="link394">Miller, Kelly - Howard University, "The Farm: The Negroes Best
       Chance," and requests for information.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">56</container>
      <unittitle id="link395">Morrison, Julia - Request for information</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">57</container>
      <unittitle id="link396">Negro Colonization of Africa - correspondence.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933">1933</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">58</container>
      <unittitle id="link397">Negro Labor Congress - Militant news clippings</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">59</container>
      <unittitle id="link398">Nelms, H.G. - Alabama, Obscure union official, requesting
       information.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1930" type="inclusive">1929-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">60</container>
      <unittitle id="link399">Paxton, A.M. - Requests information on Black occupational
       survey.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1925" type="inclusive">1924-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">61</container>
      <unittitle id="link400">Penny, Theodore R. - Pennsylvania, man with plan on home life.
       Phillips arranges interview between him and Governor Pinchet of Pennsylvania.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">62</container>
      <unittitle id="link401">Pennsylvania Railroad - menu.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">63</container>
      <unittitle id="link402">Peters, Robert J. - Pennsylvania Director of Employment Bureau,
       Phillips requests statistics from their office.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">64</container>
      <unittitle id="link403">Press Release - Race Pride versus Profit and Old Age Pension (Negro
       Labor News Service)</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">65</container>
      <unittitle id="link404">Prevailing Rate Legislation</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">66</container>
      <unittitle id="link405">Prevailing Rate Legislation - Virginia</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">67</container>
      <unittitle id="link406">Railway Workers - Indiana, reinstatement case of a woman who may have
       falsified age, recommendation from Phillips to Secretary of Labor to make railroad crimes a
       federal offense.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1932">1932</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">68</container>
      <unittitle id="link407">Requests - for literature on Blacks</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927/1928" type="inclusive">1927-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">69</container>
      <unittitle id="link408">Robins, James J. - Letters of thanks to Phil Brown and Phillips for
       aid in finding employment.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">70</container>
      <unittitle id="link409">Rosenthal, Aaron M. - "The Negro Problem"</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1925" type="inclusive">1924-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">71</container>
      <unittitle id="link410">Schields, R.G. - aid in securing appointment.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">72</container>
      <unittitle id="link411">Scott, Emmett J. - Secretary-Treasurer, Howard University, requests
       for jobs.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1929" type="inclusive">1926-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">73</container>
      <unittitle id="link412">Scruggs, Baxter S. - Director, YMCA Detroit, requests Phillips to find
       job, then gets job with YMCA and wants to coordinate efforts with DOL.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1926" type="inclusive">1924- 1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">74</container>
      <unittitle id="link413">Shepard, J.E. - President, North Carolina College for Negroes - re
       program for 3rd Annual Fact Finding Conference.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930">1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">75</container>
      <unittitle id="link414">Sherard, Thomas W. - job applicant.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">76</container>
      <unittitle id="link415">Simpson, Gordon H. - mailing list request.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927">1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">77</container>
      <unittitle id="link416">Sledge, Wesley L. - Executive Secretary, Republican National
       Committee, Routine</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">78</container>
      <unittitle id="link417">Smallwood, William H. - job applicant.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">79</container>
      <unittitle id="link418">Smith, Olander J. - friend and job applicant.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927/1929" type="inclusive">1927-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">80</container>
      <unittitle id="link419">Social Welfare - Phillips gets prison inmate job after his
       release.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928/1929" type="inclusive">1928-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">81</container>
      <unittitle id="link420">Spurlock, Anna (Compensation) - re widow of deceased Carnegie Steel
       Company employee, denied.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">82</container>
      <unittitle id="link421">Stokes, Harold Phelps - re report on Blacks on steam railway
       lines.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">83</container>
      <unittitle id="link422">Surveys - Report by Phillips distributed without permission of DOL;
       statistics on Black workers from Ohio; report on fact finding committee; re Mexico restricts
       Blacks from immigrating.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1931" type="inclusive">1924-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">84</container>
      <unittitle id="link423">Tennessee Coal Iron and Railroad Company - spring festival for
       children in school.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">85</container>
      <unittitle id="link424">Thomas, James C. - re immigration questions.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930/1931" type="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">86</container>
      <unittitle id="link425">Thompson, A.B. - President, National Association of Railway Mechanics,
       re request information on Railroad Mediation Board.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">87</container>
      <unittitle id="link426">Travel - routine travel authorizations.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1931" type="inclusive">1925-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">88</container>
      <unittitle id="link427">Trigg, J.M. Job applicant.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">89</container>
      <unittitle id="link428">Tuskegee - re summer lectures.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">90</container>
      <unittitle id="link429">Unemployment - Congress, article from "Congressional
       Record"</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">91</container>
      <unittitle id="link430">Urban League - re employment, Negroes; Boulder Dam employing Blacks;
       Survey of laundry workers; reports on industry.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1931" type="inclusive">1924-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">92</container>
      <unittitle id="link431">Vann, Robert L. - Phillips thanks editor, Pittsburgh Courier, for
       favorable write-up on Secretary Davis.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">93</container>
      <unittitle id="link432">Virgin Islands - report of Federal Commission to investigate
       industrial and economic conditions in the Virgin Islands and routine
       correspondence.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1927" type="inclusive">1924-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">94</container>
      <unittitle id="link433">Vocational Studies - New York - request for information on Black
       workers.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1931">1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">95</container>
      <unittitle id="link434">Wages - Pullman Porters - news clippings re tips; petition from
       Brotherhood of Sleeping Car Porters and Pullman Company to ICC to prevent
       tipping.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1933" type="inclusive">1925-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">96</container>
      <unittitle id="link435">Whitney, J.R.B. - job applicant.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">97</container>
      <unittitle id="link436">Warfield, William A. - reference for a steno-typist.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">98</container>
      <unittitle id="link437">Walrond, Eric D. re review of article on Virgin Islands; editorials
       from "Opportunity."</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">99</container>
      <unittitle id="link438">Ward, Colonel Joseph H. - Director of Virginia Hospital at Tuskegee
       Institute re assisting a disabled vet from Indiana.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1927/1928" type="inclusive">1927-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">100</container>
      <unittitle id="link439">Washington, Forrester B. - Director, Atlanta School of Social Work re
       requests for information, materials and favors.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1928" type="inclusive">1924-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">101</container>
      <unittitle id="link440">Webb, C. Cornelius - Phillips congratulating Webb on appointment as
       special investigator and mediator for Pullman Company.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">102</container>
      <unittitle id="link441">Welfare Department - article, "The Need of the Nation."</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925">1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">103</container>
      <unittitle id="link442">White House (Social) - re Blacks as guests at the White House;
       newspaper clippings.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1930" type="inclusive">1929-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">104</container>
      <unittitle id="link443">Williams, Georgia - request for information.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1925/1926" type="inclusive">1925-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">105</container>
      <unittitle id="link444">Wilson, Robert E. Lee - re annual report of the Secretary of
       Labor.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926">1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">106</container>
      <unittitle id="link445">Woodson, George H. - re job applicant of position of Minister to the
       Republic of Liberia.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1927" type="inclusive">1926-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">107</container>
      <unittitle id="link446">Women's Activities - Publication "Causes of Absence for Men and Women
       in Four Cotton Mills;" National Association of Colored Women Conference re planning for
       program; studies and activities of Black women in industry.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1931" type="inclusive">1929-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">108</container>
      <unittitle id="link447">Wright, Eva A. - re instruction of colored women in voting, by
       Republican Women's Club.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924">1924</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">109</container>
      <unittitle id="link448">Wright, R.R. - requests information on Black labor.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928">1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">22</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">110</container>
      <unittitle id="link449">Young, Adele - loss of money order</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link450">Division of Negro Economics. Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link451">Includes correspondence, memos and statements describing the function
       and creation of the Division of Negro Economics; clippings and question and answer mimeo re
       the Division and Negro industrial interests.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link452">re staffing suggestions; appointments; re publication,
       "Negro-Migration, 1916-1917;" meetings; plans; colored labor of the south; conditions of war
       workers; Negro Economics in Ohio; and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link453">re conferences; furlough of Forrester B. Washington to work for
       Division; staffing; cooperation with United State Employment Service; question of
       discrimination within the Department; minutes, 10/23/18; and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link454">re Negro wage earners; staffing; resolutions' publishing a bulletin;
       meetings and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link455">re William Jennifer discharge due to lack of funds; transfer of
       Jennifer and Charles Hall; Negroes in Industry; condition of colored situation in the south;
       and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link456">re mortality among Negro children; Negro women workers; financial;
       meetings; "The Racial Question," speech by Senator Selden P. Spencer (Missouri), 5/22/20;
       publication of a department bulletin; comparison of incomes of Blacks and whites in similar
       indust</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link457">re staffing; re publications of "The Negro at Work During the War and
       Reconstruction;" questionnaire; Negro from colonies; adjustment of work of Charles Hall and
       William Jennifer, Special Agents; and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link458">re functions and work of Negro Economics Advisory Service; and
       routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link459">3 page mimeo entitled "Negro Economics in Florida," no
       date.</unittitle>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link460">Financial papers, includes estimated budget for 1918-1919 and related
       documents.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link461">"Matters of Record" - details functions and organization of the
       Division.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link462">"Program of Work" and "Preliminary Programs" - outline of programs of
       conferences; outline of work plans of the Division.</unittitle>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">23</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link463">"Reports" - includes reports on various subjects; "Negro Migration
       Report;" interview with Senator Fletcher of Florida; reports of weekly and monthly activities
       of the Division; compulsory work law; reports on various localities; Negro Economics in
       Florid</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link464">Division of Negro Economics. Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link465">A- with American Unity Labor Union re discrimination of Blacks in
       labor unions; with G.W. Austin Vice-President Brotherhood of Shop Laborer's re organization
       of Blacks in southern states; "The Armenia America Society," 2 page mimeo; letters
       recommending v</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link466">B - Letters of recommendation from various sources for positions in
       the Division; with T.W. Bickett, Governor of North Carolina; with Clara H. Blackman of St.
       Petersburg Times.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link467">C - with Chicago League on Urban Conditions Among Negroes re
       cooperation with Mr. Washington, Supervisor of Negro Economics in Illinois and the Chicago
       League; with Cleveland Poll Survey Committee to W.B. Wilson, Secretary of Labor re southern
       railroad wo</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1924" type="inclusive">1918-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link468">Carter, Jeanette, President of the Woman's Wage Earner's Association
       re letters of recommendation for position with Department of Labor's Housing Bureau, her
       appointment and later removal from the position.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link469">Council of National Defense - correspondence with Governor Clarkson,
       Division of the Council re the formation of a Committee of Negroes under the Council;
       migration of Negroes from south to the north.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link470">D - re "Dillard Report" on Negro labor exodus from the southern
       states.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link471">E - with G.H. Edmunds, United Mine Workers offering his services as
       Negro Labor Advisor.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link472">F - with Governor of Florida, re discontinuance of the Bureau of Home
       Economics for Negroes in his state; racial literature circulating in Florida; formation and
       plans of Farm Service Division, United States Employment Service, to keep Negroes from
       leavin</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link473">G - letters of recommendation and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link474">H - letters of recommendation and applications for positions; with
       Charles E. Hall, Supervisor, Negro Economics, Ohio re housing facilities for Negroes,
       statistical work on Negro wage-earners; literary with Frank Hallin, Editor of "Method;" with
       Mrs. Joh</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link475">Haynes, George E. - letters of recommendation and support, release
       announcing his appointment, 7 page study and report by Haynes re model village in North
       Carolina and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link476">I - Inter-racial Council re immigration and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1925" type="inclusive">1918-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link477">J - with Mary E. Jackson, Secretary, Bureau of the Young Women's
       Christian Associations, re colored women in industry; with Paul B. Johnson, Captain, Medical
       Corps re assisting colored soldiers with finding employment after discharge and
       routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link478">Jackson, Giles B. - President, National Civic Improvement Association
       re conference with Samuel Gompers, President, AFL, concerning plans for the mobilization of
       Negro farm labor; ideas on the creation of a Bureau of Negro Labor; congested railroad
       situat</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link479">Jennifer, William - President, "The Detroit Compass," re literary
       (1920) and special agent, United States Employment Service.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1921" type="inclusive">1919-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">24</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link480">Jones, Eugene K. - Executive Secretary of National League on Urban
       Conditions Among Negroes, and later National Urban League, 2 page statement re race riots in
       Washington and Chicago distributed by National Urban League, and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link481">Division of Negro Economics. Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link482">K - letters of recommendation from State of Kansas, Governor Arthur
       Capper and other routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link483">L - with Morris Lewis, Commissioner of Conciliation, Department, re
       unemployment for Blacks in Chicago area; legislative bill and memo re creating Negro
       Industrial Commission (1924) and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1928" type="inclusive">1919-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link484">Lynching Petition - petition with several signatures, appealing to
       William Baker, Secretary of Labor, to stop allowing the lynching of Blacks.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>March 5, 1918</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link485">Land Settlement - correspondence with various realty companies re
       available farm lands for Black settlements (including some advertising
       literature).</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link486">M - routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1926" type="inclusive">1918-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link487">Migration - re problems of Blacks migrating to the north and thereby
       depleting the labor supply in the south and plans to try and control it.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917- 1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>6a - Minneapolis Strike - 1917 - re Great Northern importing Negroes to replace white
       labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link488">N - Correspondence with NAACP re colored representation on the
       Advisory Council; re survey of colored workers in New York City; model constitution for local
       Negro Workers Advisory Committee; Newport News, Virginia, re housing conditions and supply
       and dem</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link489">New Jersey - routine</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link490">O-P - routine</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link491">Q - routine</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link492">R - Republican National Committee, Division of Colored Women re their
       recommendations to the President for positions (for Blacks) in the federal government (1925);
       A. Phillip Randolph re Pullman Company; National Urban League, Ira Reid re survey of
       numbe</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1933" type="inclusive">1918-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link493">S - routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1932" type="inclusive">1917-1932</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link494">T - letters of recommendation and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link495">U - United States Employment Service, "Clearance Bulletin" for week
       ending August 23, 1919 and routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1928" type="inclusive">1919-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link496">V - routine</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link497">W - routine.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1926" type="inclusive">1918-1926</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">25</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link498">Miscellaneous memos, correspondence, etc.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1925" type="inclusive">1919-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link499">U.S. Housing Administration. Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link500">General File</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>includes memos from Division of Negro Economics to Director of United States Bureau of
       Housing and Transportation re housing conditions and Negro home registrations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link501">Bixby, Charles R. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>field agent for United States Homes Registration Committee, correspondence re setting up
       colored registries in the Central West.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link502">Bull, A. H. and Company -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence with United States Housing Corporation re application for construction of
       housing for Negroes in Elizabeth, New Jersey.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link503">Commission on Living Conditions of War Workers -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, surveys and inter- office memos re the centralizing and
       coordinating all public and private efforts for providing industrial workers in war
       industries with proper living conditions and recreational opportunities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link504">Edwards, Ray G. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Field agent, includes daily report forms giving summary of day's work, persons and places
       visited and correspondence arranging for separate reports for Negro and white registries.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link505">Ford, James -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Manage, Homes Registration and Information Service, correspondence re organizing Negro
       registries for various cities, bad housing conditions in Northern industrial centers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link506">Hege, Edwin S. - Manager, Washington Homes Division, United States
       Housing Corporation -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence and report forms re types of housing accommodations available in various
       areas; 13 page mimeo "Hearings before Committee on Public Buildings and Grounds. A Bill to
       Establish a Home or Homes for Aged and Infirm Colored People and Working Girls.. April 10,
       1918," and miscellaneous.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link507">McCracken, Fred -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Field agent, correspondence and daily reports re summary of day's work and persons and
       places visited.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link508">Negro Registries -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence re the establishment of room registration offices for dealing with colored
       people in cities; need for room registries for colored women.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link509">Parker, Carl R. -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Miscellaneous correspondence and reports re housing in Newport News - Briarfield, Virginia;
       school needs in Norfolk, Portsmouth, Newport News, Truxton, and Craddock, Virginia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link510">United States Department of Labor -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1922" type="inclusive">1918-1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>file re Negro housing, Negro population and joint resolution for relief of citizens of
       Truxton, Virginia re its housing corporation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link511">Akron, Ohio -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Field agent's detailed report re critical rooming and housing situation and problems with
       getting recommendations approved.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link512">Alabama - Nitrate Plants and Towns -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence re providing housing for workers</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">14</container>
      <unittitle id="link513">Bridgeport, Connecticut -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re Bridgeport Housing Project problems with Portuguese Negro laborers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link514">Buffalo, New York -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Field agent's report to Chamber of Commerce re building more housing for the increased
       population of that area.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">16</container>
      <unittitle id="link515">Chicago, Illinois -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence re improving housing conditions for Negroes in Chicago; meetings with Rental
       Division of the Chicago Real Estate Board; and miscellaneous.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">17</container>
      <unittitle id="link516">Cleveland, Ohio -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>field agent's summary of official visit to Cleveland; resolutions re rent profiteering;
       minutes; complaints re housing costs.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">18</container>
      <unittitle id="link517">Columbus, Ohio -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence re solutions for Columbus Negro housing problems.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">19</container>
      <unittitle id="link518">Detroit, Michigan -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>letter re Negroes forcing Italians out of certain sections of the city.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">20</container>
      <unittitle id="link519">Minneapolis, Minnesota -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re critical housing situation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">21</container>
      <unittitle id="link520">Newport News, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re values of various properties, reports on housing projects, estimates of costs for
       projects, statistical information.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">26</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">22</container>
      <unittitle id="link521">Nitro, West Virginia -</unittitle>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>report re boarding conditions at plant in Nitro. No date.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link522">U.S. Housing Administration. Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link523">Norfolk, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re housing project plans and reports for Norfolk and immediate vicinity; estimates of
       housing sites; living conditions of war workers; architects reports.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link524">Norfolk, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re housing project plans and reports for Norfolk and immediate vicinity; estimates of
       housing sites; living conditions of war workers; architects reports.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link525">Omaha, Nebraska -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>field agent's reports of official visit to Omaha re housing conditions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link526">Philadelphia, Pennsylvania -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence with R.R. Wright, President of the Colored Protective Association re not
       wanting a white person on commission of living conditions for Negroes in Philadelphia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link527">Richmond, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re housing conditions for Negroes.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
      <unittitle id="link528">Saint Paul, Minnesota -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>report re official visit to Saint Paul concerning housing conditions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
      <unittitle id="link529">Truxton, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, budgets re the Truxton Project; includes information on
       construction of development, census forms, Truxton employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">8</container>
      <unittitle id="link530">Truxton, Virginia</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, budgets re the Truxton Project; includes information on
       construction of development, census forms, Truxton employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">9</container>
      <unittitle id="link531">Truxton, Virginia</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, budgets re the Truxton Project; includes information on
       construction of development, census forms, Truxton employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">10</container>
      <unittitle id="link532">Truxton, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, budgets re the Truxton Project; includes information on
       construction of development, census forms, Truxton employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">11</container>
      <unittitle id="link533">Truxton, Virginia -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports, budgets re the Truxton Project; includes information on
       construction of development, census forms, Truxton employees.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">12</container>
      <unittitle id="link534">Washington, DC -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>correspondence, reports re housing.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">27</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">13</container>
      <unittitle id="link535">Youngstown, Ohio -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>re housing conditions</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link536">U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Survey Files.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">28</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link537">"Daily Record of Family Expenses"</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes information on Black families re wages, occupation, number of meals at home, and
       daily record of expenditures.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">28</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link538">"Cost of Living in the Year Ending July 31, 1918" -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes information on white households re annual expenses for food, clothing, housing,
       utilities, furnishings. Gives description of housing.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">28</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link539">"Cost of Living in the Year Ending July 31, 1918"</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes information on Black households re annual expenses for food, clothing, housing,
       utilities, furnishings. Gives description of housing.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">28</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link540">"Record of Food Consumption for One Work" -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes record of food brought into the home for a one-week period. Also includes data on
       income, rent, occupation and inventory of food on hand of Black households.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">28</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link541">"Family Disbursements of Wage Earners and Salaried Workers"
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes data on occupation, income, and expenditures for housing, clothing,
       transportation, medical care, education of Black households.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link542">U.S. Bureau of Labor Statistics. Survey Files.
      Miscellaneous.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">29</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
      <unittitle id="link543">"Family Disbursements of Wage Earners and Salaried Workers"
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes data on occupation, income, and expenditure for housing, clothing, transportation,
       medical care, education of white households.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">29</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
      <unittitle id="link544">"Family Disbursements of Wage Earners and Salaried Workers"
       -</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1936">1936</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes data on occupation, income and expenditures for housing, clothing, transportation,
       medical care, education of white households. Additional data given re housing description,
       assets and liabilities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">29</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
      <unittitle id="link545">National Federation of Colored Farmers, James P. Davis,
       President.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930/1931" type="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>Includes correspondence re complaints about Red Cross relief; reports; Hearing transcript,
       accusing Red Cross of refusing aid to a farmer in Mississippi; clippings.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">29</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
      <unittitle id="link546">"Negro Education, General Survey, Methods and Scope of the Study,
       Summary of Educational Facilities." United States Department of the Interior, Bureau of
       Education. Reprint.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1916">1916</unitdate>
     </did>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="box">29</container>
      <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
      <unittitle id="link547">Miscellaneous index cards</unittitle>
     </did>
    </c02>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>