<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
	<eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
		<eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06036-081av::Ruth Graeber interview on ''Pins and Needles''.)//EN">KCL06036-081av</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Ruth Graeber interview on "Pins and Needles"<date> 1997</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Graeber, Ruth interview on "Pins and Needles"</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
				<date>October 30, 2015</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>October 30, 2015</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	<revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Ruth Graeber interview on "Pins and Needles"</titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 6036/081 AV</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, January 23, 2013</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Randall Miles, October 30, 2015</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2015 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			
			<unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Ruth Graeber interview on "Pins and Needles", 1997</unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1997</unitdate>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">6036/081 AV</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Graeber, Ruth</persname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">0.1 linear ft.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:"> Machine-readable DVD.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">The collection is a video recording of Ruth Rubinstein Graeber discusses "Pins &amp; Needles" at at event sponsored by the New York Public Library.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		<physdesc><extent>0.11 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			
			<p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of
				the first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
				membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of
				its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995
				to form the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in
				1995 represented only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000 in 1969.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			
			<p>Ruth Rubinstein Graeber was born March 1, 1917. As a member of ILGWU Local 32 Corset and Brassiere workers, she was involved in the courses and activities offered by her local, mainly the dance classes. When the dance classes she attended were
				cancelled due to low enrollment, Graeber was told of the various classes and offerings available at Labor Stage. While applying for the dance classes at Labor Stage, Graeber was instead put in the drama classes where she became an actress and
				performer. She was a member of the original "Pins &amp; Needles" cast, spending two and a half years on Broadway and with the touring company. Graeber had solos in the numbers "Mussolini Handicap," "Economics I," and her most famous
				performance "Chain Store Daisy" ("Vassar Girl Finds a Job"). After the end of "Pins &amp; Needles," Graeber took a three month vacation before returning to work in the shop. She died on March 15, 2006.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			
			<p>"Sing me a song with social significance"began the musical comedy revue "Pins and Needles." Produced by the Educational Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union (ILGWU), the show with an amateur cast of garment workers won
				critics and audiences to become the longest running musical of the 1930s. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>The Educational Department began to expand beyond its original function of educating workers in labor culture, and soon started to offer recreational outlets for members including art, music and dance. In 1934, the department was reorganized
				under new director Mark Starr to create three divisions, Cultural, Recreational and Education, managed by Julius Hochman, Louis Schaffer, and Starr respectively. The Cultural Division offered classes in drama, acting, dance and music, and also
				organized a chorus and orchestra composed of union members. For years members had been trying to develop and present labor themed plays, and while many locals were successful in staging small productions, the drama department became formally
				established in the fall of 1934. With Schaffer joining the staff of the ILGWU in October 1934, a dramatic group, the ILGWU Players, was formed from members of several locals. Professionals were recruited to instruct the classes, and Schaffer
				envisioned broadening the scope of the department to create a venture that brought the labor movement to Broadway. At the American Federation of Labor (AFL) Convention in 1935, Schaffer, with the encouragement of ILGWU President David Dubinsky,
				introduced the idea of establishing founding a theater company for New York City's labor movement. With enthusiastic support, Labor Stage, Inc. a non-profit with revenue supporting the Educational Department, was established in 1935 with
				financial backing from the ILGWU. The union leased the Princess Theatre and began renovating the space to become Labor Stage, housing an intimate auditorium, studio and rehearsal space and dressing rooms, with a dedication in January 1936. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Schaffer soon set to work to make his vision, "Pins and Needles," a realitya revue style production that slyly satirized politics and the elite while skewering current events staged for working men and women. Harold Rome was brought in to write
				the music and lyrics, numerous writers contributed sketches, and Charles Friedman was hired to direct (though he would later be replaced by Robert Gordon). Union members and others active in the Educational Department were encouraged to
				audition, and a cast of fifty five garment workers were selected and began extensive rehearsals. The performers were not professionals, and in addition to learning their lines and songs, were also instructed in the fundamentals of acting and
				basic stage movement. In June of 1936, Schaffer staged an early version of "Pins and Needles" using a professional cast to demonstrate the numbers, and though well received, Schaffer chose the unorthodox decision to proceed with the cast of
				untrained garment workers. The official opening was delayed for almost a year and a half to make sure the performers, who were still working in the factories during the day, had sufficient time to practice and rehearse. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>On July 4, 1937, the cast traveled to Unity House, the union's vacation resort in the Poconos, for additional rehearsals that lasted ten days and concluded with a close to completion trial performance of the show. After numerous adjustments and
				fine tuning, "Pins and Needles" held its first invitation only performance at Labor Stage on November 6, 1937. After additional postponements, finally, on Saturday, November 27, 1937, "Pins and Needles" opened to the public. The critics were
				favorable and with good reviews and word of mouth, the show became an instant hit. The box office was busy and tickets in high demand, and by January 1938, performances were sold out. Since the performers were still working full time in the
				garment factories, initially the show only played on the weekends. The garment workers were given leaves of absence from their factory jobs to become full-time actors with pay to accommodate the increased show schedule which now included
				nightly performances. When the primary target audience, union members, found it difficult to obtain tickets to see the show, a second performing company was organized to provide daily late afternoon matinees for the workers. Close to fifty
				skits were created during the course of "Pins and Needles," of which nineteen to twenty-two were performed at each performance, including such favorites as "Sunday in the Park," "One Big Union for Two," and "Lesson in Etiquette." Revisions were
				continually made throughout the three editions, with sketches and songs added and deleted as the show evolved to adjust and adapt and remain current and timely. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>While the show ignored references to racial issues on the stage, behind the scenes racial inequality abounded. Olive Pearman was the first African American cast in the show and initially only had a supporting role and worked as the seamstress on
				the road. Additional African American cast members were added later after pressure on Schaffer, including Dorothy Tucker and Dorothy Harrison, but no Hispanics appeared in the productions. Other cast members were pressured to suppress their
				Jewish ethnicities and forgo religious observances during performance schedules, some changing names and a few altering their appearances. On the road during the touring productions, the African American cast members were often forced to follow
				local segregation laws in the cities where they were performing and encountered prejudice in finding accommodations, eating with the cast in a restaurant, or in the extreme case, being unable to perform. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>To bring the show to audiences outside of New York City, a ten month national tour of "Pins and Needles" began in April 1938 visiting cities Philadelphia, Boston, Los Angeles, San Francisco, and Chicago, as well as smaller towns in between as
				the cast made their way across the United States. For many cast members, this was their first time traveling away from New York and their families, and especially traversing the country on train. Stays in the larger cities were often extended,
				and in many instances the cast was greeted by members from local unions. Multiple companies were formed to accommodate the expanding schedule between touring, evenings and matinees. The original company went on the national road tour, second
				and third companies formed to perform the evening shows and matinees for union members. As the cast multiplied, so did the number of "ringers," or semi-professionals. Schaffer started adding "ringers," talented ILGWU members, and individuals
				with aspirations to become professional actors to replace the initially amateur cast, which created tensions among the various companies. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In March 1938 in the East Room of the White House, a smaller cast performed for President Franklin Roosevelt and Eleanor, whom had already seen the show several times. Afterward, the cast and crew performed another condensed version of "Pins and
				Needles" for the twenty-fifth anniversary of the U.S. Department of Labor. The first road show ended on January 30, 1939 after 319 performances in 34 cities across the country. The original company that was still remaining headed back to New
				York to find the new casts filling all the roles and numerous new numbers added to show. Unfortunately, most of the original and road show cast were forced to return back to their jobs in the garment factories as many became phased out by
				semi-professional replacements. The second and revamped edition of "Pins and Needles" debuted on April 21, 1939 and on June 26, 1939, the show moved to the larger Windsor Theatre. The new edition proved successful, and finally, a third edition
				of the show, "New Pins and Needles," opened on November 20, 1939. After 1,108 performances, "Pins and Needles" closed in New York City on June 22, 1940. The second national tour began a month later and toured the country before playing its last
				show in Los Angeles on May 31, 1941. After the end of "Pins and Needles," Labor Stage did not put on another play and closed. The actors returned to the shops and factories, with only a few trying to turn their experience into a career in show
				business. "Pins and Needles" challenged the idea of labor sponsored entertainment to become a popular hit with memorable lyrics, hummable tunes, and a social message that appealed to a broad audience.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			
			<p>The collection consists of a DVD recording of a program at the Muhlenberg Branch of the New York Public Library on December 4, 1997. Ruth Rubinstein Graeber was invited to speak about the history of "Pins &amp; Needles" and her experience as
				an original cast member in the show. Graeber recounted her time rehearsing and performing and had displayed posters with photographs from the show, and at the end of her talk she plays a recording of her singing "Chain Store Daisy." Also in the
				audience at the library and identified in the video were Elise Bregman Bretton, Eugene Goldstein, and Nettie Harary Schrog. Graeber begins with recounting the history of Labor Stage, the ILGWU's involvement, the classes and activities offered,
				and the drama group that sought to produce labor themed plays. She tells of her own history as a member of Local 32 Corset and Brassiere workers and her involvement in dance classes offered by her local before she came to Labor Stage and was
				recruited by the drama department. She talks of how "Pins &amp; Needles" came about and the amount of work and rehearsals that went into the show before it was ready to debut. Graeber had solos in the numbers "Mussolini Handicap" and
				"Economics I" and then rehearsed privately with the director for a new number "Chain Store Daisy" (Vassar Girl Finds a Job). She was initially concerned that she had so many solos in the show over the other cast members. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>When "Pins &amp; Needles" opened, Graeber discusses the popularity of the show and mentions how all the celebrities that went to see it were brought backstage to have photographs taken with the cast. With sold out performances, the cast
				needed to take leaves of absences from their jobs so that "Pins &amp; Needles" could play nightly. Graeber recounts that she was earning $22/23 a week as a piece worker and needed it to help her family so couldn't make any less in her new
				job as an actor. She remembers that Burgess Meredith, who was head of the Actors Equity Union came to speak to the cast about joining the union, though management did not want to pay the higher wages required ($40 a week for actors). A
				compromise was reached in where eight of the performers joined the union as actors while the remaining members of the show were counted as the chorus. With "Pins &amp; Needles playing every night, Graeber states that an additional 5:30 p.m.
				show for union members for $.25 a ticket was added and performed by a second company. </p>
			<p>Graeber tells in great detail her experience of going to the White House to perform for President and Mrs. Roosevelt. The cast only knew that they were going to play a condensed version of the show with the strongly satirical and possibly
				offensive numbers cut, at a dinner for the Department of Labor, a Labor Gala with 1,200 people. It was kept a secret until only a few hours before that Graeber and the cast would perform in the East Room. Graeber remembers the strict security
				by the secret service, an out of tune gold plated piano, a curtain strung up across the room, and shaking hands with the president who said something to each cast member. Mrs. Roosevelt served punch and cookies afterward. On April 19, 1938,
				Graeber discusses the first stop in Philadelphia, for the road show that lasted eight months and took her and the cast across the U. S. and Canada.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			
			<controlaccess>
				
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Graeber, Ruth. </persname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			
			<accessrestrict>
				
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				
				<p>Ruth Graeber interview on "Pins and Needles" #6036/081 AV. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<relatedmaterial>
			
			<p>Related Collections:
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU records</extref>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780oh.html"> 5780 OH: ILGWU Oral History</extref>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-110oht.html"> 5780/110 OHT: ILGWU Oral histories</extref>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06036-006.html"> 6036/006: Harry M. Goldman "Pins and Needles" Oral History</extref>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06036-031.html"> 6036/031: International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union "Pins and Needles" Additional Scrapbooks</extref>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06036-077.html"> 6036/077: Rose Newmark Collection on the ILGWU Musical Pins and Needles</extref>
			</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			
			<c01 level="file">
					<did>
						<container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
						<unittitle id="link7">Ruth Graeber discussing "Pins and Needles"</unittitle>
						<unitdate normal="1997">1997</unitdate>
					</did>
					<scopecontent>
						<p>1 DVD</p>
					</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>