<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
 <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
  <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06174-016::NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files.)//EN">KCL06174-016</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files.<date> 1987-2008</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files.</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by P. Leary</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
    <date>November 04, 2014</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>November 04, 2014</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 </eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files.<lb/></titleproper>
   <num>Collection Number: 6174/016</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>P. Leary, July 18, 2011</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Randall Miles, November 04, 2014</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2014 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">NYSUT Vice-President's Office Maria Neira Files, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1987-2008</unitdate>
   </unittitle>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">6174/016</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">New York State United Teachers (NYSUT)</corpname><lb/>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Neira, Maria</persname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">7 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">As vice president of New York State United Teachers, Maria Neira oversees the union's initiatives on educational policy and is NYSUT's frontline advocate to the New York State Board of Regents and the State Education Department.
    At her direction, the NYSUT Education &amp; Learning Trust, the union's professional development arm, has strengthened and expanded educational opportunities for teachers and other school staff. <lb/>
    <lb/> Neira was appointed by President Obama to serve on the President's Advisory Commission on Educational Excellence for Hispanics. She also serves on the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute Advisory Council. She is a member of the National Board for
    Professional Teaching Standards and the founding publisher of Educator's Voice. <lb/>
    <lb/> An AFT vice president, she also serves as a vice president of the New York State AFL-CIO Executive Council and as a member of the Board of Directors of the AFL-CIO's Workforce Development Institute. She is a member of the New York State Workforce
    Investment Board, the Greater Capital Region United Way Board of Directors, Capital District's 100 Hispanic Women, the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement and the National Association of Latino Elected Officials Education Fund. She directs NYSUT's
    fundraising as a statewide flagship sponsor for American Cancer Society programs, including the Making Strides Against Breast Cancer annual walks in which union volunteers have raised millions for the cause. She has served on many state committees,
    including the governor's Children's Cabinet Advisory Board and the State Committee of Practitioners, and is a member of several other professional organizations. <lb/>
    <lb/> Neira is a recipient of the Ellis Island Medal of Honor from the National Ethnic Coalition of Organizations, the Educational Leadership Award of the National Puerto Rican Day Parade and the YMCA Northeast New York Woman of Achievement Award. She has
    been honored by the United Federation of Teachers Hispanic Affairs Committee, the Hispanic Latino Cultural Center, Long Island Latino Teachers Association, the Schenectady Hispanic Heritage Committee and the Girl Scouts of Northeastern New York. <lb/>
    <lb/> She previously served as assistant to the president on education issues for the United Federation of Teachers, NYSUT's affiliate in New York City public schools, where she directed a wide range of education initiatives and helped develop strategic
    plans for education reform. She also served as director of the UFT's Special Educator Support Program. Neira began her teaching career in New York City in 1977 and was a fourth-grade bilingual teacher at the Bilingual Bicultural Mini School in Manhattan. <lb/>
    <lb/> Neira holds a B.A. and an M.S. from Hunter College of the City University of New York.</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  <physdesc><extent>7 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <p>New York State United Teachers (NYSUT) was created in 1972 by the merger of the New York State Teachers Association (NYSTA) and the United Teachers of New York (UTNY). NYSTA had been affiliated with the National Education Association (NEA), and UTNY with
    the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). UTNY was the statewide organization whose United Federation of Teachers (UFT), led by Albert Shanker, was the predominant teachers' union in New York City. In joining with United Teachers and affiliating with the
    AFT, NYSUT also became a member union of the AFL-CIO. </p>
   <p>In 1976, NYSUT voted to disaffiliate with the NEA. Some locals left NYSUT and created the NYEA (New York Educators Association), which became the state affiliate for the NEA. In the early 1980s, NYEA changed its name to NEA-NY. </p>
   <p>NYEA/NEA- NY viewed association with the AFL-CIO's industrial unions as undermining the professional image and independence of teachers. The two organizations also differed strongly on aspects of the governance structure, particularly with respect to
    ethnic minority representation, with NYSUT opposed to mandatory minimums. The rivalry between NYSUT and NYEA/NEA-NY in organizing new locals expended a great deal of resources for both labor organizations. </p>
   <p>While competition with NYEA/NEA-NY was a constant focus of NYSUT's organizing efforts for teachers, NYSUT was also organizing college faculty members, nurses, and other non-teaching personnel. Once members were organized, NYSUT continued to advocate for
    teachers' and other workers' rights through contract support and legal services at the local level and political involvement at the state and federal levels, supporting candidates and legislation that protected funding, due process, and working conditions. </p>
   <p>NEA-N Y merged with NYSUT in 2006, by which time NYSUT had grown to more than half a million members, becoming the largest union in New York State.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <p>As vice president of New York State United Teachers, Maria Neira oversees the union's initiatives on educational policy and is NYSUT's frontline advocate to the New York State Board of Regents and the State Education Department. At her direction, the
    NYSUT Education &amp; Learning Trust, the union's professional development arm, has strengthened and expanded educational opportunities for teachers and other school staff. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira was appointed by President Obama to serve on the President's Advisory Commission on Educational Excellence for Hispanics. She also serves on the Congressional Hispanic Caucus Institute Advisory Council. She is a member of the National Board for
    Professional Teaching Standards and the founding publisher of Educator's Voice. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>An AFT vice president, she also serves as a vice president of the New York State AFL-CIO Executive Council and as a member of the Board of Directors of the AFL-CIO's Workforce Development Institute. She is a member of the New York State Workforce
    Investment Board, the Greater Capital Region United Way Board of Directors, Capital District's 100 Hispanic Women, the Labor Council for Latin American Advancement and the National Association of Latino Elected Officials Education Fund. She directs NYSUT's
    fundraising as a statewide flagship sponsor for American Cancer Society programs, including the Making Strides Against Breast Cancer annual walks in which union volunteers have raised millions for the cause. She has served on many state committees,
    including the governor's Children's Cabinet Advisory Board and the State Committee of Practitioners, and is a member of several other professional organizations. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira is a recipient of the Ellis Island Medal of Honor from the National Ethnic Coalition of Organizations, the Educational Leadership Award of the National Puerto Rican Day Parade and the YMCA Northeast New York Woman of Achievement Award. She has been
    honored by the United Federation of Teachers Hispanic Affairs Committee, the Hispanic Latino Cultural Center, Long Island Latino Teachers Association, the Schenectady Hispanic Heritage Committee and the Girl Scouts of Northeastern New York. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira previously served as assistant to the president on education issues for the United Federation of Teachers, NYSUT's affiliate in New York City public schools, where she directed a wide range of education initiatives and helped develop strategic
    plans for education reform. She also served as director of the UFT's Special Educator Support Program. Neira began her teaching career in New York City in 1977 and was a fourth-grade bilingual teacher at the Bilingual Bicultural Mini School in Manhattan. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Neira holds a B.A. and an M.S. from Hunter College of the City University of New York.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <p>The Vice President's Office directs NYSUT's initiatives on educational policy and is its frontline advocate to the New York State Board of Regents and the State Education Department. </p>
   <p>The Vice President's Office oversees the Division of Research and Educational Services, created in 1974, and the Education and Learning Trust (called the Effective Teaching Program until 2005), NYSUT's professional development arm. </p>
   <p>Maria Neira was elected First Vice President in 2005 after serving as Second Vice President for six months; she succeeded Antonia Cortese, who had been First Vice President since 1985 after serving as Second Vice President since 1973. Cortese left NYSUT
    in 2004 to become executive vice president of the American Federation of Teachers (AFT). Maria Neira also serves as a vice president of the AFT. </p>
   <p>In 2007, the titles First Vice President and Second Vice President were changed simply to Vice President, with the duties of each carried over to the officers who held the former respective positions. Maria Neira remains the director of the divisions and
    programs traditionally under the first vice president's purview, and also coordinates NYSUT's fundraising activities for the American Cancer Society. </p>
   <p>Vice President Kathleen Donahue, elected second vice president in 2005, oversees Program Services, which addresses the needs of NYSUT's health care professionals, members of small and rural locals, new members and retirees. It also provides training in
    workplace health and safety issues.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Neira, M. (Maria) </persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York State United Teachers. Archives </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Teachers' union, New York (State) </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   <accessrestrict>
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    <p>NYSUT Vice-President's Office, Maria Neira Files. #6174/016. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-001.html"> 6174/001: NYSUT President's Office Files.</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-002.html"> 6174/002: NYSUT Vice-President's Office Files.</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-017.html"> 6174/017: NYSUT General Officers Records</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-017av.html"> 6174/017 AV: NYSUT General Officers Audio-Visual Materials</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-017p.html"> 6174/017 P: NYSUT General Officers Photographs</extref><lb/>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06174-018.html"> 6174/018: NYSUT Division of Research and Educational Services, Maria Neira Files.</extref><lb/> All other 6174 collections </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">Academic Bill of Rights Talking Points</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to Maria Neira with bullet points re movement by the political right across the country to enact state and federal laws threatening academic freedom of faculty under guise of student free speech, replacing peer review with potentially politically
      driven government review of institutional accreditation; list of states with pending legislation; samples of proposed legislation in Florida state legislature and U.S. House of Representatives; resolution and position paper by American Federation of
      Teachers (AFT), "Opposition to Outside Control Over Academic Decision Making Under the Banner of Intellectual Diversity," and "House Higher Ed Bill Is a Step Backward, Says AFT," noting some remedies to alleged liberal bias would require hiring of
      Republicans to faculties; How a Bill Becomes a Law in New York State</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link7">Administrative Committee (formerly Managers) 12/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tickler questions for facilitators re closing the achievement gap; memos re meeting; issue of NEA Advocate, December-January 2005-2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link8">Administrative Committee 12/07/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Meeting notice</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link9">Administrative Committee 9/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; communications checklist for managers; memo re release time for volunteers for post-Hurricane Katrina relief efforts, September 20; NYSUT constitution with redline changes in anticipation of merger with NEA; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link10">Administrative Committee re LM-30 Form</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Confidential attorney-client memos re filing of required Department of Labor Form LM-30, March-June; instructions for filing; form; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link11">Administrative Committee PAC Lists</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Cover memo to Administrative Committee re Political Action Committee binder updates; memo to PAC coordinators, March 14, 2005; list of duties and responsibilities of PAC members, revised 1/30/03; Local Presidents List by Senate District; list of
      Retiree Council presidents; list of Committee of 100 by Senate District; lists of members of NYS Senate and Assembly; list of NYSUT Board of Directors; list of labor relations specialists assigned to locals</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link12">Administrative Committee 3/29/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for NYSUT/BOCES District Superintendent Committee, March 22, 2005; memo from vice president Maria Neira alerting K-12 local presidents of Regents proposal to raise passing grade for Regents exams to 65, NYSUT's "serious concerns" about it, March
      28, 2005; related position papers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link13">Advanced Placement (AP)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to the editor from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira in Albany Times-Union, "Don't Overlook Minority Success in AP Courses," February 2, 2005; 2004 AP Overview Report in New York City schools by ethnic breakdown and by gender, overall and by
      subject</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link14">American Cancer Society Colorectal Cancer</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Fact sheets re colorectal cancer and wrist band campaign; memos re NYSUT purchase of bands</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link15">American Cancer Society Gala of Hope 3/11/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Flyer, journal tribute rate sheet, and honorary committee commitment form for Gala of Hope event, with cover memo to NYSUT president Tom Hobart from ACS executive vice president, requesting full-page ad, February 15, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link16">American Cancer Society Making Strides Against Breast Cancer Walk 08/2/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Fact sheet re walk; suggestions for activities for team coordinators; text of remarks at kickoff breakfast; printed invitation to 2005 NYSUT Kickoff Breakfast; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link17">American Cancer Society Making Strides Against Breast Cancer Walk Contract</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re NYSUT sponsorship of Making Strides Against Breast Cancer walk; list of number of NYSUT walkers and donations raised at each event location in 2004; list of breakfast dates and locations in October 2005; 2004 NYSUT/ACS Making Strides
      Against Breast Cancer letter of agreement; letter from vice president Maria Neira to NYSUT officers requesting authorization of payment for previous year's contract commitment, noting ACS had not billed for it, May 12, 2005; letter from American Cancer
      Society executive vice president, thanking Neira for checks for 2004 and 2005 sponsorship, June 15, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link18">American Cancer Society STARS</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re School Teams Achieving Results Successfully (STARS) recognition program; press release from Statewide Center for Healthy Schools re first annual awards ceremony, sponsored by NYSUT, October 1, 2004; program for First Bi-Annual New
      York Healthy STARS Awards Ceremony, September 30, 2005; brochures and related materials for 24/7 Let's Go! Healthy Lifestyle Program, by NYSUT</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link19">AFL-CIO see under <ref linktype="simple" target="link275" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">NYS AFL-CIO</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link20">AFT Collier Support Personnel Hearing</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2006">2004-2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Statement of Facts submitted by Florida Education Association re investigative proceeding re failure to transmit per capita dues by Collier Support Personnel, AFT Local 7412, January 4, 2006; FEA Governance Documents: Constitution, Bylaws &amp;
      Transition Agreement as amended May 2004; correspondence; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link21">AFT Executive Council 7/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link22">AFT Executive Council Unionism and Democracy Seminar</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to AFT vice president Maria Neira from executive director of Albert Shanker Institute re seminar, "Unionism &amp; Democracy: The Experience, the Legacy, the Future," scheduled for April 20-21; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link23">AFT Executive Council Conference Call 09/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re conference call; ballot, memo re federal court decision, and related materials re rescission of decision to create an administratorship for Federacion de Maestros de Puerto Rico and revoke charter for nonpayment of per capita dues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link24">AFT Healthcare May 2-3, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re Leadership Development Conference for school nurse members of AFT locals, January 25, with attached information sheet</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link25">AFT Job Training Improvement Act</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from AFT to House Education and Workforce Committee, opposing the Job Training Improvement Act of 2005, asserting that it would undermine the Workforce Investment Act, divert scarce job training resources from unemployed individuals and
      eliminate dislocated worker programs, February 16, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link26">AFT Latino Caucus 6/16/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>"Solidaridad!" AFT Latino Caucus New York Chapter 1st Annual Scholarship Dinner Dance Program, June 16, 2005; invitation; correspondence re ad purchase</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link27">AFT LULAC (League of United Latin American Citizens) 6/30/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed program for 76th LULAC National Convention, "Emerging Latino Communities: Strengthening America," June 27-July 2, 2005; presentation transparencies and disk for session on No Child Left Behind, "Education Policy Today: A Report Card on
      Latinos"; flyers re No Child Left Behind; AFT policy brief, "NCLB: Its Problems, Its Promise," July 2004; English and Spanish versions of brochure, "Pathways to Success: An AFT Guide for Parents"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link28">AFT NALEO (National Association of Latino Elected and Appointed Officials) June 23-25, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re NALEO 22nd Annual Conference; presentation transparencies and disk re No Child Left Behind; AFT policy brief, "NCLB: Its Problems, Its Promise," July 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link29">AFT NEAFT Partnership Joint Council</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Joint communiqu about seventh meeting, held on March 17</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link30">AFT No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Task Force 9/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from Massachusetts governor Mitt Romney to the state legislature with attached Act to Reform Education, September 22, 2005; policy brief by National Center for Research on Evaluation, Standards, and Student Testing: "Fixing the NCLB
      Accountability System," summer 2005; memo from NYSUT executive vice president Toni Cortese re materials for NCLB Task Force meeting, including outline of questions to be discussed, September 21, 2005; spreadsheet, NCLB Continues to Challenge Schools in
      2005, listing Adequate Yearly Progress (AYP) status by state, percent of schools needing improvement, percent of students who scored at or above proficient on state tests, and other measures compared with 2004; description of the No Child Left Behind
      Reform Act (S. 724) by Sen. Christopher Dodd; description of the No Child Left Behind Improvement Act; article by Stateline.org, "Higher Bar Tripping Schools," August 12; list of proposals to amend NCLB's AYP formula; explanations of selected proposals
      to fix AYP; related memos. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link311" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">No Child Left Behind</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link103" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Committee of Practitioners</ref>. </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link31">AFT NCLB Task Force Meeting 5/3/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; background materials, including Center on Education Policy report, articles re tutoring, restructuring from Education Week, New York Times, Wall Street Journal, National Journal, Philadelphia Inquirer, Chicago Tribune; article by AFT president
      Edward McElroy, "NCLB's Unintended Consequences," in American Teacher, May/June 2005; AFT list of NCLB restructuring strategies; AFT booklet, "Redesigning Low- Performing Schools: It's Union Work," 2001</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link32">AFT NCLB Action Agenda 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Bound "AFT Action Agenda for the No Child Left Behind Act, prepared for AFT Pre-K- 12 Local Presidents," March 2005; press release, "NCLB Let's Get it Right: Union Announces National Campaign to Educate Public and Elected Leaders on Improving the No
      Child Left Behind Law," May 19, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link33">AFT NCLB Task Force 2/24/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; minutes of NYSUT Task Force on Value-Added Accountability/Assessment, February 9, 2005; copy of Time cover story, "What Teachers Hate about Parents," February 21, 2005; newsletter, Title I Report: Compensatory Education's Comprehensive News
      Source, January 2005; Federal Funds Information to States VIP Series lists of grants to states, February 2005; list of funding shortfalls by state, from Office of the Democratic House Leader, "Republicans Break Their Promise on Education Funding,"
      September 9, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link34">AFT Paraprofessionals and School-Related Personnel Conference March 31 - April 3, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative 28th annual PSRP conference schedule: "Moving the Union On"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link35">AFT Teachers Program and Policy Council Meeting 5/19-20/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; chair's report; related meeting materials re charter schools, secondary school reform, English Language Learners; AFT press release re No Child Left Behind. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link395" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">(NYSUT) Policy Council</ref>. </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link36">AFT Teachers Program and Policy Council Meeting 10/20-21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; chair's report; related meeting materials; AFT draft resolution on English Language Learners, October 4, 2005; draft resolution on elevating the practitioner voice in secondary school reform; list of members of AFT Program &amp; Policy
      Council, 2005-2006; letter to Rep. John Boehner, chair of Committee on Education and the Workforce, from AFT president Edward McElroy, opposing Family Education Reimbursement Accounts, asserting that it would divert needed funds away from victims of
      Hurricanes Katrina and Rita, October 19, 2005, with attached AFT Proposal under the Provisions of No Child Left Behind to Aid Students Displaced by Hurricane Katrina; documents, Standards for Responsible and Responsive Teacher Unions; minutes of AFT
      Teachers Program &amp; Policy Council, May 19-20, 2005; CD-ROM, Welcome to Teaching from the AFT; NYSUT Policy Council notes for the October meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link37">AFT State Federation Presidents Conference November 16-19, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative agenda; program; text of Columbia State Federation case; memos re travel arrangements</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link38">AFT Video 7/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re filming of AFT video to include NYSUT officers' overseas visit</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link39">Auditor see <ref linktype="simple" target="link510" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Zimmerman</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link40">Bargaining Units Retreat Planning Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for November 14, 2005, meeting; handouts for NYSUT Manager's Retreat, June 7-8; correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link41">NYSUT Benefit Trust Meeting 9/13/03</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Minutes of June 29, 2003, meeting; notification of September 13 meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link42">NYSUT Benefits Conference November 5-6, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link43">Board of Directors Reception Dinner and Meeting December 9-10, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative meeting agenda; memo to NYSUT Board of Directors from president Dick Ianuzzi re constitution update to accommodate unification with NEA, November 4, 2005; redline edits to constitution; memo with text of Randi Weingarten statement re UFT
      contract ratification, November 7, 2005; memo to local president from Ianuzzi re training available for public relations campaigns to support school budgets, November 2; NYSUT Solidarity Fund application form; evaluation form for NYSUT Board of Directors
      retreat of September 16-18, 2005; report of executive vice president Alan Lubin re election results and plans for 2006, November 29; report of second vice president Kathleen Donahue; Report of NYSUT Task Force on Retiree Services, 2002; report of
      secretary-treasurer Ivan Tiger; NYSUT balance sheet as of August 31, 2005; NYSUT membership comparison as of October 31, 2005, vs fiscal year end 2005 (August 31, 2005); consolidated financial statements for years ended August 31, 2005 and 2004; NYSUT
      Benefit Trust Summary of Material Modifications and Notice to Participants, May 2005; related financial documents; social services report; field and legal report; organizing report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link44">Board of Directors Retreat Planning Committee 7/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of retreat committee members; memo re planning committee meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link45">Board of Directors Meeting 6/27/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo; outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link46">Board of Directors New Board Orientation 5/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program; report of first vice president Maria Neira; list of attendees; list of Board of Regents, with summary of powers and duties; NYSUT booklet, Education and Learning Trust: Your Professional Development Source: Summer 2005 Course Catalog; NYSUT
      booklet, School Related Professionals: Professional Development Program; NYSUT Briefing Bulletin, May 2005, "83.5% of School Budgets Passed," with list of school districts whose budgets were defeated; NYSUT Information Bulletin re role of the mentor in
      district-based mentoring programs</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link47">Board of Directors Meeting January 28-29, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira; dues proposal; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link48">Board of Directors Officers and Associates Meeting 1/25/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agenda for Executive Committee meeting of January 28; agenda for Board of Directors' meeting of January 28-29; notes from Officers' meeting of January 4, 2005; list of management/confidential salary adjustments for FY 2004/2005, per May 11,
      2004, Officers' meeting; working 2004-05 salary schedule; 2005 Constituency Awards nominees; balance sheet for Retiree Funds for fiscal years ended 8/31/01 8/31/04; organizing flyers for Associate Member for Higher Education program; memo from NYSUT
      Office of Special Counsel re draft revised NYSUT policy prohibiting sexual harassment, January 25; benefit plan comparison chart; revised dues and revenue projection; 2005 constitutional changes, with marked-up copy; proposed 2005 Representative Assembly
      Resolutions Committee chairs and vice chairs; memo re upcoming AFT conferences re SRP (School Related Professionals), special conference re civil human rights, women's rights, higher education, January 25. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link358" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Officers' and Associates meetings</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link49">Board of Directors Meeting December 10-11, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re tentative meeting agenda; minutes of Board of Directors meetings of September 10-11, 2004, and October 31, 2004; president's report; report of first vice president Richard Ianuzzi; report of executive director, Field &amp; Legal Services;
      list of requests for affiliation; post-election summary from executive vice president Alan Lubin; newsletter of New York State Labor-Religion Coalition re sweatshops; report, Future of NYSUT's Retiree Program; NYSUT Managerial Positions, for approval by
      NYSUT Executive Committee and Board of Directors, December 10-11, 2004; NYSUT Building Corporation membership meeting agenda, December 11, 2004; document, Implementation of Actions by the 2004 Representative Assembly, March 25-27, 2004; 2005
      Representative Assembly action items for Board approval; spring 2005 course catalog, Education and Learning Trust; disks marked BOD Power Point</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link50">Board of Directors Retreat October 28-31, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re plans for retreat; proposed schedule (agenda); list of social/recreational events; evaluation summary of Board of Directors' retreat, November 11; summary reports of items discussed; materials re Regents middle-level policy</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link51">Board of Directors Meeting September 10-11, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agenda for Executive Committee meeting; president's report; vice president's report; report of first vice president Toni Cortese; report of executive director, Field &amp; Legal Services; report of the secretary-treasurer; report of the
      Task Force on Small and Rural Locals: One Tree Many Branches; requests for affiliation; legislative update; State Education Department Resolution in Recognition of Distinguished Service for Toni Cortese; journal, International Project of the New York
      State Labor-Religion Coalition; minutes of Board of Directors meeting of August 4, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link52">Board of Directors Meeting 8/4/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; minutes of June 28, 2004, meeting; materials re 2004 Presidents' Conference on Endorsements; list of members of Political Action Committee; conference agenda; glossy printed flyers by NYSUT re Democratic presidential candidate John Kerry on
      mandatory overtime, access to higher education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link53">Board of Directors Meeting January 23-24, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Outline of report of first vice president; Regents' Report Card; memo re expiration of the term of office of members of the Board of Regents, January 7, 2004; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link54">BOCES District Superintendent Committee 05/16/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link55">BOCES District Superintendent Committee 4/4/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link56">BOCES District Superintendent Committee 12/13/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; county by county impact of alternative state aid scenarios for 2006-07</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link57">BOCES District Superintendent Committee 11/15/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of meeting dates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link58">BOCES District Superintendent Committee 5/24/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link59">BOCES District Superintendent Committee 11/16/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link60">BOCES Leadership Conference September 29-October 1, 2006</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed program for 34th annual conference; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link61">BOCES Leadership Conference 10/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Registration materials; request for speaker</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link62">BOCES Conference October 22-23, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>BOCES issues/comments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link63">BOCES Lobby Day 2004-2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Brief memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link64">BOCES Merger Studies</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re possible merger of Monroe 1 BOCES with Monroe 2 BOCES, August</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link65">Buchbinder Tunick &amp; Co see <ref linktype="simple" target="link510" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Zimmerman</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link66">Budget NYSUT Proposed Budget</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005/2006">2005-2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Executive Committee presentation of draft NYSUT 2005-06 Budget, with cover letter from secretary-treasurer Ivan Tiger, June 2, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link67">Budget Management Planning Committee 5/11/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to NYSUT officers and associates re management/confidential compensation analysis, May 16, 2005; confidential Dick Ianuzzi's Officers' Retreat notes, April 26-27, 2005; outline of officers' meeting, May 3, 2005; program of the 2005 NYSUT
      Leadership Institute at Cornell University, August 5; 2005 committee nominations; testimony of Antonia Cortese, First Vice President, New York State United Teachers to the Senate and Assembly Standing Committees on Education on the Regents Learning
      Standards and High School Graduation Requirements, October 22, 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link68">Budget State Budget</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2005-06 Budget Analysis: Review of Enacted Budget, from the Office of the State Comptroller, Alan G. Hevesi, May 17, 2005; review of the 2004-05 Legislative Budget Agreement, New York State Division the Budget, George E. Pataki, Governor, August 20,
      2004; memo from AFT legislative associate re passage of 2006 congressional budget, noting tax cuts and cuts to education, Medicaid, job training, and other domestic programs, failure of several AFT-supported amendments, links to individual legislators'
      votes, April 29, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link69">Business Council of New York State, Inc. Education and Business Expo</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1989/2004">1989-2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Printed brochure, "Engage New York: A Call to Engage Business in Promoting Education Excellence," by the Business Council; charts correlating reading scores, 4th grade English Language Arts, and funding; program for event at Southern Saratoga County
      Chamber, featuring Commissioner of Education Richard Mills; press release re Education and Business Expo for October 1, 2004; 1990 Business/Labor Education Symposium agenda; Business Council and NYS AFL-CIO working paper for symposium, "Schools for the
      Future"; brochure, "Viewpoints: Raising Our Sights in Education," remarks of R. Quintus Anderson, chairman, The Aarque Companies, before the NYS Board of Regents, published by Public Policy Institute, February 1990; The Anderson Committee Report: Report
      of the Statewide Steering Committee on Preparation for Employment and/or Postsecondary Education, by R. Quintus Anderson, chairman, submitted to the NYS Board of Regents, January 16, 1990; position paper, "What the Business Council of New York State,
      Inc., Thinks about Public School Choice," October 1989</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link70">Business Council of New York State, Inc. Dan Walsh 10/19/99</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1999">1999</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence between NYSUT president Tom Hobart and Dan Walsh, Business Council of New York State, Inc., re meeting to discuss proposal that NYSUT, AFT, and Business Council develop model for validating teaching practices, December 1996-January,
      1997; related correspondence with Marge Mayo, Al Shanker; special report, "Measuring Up in Our Schools: Improving Assessment and Accountability," by the Public Policy Institute, December 1988, with cover letter from Walsh (as president of institute) to
      Hobart; related press release; newspaper clippings</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link71">Business Council of New York State, Inc. Mayo 1997-1998</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1997/1998">1997-1998</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Advance copy of Public Policy Institute report, "Separate and Unequal: The Reading Gap in New York Elementary Schools," with cover letter from the corporate secretary of the Business Council, noting that Marge (Margarita) Mayo, Business Council
      director of quality, education and training, had suggested sending it to NYSUT first vice president Antonia Cortese, February 18, 1998; letters from Cortese commenting on report; cover letter from Mayo to Cortese with article from The Economist, April 3,
      1997; article, "Don't Read, Don't Tell: Clinton's Phony War on Illiteracy," citing high cost and high failure rate of Reading Recovery program, by Robert W. Sweet, Jr., with note from Mayo to Cortese, March 2, 1997; paper evaluating cost and
      effectiveness of Reading Recovery program, January 1, 1997; draft NYSUT Reading Resolution for 1998 Representative Assembly, supporting early phonics instruction, February 20, 1998; draft resolution on BOCES, February 20, 1998; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link72">Business Councils Education Task Force 1/18/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Linda Sanford (IBM executive and chair of the Business Council Education Task Force) comments to the New York State Board of Regents, 9/10/ 04; letter from Sanford to Maria Neira, requesting a meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link73">Cabinet Meeting 12/13/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes from October 25 Cabinet meeting; organizational chart of NYSUT departments; list of future organizing opportunities; Bicentennial Commission Abraham Lincoln Bicentennial Strategic Plan executive summary; letter to UFT president Randi
      Weingarten from Republican Assembly member Vincent Ignizio, soliciting support for elimination of sales tax on books ("reading tax"), November 14</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link74">Cabinet Meeting 10/25/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes from September 27 Cabinet meeting; annual report of the general counsel to the executive director and officers for the 2004-2005 administrative year; 2004-05 Organizing Report; evaluation form, NYSUT Board of Directors' Retreat, September
      16-18, 2005; letter from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi to Gerald Reynolds, chair, U.S. Commission on Civil Rights, expressing deep concern over remarks Reynolds made re Albany City School District, noting diversion of millions of dollars in funds from
      public education by unproven charter schools, lack of federal funding for No Child Left Behind mandates, September 28; background paper, "Current Increases in Energy Costs Present a Serious Problem for School Districts Operating Under a Contingency
      Budget, and an Opportunity to Change the Rules," with recommended resolution urging the addition of energy costs to expenditures exempt from contingency budget spending caps</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link75">Cabinet Meeting 9/27/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes from September 13 and June 22 Cabinet meeting; organizational chart of NYSUT departments; memo re Republican Mainstream Coalition, a group of Republicans with moderate views, and its 501(c)3 not-for-profit research arm, the Center for
      Economic and Environmental Partnership (CEEP), recommending a $2000 contribution from NYSUT for its operating budget, September 26; materials re Higher Education Database Project; memo re retirement consultants</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link76">Cabinet Meeting 9/13/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; flyer, "No Child Left Behind," showing images of children from Hurricane Katrina, photos of President Bush and advisors, with timeline of White House response to event; resolutions due to expire in 2006; memo re retiree health insurance for
      management and confidential staff who were not grandfathered into enhanced benefits, July 21, 2005; production chart for ads and editorial support, online communications</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link77">Cabinet Meeting 5/25/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes of Officers and Associates' meeting of April 12, 2005; memo re PSC support; memo from director of human resources, recommending that mandatory post-hiring medical exams on new hires be continued despite learning of no cost savings on
      insurance rates, May 16, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link78">Cambridge International Career Awards 5/1/00</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2000">2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>University of Cambridge Local Examinations Syndicate Home Economic Examinations syllabus for 2001; materials re Cambridge Career Award for Information and Telecommunications Technology; Cambridge International Examinations meeting agenda, May 1,
      2000</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link79">Campaign for Youth</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to President George W. Bush ("Memo to the White House on Reconnecting Our Youth") with attached recommendations endorsed by over listed 200 organizations for disadvantaged youth, January 27, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link80">Capital Area Labor of Love 5/23/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation; program for tribute dinner "honoring our government, business, labor, and community partners for their leadership, vision, commitment" to benefit the Capital Area Boys &amp; Girls Clubs. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link491" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Two Together</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link81">Capital District Labor Parade Committee Tribute Reception 12/16/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link82">Capital District Labor Parade 10/2/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to NYSUT staff re Capital District parade</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link83">Capital District Regional Office see <ref linktype="simple" target="link418" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Regional Offices</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link84">Celebration of Learning see <ref linktype="simple" target="link508" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Widmeyer Communications</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link85">Charter Schools Q and A 11/22/04 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Fact sheet (questions and answers) about charter schools with cover note from UFT to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, received November 22, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link86">Charter Schools Articles, Reports</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1996/2002">1996-2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>AFT report, "Charter School Laws: Do They Measure Up?" 1996; U.S Department of Education National Study of Charter Schools, "The State of the Charter Schools: Third-Year Report," May 1999; AFT Educational Issues Policy Brief, "Charter Schools Update,"
      June 1999; AFT Charter School Study, "Do Charter Schools Measure Up? The Charter School Experiment after Ten Years," May 14-15, 2002; downloaded articles from Education Week, Education Daily, New York Times, Albany Times-Union, other publications; Hart
      opinion survey of charter school teachers, 1998; NYSUT Policy on Charter Schools, approved by Board of Directors 3/12/99; Charter Schools Institute, State University of New York, press release announcing 90 applications to open new schools in 40
      communities, with attached list, October 25, 1999; materials from the Michigan Prospect for Renewed Citizenship, including three papers, "Are Charter Schools Accountable?' "Evaluating Charter Schools: Questions We Should Ask and Why" and "Test Scores:
      Charter School Students Compared to Those in Neighborhood Public Schools"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link87">Charter Schools For-Profit Industry</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1999/2000">1999-2000</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Profiles of for-profit charter school companies, with cover narrative, "The Changing Face of Charter Schools: Overview of the For-Profit Charter School Industry," 1999"; materials of State Education Department Board of Regents meetings, including
      announcement re Status of Schools under Registration Review (SURR), January 7, 2000, amendment to Commissioner's Regulations re charter school, June 29, 1999, and approvals of charter school applications, March 15, 2001; NYSUT memo re update on charter
      school approvals, May 26, 2000; fiscal implications of New York charter schools</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link88">Choice (School Choice)</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1989/1996">1989-1996</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>AFT report, "Myths and Facts about Private School Choice," fall 1993, with cover memo to AFT Executive Council; AFT research report, "Public School Teachers &amp; Their Private School Choices: Getting the Facts Straight," April 1996; draft special
      report by Carnegie Foundation, "School Choice," 1992; School Choice Proceedings: The Fourteenth Conference of the University/Urban Schools National Task Force, CUNY, October 29-30, 1992; correspondence re regional strategy meeting on choice, 1989; AFT
      legislative alert, November 21, 1991</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link89">Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Meeting 12/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>CLUW National Officers Council meeting agenda, December 6, 2006; Labor Coalition for Community Action Mission Statement; list of duties of national CLUW officers; state assignments of CLUW National Officers Council as of December 2005; list of standing
      committee co-chairs; 13th biennial CLUW convention program, amended constitution, and adopted resolutions, including "The Disgrace of Hurricane Katrina," condemning federal response, calling for increase in minimum wage, "Stop Pension Piracy," re airline
      industry attempt to default on pension obligations, "Opposition to Roberts Nomination for Chief Justice of U.S. Supreme Court," "Wake Up Wal-Mart," "Healthcare Coverage for All," others</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link90">Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Conf. Call 12/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; convention resolutions; event information grid</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link91">Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) International Human Rights Day 12/10/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Restoring every worker's right to a Voice @ Work: Toolkit for Day of Action to Restore Workers' Freedom to Form Unions and Bargain Collectively (AFL-CIO); agenda, resolutions, and related material from CLUW National Officers Council meeting, 12/6;
      health-related flyers (cervical cancer screening, HIV/AIDS)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link92">Coalition of Labor Union Women (CLUW) Correspondence</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from CLUW membership coordinator reminding NYSUT vice president Maria Neira that as national vice president of CLUW, she needed to renew her national CLUW membership, with attached membership application; newsletter, CLUW News (convention summary
      issue), July-September 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link93">Commissioner Mills Meeting 11/7/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Meeting agenda; comments from NYSUT vice president Neira on Regents Policy Statement on Early Education for Student Achievement in a Global Community, September 29; internal NYSUT memos re algebra exam, literacy program; materials re teacher pay
      incentives in Denver, Colorado, public school system. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link112" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Johanna Duncan-Poitier</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link206" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">James Kadamus</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link94">Commissioner Mills Meeting 9/20/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative agenda; June 2005 Regents Surveys Overview Summary re survey of teachers re their experience with the Regents exams; internal memos re exams; memo from Chuck Santelli to NYSUT officers re Education Summit 2005; description of NYSUT goals for
      NYS High School Reform Destination Diploma Forum of March 21-22, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link95">Commissioner Mills Meeting 7/11/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; materials re legal requirements for school year calendar; process for resolving local disputes; important dates for grade 3-8 tests in 2005-06</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link96">Commissioner Mills Meeting 5/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative agenda; issues of concern for meeting with commissioner; review of preliminary draft middle-level regulations; examination dates for 2005-06 school year; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link97">Commissioner Mills Meeting 3/16/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative and revised agenda; list of members of Commissioner's Advisory Council on Higher Education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link98">Commissioner Mills Meeting 10/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from vice president Neira to NYSUT Board of Directors re State Education Department's latest middle-level proposal, September 24; text of SED proposal, August 26</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link99">Commissioner Mills Meeting 5/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft letter (marked confidential) from NYS Council of School Superintendents to superintendents urging support for school finance reform, noting pending court decision in Campaign for Fiscal Equity, May 2004; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link100">Commissioner Mills Meeting 1/28/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; proposed resolution by NYSUT Board of Directors re middle-level education; eligibility criteria for students with disabilities participating in the state's assessment system; spreadsheet showing umber of public and nonpublic school students
      with severe disabilities in various subject categories, 2002; bar graphs showing increases in student achievement since 1999</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link101">Committee of 100 March 14-15, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of NYSUT officers; NYSUT flyer, There's Still a Better Choice, re implementation of Campaign for Fiscal Equity decision; fact sheets on teacher centers, health care, CUNY, SUNY, SUNY Community Colleges, UFT (NYC), K-12; tentative agenda for
      lobbying day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link102">Committee of 100 May 23-24, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Fact sheets on retirement issues, charter schools, higher education, health care, labor, and K-12, with cover letter to the members of the NYS legislature from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin, May 24, 2005; lists of members of state Senate
      and Assembly, Assembly Education Committee, Senate Finance Committee, Assembly Higher Education Committee, Assembly Governmental Employees Committee; agenda for lobbying day</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link103">Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) Pre-Meeting November 28-29, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of members; Recommendations on the Reauthorization of the No Child Left Behind Act; No Child Left Behind: A Road Map for Implementation, from U.S. Secretary of Education Margaret Spellings, November 10, 2005; presentation points to NYS
      Committee of Practitioners re No Child Left Behind Act of 2001; fact sheets; AFT document, NCLB: Let's Get It Right; memo to NCLB Committee of Practitioners from State Education Department NCLB Coordinator Raymond Kespel re theme of retreat,
      reauthorization of NCLB, November 18; memo from deputy education commissioner James Kadamus re proposed amendment to Commissioner's Regulations re uniform violent and disruptive incident reporting system, October 14; handwritten notes. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link311" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">No Child Left Behind</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link30" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT No Child Left Behind</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link104">Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) November 28-29, 2005 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials as above; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link105">Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) 9/14/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for pre-meeting, September 14; agenda for NCLB Committee of Practitioners, September 14; presentation sheets, Update on Accountability, September 2005; spreadsheet re committee key recommendations and status; flexibility for determining AYP for
      students with disabilities; Board of Regents press releases, "Five Schools Named as Persistently Dangerous under NCLB," and "511 Schools Statewide 'In Need of Improvement' under NCLB," September 9; memo to school superintendents from State Education
      Department re testing program for grades 3-8, July 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link106">Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) 5/10/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for pre-meeting; brochure, New York Public Schools at a Glance: Achievement, Enrollment, Funding, by New York State School Boards Association, 2005; draft document by State Education Department, Supplemental Educational Services, school year
      2003-2004; lists of approved providers; School and Accountability Rules Implementing No Child Left Behind, April 2005; presentation sheets, Update on Accountability, May 2005; draft amendment to Commissioner's Regulations re accountability; agenda for
      forum on the Destination Diploma, May 23-24, 2005; draft document, Supplemental Educational Services (SES) Reference &amp; Procedures, May 2005; framework for New York's NCLB Accountability Plan</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link107">Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) 3/2/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Pre-meeting suggested discussion questions re testing for grades 3-8; memo to NYSUT Board of Directors from vice president Maria Neira re summary of major issues, re revised math standards and assessments for grades 3-8, middle-level education,
      December 7, 2004; letter (draft?) to Regents from Neira re accountability and test administration and scoring, December 2, 2004; presentation sheets, "10 Years of Standards in New York State: A Data Based Assessment of Progress Made and How Far We Need
      to Go," March 2, 2005; memo to school superintendents from State Education Department deputy commissioner James Kadamus re Uniform Violent and Disruptive Incident System, January 2005; related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link108">Committee of Practitioners (COP) No Child Left Behind (NCLB) 10/19/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to committee from State Education Department deputy commissioner James Kadamus re next meeting, with attached agenda; State Education Department Learning Standards for English Language Arts, Mathematics (revisited); correspondence from committee
      member Bill Roney re need for more group discussion time, request to put items on agenda, including consideration of expanding committee membership</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">2</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link109">Community College Conference 11/5/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link110">Ann Cook see <ref linktype="simple" target="link399" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Policy Issues Meeting</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link111">Disney Teacher Awards</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Announcement of award recipients for Disney Teacher Awards</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link112">Johanna Duncan-Poitier at State Education Department 6/21/05, 2007</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda, with recommendations for appointments; confidential NYSUT Personnel Committee Principles re promotion when there is a substantial change in the nature of employee's duties, June 16, 2005; letter to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira from
      Duncan-Poitier as Senior Deputy Commissioner of Education P-16, June 4, 2007</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link113">Johanna Duncan-Poitier 11/16/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Proposed agenda for meeting with Johanna Duncan-Poitier; letter from NYSUT vice president Antonia Cortese to Johanna Duncan-Poitier, deputy commissioner, State Education Department, urging consideration of appointments from segments of the higher
      education community not represented on the Professional Standards and Practices Board, specifically direct instructional faculty members from SUNY and CUNY, June 19, 2003; letter from Cortese to Duncan-Poitier, urging the appointment of three teachers
      recommended by NYSUT, July 16, 2004; draft of letter to Duncan-Poitier from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, urging appointment of teachers to two remaining vacancies on the board, October 22, 2004; State Professional Standards and Practices Board
      Membership Matrix, 9/04; list of mentoring concerns; NYSUT's Review/Comments re SED Draft Rubric for Assessing District Teacher Mentoring Programs 11/5/04; letter to Richard Mills, Commissioner of Education, from co-chairs of Professional Standards and
      Practices Board, urging no reduction in 50% rule for full-time faculty in teacher education programs, November 4, 2004; letter to chancellor of the Board of Regents from the Commission on Independent Colleges and Universities re teacher accreditation
      process, October 20, 2004; letter to deputy assistant commissioner of education Duncan-Poitier from NYSUT vice president Cortese, expressing NYSUT opposition to change in Commissioner's Regulations requiring that a majority of teacher education courses
      be taught by full-time faculty, September 2, 2004; Report on the Regents Higher Education and Professional Practices Committee Statewide Plan for Higher Education 2004-2012; Certification Concerns under the New Requirements. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link93" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Commissioner Mills</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link114">Johanna Duncan-Poitier and Joe Frey 10/22/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Talking Points for the Meeting with Johanna Duncan-Poitier: Issues Raised by Professional Standards and Practices Board Opposing the Amendments to Section 52/Full-time Faculty Requirements; Teacher Education Program: Need for Full-Time Faculty, with
      handwritten notation, "Bill Scheverman's comments"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link115">Early Childhood Education Committee 10/29/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda of meeting of Early Childhood Subject Area Committee; letter to Education Commissioner Richard Mills from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira re draft Regents Policy Statement on Early Education for Student Achievement in a Global Community, with
      specific comments on policy recommendations, September 29, 2005; memo from State Education Department re policy statement, July 7, 2005; websites of interest</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link116">Early Childhood Education Briefing Papers 2000-2001</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2001">2001</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Center for Early Care and Education briefing paper, "Early Care and Education for All: Making a Commitment to Our Youngest New Yorkers," Rensselaerville Institute, November 28-30, 2001; Early Childhood Research and Practice, vol.2, no. 2, Readiness for
      School: A Survey of State Policies and Definitions, fall 2000; newsletter of Labor Project for Working Families, Labor News for Working Families, noting paid paternity leave time in other countries, summer 2001</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link117">(ED) Election District Meetings ED 1-4 Western / Southwestern NY 11/8/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira ED 1-4 At- Large Directors Meeting, Williamsville, with handwritten edits, re testing issues for grades 3-8, early childhood proposals, unification with NEA, November 8, 2005; Neira biographical sketch;
      handwritten notes; facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link118">Election District Meetings ED 9-10 Plattsburg 03/11/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Flyer for "Farewell to President Hobart" event; facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link119">Election District Meetings ED 13 Mid-Hudson 09/15/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; vice president Neira's remarks to ED 13 meeting in Kingston, re No Child Left Behind, unification with NEA; draft talking points; handwritten notes; alert memo to PreK-12 local presidents re use of Superintendents' Conference Days for state
      grade 3-8 assessment rating, September 15</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link120">Election District Meetings ED 5-6 Rochester 03/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for NYSUT ED 5-6 Local Leaders' Summit; draft remarks for NYSUT 2nd Vice President Maria Neira, ED 5-6, with handwritten edits; text of Neira's introduction of Education Commissioner Richard Mills; notes to Neira re attendance by Rochester
      Association of Paraprofessionals member who would be recognized as School-Related Professional of the Year; candidate statements by Theresa McSweeney and Kathleen Donahue, running for second vice president; answers from State Education Department to
      questions submitted by NYSUT re grade 3-8 testing program, February 7, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link121">Election District Meetings ED 15-16 Westchester 1/13/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link122">ED 14 Newsletters Tracey Campaign 9/27/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Flyer to Election District 14 local presidents calling for help in electing Dennis Tracey to the NYS Assembly, noting consistent vote by incumbent to block override of Gov. Pataki line-item vetoes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link123">ED 13 and 14 Meeting Honoring Hobart/Ianuzzi Culinary Institute 3/17/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to St. Patrick's Day at the Culinary Institute for contiguous meeting of ED 14 and 14</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link124">Election District Meetings ED 13 Mid-Hudson (Carol Slotkin) 12/2/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; draft remarks for 2nd vice president Maria Neira; facilitative memos. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link478" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Carol Slotkin Conference Call</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link125">Election District Meetings ED 11-12 Oneonta (Dona Vermilya) 11/5/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Final and draft versions of Maria Neira's remarks</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link126">Election District Meetings ED 11-12 Overheads 11/5/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Presentation points re No Child Left Behind</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link127">Election District Meetings ED 5-6 Rochester 10/7/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for NYSUT Directors' Meeting and Local Leaders' Summit; related memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link128">Election District Meetings ED 1-4 Buffalo 10/6/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; newsletter, Southwestern Regional Office Report, September 2004; NYSUT Western Regional Calendar; October 2004 WNYPAC telephone bank volunteer schedule; memo re ING Opportunity Plus 403(b) tax-deferred annuity, termination of relationship with
      L&amp;M Financial Services, September 28, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link129">Election District Meetings ED 5-6 Rochester 3/11/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Final Title I Regulations: Alternate Assessments for Students with Significant Cognitive Disabilities: Talking Points; overview of No Child Left Behind; State Education Department paper, Strategy for Implementing the Regents Policy Statement on
      Middle-Level Education, February 6, 2004; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link130">Election District Meetings ED 1-3 Amherst 2/10/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Information Bulletins re state assessments in English Language Arts and mathematics for grades 3-8, State Education Department approval of alternatives to Regents exams, district-based teacher mentoring programs, No Child Left Behind requirements
      for paraprofessionals, High Objective Uniform State Standard of Evaluation (HOUSSE); New York State definition of a "highly qualified" teacher; January 2004 Math A Regents Exam talking points for Executive Committee meeting, February 12, 2004; overview
      of No Child Left Behind; questions and answers re AFT endorsement of John Kerry; flyers supporting John Kerry, opposing Medicare drug benefit</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link131">Election District Meetings Meeting on Speeches 10/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re meeting on how remarks are prepared for speaking engagements</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link132">Education and Learning Trust 12/13/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Board of Directors meeting; minutes of June 22 and September 27, 2005, meetings; memo from Ro (Rosemarie) Rosen to Maria Neira and Chuck Santelli re interim financial and enrollment report, November 2; memo from Ro Rosen to Neira and
      Santelli requesting approval for online, in-service courses through Video Journal, October 17</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link133">Education and Learning Trust Effective Teaching Program New Course</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Proposal to Chuck Santelli from Ro Rosen for new course under Effective Teaching Program, June 16, 2005; course outline and syllabus, "A Framework for Teacher Leadership". See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link143" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Effective Teaching Program</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link134">Education and Learning Trust Ro Rosen Meeting (In-Service Course) 10/31/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from Ro Rosen to Neira and Santelli requesting approval for online, in-service courses through Video Journal, October 17; memo from Ro Rosen re Teachscape; memo from Ro Rosen re database search results for contract language for "lead teacher,"
      guidance for proposed course, October 14, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link135">Education and Learning Trust Ro Rosen Meeting 9/30/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Brainstorming agenda; memo from Ro Rosen, with Education and Learning Trust timeline of key events, brainstorm framework, Effective Teaching Program enrollment timeline, 1978-2005; background data for staff brainstorming session</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link136">Education and Learning Trust Ro Rosen: Professional Development 8/25/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of areas for discussion, including Teacher as Leader course, need for Education &amp; Learning Trust to have more contact with local leaders</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link137">Education and Learning Trust Ro Rosen Meeting 11/16/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to Chuck Santelli from Ro Rosen re budget; 2004 new member teacher survey summary</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link138">Education and Learning Trust Ro Rosen Meeting April 13 and 19, 2006</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re Record Schedule meeting, meeting re materials for Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link139">Education and Learning Trust Sungard Powercampus Software Demo 01/23/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Message requesting a meeting with Maria Neira and Chuck Santelli for software demonstration</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link140">Educational Conference Board 12/6/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for first annual policy conference, re investment and accountability for student success; conference program; list of attendees; letter to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira, confirming registration; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link141">Educational Conference Board 11/10/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link142">Educational Conference Board 10/6/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; financial statement, October 5 and September 3, 2004; minutes of September 7 meeting; list of dues invoiced to member entities; proposed amendments to Articles of Agreement; list of recurring and priority issues for 2004-05; Preliminary Report
      of the Charter Schools Work Group, presented October 6, 2004; materials from New York State Council of School Superintendents: 2004-05 Enacted Budget Summary, Assessing the Assessments 2004; county-by-county impact of alternative state aid scenarios for
      2005-06</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link143">Effective Teaching Program 12/15/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Updated ELT (Education and Learning Trust) staff meeting agenda for December 15, 2004; memos re December 15 staff meeting of Effective Teaching Program, noting Ro Rosen was director; list of questions, Marketing Phone Conference Follow-Up, December 2,
      2004. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link133" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Education and Learning Trust</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link144">Election see <ref linktype="simple" target="link207" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Kerry</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link400" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Post-Election Summary</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link145">Ellis Island Medal of Honor 5/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program of 2005 award recipients; schedule of events; table seating list; flyer congratulating NYSUT vice president Maria Neira on receiving the Medal of Honor; letters from National Ethnic Coalition of Organizations Foundation, Inc., to Neira,
      informing her of her nomination, January 26 and February 11, 2005; partial list of past recipients; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link146">English Language Arts</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to members of NYSUT Subject Area Committees for Elementary Education and English Language Arts re request by State Education Department for review of revised English Language Arts Resource Guide with Core Curriculum, March 11, 2005; list of focus
      questions; analysis of current ELA core curriculum, comparison with revised core, March 10, 2005; draft of core curriculum, March 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link147">English Language Learners Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005/2008">2005-2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of committee members; invitation to first meeting, with tentative agenda, November 29, 2005; U.S. Department of Education No Child Left Behind Biennial Evaluation Report to Congress on the Implementation of the State Formula Grant Program
      2002-2004; English Language Acquisition, Language Enhancement, and Academic Achievement (ESEA, Title II, Part A), March 15, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link148">English Language Learners (ELL)</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2003/2005">2003-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to vice president Maria Neira and Chuck Santelli re proposed legislation, recommending drafting a memo in opposition, March 17, 2005; text of proposed legislation to allow local high school diploma to be given to students who pass a proficiency
      exam in their native language; NYSUT Special Education Committee 2003-2005 End of Term Report, revised February 2, 2005; report by National Hispanic Caucus of State Legislators, "Closing the Achievement Gap: Improving Educational Outcomes for Hispanic
      Children," July 2003; Testimony of Aminda Gentile, UFT Vice President and director, UFT Teachers Center to the City Council Education Committee Hearing on English Language Learners Programs in the New York City Public Schools, October 5, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link149">English Language Learners Bilingual News Clips</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Article from New York Times re NYC Mayor Bloomberg's change in position on bilingual education, June 25, 2003; National Task Force on Early Childhood Education for Hispanics web pages re task force mission, list of members, 2004; article from Education
      Week re persistently high dropout rate among Hispanics, November 17, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link150">English Language Learners New York State Association for Bilingual Education (NYSABE) Conference March 3-6, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Newsletter re NYSABE 28th annual conference, recent activities, fall 2004; conference flyers; related information</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link151">English as a Second Language NYSESLAT 3/03/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation from the State Education Department to Standard Setting Conference for the New York State English as a Second Language Achievement Test (NYSESLAT)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link152">Executive Committee 9/20/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report of the executive director; 2007 end of legislative session update (NYSUT legislative program priorities and bills that passed both houses of the legislature); memo re final 403(b) regulations; resolution authorizing location of 2009
      Representative Assembly to be moved from Rochester to Buffalo if the labor dispute with the Crowne Plaza-Rochester is not resolved; memo re Citizen Action campaign for comprehensive health care reform</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link153">Executive Committee 12/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda and minutes; agenda of NYSUT Board of Directors meeting; minutes of NYSUT Board of Directors meeting of September 17; procedure for reviewing expiring resolutions; president's report; by-laws of Unity Caucus; agenda for Unity Caucus meeting of
      December 9, 2005; document from State Education Department, "A Call to Action: Follow-Up to the New York Education Summit"; NYSUT Executive Committee managerial appointments; resolutions referred to the Board of Directors by the 2005 Representative
      Assembly; 2006 Representative Assembly action items for Executive Committee and Board approval; NYSUT Building Corporation Board of Directors meeting agenda and minutes of December 9; Building Corporation membership meeting agenda, December 10; minutes
      of Building Corporation membership meeting of September 17, with balance sheet; minutes of NYSUT Executive Committee meeting of November 3, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link154">Executive Committee 11/3/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Booklet honoring former AFT president Sandra Feldman; list of potential speakers for Sandra Feldman memorial; outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira; letter from Citizen Action of New York re Progressive Leadership Awards event,
      October 5, 2005; letter from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi to local leaders re high budget defeat rate, professional development workshops available to build public relations skills, November 2</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link155">Executive Committee 10/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira; resolution supporting creation of disaster relief and scholarship fund; BOCES Committee nominations; memo re management/confidential retiree health insurance, recommending shorter
      vesting period, October 3, 2005; report to the AFL-CIO Executive Council, "Overcoming Barriers to People of Color in Union Leadership," October 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link156">Executive Committee 9/16/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>President's Report; report of first vice president Maria Neira; report of second vice president Kathleen Donahue; report of secretary-treasurer Ivan Tiger; NYSUT membership comparison as of August 31, 2005; report of executive director Pauline
      Kinsella; 2006 Representative Assembly action items for Executive Committee and Board approval; membership maps; New York Teacher December 8, 2005, reprint re combating the achievement gap; description of "Academic Bill of Rights" and "Student Bill of
      Rights," created by California-based conservative think tank to counter liberal views in higher education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link157">Executive Committee 6/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; minutes of May 24 meeting; report and outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira; requests for affiliation; NYSUT Building Corporation Board of Directors agenda; An Open Letter to [CUNY] Chancellor Goldstein on Academic Freedom,
      from Barbara Brown, president, Professional Staff Congress, June 3; document, "We Are CARU: the CUNY Alliance for Responsible Unionism," re "petition decrying the PSC's silence on the blacklisting of Israeli academics"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link158">Executive Committee 5/24/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; report and outline of oral report of first vice president Maria Neira; report of executive director of Field &amp; Legal Services Pauline Kinsella; NYSUT management list; list of officer liaisons to committees; 2005 delegate survey summary;
      2005 Post RA Survey Summary; report on attendance at 2005 Representative Assembly press release and related materials re No Child Left Behind: Let's Get It Right campaign; memo re Forbes article and Attorney General probe into 403(b) tax-deferred
      annuities and the unions that endorse them, April 14</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link159">Executive Committee 3/15/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; report of first vice president Maria Neira; report of executive director of Field &amp; Legal Services Pauline Kinsella; minutes of Executive Committee video conference of February 15; materials re Task Force on Value-Added
      Accountability/Assessment; handwritten notes </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link160">Executive Committee 2/15/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; report of first vice president; testimony of Alan Lubin, executive vice president, NYSUT, to the Senate Finance Committee and Assembly Ways and Means Committee, February 8 and 14; NYSUT press release, "Poll: Committee Chairs' Constituents
      Support Higher Taxes on Wealthy; Want Tax Revenue to Help Pay for Public Schools," February 14, 2005; survey results by Benchmark Polling Group; report by AFL- CIO Committee in the Evolution of Work, "The Changing Situation of Workers and Their Unions,"
      February 1985, with cover note to AFT Executive Council, February 25, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link161">Executive Committee 1/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; presidents' report; preliminary draft for internal use only, "Potential Impact of Changing Regents Passing for 55 to 65"; nominations for "Not for Ourselves Alone" Outstanding Leadership Award; list of NYSUT Constituency Award recipients; NYSUT
      Building Corporation Board of Directors agenda for January 28 meeting and minutes of December 10, 2004, meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link162">Executive Committee 12/10/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; report and outline of oral report of first vice president; list of 2005 Field Service conferences; draft NYSUT policy statement on SED proposals to amend Commissioner's Regulations Section 52.21 related to full-time faculty staffing and
      workload requirements for teacher preparation programs, December 2004; educational issues briefing to NYSUT Board of Directors</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link163">Executive Committee Video Conference 11/15/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos from NYSUT president Tom Hobart re NYSUT/NEA unity, with attached document, "Fundamental Beliefs to Create a Single State Union," November 11, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link164">Executive Committee 6/10/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; report of first vice president; 2004-2005 budget presentation; report by executive vice president Alan Lubin</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link165">Executive Committee 5/24/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; minutes of April 15 video conference; report and outline of oral report of first vice president; addendum: NYSUT Reactions to the May 6, 2004, SED Middle-Level Proposal; text of proposal; financial statement as of April 30, 2004; brochure,
      "Teachers, Unions, and the Fight for Civil Rights"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link166">Executive Committee 4/15/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; report of first vice president; membership and financial report from secretary- treasurer Ivan Tiger; "Middle-Level Talking Points," highlighting newest SED proposal; list of members of proposed task force on future of RAs </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link167">Executive Committee 2/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report of first vice president; minutes of March 25, 2004, meeting; resolution submitted to the NYSUT Board of Directors, Care of Diabetic Children in Schools, calling for licensed registered nurse in every school; material re Regents Examination in
      Mathematics A; spreadsheet re NYSUT/LSA negotiations, tentative agreement</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link168">Exemplar Todd Feigenbaum 11/17/05 </unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence between Maria Neira and Feigenbaum, managing partner, Exemplar LLC, to arrange meeting, noting (USNY?) summit</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link169">Expiring Resolutions</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2002">2002</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Several edited drafts of procedure for expiring resolutions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link170">Sandra Feldman Conference Calls 11/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of potential speakers; minutes of 10/28/05 planning meeting; draft of script for recorded outgoing message on RSVP phone line, 11/2/05, with handwritten list of conference call dates; notice of next planning meeting, with conference call
      information</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link171">Field and Legal Services 12/8/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link172">Field and Legal Services Management 9/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link173">Field and Legal Services Meeting 4/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link174">Field and Legal Services 3/3/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Newspaper clippings, including op-ed from Schenectady Daily Gazette, "National teacher certification isn't worth it," March 2, 2005; presentation re Rochester Teachers Association Dial-a-Teacher tutoring program; Rochester City School District
      Supplemental Education Plan (SEP); handwritten notes from regional staff meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link175">Field and Legal Services Labor at the Crossroads Conference December 2-3, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link176">Field and Legal Services Legal Staff Meeting 11/22/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda of staff meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">66</container>
     <unittitle id="link177">Field and Legal Services Management Regional Staff Directors Retreat 11/9/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>A Guide to Field &amp; Legal Services; agenda for retreat, November 8-10; list of discussion items for officers Tom Hobart, Dick Ianuzzi, Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">67</container>
     <unittitle id="link178">Four-State Study on Improving College Readiness and Success</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>The Governance Divide: A Report on a Four-State Study on Improving College Readiness and Success, September 2005, by Institute for Educational Leadership, National Center for Public Policy and Higher Education, Stanford Institute for Higher Education
      Research</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">68</container>
     <unittitle id="link179">Grow Network 3/3/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Meeting agenda, March 3, 2004; presentation sheets, "AFT and Grow Network: Making Data Useful for Instruction"; newsletters/reports, including sample showing individualized 2004 standardized test results in NYC; folder packets</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">69</container>
     <unittitle id="link180">Health and Safety Conference March 11-13, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative program; invitation to local presidents</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">70</container>
     <unittitle id="link181">PFT Health and Welfare Fund February 25-26, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Poster for "Programs for Teaching" conference sponsored by Philadelphia Federation of Teachers Health and Welfare Fund; agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">71</container>
     <unittitle id="link182">High School Focus Group 5/17/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of teachers, high school focus group participants; memos; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">72</container>
     <unittitle id="link183">High Schools PSA 4/26/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of high school focus group participants; memos; list of low-performing schools</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">73</container>
     <unittitle id="link184">High-Tech High Schools 6/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re setting up meeting to discuss high-tech high schools, with handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">74</container>
     <unittitle id="link185">Higher Education Council Meeting 9/30/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; outline of introductory remarks, noting attendance by Deputy Commissioner of Education Johanna Duncan-Poitier</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">75</container>
     <unittitle id="link186">Higher Education Council Meeting 4/7/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Minutes of NYSUT Higher Education Council meeting of April 7; articles from Inside Higher Education: "Next Step for Higher Ed Act," September 9; "Rare Win for Private College Unions," "A Gag on Public Faculty?" "New Challenge to Evolution," August 29;
      "Calling Off Ann Coulter," September 1</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">76</container>
     <unittitle id="link187">Higher Education Council Meeting January 7-8, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">77</container>
     <unittitle id="link188">Higher Education Council Meeting October 22-23, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of members of council; draft Master Plan 2004- 2008, State University of New York; Master Plan 2004-2008, City University of New York; articles from Chronicle of Higher Education; correspondence from State Education Department</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">78</container>
     <unittitle id="link189">Higher Education Database Project 5/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Meeting agenda; statement of purpose; outlines of design team, finance elements, characteristics of students and faculty; charts showing changes in state and local share of school revenues, 1982-2004, annual change in state aid, 1990-2005; school aid
      in the 2005-06 legislative budget; School District/ Community Special Information Packet: Newark, for Rochester Regional Office Negotiations Workshop, January 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">79</container>
     <unittitle id="link190">Higher Education Full-Time Faculty Policy Modification 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence between NYSUT vice president Maria Neira and Education Deputy Commissioner Poitier re change in Commissioner's Regulations re full-time faculty requirements for accreditation of institutions of higher learning for education programs</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">80</container>
     <unittitle id="link191">Higher Education Lobby Day February 28-March 1, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">81</container>
     <unittitle id="link192">Hispanic Affairs Committee (HAC) Gala (UFT) 1/26/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation and correspondence; handwritten notes for remarks; newspaper clipping (opinion column re teacher pay); tickets to event; memorabilia; letter to Randi Weingarten, president, UFT, from Puerto Rican Legal Defense and Education Fund re annual
      awards gala, November 17, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">82</container>
     <unittitle id="link193">HAC Gala Event 11/30/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program; handwritten notes for remarks; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">83</container>
     <unittitle id="link194">HAC/Somos El Futuro</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of contacts</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">84</container>
     <unittitle id="link195">2005 Hispanic Heritage Month</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Census facts; list of events</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">85</container>
     <unittitle id="link196">Hispanic Caucus</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Top 3 Policy Recommendations from 2004 Issues Conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">86</container>
     <unittitle id="link197">NYSUT History Project</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1989/1990">1989-1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to vice president Antonia Cortese re NYSUT history project, with attached questions for oral history interview, developed by interns, November 1, 1989; follow-up letter from Hobart admitting to not reading the
      questions thoroughly, noting that questions re 1978 convention were inappropriate and would not be included, November 2; Outline for Video History of New York State United Teachers, covering period 1960-71, discussing issues re merger between NYSTA and
      United Teachers of New York; brochure, "We Are the People Who Help New York to Learn" April 1990</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">3</container>
     <container type="folder">87</container>
     <unittitle id="link198">Holiday/ Solidarity Reception 12/3/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Flyer for Holiday/Solidarity Reception at NYSUT Southwest Regional Office</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link199">Independent Commission on Public Education (ICOPE)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Documents, ICOPE's Vision and ICOPE Education Action Summit Platform: Building a Human Rights Vision for New York City Public Schools; list of Teachers of the Year, 1965-2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link200">ING Life Insurance: Opportunity Plus</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Description of benefit for NYSUT members; letters to members from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi and benefits chair Ivan Tiger</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link201">Inservice Meeting 5/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Progress report for planned conference, tentatively planned for March 23-24, 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link202">In-Service Conference Debriefing 2/3/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference Evaluation Report on 23rd Annual Statewide Conference on Inservice Education, October 23-24, 2004; debriefing reports from co-chairs, others; revenue and expense reports</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link203">Inservice Conference 10/24-26/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program for 23rd Annual Statewide Conference on Inservice Education, "Strengthening Teaching and Learning"; talking points and text of remarks for Maria Neira, introducing keynote speaker, Dr. Terrence Roberts; biography of Dr. Roberts</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link204">Job Training Improvement Act see <ref linktype="simple" target="link25" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT Job Training Improvement Act</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link205">Just For The Kids 11/19/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to NYSUT president Tom Hobart from Susan D. Phillips, chair of Just For The KidsNew York (JFTK) and dean of the School of Education, SUNY University at Albany, inviting him to join Advisory Board of JFTK, describing program, October 20, 2004;
      handwritten note re conversation with Jeanette Angelo, SUNY Albany, November 3, 2004; memo from Phillips to Chuck Santelli, welcoming him to advisory board, November 10, 2004; memo from Phillips re high performing schools, with attached list, including
      racial and income demographics; minutes of Advisory Board meeting of 11/19/04</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link206">James Kadamus Q and A Grades 3-8 Testing Program New York Teacher Article December 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Article by James Kadamus, State Education Department Deputy Commissioner for Elementary, Middle, Secondary, and Continuing Education; questions and answers re mathematics and English language arts test for grades 3-8. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link251" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Mathematics Standards Committee (SED)</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link207">Kerry/Bush Debate House Party 9/30/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to NYSUT Headquarters staff, Public Employees Federation, CSEA, and Capital District Area Labor Federation, from NYSUT executive director Alan Lubin, inviting them to party to view screening of film about Democratic presidential candidate and
      decorated Vietnam war hero, "Going Upriver: The Long War of John Kerry," attend dinner, and then watch the presidential debate between Kerry and incumbent president George W. Bush, September 20; save-the-date memo from Lubin to NYSUT headquarters staff
      re September 30 Kerry/Bush debate "house party," September 16. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link207" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Post-Election Summary</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link208">LM-2 Reporting</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from Maria Neira estimating percentage of time spent on U.S. Department of Labor categories (representational, political and lobbying, contributions, gifts, and grants, general overhead, and union administration), for annual LM-2 report, November
      10, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link209">Local Action Project (LAP)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Presentation sheets, mostly photos, "Energizing Locals for Greater Success"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link210">LAP 2005 (2004 Conference Evaluations et al.)</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Program for 2005 conference; evaluations; applications, with local information; letters to Hempstead Teachers Association and several other locals re acceptance in Local Action Project, May 9, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link211">LAP Review of 2005 LAP Planning Conference 9/26/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2005 NYSUT LAP Conference (July 18-21, 2005) Evaluations; Local Action Project 2005 program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link212">LAP Summer Planning Conference July 18-21, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2005 Local Action Project Summer Planning Conference: Maria Neira's Opening Remarks (several drafts); introduction of Mark Richard by Maria Neira; program; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link213">LAP Summer Planning Conference 7/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Local Action Project Summer Planning Conference: Maria Neira's Opening Remarks</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link214">LAP 2005 4/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Notes on meeting of April 22; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link215">LAP Budget Requests</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2006/2007">2006-2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>LAP budget requests for various locals, marked "Class of 2005," "Class of 2006," "Class of 2007"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link216">LAP Budget Meeting 10/31/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Annual budget submission instructions; memo to LAP Committee re 2005-2006 grant requests, November 1, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link217">LAP Budget Meeting 7/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Instructions for annual budget submission; memos re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link218">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee Meeting 3/6/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Pre-RA Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference meeting agenda, March 6, 2006; meeting minutes of January 27, 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link219">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee Meeting 12/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference program, May 3-4, 2006; meeting minutes of Pre-RA Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference planning meeting of October 4, 2005;</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link220">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee Meeting 2006 Zoilo Rodriguez 10/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Tentative schedule for Pre-RA Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference, April 6-7, 2005; program; meeting agenda of October 4, 2005; 2005 Local Presidents' Conference Evaluations; correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link221">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee Meeting 10/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link222">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee Tom Anapolis Meeting 4/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>2005 New Local Presidents' timeline; program; flyer re conference; letters of invitation; related correspondence. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link272" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">New Local Presidents</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link223">Local Presidents Conference Summary April 6-7, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summary of responses to questions re testing requirements, other issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link224">Local Presidents Conference Meeting 3/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link225">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee 11/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; tentative schedule for NYSUT Pre-RA Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference, April 6-7, 2005; program for Pre-Representative Assembly NYSUT Local Presidents' Conference, March 23-25, 2004; 2004 Local Presidents' Conference Evaluation
      Form</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link226">Local Presidents Conference Planning Committee Meeting 12/17/03</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; tentative schedule for NYSUT Pre-RA Local Presidents' Conference, March 24-25, 2004; Newsweek column, "A New Kind of Poverty," by Anna Quindlen, December 1, 2003; memos; evaluations from 2003 Local Presidents' Conference; related
      correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link227">Local Presidents Survey K-12 Executive Summary 2004-2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft executive summary</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link228">Pre-RA Local Presidents Conference Planning Meeting 2/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda of 2005 Pre-RA Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference planning meeting of February 23, 2004; conference agenda; planning meeting minutes of December 15, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link229">Pre-RA Local Presidents and Retiree Council Conference Planning Meeting 12/15/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Local and Retiree Council Presidents' Conference program, April 6-7, 2005; conference planning meeting minutes of November 12, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link230">Management Meeting 12/9/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; materials re "Effective Teaching Program, NYSUT's Education and Learning Trust"; letter to local presidents re Education and Learning Trust, December 6, 2004; 2005 course catalog for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link231">Managers Monthly Reports December 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Research Department manager's report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link232">Managers Monthly Reports November 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Educational Services Department manager's report; Research Department manager's report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link233">Managers Monthly Reports September 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; Research Department manager's report; July/August monthly report for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link234">Managers Monthly Reports August 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Educational Services Department manager's report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link235">Managers Monthly Reports July 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress reports for July and August; Educational Services Department manager's report; Research Department manager's report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link236">Managers Monthly Reports June 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; Educational Services Department manager's report; Research Department manager's report; monthly report for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link237">Managers Monthly Reports May 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; Educational Services Department manager's report; Research Department manager's report; monthly report for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link238">Managers Monthly Reports April 05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; Educational Services Department manager's reports for March and April; Research Department manager's report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link239">Managers Monthly Reports March 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link240">Managers Monthly Reports January 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link241">Managers Monthly Reports December 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; monthly report for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link242">Managers Monthly Reports November 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; Research Department manager's report; monthly report for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link243">Managers Monthly Reports October 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>School Finance and Policy Development progress report; Research Department manager's report; monthly report for Education and Learning Trust</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link244">Managers Meeting 7/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo reminder of meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link245">Managers Retreat June 7-8, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Participant feedback sheets; text of welcoming remarks by first vice president Maria Neira, outlining objectives of the meeting; text of remarks by president Richard Ianuzzi, discussing mission statement, unification, changes in management titles;
      small group discussion items</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link246">Managers Retreat Planning Committee Meeting 6/03/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi re management title changes, June 3, 2005; 2005 NYSUT Management list; 2005-2008 NYSUT Committees Officer Liaisons</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link247">Managers Retreat Planning Committee Meeting 5/24/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Proposed retreat agenda; minutes of Planning Committee meeting of May 11; agenda of Planning Committee meeting of May 4; possible questions for discussion; text of Maria Neira's and Richard Ianuzzi's remarks; small group discussion items</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link248">Math League see <ref linktype="simple" target="link282" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">NYS Math League</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link249">Math Test Grades 4 and 8 Press Conference 10/6/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Charts, graphs, and spreadsheets re elementary and middle-level mathematics in public schools, 1999-2004, district and school performance for intermediate-level mathematics; memo re press conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link250">Mathematics and Science Partnership Grant Program see <ref linktype="simple" target="link313" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">NCLB Mathematics and Science Partnership Grant Program</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link251">Mathematics Standards Committee (SED) Grades 3-8 November 17, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>State Education Department Math Survey: Suggested NYSUT Response; report of the State Education Department Mathematics Standards Committee, October 27, 2005; request for public comment; agenda for NYSUT mathematics meeting, November 17, 2004; list of
      participants; draft survey questions for new math standards; presentation sheets re NYS's learning standards and grade 3-8 testing in English language arts and mathematics, fall 2004. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link206" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">James Kadamus Q&amp;A Grades 3-8 Testing Program</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link252">Mentor-Teacher Contract Language Search 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Document by NYSUT Research Department, Contract Language Search on Mentor/Teacher, listing text of contract language from South Lewis, Fredonia, Beaver River, Cazenovia, Harrison, South Glens Falls, Clarence, Fairport, Grand Island, Kenmore, and
      Hunter-Tannersville teachers associations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link253">Middle Level Education</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2007">2004-2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Preliminary draft of proposed amendments to sections 100.3 and 100.4 of Commissioner's Regulations relating to implementation of Middle-Level Strategy, April 29, 2005; ACT policy report, College Readiness Begins in Middle school, 2005; revised Strategy
      to Implement the Regents Policy Statement on Middle-Level Education, December 1, 2004; Report of the New York City Council Middle School Task Force, August 2007; Executive Summary, Breaking Ranks in the Middle: Strategies for Leading Middle Level Reform,
      by National Association of Secondary School Principals and the Education Alliance, Brown University; A Voice from the Middle: Highlights of the 2007 NASSP/PDK Middle School Student Poll; Regents discussion items, Public Reaction to Alternative Approaches
      to Implementation of the Regents Policy Statement on Middle-Level Education, January 7, 2004, and Strategy for Implementing the Regents Policy Statement on Middle-Level Education, February 6, 2004; State Education Department press release, "The New York
      State Education Department Announces Essential Elements: Schools-to-Watch Recognition Program," March 1, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link254">Middle Level Liaisons Meeting 05/19/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; materials from the May 20-21, 2004, meeting of Middle-Level Liaisons, October 4, 2004; Essential Elements of Standards-Focused Middle-Level Schools and Programs, revised 2003; Middle Level Rubric Development, by Learner-Centered Initiatives,
      Ltd., for Statewide Network of Middle Level Education Liaisons, May 21, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link255">Middle Level: Hudson City Schools</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from Deputy Commissioner James Kadamus to James N. Baldwin, district superintendent of Rensselaer, Columbia and Greene Counties, re issues identified in Hudson City School District, including continued over-classification of black students as
      disabled, highest percentage of reported incidents of disruptive or violent behavior in the state, requesting meeting, July 1, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link256">Middle Level Proposal</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from State Education Chancellor Robert M. Bennett to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira re Three-Model Strategy to Implement the Regents Policy Statement on Middle-Level Education, specifically her concerns re Model C applications and ability of
      district superintendents to approve applications, March 2, 2005; memo from Maria Neira to NYSUT Board of Directors re her letter to Kadamus, continuing uncertainty over implementation of models, November 2, 2004; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link257">Middle Level Education Lee Cutler October-November 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from Maria Neira to Chancellor Robert M. Bennett re latest version of Middle-Level proposal, October 28, 2004; memos re Lee Cutler</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link258">NAEP (National Assessment of Educational Progress) Science Report</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>"Less Than Proficient: A Review of the Draft Science Framework for the 2009 National Assessment of Educational Progress," by Paul R. Gross, October 24, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link259">National Association of Latino Elected and Appointed Officials (NALEO) DC Summit 10/13/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft agenda for summit, the State of Latino Education; summary of National Council of State Legislatures (NCSL) final report on No Child Left Behind; recommendations of NCSL task force; presentation sheets on NCLB for NYS NAACP workshop; report,
      Immigration Trends and Their Implications for U.S. Schools, Migration Policy Institute; AFT presentation sheets re NCLB</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link260">NALEO National Education Leadership Initiative (NELI) National Advisory Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to Maria Neira from NALEO, thanking her for agreeing to serve on advisory committee of NELI, January 5, 2005; invitation to join and description of NELI, October 18, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link261">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005/2007">2005-2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to Maria Neira from Johanna Duncan-Poitier, deputy commissioner of education, re districts receiving Mentor Teacher Internship Program (MTIP) funds, July 14, 2005; Education Week article, "Sidetracking the Debate On Teacher Quality," November
      15, 2005, with cover letter to Board of Directors of National Board for Professional Teaching Standards (NBPTS), December 14, 2006; NBPTS biographies of slate of candidates for Exceptional Needs Standards Committee, with cover letter to Board of
      Directors, November 20, 2006; NYSUT charts, National Board Certified Teacher Data as of January 9, 2007; Education Week online article, "National Board Teachers No Better Than Other Educators, Long-Awaited Study Finds," May 9, 2006; NBPTS bylaws, list of
      board members, and other materials, sent to Maria Neira as new board member, November 9, 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link262">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Meeting 12/8/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Information Bulletin re National Board Certification, February 2006; Q&amp;A for NYSUT Local Leaders; paper, "Using National Standards to Redesign Master's Degrees for Teachers: A Guide for Institutions of Higher Learning" by Joan Packer
      Isenberg, February 2003; brochures; presentation sheets re statistics on certification, funding; list of certified teachers in NYS; CD, "Awareness and Recruitment Toolkit," December 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link263">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Certification 2005-2007</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>A Candidate's Guide to National Board Certification, 2006-2007 and 2005; letter from Maria Neira congratulating teacher for certification, with tentative agenda for celebration event, March 2005; proposal for summit meeting; fact sheet on certification
      rates; list of candidates (?); map of 2004 National Board Certified Teachers by school district locations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link264">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Press Conference 12/2/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NBPTS Press release, "Students of National Board Certified Teacher Achieve Larger Gains on Statewide Math Test in Florida; New Research Points to National a Board Certification as Key Indicator of Teacher Quality," November 17, 2004; NYSUT press
      release with attached list of NYS teachers earning national certification, December 2, 2004; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link265">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Press Conference 11/30/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Press conference agenda, November 30, 2005; talking points for Maria Neira for National Board Certified Teachers Press Conference; text of remarks by Neira; memo with additional information as context for Neira; national data re certified teachers;
      list of certified teachers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">4</container>
     <container type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link266">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards National Board Certified Teachers</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005/2007">2005-2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Key points about the 2006 NBPTS score release, noting dramatic increase; press release, "Number of National Board Certified Teachers Tops 55.000: Nearly 7,800 teachers achieve National Board Certification in 2006," January 9, 2007; 2006 NBPTS Score
      Release Key Messages and Talking Points; talking points for Maria Neira at May 21, 2005, press conference; presentation sheets for NBPTS Board of Directors meeting, "National Board Certified Teachers: Rhetoric, Research, and Reality," October 14, 2006;
      Education Week article, "Sidetracking the Debate on Teacher Quality: Have high expectations given way to the lowest common denominator?" re shift in emphasis since of No Child Left Behind; press release, "NBPTS Elects New Board Members: Board members
      include 11 National Certified Teachers," November 14, 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link267">National Center for Missing and Exploited Children, n.d.</unittitle>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Description of nonprofit organization and services</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link268">NEA Staff Meet and Greet 11/30/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation and memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link269">NYSUT Employees Outreach Network (NEON) Committee 9/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from NEON Committee re year-end results and 2005-2006 planned activities; report of activities and charities benefitting from Dress Down Day, June August 2005; materials re Guide Dog Foundation for the Blind, Catholic Charities, March of Dimes,
      American Cancer Society, other charitable organizations; memos re events</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link270">NEON: Special Events Day 4/29/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letters to community charity organizations from NEON Committee, and copies of contribution checks</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link271">NEON Committee</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for September 22 meeting; minutes of September 9 meeting; holiday gift wrapping service/fundraiser flyer and signup sheet; year-end report and 2005-06 schedule; list of Title I schools in need of improvement under No Child Left Behind, for NYC
      and upstate, September 2002; correspondence re NEON activities for March-May 2005, December 2004-February 2005; materials re Dress Down Day </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link272">New Local Presidents Conference July 11-14, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference program; bullet points, Maria's intro for Jim Wood (final and earlier draft); outline of general remarks by Maria Neira; intro to AFT History Video: "A Proud Tradition," NLPC, July 12; agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link273">New Local Presidents Conference (NLPC) Debriefing 10/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Evaluation forms</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link274">New Local Presidents Conference (NLCP) Meeting 7/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference program; related correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link275">NYS AFL-CIO</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005/2006">2005-2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Constitution of New York State AFL-CIO, as amended through August 2004; letter from NYS AFL-CIO president Denis Hughes to Maria Neira, congratulating her on her election as vice president of the state federation, September 12, 2005; cover memo to
      Executive Council members re federal election law for union staff using union resources, with attached document, January 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link276">NYS AFL-CIO Executive Council Meeting 12/09/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Meeting agenda; resolution re executive structure; resolution re retirement of Paul Cole as secretary-treasurer; letter of resignation from Cole, November 3, 2005; minutes of August 3, 2005, meeting; budget projection, by department, for period of July
      1, 2005 to June 30, 2006; letter to Maria Neira informing her that she had been recommended for election as vice president of the New York State AFL-CIO, October 31, 2005; Neira biographical sketch; list of program services recommended for Retiree
      Services; Unity Caucus 2005 membership list (directors); letter to NYS AFL-CIO president Denis Hughes from Rep. Vito Fosella, informing him that Worker's Compensation funding of $125 million for 9/11 recovery workers had been restored, November 29,
      2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link277">NYS AFL-CIO COPE (Committee on Political Education) Report 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from House Speaker Dennis Hastert to Rep. Vito Fosella, assuring him that $125 million in Worker's Compensation funding for 9/11 recovery workers would be restored, November 21, 2005; newspaper clipping from The Chief Civil Service Leader: The
      Civil Employees' Weekly, re restoration of funding, December 2, 2005; COPE Report, calling field operation for Budget Reform proposal one of the worst statewide efforts in recent history, in contrast to the winning campaign for the Transportation Bond
      Act, December 9, 2005; campaign materials for propositions and candidate; unofficial Board of Elections results for propositions, by county</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link278">NYS AFL-CIO COPE Day at the Races 16th Annual Benefit 8/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to benefit for Committee on Political Education (COPE) at Saratoga Race Course</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link279">National AFL-CIO Convention 7/25-29/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>AFL-CIO Convention Key Issues for AFT Delegates, noting AFT position on resolutions; letter from Westchester-Putnam Counties AFL-CIO Central Labor Body to Maria Neira, asking that NYSUT pay one-time extra month in dues to AFL-CIO so that delegates
      would be assured of ability to vote at convention, August 1, 2005; critical report of July 4, 2005, NEA convention, by the Education Intelligence Agency, forwarded to NYSUT officers, July 5, 2005; e-mail reports of NYSUT at AFL-CIO convention, July
      24-28, 2005; update from AFT Legislation Department, "House Narrowly Approves CAFTA After Midnight Vote," July 28, 2005; AFT press release, "Statement by Edward J. McElroy, President, American Federation of Teachers, on CAFTA (Central American Free Trade
      Agreement): Wrong Rx for U.S. Economy and Workers," July 28, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link280">NYS AFL-CIO 1/5/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to State of the State Breakfast Reception</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link281">NYS Council of School Superintendents September 25-27, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Conference program: "Achievement and the Arts: Advancing Student Success"; letters of invitation to Charles Santelli and Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link282">NYS Math League</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos requesting check for winner of 2005 Mathematics League Competition, address correction; copy of check; correspondence re 2004 winner; memo ordering plaque, specifying wording; correspondence re 2003 and 2002 winners</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link283">New York Teacher 9/5/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; NEA wraparound for NEA members, to accompany first mailing of New York Teacher, post-merger, September 7, 2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link284">New York Teacher Meeting 2/15/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link285">New York Teacher 10/3/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; halftone photos with captions. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link206" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Kadamus</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link286">New York Teacher Meeting 9/19/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link287">New York Teacher 8/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; production schedule; schedule of Communications Planning meetings </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link288">New York Teacher 6/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link289">New York Teacher: Standards 6/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link290">New York Teacher 5/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link291">New York Teacher 5/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; memos re meetings</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link292">New York Teacher 4/25/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; article from Wall Street Journal, "Reading, 'Riting, Reform," 4/7/05, with note to Maria Neira's attention; partial AFT executive vice president report (via e-mail)</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link293">New York Teacher 3/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link294">New York Teacher 2/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link295">New York Teacher 2/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link296">New York Teacher 1/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link297">New York Teacher 1/18/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; article, "Governor's Budget Proposal Better Than Expected"; proposed officer visit schedule, 2004-2006</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link298">New York Teacher Meetings</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2004/2005">2004-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of Communications meetings for the remainder of New York Teacher publishing year</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link299">New York Teacher Meeting 11/15/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list; memos re unification talks</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link300">New York Teacher Meeting 11/1/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link301">New York Teacher Meeting 10/18/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link302">New York Teacher Meeting 10/4/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link303">New York Teacher Meeting 4/5/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link304">New York Teacher / Communications Meeting 5/17/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link305">New York Teacher / Communications Meeting 5/3/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link306">New York Teacher / Communications Meeting 4/19/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link307">New York Teacher / Communications Meeting 3/8/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link308">New York Teacher / Communications Meeting 2/9/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link309">New York Teacher / Communications Meeting 1/26/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New York Teacher story list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link310">New York Teacher Communications Brainstorming Day 6/11/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Communications Brainstorming Day; handwritten notes; memo re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link311">No Child Left Behind (NCLB) 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from the NYS Education Department to U.S. Department of Education with formal submission of revised Accountability Workbook reflecting NYS's approved plan to calculate Adequate Yearly Progress under No Child Left Behind, and formal amendment to
      workbook for calculating progress of students with significant cognitive disabilities, August 21, 2004; "Failing Our Children" summary report by FairTest: The National Center for Fair and Open Testing, critiquing No Child Left Behind, May 2004;
      "Accountability Left Behind: While Children and Schools Face High Stakes Testing, Tutoring Companies Get a Free Ride," a study by the Association of Community Organization for Reform Now (ACORN) and the American Institute for Social Justice; list of
      schools failing to meet AYP under No Child Left Behind, September 20, 2004; State Education Department field memos. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link30" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT No Child Left Behind</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link103" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Committee of Practitioners</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link312">NCLB National Conference of State Legislatures (NCSL)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to NYSUT executive vice president Antonia Cortese from the president of Nassau BOCES Central Council of Teachers, Local 2551, noting that the National Council of State Legislatures issued a report that No Child Left Behind was a flawed,
      convoluted, unconstitutional education initiative that had usurped state and local control of public schools, and asking why the law had not been challenged in court and what action the AFT might take, March 16, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link313">NCLB Mathematics and Science Partnership Grant Program</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>State Education Department list of awarded partnerships, 2004-2007. See also under <ref linktype="simple" target="link251" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Mathematics</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link314">NCLB Rochester Tutoring</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Text of article from American Teacher, "Rochester to Provide Local Tutoring," May/June 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link315">NYSUT Annual Reports</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1987/1990">1987-1990</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Annual reports for 1987, 1988, and 1990</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link316">NYSUT / NEA Membership Map</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Map of NYSUT Election Districts, with list of school districts and affiliations (NYSUT, NEA, or both), cover memo, December 1, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link317">Officers Advisory Committee Meeting 11/17/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; draft (not yet submitted) New York State Center for (Independent) State Testing Reviews (STR), submitted by Westchester Institute for Humans Services Research, Inc., to Gov. George Pataki, 11/3/05; NYSUT Regents' Report Card re November 2004
      Board of Regents meeting; Member Benefits Chairperson Report by Ivan Tiger</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link318">Officers Advisory Committee Meeting Education and Learning Trust 6/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials for new course proposed by Ro Rosen of the NYSUT Education and Learning Trust, "A Framework for Leadership," with cover letter to Chuck Santelli, June 16, 2005; course outline and syllabus; presentation sheets for NYSUT Education and Learning
      Trust; 2005-2006 budget proposal overview; agenda of Education and Learning Trust Board of Directors meeting, June 22; minutes of March 1 meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link319">Officers Advisory Committee Meeting 6/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re management/confidential salary adjustments for 2005-2006; lists of individual salaries, 2004-06 to 2007-08; full employment and salary histories of several individuals since hire</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link320">Officers Advisory Committee Meeting 6/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT 2005-06 Budget</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link321">Officers Advisory Committee 4/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link322">Officers Advisory Committee Meetings 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Schedule of meeting dates for 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link323">Officers Advisory Committee Meeting 7/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Packet of resolutions referred for implementation by the Representative Assembly, with cover letter, July 22</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link324">Officers Cabinet Retreat June 4-5, 2007</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Officers' Retreat agenda, June 4-5; Cabinet Retreat agenda, June 5; agenda for NYSUT Local Action Project 2007 Summer Planning Conference Agenda, July 16-20, 2007; draft agenda for NYSUT New Local Presidents Conference, June 26-29, 2007; text of oral
      report of first vice president Maria Neira to NYSUT Executive Committee, June 7; confidential results from Equal Employment Opportunity Commission Report re racial and gender breakdown of full-time and other regular staff, 1999-2006; report re declining
      membership of AAUP (American Association of University Professions); dress code policy; list of NEA and/or AFT meetings/conferences, September 2006-August 2007; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link325">Officers Meeting 5/8/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; May 2007 issue of Latino New York, monthly magazine of the Capital Region; VOTE/COPE 2006 Report, showing charts, graphs, and lists by regional office; management/confidential salary adjustments for FY 2007-08; memo to NYSUT president Dick
      Ianuzzi re resolutions to come before the AFT Exec Council meeting, May 7; list of regional office staffing; memos requesting new positions or extraordinary salary increases. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link45" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Board of Directors meetings</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link326">Officers Meeting 3/27/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list, NYSUT Leadership Class of 2007; tax info for NYSUT locals; booklet, NYSUT Dues Proposal 2007-08 and 2008-09 Questions and Answers; standing rules for NYSUT delegation, 2007 NEA Representative Assembly; proposed officer visit schedule;
      flood relief accounting as of March 20, 2007; memo re appointment of legislative representative, salary, March 26</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link327">Officers Meeting 3/12/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Executive Committee agenda for March 16 meeting; NYSUT booklet, Guide to Program Services; AFL-CIO Executive Council Statement, "End Our Military Involvement in Iraq," March 7, 2007; confidential memo requesting increase in staffing of Travel
      &amp; Conference Services, February 27</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link328">Officers Meeting 2/21/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; letter to Maria Neira from New York Immigration Coalition requesting sponsorship of Builders of New York awards celebration, February 2; materials re 2006 contribution to coalition; memo re reclassification of position, February 8; materials re
      NEA Representative Assembly</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link329">Officers Meeting 2/6/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Executive Committee agenda for February 9; Board of Directors meeting agenda for February 9- 10; memo re 2007 community service award winners</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link330">Officers Meeting 1/16/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Executive Committee agenda for February 9; Board of Directors meeting agenda for February 9- 10; memo re fundraising campaign for Martin Luther King, Jr., memorial; memo re 2007 Representative Assembly move from printing to web publication,
      invited speakers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link331">Officers Meeting Dues Discussion 1/8/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo confirming meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">66</container>
     <unittitle id="link332">Officers Meeting 8/7/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Executive Committee agenda for August 9; Board of Directors meeting agenda for August 9; memo re NYSUT Solidarity Grant, June 20; program for NYSUT Local Presidents' Conference, August 6-8, 2006; 2006-2007 proposed governance calendar (list of
      meetings), updated August 1, 2006; list of NYSUT attendees at 2006 AFL-CIO COPE Convention; presentation sheets re NYSUT Research &amp; Educational Services, presented at Local Presidents' Conference, August 2006; memo alert re training for Violent
      and Disruptive Incident reporting (VADIR), July 20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">67</container>
     <unittitle id="link333">Officers Meeting 6/20/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes for opening session of staff training conference of June 19; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">68</container>
     <unittitle id="link334">Officers Retreat June 14-15, 2006</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">69</container>
     <unittitle id="link335">Officers Meeting 6/6/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo re opposition to rural power line proposal; memo re deletion of term "English immersion" from proposed resolution</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">70</container>
     <unittitle id="link336">Officers Meeting 5/24/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Executive Committee agenda for June 8; Board of Directors meeting agenda for June 26; NYSUT 2006-2007 budget: revenue and expense narrative; application for regional staff director for the Southern Tier, with attached resume; list of possible
      resolutions for submission to the 2006 AFT Convention, from the 2005 and 2006 Representative Assemblies</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">71</container>
     <unittitle id="link337">Officers Meeting 5/9/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; officer compensation comparison with other unions; New York Post editorial re relationship between NYSUT and financial services firm ING</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">72</container>
     <unittitle id="link338">Officers Meeting 4/18/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; New York Times clipping re "taxpayer revolt" movement stopping school budgets, April 16; proposed Administrative Professionals Day mailing lists</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">73</container>
     <unittitle id="link339">Officers Meeting 4/7/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Professional Issues Forum on Health Care program, sponsored by NYSUT Health Care Professionals Council, April 1; memos re management/confidential promotion recommendation from general counsel's office, April 4; 2006 Leadership Institute
      applicants; proposed Leadership Institute Class of 2006; letter from NYSUT Civil &amp; Human Rights Committee to NYS Teachers Retirement System, urging gradual divestment in Wal-Mart, March 15; list of state retirement systems invested in companies
      active in Sudan; list of priority consensus statements from March 8 Administrative Committee meeting, March 21</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">74</container>
     <unittitle id="link340">Officers Meeting 3/8/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; timeline, Communications Response to Governor's Backdoor Voucher Scheme (as of March 8, 2006); list of 2006 conferences; list of guests at 2006 Representative Assembly; urgent memo from NYSUT president Ianuzzi to Nassau presidents re need to
      respond immediately to tuition tax credit proposal, March 8</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">75</container>
     <unittitle id="link341">Officers Meeting 2/14/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Executive Committee meeting agenda for February 16; draft guidelines for summer internships, February 14, 2006; Associate Press article, "Tax credits for private school parents pressed," February 14; draft letter with handwritten edits, to
      producers of ABC television show 20/20, demanding an on-air apology by John Stossel for his January 13 segment, "Stupid in America," which criticized teachers "who strive against enormous adds [sic]"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">76</container>
     <unittitle id="link342">Officers Meeting 1/17/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; draft Officers' Advisory Committee meeting agenda, January 19; draft NYSUT Bargaining Units Retreat Agenda, February 15; press release, "NYSUT: Governor Turns Back on Seniors, Students and Middle Class," January 17; text of governor's budget
      address, January 17; draft letter to Education Commission Mills from NYS Educational Conference Board; legislative newsletter</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">77</container>
     <unittitle id="link343">Officers Meeting 1/10/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Schedule for management/confidential salary proposals, 2006; salary histories for several individuals</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">78</container>
     <unittitle id="link344">Officers Meeting 11/15/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Update to NYSUT Officers on Unification Planning and Implementation, November 9, 2005; Update on Unification Planning and Implementation, October 28, 2005; letter to Kathleen Lyons, NEA-NY Executive Director, from Pauline Kinsella, NYSUT
      Executive Director, re unification, October 25, 2005; memos re scope of work for various capital projects; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">79</container>
     <unittitle id="link345">Officers Meeting 11/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; calculator wheel for determining annual out-of-pocket costs for prescriptions for Medicare beneficiaries; memo revising reimbursement process for meals by officers when travelling or entertaining, October 24; materials re 2006 Representative
      Assembly; correspondence between retired NYSUT president Tom Hobart and Organization of NYSUT Staff Retirees, May-October 2005; Retiree Leadership Handbook; sketches for Sandra Feldman Memorial Garden; newspaper clipping re dedication of annual Strides
      Against Breast Cancer Walk to Sandra Feldman</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">80</container>
     <unittitle id="link346">Officers Meeting 9/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Peer Intervention Program Year 17 Final Report; letter from League of Women Voters of New York State Education Foundation, requesting $20,000 to expand Students Inside Albany program, June 23, 2005,with cover memo from NYSUT executive vice
      president Alan Lubin noting that NYSUT had given $10,000, September 9; NYSUT's 2005 Retire Services Survey Results; memo re release time for staff participating in Hurricane Katrina relief efforts, September 19</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">81</container>
     <unittitle id="link347">Officers Meeting 9/7/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Board of Directors' meeting agenda for September 17; Executive Committee meeting agenda for September 16; booklet from National Center for Educational Statistics, Mobility in the Teacher Workforce: Findings from the Condition of Education 2005;
      memo re need for volunteers to assist with Hurricane Katrina relief; proposed timeline and other materials re 2006 Representative Assembly; proposed program for Thomas Hobart dedication on September 26; list of retired part-time employees and hourly
      wages, January 1, 2004- July 31, 2005; list of NYSUT payments to AFL-CIO Central Labor Councils as of August 2005; article from Washington Post re two former teachers union officials convicted of embezzlement, September 1; memo re NYSUT holiday parties,
      August 26; request from regional staff director Fred Monaco for contribution of $1500 to Center for Missing and Exploited Children's Ride for Missing Children, January 12</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">82</container>
     <unittitle id="link348">Officers Meeting 6/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Directory of Board of Directors; materials for AFT Solidarity Fund, NYSUT Solidarity Fund</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">83</container>
     <unittitle id="link349">Officers Meeting 6/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re membership cards; survey results for start time for board meetings; annual estimated per capita for 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">84</container>
     <unittitle id="link350">Officers Meeting 6/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; confidential memo from Office of Counsel to the President re Department of Labor LM-30 Form update and recommended course of action, June 30; Cabinet Meeting notes of May 25; memo re AFT financial support, June 21</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">85</container>
     <unittitle id="link351">Officers Meeting 6/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo confirming meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">86</container>
     <unittitle id="link352">Officers Meeting 6/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re budget reform bills; confidential memo re Political Action Committee appointments; 2005-2006 budget requests for new positions, promotions, and upgrades</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">87</container>
     <unittitle id="link353">Officers Meeting 5/24/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Executive Committee meeting; confidential memo re Political Action Committee appointments; list of staff requesting to attend QuEST; proposed 2005 nominations for Referred Resolutions Committee; list of officers attendance at NYSUT
      Regional/Statewide Leadership Conferences, updated 5/11/05</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">88</container>
     <unittitle id="link354">Officers Retreat April 25-27, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Retreat agendas; site information</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">89</container>
     <unittitle id="link355">Officers Meeting 4/19/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo confirming meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">90</container>
     <unittitle id="link356">Officers Meeting 3/8/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Officers' Advisory Committee meeting; agenda for Executive Committee meeting of March 13; Maria Neira's talking points re National Colorectal Cancer Awareness Month; confidential legal memo re bylaws of UNITY Caucus</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">5</container>
     <container type="folder">91</container>
     <unittitle id="link357">Officers Meeting 2/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda and revised agenda for Board of Trustees meeting of NYSUT Education and Learning Trust; minutes of November 23, 2004, meeting; course outlines for "Multiple Intelligence Strategies" and "Instructional Strategies for the Cooperative Classroom";
      memo to Chuck Santelli from Ro Rosen re Sunguard software proposal, February 7, 2005; description of items to be discussed by the board, from Ro Rosen; summary of major provisions of The Schools for New York's Future Act, with school aid chart; Benchmark
      (NYSUT) Polling Group results of survey of prime voters statewide re New York State representatives and issues, conducted January 31 through February 3, 2005; flyer supporting the UNITY team</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link358">Officers and Associates Meeting 4/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes of Officers meeting of March 29, 2005; Forbes article re costly, low-quality retirement plans sold to teachers by AIG-affiliated vendor, April 25, 2005; draft letter to the editor of Forbes from director of NYSUT Benefit Trust re
      ING-affiliated plan, noting satisfaction with it, April 12, 2005; letter from NYSUT president Ianuzzi to NYSUT members re ING-affiliated Opportunity Plus supplemental retirement savings plan (tax-deferred variable annuity, TDA); information re filing
      Form LM-30 with Department of Labor</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link359">Officers and Associates Meeting 3/29/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Executive Committee and Board of Directors' meeting agenda for April 7, 2005; notes of Officers meeting of March 15, 2005; list of officers on UNITY Caucus Nominations Committee; Subcommittee on Education Report to the General Conference Committee;
      Senate and Assembly Higher Education Conference Committee Recommendations; memo to NYSUT officers re request for new legislative representative position, March 28, 2005; Research and Educational Services Staff Planning Session Framework; materials re
      Regents proposal to increase the passing grade on Regents exams to 65; NYSUT Recommendations re NYS's Implementation of the Individuals with Disabilities Education Improvement Act of 2005, with cover letter from vice president Maria Neira to deputy
      commissioner of Office of Vocational and Educational Services for Individuals with Disabilities, March 28, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link360">Officers and Associates Meeting 3/15/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link361">Officers and Associate Meeting 3/1/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes of Officers meeting of January 25, 2005; draft executive summary of the K-12 Local Presidents' Survey, 2004-05; report of Field &amp; Legal Services, February 28, 2005; summary of NYSUT 2005-06 budget, prepared by the Office of the
      Secretary-Treasurer; list of executive salaries for 2005-06; memos re retiree health insurance for management and confidential staff, January 15 and February 23, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link362">Officers and Associates Meeting 1/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes from November 23 and December 21, 2004, Officers' Meetings; State Education Department press release, "Eleven Schools Placed on SURR List, 19 Removed in New York City, Yonkers, Buffalo, Syracuse and Hempstead," January 4; draft NYSUT
      press release, "New SURR List Shows Progress: Teachers Frustrated by State's Inaction," January 4; blast e-mail to media, statement by Randi Weingarten calling SURR news bittersweet, January 4; 2005 Representative Assembly materials, including tentative
      list of speakers, proposed resolutions; materials re NYSUT member benefits, auto policy; AFT Guidelines for Audit Committees, fall 2003; memo re NYSUT-CWA tentative agreement, with salary steps, January 4</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link363">Officers and Associates Meeting 11/23/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Officers' and Associates' meeting, November 23; draft statement of operations for year ended August 31, 2004; Education and Learning Trust Board of Trustees meeting agenda, November 23; minutes of September 8 meeting; budget note to Chuck
      Santelli from Ro (Rosemarie) Rosen of the Education and Learning Trust, October 26; course outline and syllabus for proposed new course, Differentiated Instruction: Improving the ODDS, with cover memo from Ro Rosen, October 27; memo from Ro Rosen re
      proposed partnership with the Sage Colleges and Concordia College, with attached financial arrangement, November 17; NYSUT Cell Phone Policy (addendum to Travel and Expense Reimbursement Policy), effective 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link364">Officers and Associates Meeting (Canceled) 11/16/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo notifying of cancellation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link365">Officers and Associates Meeting 4/13/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for Officers' and Associates' meeting of April 13; agenda and notes from Officers' meeting of March 18; agenda and notes of Officers' meeting of April 13; NYUSUT Financial Statements as of February 29, 2004; membership and financial report from
      Ivan Tiger, April 12; report on attendance of the 2004 Representative Assembly; list of members of task force on future of RAs, revised 4/5/04;</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link366">Officers Meeting 3/18/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes of March 2 Officers' meeting; minutes of February 17 Officers' meeting; special order of business, Response to Secretary of Education Paige's "Terrorist" Comments, re Bush administration official's remark that National Education
      Association was a terrorist organization; New York State Teachers Retirement System Trustee Agreement, April 6, 1992; tentative agenda for 2004 AFT Super Conference Northeast Regional Meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link367">Officers Meeting 3/2/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; NYSUT letter to AFT re per capita dues from Public Employees Federation, February 20; lists of bargaining units; 2004 Representative Assembly draft general session tentative speakers and program; interim report on security and civil liberties,
      to AFT officers and Executive council, from Democracy Committee, May 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link368">Officers Meeting 2/17/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; draft of certified letter to Hudson Valley Community College, severing joint sponsorship agreement between NYSUT Education and Learning Trust and college; memos re per capita dues collection for AFT from Public Employees Federation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link369">Officers Meeting 1/15/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws, effective April 2003; memo re health insurance for retirees/managers under current NYSUT policy, January 5, 2004; NYSUT special projects budget, 2002-2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link370">Officers Meeting 1/6/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo re associate member dues; comparison between Regents proposal and NYSUT Ad Hoc Task Force on School Finance Report; letter requesting sponsorship of Albany Law School Government Law Center's 2004 Warren M. Anderson Legislative Breakfast
      Seminar Series, December 16, 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link371">Officers and Associates Meeting 9/8/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; materials re CUNY Professional Staff Congress (PSC) request for financial assistance, September 7; Report of the Task Force on Small and Rural Locals, July 23, 2004; letter from Pauline Kinsella, NYSUT Executive Director of Field and Legal
      Services, to president of Professional Staff Association re his concern over number of management/confidential positions at NYSUT</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link372">Officers and Associates Meeting 8/2/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agendas for Executive Committee and Board of Directors' meetings of August 4; notes from Officers' meeting of June 16; recommended procedures for AFT/Kerry presidential campaign volunteer expense reimbursement; memo re financial statement
      recording of dues collected for AFT, August 2; correspondence re theft by one of Port Jefferson paraprofessionals co-presidents; confidential draft, NYSUT Personnel Committee Principles re promotions for CWA/PSA/LSA employees, with attached appendix of
      salary steps</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link373">Officers Retreat June 15-16 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for retreat; list of issues for retreat; agenda for Officers' and Associates' meeting of June 16; list of Officers' and Associates' meetings for 2004-2005; agenda and notes from Officers' meeting of June 1; Personnel Committee recommended salary
      adjustments; materials re Fundamental Beliefs to Create a Single State Organization, differences with existing policies of NEA-NY and NYSUT; NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link374">Officers and Associates Meeting 6/1/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agenda and notes from Officers' meeting of May 19; map of 2002-03 NYS School Districts Median Teacher Salary Ranges, with report on classroom teacher salaries; anonymous letter to NYSUT president Tom Hobart re "antics" of president (?) of
      Syracuse Teachers Association, May 17; memo re content management/portal expenditure, June 1; estimated costs associated with attending NYS AFL-CIO Constitutional Convention, August 8-10, 2004; emerging leader accomplishments</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link375">Officers and Associates Meeting 5/19/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agendas for May 19 and 20 meetings; working 2004-05 salary schedule; memo to Tom Hobart re 2004-2005 budget, May 10; handwritten notes from May 11 budget meeting; typed notes from 5/11 budget meeting with officers; brochure from the Eleanor Roosevelt
      Center at Val-Kill (Hyde Park, NY), with memo re NYSUT contribution, May 13; Peter D. Hart Research Associates survey results re public opinion of state of education, taxes, perception of teachers, April/May 2004; memo from NYSUT legal counsel re
      Appellate Division decision re duty to fairly represent retirees in Baker et al. v. Hoosick Falls Central School District et al., recommending settlement, May 17</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link376">Officers and Associates Meeting 5/19/04 2005 Budget Draft</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT 2004-2005 Budget officers' presentation, June 1, 2004; NYSUT Building Corporation Annual Report, June 10, 2004; budget drafts; summary of major changes version #1 to version #2; major equipment request schedule; list of special projects;
      committee budget lines; management/confidential salary adjustments per 5/11/04 Officers' Meeting; notes from 5/11 budget meeting with officers (accounting notes as of 5/19); additional areas to consider for potential cost containment</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link377">Officers Meeting 4/26/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; proposed new procedure for Associate Member Program, effective September 1, 2004; agenda and notes of Officers' meeting of April 13; memo from NYSUT president Tom Hobart to Board of Directors re NEA-NY convention's approval of "sanitized" unity
      resolution that left unresolved a list of issues that had traditionally divided NYSUT and NEA, April 26, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link378">Officers Retreat October 19-20, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Confidential draft notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link379">Officers and Associates Meeting 12/21/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting, January 12, 2005; memo re AFT financial support, with attached Rationale for the Continuance of AFT Technology Support in New York, November 12; memo to officers re private higher education faculty
      Associate Membership Program, December 15; NYSU travel and expense reimbursement policy, effective 2004; policy sheet re press releases; list of possible 2005 Representative Assembly Resolutions Committee chairs and vice chairs, December 21; materials re
      charter school test data, December 20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link380">Officers Meeting 12/07/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; summary sheet, 2005 NYSUT Campaign and Election Procedures; materials from 2004 NYSUT Board retreat, October 29-31; list of recipients of Albert Shanker Award for Distinguished Service; NYSUT Constitution and Bylaws, effective March 2004; Davis
      Vision/Wal-mart Update, outlining options for possible switch from optical provider who distributed at Wal-Mart, with responses to informal Request for Information</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link381">Officers Meeting 11/23/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; proposed management meeting structure; unsupportive letter to AFT president ED McElroy from NEA president Reg Weaver re possible merger/affiliation arrangement, November 18, 2004; officer Transition Policy after a Successor is Elected and
      Installed, 11/23/04</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link382">Officers and Associates Meeting 11/02/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re meeting time with "cancelled" notation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link383">New Officers Gathering 10/8/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re meeting time</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link384">Officers and Associates Meeting 10/5/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agenda for Administrative Committee meeting; presentation sheets re new LM-2 reporting requirements</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link385">Officers Meeting 10/03/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; NYSUT Retiree Fund 2005-05 Budget; job description for retiree services consultant; related materials; memo re Education Summit 2005; memo from Maria Neira re gaps in committee appointments, with spreadsheet; memo re miscellaneous headquarters
      items, re Sandra Feldman memorial, Founders' Room, September 30; memo from NYSUT general counsel James Sandner, recommending declining to represent case of probationary teacher, now resigned, charged with several counts of sexual misconduct with a child,
      September 27; letter from Greenburgh Eleven Federation of Teachers to NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link386">Officers Meeting 9/29/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo confirming meeting date; notes form Officers' meeting of September 8</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link387">Opportunity Plus see <ref linktype="simple" target="link200" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">ING Life Insurance</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link388">Para Festival (UFT) 2/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to Maria Neira inviting her to awards ceremony honoring outstanding paraprofessionals</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link389">Paras New Certification Requirements 2002-2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2002/2005">2002-2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from NYSUT Education and Learning Trust re Paraprofessional Education Program: Pathway to a Career in Education, August 10, 2005, with attached document; text of bill introduced by Rep. Jose Serrano (D-NY), Paraprofessionals in the Classroom Act
      of 2005, with fax cover from congressional office, January 10, 2005, and memo to Maria Neira summarizing legislation, February 8, 2005; UFT newsletter, ParaScope, fall 2004; NYSUT Information Bulletin re new certification requirements for teaching
      assistants, January 2003; text of Schools for New York's Future Act; U.S. Department of Education Draft Non-Regulatory Guidance re Title I Paraprofessionals under No Child Left Behind, November 15, 2002</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link390">Paraprofessionals see <ref linktype="simple" target="link34" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT Paraprofessionals and School-Related Personnel Conference</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link391">Parent-Teacher Conferences see <ref linktype="simple" target="link415" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Radio Ad</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link392">Personnel Committee Meeting and Materials</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re meeting, noting planned review of recommendations for promotions, with guidelines, May 3, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link393">Policy/ PR Campaign Meeting 12/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of Policy Council planned meetings for 2005-2006, with major topics to be discussed; message from Maria Neira to Policy Council members on listserv; Procedure for Expiring Resolutions; memo to Research and Educational Services managers from Chuck
      Santelli re "to-do" list from Executive Council and Board of Directors meetings, 12/12/05</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link394">NYSUT Policy Council Members</unittitle>
     <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="2005/2008">2005-2008</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of members with e-mail and street addresses, district affiliations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link395">NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 10/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re 2005-06 Policy Council meetings; memo re topics for discussion at October 12 meeting. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link352" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT Teachers Program and Policy Council</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link396">NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 1/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of attendees; list of those not attending or responding; draft 2004- 05 K-12 Local Presidents' Survey Summary; survey overview; survey possible discussion points; materials from State Education Department re assessment review and action on
      student performance, January 6; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link397">NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 11/8/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of upcoming meetings; memo from Maria Neira re State Education Department's latest middle-level proposal, September 24, 2004; letter from Neira to Chancellor Bennett, expressing concern over latest middle-level proposal, October 28, 2004;
      related materials; questions on grades 3-8 standards &amp; assessments; list of Policy Council members; flowchart, New York State Education Department Examination Development Process; NYSUT Research and Educational Services report, "Assessments in
      New York State: List of tests students in New York face as they progress from kindergarten through public higher education," October 2004; presentation sheets, Current Issues and Future Directions for Testing, Assessment and Accountability, by Howard J.
      Goldsmith, coordinator of operations, NYSED Office of State Assessment; description of State Education Department Mathematics Standards Committee; list of contract expirations, 2002-04; draft document re alternative compensation plans; handwritten
      notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link398">NYSUT Policy Council Meeting 4/21/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; notes from January 7, 2004, meeting; report of the First Vice President, for Executive Committee, April 15; materials re middle-level options; NYSUT report, Explosion of Excellence: The education revolution no one is talking about, March 2004;
      state fiscal policy recommendations, "There's Still a Better Choice," by NYSUT Committee of 100; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link399">Policy Issues Ann Cook Meeting 01/7/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos arranging a meeting; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link400">Post-Election Summary 11/11/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo from NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin to NYSUT Board of Directors, officers, and staff, analyzing results of presidential, congressional, and state legislative races, efforts of NYSUT volunteers, with attached NYSUT flyers for Democratic
      presidential candidate John Kerry. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link207" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Kerry</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link401">Practitioners Advisory Panel January-February 2003</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>List of assessment committee members; summary of initial meeting, February 3; State Education Department Information for Practitioners' Advisory Panel Discussion, with handwritten notations</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link402">Practitioners Panel on Testing 3/12/03</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summary of January 30, 2003, meeting; letter to NYSUT first vice president Antonia Cortese from State Education Department assistant commissioner, describing the advisory panel's assignment, January 3, 2003; NYSUT Feedback Form for Comments Regarding
      SED's Practitioners' Advisory Panel on Grades 3-8 Testing, with cover letter from NYSUT vice president Cortese to participant, February 10, 2003; filled-out form from another participant; Request for Proposal from State Education Department for State
      Assessment in Elementary and Intermediate (Middle) Level English Language Arts and Mathematics (scoring proposals); handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link403">Professional Development Educational Issues: Video Conference 5/26, 5/31, 6/01 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>NYSUT Educational Services list of topics and issues for videoconference briefing to NYSUT regional offices, May 26, 31, and June 1, 2005; revised announcement, Critical Issues Briefing: Educational Issues Videoconference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link404">Professional Development Meeting 9/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos arranging a time for the meeting; State Education Department document to superintendents of selected school districts re Title IIA and Professional Development Plan Monitoring, September 28, 2004; paper, School Variation and Systemic
      Instructional Improvement in Community School District #2, New York City, by Richard F. Elmore and Deanna Burney, October 1997; earlier version, August 1997</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link405">Professional Standards and Practices Board for Teaching (PSPB) Meetings 9/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for breakfast meeting; agenda for full day's meeting; list of attendees; list of issues re mentoring; comparison of the Teaching Commission report recommendations and NYS initiatives to date (draft) re improving state licensing and certification
      requirements, more authority to principals; draft proposal re performance assessment of teaching skills, 9/12</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link406">PSPB March 23-24, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials re legislative (lobbying) visits</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link407">PSPB 6/2/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; draft minutes of March 23-24, 2005, meeting; memo re proposed certification regulations; draft of letter, with handwritten edits, to deputy education commissioner Johanna Duncan-Poitier, re teacher mentoring program, May 25; document,
      Recruiting and Retaining Quality Teachers in High Need Districts: A discussion and recommendation presented by the Professional Standards and Practices Board for teaching; list of PSPB members; executive summary of State Education Department Educational
      Leadership Certification Regulation, Goal 3, April 29</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link408">PSPB 3/23/2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; May meeting agenda; draft minutes of January 20-21 meeting; paper for Education Policy Archives, "Catching Up With the Vaughn Express: Six Years of Standards-Based Teaching Evaluation and Performance Pay," by Eileen M. Kellor, University of
      Wisconsin-Madison, January 23, 2005; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "The Role of Mentor in District-Based Mentoring Programs," March 2005; document, Alternative Teacher Preparation Programs in New York State 2003-2004 Highlights, February 7, 2005
      (statistics, charts and graphs); draft, Empire Promise Teacher Opportunity Corps</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link409">PSPB January 20-21, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Minutes of October 14-15 and November 18-19, 2004, meetings; booklet by National Education Association, Teacher Quality: Moving Forward (A Dialogue with the Teaching Commission: Teaching At Risk: A Call to Action), June 2004; memo to the Board of
      Regents from deputy education commissioner Johanna Duncan-Poitier re update on Educational Leadership Initiative, Goal 3, January 3, 2005; memo to Johanna Duncan-Poitier from NYSUT vice president Maria Neira re performance-based modifications re faculty
      staffing in teacher education programs, January 20, 2005; report, "Keeping Quality Teachers; The Art of Retaining General and Special Education Teachers: A Practical Guide for School Leaders Held Accountable for Student Success," 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link410">PSPB November 18-19, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for PSPB Teacher Meeting; materials on 2004 legislative activity, how to lobby in 2005; NYSUT review and comment on State Education Department Draft Rubric for Assessing District Teacher Mentoring Programs 11/15/04; SED Office of School
      Personnel Review and Accountability Annual Part 83 Report, November 18, 2004; SED Report of the Mathematics Standards Committee, October 27, 2005; materials for nomination of 2006 New York State Teacher of the Year; draft document, Assessing the
      Development of Your District Teacher Mentoring Program, NY State Education Department Office of Teaching Initiatives, fall 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link411">Peer Intervention Program</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Bound final report</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link412">Public Schools see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link476" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Rise of Mass Public Schooling before 1914</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">6</container>
     <container type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link413">Public Schools for the 21st Century (PS21) Honor Roll Photo Exhibit 10/21/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to event</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link414">RMC Research Corporation</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from Deputy Commissioner of Education James Kadamus to Maria Neira re RMC Research Corporation contract from the U.S. Department of Education to establish a regional center to help school districts meet the requirements of the No Child Left
      Behind Act of 2001, inviting Neira to nominate two classroom teachers to be members of advisory board, January 30, 2006; memo with names of teachers to serve on advisory board</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link415">Radio Ad 10/18/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Script for public-service announcement for Maria Neira, urging parents to come to parent-teacher conferences</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link416">Regents Candidates 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Resumes of candidates David Ochoa and Howard M. Koenig, with cover letter from NYSUT president Richard Ianuzzi to Maria Neira indicating interest in Koenig, and related materials</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link417">Regents Interviews 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Questions by interview panel to Regent candidates; resumes of candidates Roger Bruce Tilles and Charles W. Fowler, with letter to NYSUT executive vice president Alan Lubin from president of the Nassau BOCES Central Council of Teachers (NABCOT), noting
      nomination of Fowler by Assemblyman Harvey Weisenberg, concurring with recommendation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link418">Regional Offices At-Large Directors Meeting 6/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Spreadsheet re costs to bring regional staff to NYSUT headquarters for meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link419">Regional Offices Capital District Regional Office Presidents Conference 2/3/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link420">Regional Offices Capital District Regional Office Staff Meeting 10/21/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link421">Regional Offices Capital District Regional Office (CDRO) Regional Action Program (RAP)</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summary of Regional Action Program; 2004-2005 RAP Activities for Cambridge, Averill Park, North Warren, Mohonasen, and Hadley-Luzerne teachers associations; list of participating teacher associations; cover memo to Executive Director for Field and
      Legal Services Pauline Kinsella, re CDRO staff assessments, year 3, April 4, 2005; description of Mohonasen Teachers Association Action Plan (MAP), with attached Action Plan Calendar</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link422">Regional Offices Herkimer County Teachers Council Dinner 11/10/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; invitation to dinner; memo from Executive Vice President Antonia Cortese, soliciting recommendations for alternative compliance options and sanctions under Annual Yearly Progress requirement under No Child
      Left Behind, October 25; NYSUT press release praising SUNY Board of Trustees</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link423">Regional Offices Nassau County 12/14/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; NYSUT press release re "great victory" in Campaign for Fiscal Equity</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link424">Regional Offices Nassau Regional Office 11/30/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Materials re meeting between Maria Neira and Mike Margolis</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link425">Regional Offices North Colonie TA 5/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter from North Colonie Teachers Association congratulating Maria Neira for election as First Vice President, inviting her to attend next meeting, with handwritten "yes"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link426">Regional Offices Southern Tier Regional Office (STRO) Spring Leadership Conference 3/17/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; program, for event; letter from AFT to all U.S. Senators, protesting record $3.5 billion cut in education funding in Bush administration FY 2007 budget, bringing to $55.7 billion the shortfall from what was
      promised for No Child Left Behind in the three years since the law was enacted, March 14; letter from AFT to U.S. Senators in support of amendment to increase Title I funding for FY 2007, noting cumulative gap of $40.3 billion (through FY 2006) between
      authorized and appropriated funding, March 15; agenda for NYSUT Education and Learning Trust training workshop, "Promoting Literacy for ELLs [English Language Learners, aka non-native speakers] at All Levels: A Training of the Trainers," March 18; State
      Education Department reports, "Overview of District Performance in English Language Arts, Mathematics, and Science and Analysis of Student Subgroup Performance for Sharon Springs Central School District," February 2005, "Accountability Status Report:
      English Language Arts, Mathematics, Science, and Graduation Rate for Sharon Springs CSD: 2004-05 Accountability Status: District in Need of Improvement Year 1 for English Language Arts," and Secondary-Level English Language Arts, March 6, 2006; newspaper
      clipping re sample questions appearing on state standardized math exam, lack of explanation for error, March 16, 2006 </p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link427">Regional Offices Southern Tier Leadership Conference August 23-25, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda and materials for conference topic, "Employee Disciplinary Due Process Rights"; remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link428">Regional Offices Suffolk Leadership Conference 1/21/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">16</container>
     <unittitle id="link429">Regional Offices Suffolk County Directors Meeting 10/25/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; report by Neira; materials re Labor-Religion Coalition</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">17</container>
     <unittitle id="link430">Regional Offices Suffolk Regional Office 11/30/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re visit by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">18</container>
     <unittitle id="link431">Regional Offices Suffolk County 11/29/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; press release, "NYSUT Honors New York's XXX New Nationally Certified Teachers"; memo re meeting and agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">19</container>
     <unittitle id="link432">Regional Offices Syracuse Regional Office Workshop November 12-13, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; agenda; workshop participant list; list of VOTE/COPE (political action) contributions by local</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">20</container>
     <unittitle id="link433">Regional Offices Ulster County Newly Tenured Teachers Reception 10/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira; edited draft</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">21</container>
     <unittitle id="link434">Regional Offices Utica Regional Office Educational Conference 11/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; evaluation form; handwritten opening remarks</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">22</container>
     <unittitle id="link435">Regional Offices Watertown New Member Regional Workshop 10/27/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Remarks by First Vice President Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">23</container>
     <unittitle id="link436">Regional Offices Western NY Winter Leadership Conference 3/11/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Facilitative correspondence</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">24</container>
     <unittitle id="link437">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 12/19/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; proposal from Thirteen/WNET for event, The Celebration of Teaching and Learning; list of potential 2006 RA resolutions; resolution re state support for higher education</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">25</container>
     <unittitle id="link438">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 11/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of planned meetings and discussion items for future NYSUT Policy Council, 2005-06; October Research Department manager's report; October Educational Services Department manager's report; School Finance and Policy Development progress
      report for October 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">26</container>
     <unittitle id="link439">Research and Educational Services Staff Meeting 11/18/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; recommendations of Summer 2005 Planning Committee, August 17</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">27</container>
     <unittitle id="link440">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 11/07/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; NYSU Information Bulletin re Classroom Teacher Salaries 2003-04</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">28</container>
     <unittitle id="link441">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 10/24/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">29</container>
     <unittitle id="link442">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 10/11/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; 2006-07 Regents State Aid Proposal; list of responsibilities of NYSUT committees and task forces, staff</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">30</container>
     <unittitle id="link443">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 9/26/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; agenda for NYSUT Policy Council meeting of October 12; related memo from Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">31</container>
     <unittitle id="link444">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 9/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; overview summary of June 2005 Regents telephone surveys; agenda for Pre-COP meeting of September 14</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">32</container>
     <unittitle id="link445">Research and Educational Services Staff Meeting 9/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; recommendations of 2005 Summer Planning Committee, September 6</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">33</container>
     <unittitle id="link446">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 6/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Protocol for Resolving Disputes between Local Teacher's (sic) Union and Local School Districts Regarding Educational Programs Required by Statute, Regulation or Bargaining</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">34</container>
     <unittitle id="link447">Research and Educational Services Staff Meeting 6/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Summary of planning process for report by first vice president</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">35</container>
     <unittitle id="link448">Research and Educational Services 6/6/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; Final Report to the NYSUT Working Committee on Web Redesign, by CMS Watch, May 20</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">36</container>
     <unittitle id="link449">Research and Educational Services Staff Planning Committee 5/31/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re setting up meeting; list of participant feedback from staff planning session</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">37</container>
     <unittitle id="link450">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 5/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; 2005 committee nominations; letter of resignation for Policy Council member Donald Luisi; State Education Department report to Regents for discussion, "Policy Review of Early Childhood Education," February 23; letter from NYSUT president
      Richard Ianuzzi re support for UFT rally in Madison Square Garden on June 2</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">38</container>
     <unittitle id="link451">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 5/2/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; program for New Local Presidents' Conference</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">39</container>
     <unittitle id="link452">Research and Educational Services 4/18/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>New Board Orientation program, May 23; summary of public opinion research survey by Peter D. Hart Research Associates</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">40</container>
     <unittitle id="link453">Research and Educational Services 4/4/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo re computer installation</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">41</container>
     <unittitle id="link454">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 2/22/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; NYSUT Information Bulletin re Role of the Union in Educational Programs</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">42</container>
     <unittitle id="link455">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 2/10/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; January Research Department manager's report; January Educational Services Department manager's report; January monthly report of the Education and Learning Trust; School Finance and Policy Development Progress Report for January 2005; list of
      districts in need of improvement under Title I based on performance in 2003-04 school year; Education Daily highlights of President Bush's fiscal 2006 budget request; brochure by New York State Council of School Superintendents re workshop Assessments
      for Learning, March 31</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">43</container>
     <unittitle id="link456">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 1/19/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">44</container>
     <unittitle id="link457">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 12/20/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo re retreat; NYSUT Policy Council agenda for January 12, 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">45</container>
     <unittitle id="link458">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 12/7/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo to NYSUT Board of Directors from Maria Neira re summary of major issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">46</container>
     <unittitle id="link459">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 11/23/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; memo to local presidents from Maria Neira re NYSUT- Staples Partnership grant</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">47</container>
     <unittitle id="link460">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 11/11/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; NYSUT Information Bulletin, "Report in the NYSUT Questionnaire for Presidents of Elementary and Secondary Teacher Locals, 2000-2001"; 2000-2001 Local Presidents' Phone Survey, January 2001; AFT QUEST workshop proposals; Toni Cortese Retirement
      List (programs and committees); Comments for SED Revisited Math Standards Survey</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">48</container>
     <unittitle id="link461">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 10/27/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">49</container>
     <unittitle id="link462">Research and Educational Services Staff Meeting 10/22/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; list of those absent and reasons for not attending; handwritten notes re Kerry campaign</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">50</container>
     <unittitle id="link463">Research and Educational Services Meeting 10/12/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>September Educational Services Department manager's report; September Research Department manager's report; September monthly report for the Education and Learning Trust; School Finance and Policy Development Progress Report for September 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">51</container>
     <unittitle id="link464">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 5/21/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; 2004 Local Presidents Conference summary of evaluations; NYSUT Committees 2004-05 Budget; NYSUT Research &amp; Educational Services Staffing list</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">52</container>
     <unittitle id="link465">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting February 11-13, 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; January Educational Services Department manager's report; January Research Department manager's report; January monthly report for the Education and Learning Trust; School Finance and Policy Development Progress Report for January 2004</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">53</container>
     <unittitle id="link466">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 11/10/03</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; October Educational Services Department manager's report; October Research Department manager's report; October monthly report for the Education and Learning Trust; School Finance and Policy Development Progress Report for October 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">54</container>
     <unittitle id="link467">Research and Educational Services Managers Meeting 10/27/03</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2003">2003</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda; October Educational Services Department manager's report; September Research Department manager's report; September monthly report for the ETP; School Finance and Policy Development Progress Report for September 2003</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">55</container>
     <unittitle id="link468">Retirement Events Jane Conetta Retirement Party 6/4/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to dinner event honoring retiring Board of Directors member</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">56</container>
     <unittitle id="link469">Retirement Events Toni Cortese Retirement Party 1/28/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to event honoring AFT Executive Vice President Antonia Cortese</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">57</container>
     <unittitle id="link470">Retirement Events Hobart Building Dedication 9/16/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to event</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">58</container>
     <unittitle id="link471">Retirement Events Hobart Building Dedication Meeting 5/12/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">59</container>
     <unittitle id="link472">Retirement Events Tom Hobart Long Island Tribute 3/18/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation from Syosset Teachers' Association to event honoring retiring NYSUT president Tom Hobart</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">60</container>
     <unittitle id="link473">Retirement Events Tony McCanns Retirement 6/22/06</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2006">2006</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to event honoring retiring teacher</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">61</container>
     <unittitle id="link474">Retirement Events Stanley Rosengarten / Joseph Dixon Retirement Dinner 11/10/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to event honoring Stanley Rosengarten and Joseph Dixon</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">62</container>
     <unittitle id="link475">Retirement Legislation Passed Both Houses</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Spreadsheet of NYSUT-supported legislation affecting NYS retirement plans</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">63</container>
     <unittitle id="link476">The Rise of Mass Public Schooling before 1914 5/31/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Copy of book chapter</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">64</container>
     <unittitle id="link477">School Without Walls 9/14/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to Maria Neira from principal of School Without Walls, requesting a telephone conversation re Regents policy on NY consortium schools, September 14, 2005</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">65</container>
     <unittitle id="link478">Carol Slotkin Conference Call 5/9/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence with president of Sullivan West District local re difficult new superintendent, layoffs, with attached statement by Slotkin, The State of Our Union Pursuing Excellence is Union Work, April 26. 
      See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link119" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">ED 13 Mid-Hudson</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">66</container>
     <unittitle id="link479">Social Security Interview 3/21/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Questions and answers by Maria Neira re Bush plan to privatize/eliminate Social Security program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">67</container>
     <unittitle id="link480">Social Security Privatization</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Questions and answers for Maria Neira re Social Security privatization; AFL-CIO flyers, "What Is Social Security?", "What You Should Know about Social Security Privatization," "Don't Believe the Spin," "What Privatizing Social Security Would Mean for
      Women," "What Social Security Privatization Would Mean to Young Workers," "What Privatizing Social Security Would Mean for African Americans," "What Social Security Privatization Would Mean for Latinos," "What Privatizing Social Security Would Mean for
      Public Employees," "What Privatizing Social Security Would Mean for Manufacturing Workers"</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">68</container>
     <unittitle id="link481">Social Workers</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos between Maria Neira and staff re draft reply to letter from social worker Steven Press about relationship between NYSUT and New York State School Social Workers Association, other issues</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">69</container>
     <unittitle id="link482">Staples Partnership Grant Karen Smith</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Confidential memo re investigation of Smith and Staples grant funds, September 16, 2005; end-of-project final report re Student of the Month Enrichment Program, by Karen Smith, September 1, 2005; letter to NYSUT executive assistant from City of New
      York Special Commissioner of Investigation for the New York City School District, requesting copy of cancelled check issued to Karen Smith, August 8, 2005; grant application from Karen Smith; related memos</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link483">State Education Department see <ref linktype="simple" target="link93" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Commissioner Mills</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link112" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Johanna Duncan-Poitier</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link206" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">James Kadamus</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link251" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Mathematics Standards Committee</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">70</container>
     <unittitle id="link484">Summer Intern Program</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re NYSUT sponsorship of Summer Intern Program for Undergraduate and Graduate students, primarily intended for children of NYSUT staff and activists</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">71</container>
     <unittitle id="link485">Supplemental Educational Services 2/23/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence re meeting; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link486">Teacher Aides see <ref linktype="simple" target="link389" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Para</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link34" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT Paraprofessionals and School-Related Personnel Conference</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link487">Teacher Awards see <ref linktype="simple" target="link111" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Disney Teacher Awards</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link488">Teachers Program and Policy Council see <ref linktype="simple" target="link35" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT Teachers Program and Policy Council</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link489">Teaching Assistants see <ref linktype="simple" target="link389" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Para</ref>; see also <ref linktype="simple" target="link34" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">AFT Paraprofessionals and School-Related Personnel Conference</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link490">Ron Thorpe see <ref linktype="simple" target="link508" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Widmeyer Communications</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">72</container>
     <unittitle id="link491">Two Together</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo to Pauline Kinsella, executive director of Field &amp; Legal Services, describing Two Together, an after-school tutoring program in the Capital Region supporting literacy and language skills among elementary school children in Albany's South
      End, noting that regional staff director Linda Stanczik had been appointed to its Board of Directors. See also <ref linktype="simple" target="link80" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Capital Area Labor of Love</ref></p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">73</container>
     <unittitle id="link492">Two Together Giffen School 04/22/07</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2007">2007</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memo re "Cooks for Kids" event at Giffen School for after-school mentoring and tutoring program</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">74</container>
     <unittitle id="link493">UUP Meeting 06/13/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Letter to NYSUT vice president Maria Neira from William Scheuerman, president, United University Professions</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">75</container>
     <unittitle id="link494">USNY (University of the State of New York) Summit on New York Education 11/2/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Invitation to attend Summit on New York Education sponsored by the University of the State of New York and the Board of Regents, with attached confidential background and talking points, October 20; expected attendance list; agenda; Call for a Summit
      on New York Education; document, The Aims of the University: How Are We Doing Now?; presentation sheets re early childhood, key issues to close the performance gap; handwritten notes</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">76</container>
     <unittitle id="link495">USNY Summit Regional Conversation 4/29/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agenda for USNY Summit Glens Falls Regional Conversation; letters to Maria Neira and Charles Santelli from Education Commissioner Richard Mills, thanking them for accepting invitation to attend, noting enclosed background papers</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">77</container>
     <unittitle id="link496">USNY Summit Regional Meetings 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Agendas for meetings in Rochester, Syracuse, Long Island, Glens Falls, Hudson Valley, and NYC; related memo</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">78</container>
     <unittitle id="link497">Vice Presidents Report December 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">79</container>
     <unittitle id="link498">Vice Presidents Report November 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">80</container>
     <unittitle id="link499">Vice Presidents Report September 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">81</container>
     <unittitle id="link500">Vice Presidents Report May 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">82</container>
     <unittitle id="link501">Vice Presidents Report February 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">83</container>
     <unittitle id="link502">Vice Presidents Report January 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">84</container>
     <unittitle id="link503">Vice Presidents Report December 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">85</container>
     <unittitle id="link504">Vice Presidents Report November 2004</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Report by Maria Neira</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">86</container>
     <unittitle id="link505">Walmart: The High Cost of Low Prices 11/17/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Flyer invitation to film preview, dinner, and reception at NYSUT headquarters</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">87</container>
     <unittitle id="link506">Welcome to Kindergarten Debra Wing 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Preview material and order form for book Welcome to Kindergarten; correspondence between Maria Neira and author and kindergarten teacher Debra Wing</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">88</container>
     <unittitle id="link507">Women of Color Union Leaders: Niki Dickerson Phone Interview 11/18/05</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Correspondence to arrange interview between NYSUT vice president Maria Neira and Niki Dickerson, author of a book chapter on black and Latina women in the labor movement</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">89</container>
     <unittitle id="link508">Widmeyer Communications Ron Thorpe Celebration of Learning December 13, 2005</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2005">2005</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Memos re meeting</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <unittitle id="link509">Youth see <ref linktype="simple" target="link79" show="replace" actuate="onrequest">Campaign for Youth</ref></unittitle>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">7</container>
     <container type="folder">90</container>
     <unittitle id="link510">John Zimmerman, Buchbinder Tunick and Company Meeting with Auditor 12/9/04</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="2004">2004</unitdate>
    </did>
    <scopecontent>
     <p>Draft consolidated financial statements, December 8, 2004; memo re meeting with John Zimmerman, outside auditor with Buchbinder Tunick &amp; Co. to present overview of audit process</p>
    </scopecontent>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>