<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05100::New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers'' Association of Fulton, New York Records.)//EN">KCL05100</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers' Association of Fulton, New York Records<date> 1914</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers' Association of Fulton, New York Records</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
				<date>October 28, 2016</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>October 28, 2016</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers' Association of Fulton, New York Records<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 5100</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, November 11, 2013</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Randall Miles, October 28, 2016</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2016 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers' Association of Fulton, New York Records, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1914</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5100</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration</corpname>;<lb/>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Glove Manufacturers' Association</corpname>;<lb/>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> International Glove Workers' Union</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.3 linear ft.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Transcripts.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Transcript of testimony and decision of the Board concerning the Glove Cutters' strike at Gloversville and Johnstown, NY.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		<physdesc><extent>0.33 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<p>At the request of the Commissioner of Labor the New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration convened in Gloversville on October 5, 1914 to attempt to settle the glove cutters strike which had idled 1500 men in 150 plants. Members of the
				Board included Mr. William C, Rogers, chief mediator; Mr. James C. McManus; and Mr. P.S. Downey. </p>
			<p>On August 21, 1914 the glove cutters held a mass meeting in which they voted to ask the Glove Manufacturers Association for an increase of 25 cents per dozen on men's and boys' gloves and 20 cents per dozen on ladies' gloves. The glove cutters
				were earning an average of $13.30 per week and had not had an increase in wages for 17 years. The glove cutters struck when the manufacturers turned down the request for an increase. Since glove making was the only industry in Fulton County the
				Board was instructed to investigate the situation. During the course of the strike several employers settled with their employees for 15 cents a dozen, and the Board recommended that the strikers return to work and continue negotiations for an
				increase of not less than 15 cents. The Board's proposals were turned down by the men.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<p>This collection consists of a transcript of testimony and decision of the Board concerning the Glove Cutters' strike at Gloversville and Johnstown, NY. </p>
			<p>Witnesses include (in order of appearance) Julius Ehrlich, Herman Abbott, George Mansell, Algeron Lewis, Edward Etman, August Willmer, Arthur Day, Charles Kuehnel, John Compipiano, Nathan James, John Sturm, Simon Lieberman, Antonion Compo,
				William Windsor, George Tozzi, Theodore Abbott, Frank Harper, Edward Loveys, Thomas Jones, Leo Martin, Earl Dente, Harris Schwieb, William Dare, Gustave Walters, Samuel Spares, Jacob Pitonberg, Louis Wallach, Samuel Ziller, Max Rosen, John
				Desendels, Samuel Spinnock, Harry Ribraud, John Hager, Marvin Haverley, George Hanson, Max Steiner, Robert Koberlein, Albert Alvano, Isidore Berliner, Miroslav Cermek, Max Silver, Edward Barcosi, Edward Swetman, William Buckley, George Linto,
				Jacob Katz, George H. Taylor, Eugene Simmo, Abraham Lehr, Albert Aaron, William Stitt, Joseph Moses, Samuel Lehr, Abraham Bachner, Alfred Saunders, Claude A. Pedder, G.W. Mandress, George Potter, James Ireland, Abraham Nelson, Martin Kennedy,
				J.K. Northrup, Wendell Murray, John Hager, Ellius Rob, C.J. Cittenberg, George Mansell, and Isaac Moses.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">New York (State). Board of Mediation and Arbitration. </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Glove industry - New York (State) - Johnstown. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Glove industry - New York (State) - Gloversville. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Wages - Glove industry - New York (State) - Johnstown. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Wages -Glove industry - New York (State) - Gloversville. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Strikes and lockouts - Glove industry - New York (State) - Johnstown. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Strikes and lockouts - Glove industry - New York (State) - Gloversville. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Glove industry - Employees. </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<accessrestrict>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<p>New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers' Association of Fulton, New York Records #5100. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<relatedmaterial>
			<p>Related Collections:<lb/>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05100mf.html"> 5100 mf: New York State Board of Mediation and Arbitration Glove Manufacturers' Association of Fulton, New York on Microfilm</extref><lb/>
			</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link8">Transcript of proceedings [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1914">1914</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>October 1914, pages 1 to 350.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link9">Transcript of proceedings [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1914">1914</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>October 1914; pages 351 to 697, plus index and report of findings and recommendations.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>