<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05205mf::National Railway Labor Conference Records on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05205mf</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the National Railway Labor Conference Records on
						Microfilm<date> 1907-1955</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">National Railway Labor Conference Records on
					Microfilm</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by E. Parker</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
					University Library</publisher>
				<date>April 05, 2017</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p>
						<subject>Labor</subject>
					</p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and E. Parker, <date>April 05,
					2017</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the National Railway Labor Conference Records on
				Microfilm<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 5205 mf</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
						P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
						Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>E. Parker, April 04, 2017</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, April 05, 2017</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2017 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library </date>
			<sponsor>This collection was processed with the help of generous funding from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC).</sponsor>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">National Railway Labor Conference
				Records on Microfilm, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1907-1955</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5205 mf</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">National Railway Labor
					Conference</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">64 microfilm reels</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents), microfilm.</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
				Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Selected microfilmed records accumulated by the Western,
				Eastern and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees which served as the
				collective bargaining units for the member railroads in their jurisdictions prior to
				the establishment of the National Railway Labor Conference.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		<physdesc><extent>7.11 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
			<p>The National Railway Labor Conference [NRLC] was formed in October 1962 to represent
				the carriers in negotiations with railroad unions. The NLRC is a not-for-profit
				association and represents member railroads in dealing with representatives of
				organized employees on a national level in matters involving railroad labor
				relations, health and welfare benefits, appropriate matters before the courts,
				Congressional committees, and other governmental bodies, and other matters of
				interest or concern to its members. Membership is open to any railroad within the
				continental United States. Until 1962, the carriers negotiated through regional
				committees; they were the Western, Eastern, and Southeastern Carriers Conference
				Committees, which coordinated their positions in reaching industry-wide settlements. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>As the successor organization to these committees, the NRLC is in possession of
				numerous records of historic importance. As part of an initiative by Cornell
				University's ILR School to document the history of Railroad Industrial Labor
				history, the NRLC provided copies of some of their historic records from these
				committees. The majority of the copies were provided on microfilm, which are located
				in this collection; thirteen bound, photocopied volumes donated by the NRLC may be
				located in collection 5205.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Inclusive date range: 1907-1955 </p>
			<p>Bulk dates: 1907-1955 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>This collection consists of 64 microfilm reels of records from the Western, Eastern,
				and Southeastern Carriers Conference Committees. They were filmed by the National
				Railway Labor Conference [NRLC]. The 64 reels represent files which the NRLC
				considered to be of historical value for the period from 1907 to 1955. Filmed
				records include correspondence, minutes, reports, transcripts, exhibits, and
				arbitration awards relating to the carrier conference committees, the operating and
				non-operating craft unions with whom they negotiated and the various government
				agencies which regulate the railroad industry. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>The researcher should be forewarned that the film in exceedingly difficult to read.
				The Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives was not responsible for the filming and
				regrets its condition. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Numbers in the below index refer to the microfilm reel on which the documents are
				located. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>CARRIERS </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Conferences Committee 1924 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>38-39: Master file – Statement of W.M. Jeffers 7-24-24 with copies of briefs,
				statements, etc., also statement September 8, 1924 Wage Deduction Conferences </p>
			<p>36-37: Authorizations to Presidents </p>
			<p>36-37: Replies to Circular January 4, 1932 – Organizations that agreed to defer
				conferences </p>
			<p>36-37: Authorizations to Conference Committee – (Not used) </p>
			<p>36-37: Miscellaneous papers – statistical and otherwise </p>
			<p>36-37: Circular letters, resolution December 18, 1931, etc. </p>
			<p>36-37: Statement of Railway Labor organizations answering financial argument
				presented by Railway Presidents Committee in support of Railway request for ten per
				cent pay roll deduction – January 23, 1932 </p>
			<p>36-37: Memo supplementary to statements made by the Chairman of the Railway
				Presidents' Committee in support of the request of the Rys. </p>
			<p>36-37: 1 copy of replies of committee of Railway Presidents January 24, 1932, from
				outline of program of Railway Labor Executives Association under "Immediate
				Measures" </p>
			<p>36-37: Letter Nov. 21, 1931 D.B. Robertson to D. Willard </p>
			<p>36-37: Nov. 21, 1931 D. Willard to D.B. Robertson </p>
			<p>36-37: Nov. 21, 1931 D.B. Robertson to D. Willard </p>
			<p>36-37: Nov. 22, 1931 D. Willard to D.B. Robertson </p>
			<p>36-37: Memo of Agreement dated 1-31-32 and effective Feb. 1, 1932 – 10% wage
				deduction </p>
			<p>36-37: Copy of statement (and work sheets) showing the Western Railroad that
				authorize Messrs. Downs, Baldwin and Gorman to represent and act for them in
				negotiations with representatives of the Railway Labor Executives' Association in
				accordance with Presidents' Resolution of December 18, 1931 </p>
			<p>36-37: General File (Willard Committee)  </p>
			<p>33-34: Complete sets of statements and proposals passing between Conference Committee
				of Mgrs. and Railway Labor Executives Association commencing December 12, 1932 and
				ending December 22, 1932 </p>
			<p>33-34: 2 complete sets of minutes – 1 for S.H. Schneider; 1 for W.F. Thiehoff
				starting August 17, 1932 </p>
			<p>33-34: General File – Contains all papers commencing with March, 1932 and terminating
				with the end of the 1933 </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Extra copies of minutes of minutes of meetings February 15 to April 28,
				1934, inclusive, also stencils </p>
			<p>76-79-84: A.W.R. circulars and memorandum regarding Canadian Railways wage deduction
				agreements </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Complete set of minutes – 1 for S.H. Schneider; 1 for W.F. Thiehoff
				starting August 17, 1932 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Carriers' Conference Committee </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>36-37: Replies to Circular No. 172-17, dated July 26, 1938, as to the application of
				Article 1 (d) of Mediation Agreement dated October 3, 1947, in the matter of
				arbitraries and special allowances for train and enginemen </p>
			<p>36-37: Books containing corrected "Analysis of Certain Train, Engine and Yard Service
				Working Rules which Augment Compensation Through Constructive Additions to Basic
				Rates of Pay and Extensions of Service Time or Mileage," for Eastern, Western and
				Southeastern territories </p>
			<p>36-37: "Master File" containing corrections and additions and "marked copies" of
				above described books, together with the stencils and correspondence file </p>
			<p>36-37: Circular No. 172-15 of 10/5/37 attaching copy of Carriers' Conf. Committees
				Report dated 10/4/37, and requesting information as to certain rules in Train,
				Engine and Yard schedules and application of awards thereto and practices thereunder </p>
			<p>36-37: Miscellaneous papers regarding request for rules changes, Train and Enginemen
				– 1937 Wage movement </p>
			<p>36-37: Replies from railroads to Circular 172-15 (originals and duplicates) showing
				information as to certain rules of Train, Engine and Yard schedules and application
				of awards thereto and practices thereunder </p>
			<p>36-37: 6-Page Memorandum (not dated) for Carriers' Conference Committee, dealing
				among other things, with effect of restrictive legislative activities of the
				Brotherhood organizations; certain schedule rule changes such as starting time of
				crews in yard service; road crews switching at terminals and intermediate points,
				etc. and correction of difficulties arising out of activities of the 1st Division,
				NRAB </p>
			<p>36-37: Chairman Enochs' letter 11/23/37 (with various attachments) to railroads,
				outlining procedure in serving request on train, engine and yard service employees
				for desired changes or modifications in existing rules; also Mr. Enochs' letter
				12/15/37 advising that Conference Committee had discontinued its efforts to secure
				authorization for handling rules revision on a national basis and remanding the
				matter to individual lines for such handling as they deem proper </p>
			<p>36-37: Printed pamphlet captioned "The True Story of Wage Negotiations" signed by
				Pres. Phillips of O.R.C., also circular letter dated 9/20/37 and signed by Messers.
				Robertson, Whitney, Johnston, Phillips and Cashen dealing with duties of members and
				officers of the Organizations in conduct of strike. (Sent to COO without comment
				11/1/37 – numbered 460) </p>
			<p>36-37: Copies of Conference Committee bills against railroads and Express Agency,
				Inc. covering Assessments Nos. 1, 2 and 3; also papers re refund of unused amount
				raised by Assessment No. 3 </p>
			<p>36-37: Mimeographed tabulations showing number of employees and rates in effect as of
				3/1/33 – for Eastern Railroads, represented by Conference Committee- of Managers
				(compiled for Carriers' Conference Committee-1937) covering Clerical and Station
				Forces, M of W, etc; also mimeographed tabulation showing number of men, rates, etc.
				for Police Dept. employees, and information re Train Riders of Patrolmen performing
				duties of Train Riders, as of November 1, 1936 </p>
			<p>36-37: In re Item 2 (Share-the-Work Practices) of Mediation Agreement (Case A-395) of
				August 5, 1937, consisting of: (1) Chairman Enochs' circular letter of 11/13/37 to
				railroads relative meeting of subcommittee of Carriers' Conference Committee and
				committee of 14-non-operating organizations, at Chicago 11/12/37; copies of Mr.
				Enochs' further circular letters of 11/15 and 11/20/37; (2) Replies to A.W. Rys
				Circular 170-20 of 1/14/38 re disputes on the various railroads dealing with
				application of Item 2 of mediation agt.; copies of transcript of Proceedings
				(Vol.1-2) of hearing before Natl. Med. Bd. April 11-12, 1938 in re Int. of Item 2,
				and A.W. Rys. Circular 170-20 (a) of 5/28/38 transmitting Interpretation of Med. Bd.
				Dated 5/21/38; (3) Miscellaneous papers dealing with application of Item 2 </p>
			<p>36-37: In re Item 1 (Application of the 5 cent p.h. increase) of Med. Agt. (Cast
				A-395) of August 5, 1937, consisting of: (1) Summary of replies to A.W. Rys.
				Circular 170-17 to 10/1/37 covering disputes on the various railroads re application
				of Item 1; (2) Chairman Enochs' circular letter of 11/13/37 to railroads relative
				meeting of subcommittee of carriers' conf. committee and committee of 14
				non-operating organizations, at Chicago, 11/12/37; and copies of Enochs' further
				circular letters of 11/15 and 11/20/37; (3) Miscellaneous papers dealing with the
				application of the 5 cent per hour increase </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Carriers' Joint Conference Committee </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>35: Memorandum to Mr. Enochs by C.P. Neill, dated 9/29/38 (with attachments)
				regarding the following: (1) Award of Board of Arbitration 8/12/38 in case of Lake
				Superior Newspaper Guild and Duluth Herald and News-Tribune; (2) Report of Fact
				Finding Board in the Canned Salmon Industry, issued 8/26/38; (3) Award of Board of
				Arbitration 8/15/38 in case of Typographical Union No. 54 and the News-Observer of
				Raleigh, N.C.; (4) Decision of the Arbitration Board 7/1/38 in case of Federal Barge
				Lines and Intl. Long-shoremen's Assn. and Inland Boatmen's Assn. </p>
			<p>42-43-44: 1946 Emergency Board, Pullman Conductors Case – Demand for monthly increase
				of $44.00 in lieu $41.62 (Transcripts, Exhibits, and Daily Write-Ups of Case) (See
				File 200-151-1) </p>
			<p>58-60: Arb. ORC&amp;B-Pullman, May 1954 File 200-361 </p>
			<p>  </p>
			<p>OPERATING CRAFTS </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Conductors &amp; Trainmen </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>35: Preliminary report Committee of General Managers, Western Railroads in conference
				with Conductors and Trainmen, Chicago, Jan. 28 to Feb. 27, 1907 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Committee of General Managers, Western Railroads, in conference with
				ORC-BRT- &amp; BLF&amp;E at Chicago, April 7-19, 1908 </p>
			<p>33-34: Arbitration Proceedings between Conductors, Trainmen and Yardmen on New York
				Central and New York Center &amp;Hudson River RR, April 18-19, 1910,
				and decision of arbitrators. (Clark-Morrissey Award) </p>
			<p>35: Report of Committee of General Managers, Western Railroads – Conference with
				Conductors and Trainmen, Chicago, Nov. 28 to Dec. 29, 1910 </p>
			<p>67-68-70: Printed transcript of proceedings Eastern Conductors' &amp;
				Trainmen arbitration, October-November 1926 </p>
			<p>35: Orders for Proceedings of Eastern Conductors' &amp; Trainmen's
				Arbitration – 1926 </p>
			<p>59-61-64: Complete sets of mimeographed transcript of hearings before Emergency Board
				in dispute between Tex &amp; Pac Ry. and Train and Engine Service
				Brotherhoods Vols. 1 to 8, inc., April 1929 </p>
			<p>58-60: Mimeographed transcript of hearings between Kan. City Sou. Sys. and its Train
				and Engine Service employees before Emergency Board, and Kan. City, Mo., June 22 to
				July 8, 1933 (1 complete set) </p>
			<p>65: Statements prepared by Conference Committee, Sept. 1913 (Eastern Conductor's and
				Trainmen's Arbitration) </p>
			<p>76-79-84: 1 complete set Reporters' transcript (Vol. 1-38, incl.) property of Mr.
				Higgins </p>
			<p>53-55: Complete set of Exhibits – Railroads' &amp; Employees' – (Personal
				property of MR. J.W. Higgins as Arbitrator) </p>
			<p>82-83-85: Miscellaneous data, Conductors' &amp; Trainmen's Wage Movement,
				1926 </p>
			<p>35: Copies of printed brief for the respondent carriers, May 23, 1937 </p>
			<p>35: W.M. Jeffers' file containing signed agreement to arbitrate and correspondence
				notifying Board of Mediation and others of appointment of arbitrators </p>
			<p>35: Conductors and Trainmen legislation </p>
			<p>35: Majority and minority reports, Condrs. and Trainmen vs. Can. Pac. Ry. and Can.
				Natl. Rys.; Settlement Condrs. &amp; Trainmen and Can. Pac. Ry.
				&amp; Can. Natl. Rys. </p>
			<p>82-83-85: 1 Complete set of Reporters' transcript of proceedings of Emergency Board
				(Vols. 1 to 16, incl.) </p>
			<p>53-55: Extra copies of printed record of proceedings, July 16 to Aug. 9-1928, in
				connection with organizations' demands of Nov. 1-1927 </p>
			<p>42-43-44: Data, papers statements, etc. on doubleheader restrictions, tonnage limits,
				etc. witness' files, etc. </p>
			<p>49-50: Earnings statements, year 1927 – AT&amp;SF, Yard Service; Un.
				Pac., Road and Yard Service, Nor. Pac., Road and Yard Service </p>
			<p>53-55: Complete set of railroad exhibits </p>
			<p>67-68-70: Complete set of employees' exhibits (Except Nos. 2 and 53) </p>
			<p>82-83-85: Memorandum of agreement between ORC and BRT and Conference Committee of
				Managers Western Rys. dated November 23, 1928 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Engineers and Firemen </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>33-34: Supplemental report, Conference Committee of Managers, Western Railroads,
				Conference with Firemen, Chicago, Jan. 16, 1911 to Jan. 23, 1911 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Conference Committee of Managers, Western Railroads in conference with
				Firemen, Chicago Dec. 27, 1909 and Mar. 24, 1910 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Committee of General Managers, Western Railroads, conference with
				Firemen, Chicago, March 6 to April 8, 1907 </p>
			<p>35: Preliminary report of Conference Committee of Managers, Western Railroads in
				conference with Engineers, Chicago, September 26 to November 7, 1910 </p>
			<p>35: Final report of Conference Committee of Managers, Western Railroads in conference
				with Engineers, Chicago, September 26 to Dec. 24, 1910 </p>
			<p>35: Final report of Conference Committee of Managers, Western Railroads in conference
				with Firemen, Chicago, May 16 to June 4, 1910 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Committee of General Managers, Western Railroads in conference with
				Train and Enginemen, Chicago, April 7 to 19, 1908 </p>
			<p>35: Interpretation of Award, June 4, 1910, by Arbitrators appointed to settle wage
				controversy between Western Railroads and Firemen </p>
			<p>56-57: Proceedings of Arbitration Board C&amp;WI RR and Belt Ry. of
				Chicago and Engineers, Firemen and Trainmen, Chicago, August 28 to September 12,
				1913 </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Minutes of Meeting, December 18, 1922 – re Hearing before Labor Board Jan.
				15, 1923, rates, rules and working conditions, Engineers, Firemen, Conductors and
				Trainmen </p>
			<p>88-89: Correspondence, submissions, exhibits and data, hearing before U.S.R.R.L.B.
				train and enginemen, Jan. 15, 1923 </p>
			<p>88-89: Transcript, Exhibits, Award – Southeastern Engineers Arbitration Jan. 1928 (1
				complete set) </p>
			<p>33-34: One complete set of Railroad and Employees exhibits before Emergency Board T
				&amp; P Ry case, April 10-20, 1929 </p>
			<p>35: Mimeograph transcript of proceedings on arbitration board (Vols. 1-4) in case
				BLF&amp;E vs Boston &amp; Maine, re: Pay to firemen on
				B&amp;M while learning to operate mechanical stokers, Oct. 1929 </p>
			<p>52-54: Proceedings of the Emergency Board appointed to investigate dispute between
				L&amp;amp;amp;amp;A and LA&amp;T Rys. and certain employees represented
				by BLF&amp;E, etc. Mar. 1932 </p>
			<p>33-34: Report of Emergency Board, Aug. 26, 1933, Louisiana, Arkansas
				&amp; Texas Ry vs. Train and Enginemen; and miscellaneous papers thereon </p>
			<p>42-43-44: 1 Complete set of mimeograph proceedings of Arb. Bd – Case of
				N.C.&amp;ST. L.R.R. &amp; Engineers, Firemen, Cond. And
				Trnmn. Aug. &amp; Sept. 1933 (Vols. I-XVI Incl.) </p>
			<p>33-34: File on La.&amp;Ark.Ry. strike of Train &amp; Engine
				Service employees Sept.-Oct. 1936 </p>
			<p>35: Extract from testimony of J.C. Stuart, Vice President, Erie RR before Arbitration
				Board, Eastern Engineers, July 26, 1912 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Board of Arbitration – Engineers – November 2, 1912 </p>
			<p>59-61-64: Correspondence and data, Engineers' and Firemen's wage movement 1914-15 </p>
			<p>45-46: Rulings as to meaning or application of award – rulings made 8-30-15 </p>
			<p>45-46: Argument of J.M. Sheean on behalf of Railroads </p>
			<p>45-46: Brief on behalf of Railroads </p>
			<p>45-46: Closing argument by W.S. Stone on behalf of employees before Bd. Of Arb. </p>
			<p>45-46: Brief and argument on behalf of Engineers, Firemen and Hostlers </p>
			<p>45-46: Extra copies of Award of April 30, 1915 </p>
			<p>35: Statement of Conference Committee of Managers, June 1, 1914 </p>
			<p>35: Supplement "A" to preliminary report of Conference Committee of Managers,
				Chicago, July 14-18, 1914 </p>
			<p>35: Supplement B to preliminary report of Conference Committee of Managers Chicago
				7-20-14 to 8-3-14 </p>
			<p>35: Railroad Arbitration – Pamphlet by Hon Chas. Nagel, July 18, 1915 on Western
				Award </p>
			<p>35: Index to official stenographic report, Western Arbitration 1914-15 </p>
			<p>86-87-90: Circulars, Correspondence and data, E&amp;F Arbitration, 1914 </p>
			<p>40-41: One complete set of Reporter's transcript of proceedings – property of Mr.
				J.W. Higgins as Arbitrator </p>
			<p>88-89: Correspondence regarding firemen waiving promotion on T&amp;P Ry. </p>
			<p>88-89: Statement of B.S. Hollimon, Superintendent, Southern Pacific (Texas
				&amp; La.) regarding Chicago Joint Working Agreement </p>
			<p>88-89: Comparison firemen's and switchmen's rates various terminal companies </p>
			<p>88-89: Copies of brief for the employees in arbitration proceedings </p>
			<p>88-89: Copies of Summary and index of exhibits filed by railroads and employees </p>
			<p>54: Copies of petition of certain Western railroads to impeach alleged award, filed
				in District Court of the U.S. </p>
			<p>88-89: Reply brief for railroads, filed in District Court of U.S. </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Brief for Western railroads in opposition to motion to dismiss petition to
				impeach alleged award, filed in District Court of U.S. </p>
			<p>88-89: Brief for employees in support of: (1) Motion to dismiss petition of railroads
				to impeach award; (2) Motion for judgment on award </p>
			<p>54: Brief on behalf of Appellants, No. 4009, filed in U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals,
				Western Railroads and Firemen (AT&amp;SF, et al vs
				BLF&amp;E) </p>
			<p>54: Reply brief for appellants, No. 4009, filed in U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals,
				Western Railroad and Firemen (AT&amp;SF et al vs. BLF&amp;E) </p>
			<p>54: Brief on behalf of Appellee, No. 4009, filed in U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals,
				Western Railroads and Firemen (AT&amp;SF et al vs.
				BLF&amp;E) </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Printed copies of decision of U.S. Circuit Court of Appeals dated May 24,
				1928, sustaining decision of the four arbitrators in award made in Firemen's wage
				case at Denver, December 17, 1927 </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Miscellaneous papers of W.M. Jeffers </p>
			<p>88-89: Additional copies of Award dated December 5, 1927 </p>
			<p>88-89: Additional copies of Award dated December 17, 1927 </p>
			<p>88-89: Copies correspondence reference furnishing statistics, earnings etc. </p>
			<p>88-89: Letter August 25, 1927 from Robertson </p>
			<p>88-89: August 26, 1927 Jeffers' reply </p>
			<p>88-89: August 30, 1927 from Robertson </p>
			<p>88-89: August 21, 1927 Jeffers' reply </p>
			<p>88-89: Sept. 9, 1927 from Robertson </p>
			<p>88-89: Sept. 14, 1927 Jeffers' reply </p>
			<p>88-89: Sept. 14, 1927 Jeffers to Robertson transmitting locomotive information </p>
			<p>88-89: Sept. 23, 1927 Jeffers to Robertson </p>
			<p>88-89: Sept. 26, 1927 Robertson's reply </p>
			<p>88-89: One copy each of various telegrams sent by Conference Committee </p>
			<p>88-89: J.W. Higgins file as Arbitrator containing correspondence with Board Mediation
				confirming appointment, meetings with other arbitrators to select neutrals,
				organization, etc. </p>
			<p>88-89: D.R. Richberg's objections to carriers exhibits tendered Oct. 17, 1927 </p>
			<p>88-89: D.R. Richberg's letter Nov. 18, 1927, to H.P. Burke will not prepare reply
				brief </p>
			<p>88-89: J.W. Higgins statement to Arbitration Board Dec. 2, 1927 </p>
			<p>88-89: D.R. Richberg's draft of proposed award </p>
			<p>88-89: J.W. Higgins and Judge Fletcher's dissenting opinion (Memo: Not used) </p>
			<p>88-89: Copy Dec. 5, 1927 award, telegrams and other papers regarding reconvening
				Board, etc. </p>
			<p>88-89: General file and miscellaneous correspondence </p>
			<p>88-89: Correspondence with D.B. Robertson regarding including several short lines in
				arbitration </p>
			<p>88-89: Complete set of correspondence prior to signing of agreement to arbitrate </p>
			<p>88-89: Complete set of circulars issued by Conference Committee </p>
			<p>88-89: Miscellaneous papers since Dec. 5, 1927 award. Also one set transcripts of
				hearings before courts – newspaper clippings </p>
			<p>94: Decisions by Committee created under Sec. VI of Memorandum of Agreement 2/28/37
				(National Diesel-Electric Agreement), on questions considered at meeting of Joint
				Conf. Committee and representatives of Bro. of L. F.&amp;E at
				Washington, Jan. 11, 1939. (COO Cir. 165-9) (Interpretations). </p>
			<p>  </p>
			<p>Yardmen </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>82-83-85: Circular letters and correspondence, BRT Yardmen, Chicago, Dec. 1913-1916 </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Circular letters and correspondence, BRT Yardmen, Chicago, Jan. 1913 to
				April 1917 </p>
			<p>56-57: Transcript and minutes conference with BRT Yardmen, Chicago, February, July,
				August and November, 1917 </p>
			<p>33-34: Correspondence relative strength of BRT AND SUNA, Chicago Switching District,
				1917, circular 2533 </p>
			<p>49-50: Correspondence and negotiations on application of settlement awarded by
				Committee of the Council of National Defense on Adamson Law between Committee of
				Managers and BRT-Trainmen-Chicago Switching District, April 2 to 14, 1917 </p>
			<p>35: Final report of Committee of General Managers in conference with BRT Chicago
				District, February 17 to April 17, 1913 </p>
			<p>35: Preliminary report of Committee of General Managers in conference with BRT,
				Chicago District, Jan. 22, 1910 to Feb. 12, 1910 </p>
			<p>33-34: Memorandum of Agreement, April 17, 1913, BRT and General Managers' Committee </p>
			<p>35: Final Report, Committee of General Managers and BRT (Yardmen, Chicago Switching
				District) March 19, 1910 </p>
			<p>33-34: Rulings of Managers' Conference Committee (BRT) Oct. 28, 1915, on agreement
				effective April 16, 1913 (Chicago Switching Dist.) </p>
			<p>33-34: Rulings of Managers' Conference Committee (BRT) Jan. 31, 1919 on agreement
				effective April 16, 1913 (Chicago Switching Dist.) </p>
			<p>35: Rulings of Managers' Conference Committee (BRT) December 28, 1915 on agreement
				effective March 25, 1910 (Chicago Switching Dist.) </p>
			<p>35: Minutes of meetings, Conference Committee of Managers, March and April, 1920 </p>
			<p>33-34: Agreement with BRT, Chicago Switching District, meal hour rule, November 1917,
				Circular 2656 </p>
			<p>33-34: Questions and rulings by Managers' Conference Committee (BRT) January 31, 1919
				on agreement of August 2, 1917 (Chicago Switching Dist.) </p>
			<p>33-34: Memorandum of agreement, BRT, Chicago Switching Dist., August 2, 1917, copies
				correspondence and data thereon </p>
			<p>33-34: Copies of opinion of Supreme Court of U.S. No. 640, Oct. 1917, re violation of
				Hours of Service Act, C&amp;A case </p>
			<p>33-34: Correspondence November, 1929, reinstating Chicago Memorandum of Agreement </p>
			<p>38-39: Earnings of yard foremen and yard helpers and switchtenders, 1923, compiled by
				USRRLB. Vols. 4 and 5 </p>
			<p>71-72-75: Copies of report of Emergency Board dated 3/7/37; also copies of transcript
				of hearings held at Chicago Feb. 15-16, 1937, in re dispute between CGW RR and its
				train-, engine- and yardmen relative interpretation of certain awards of 1st Div.,
				Nat'l. R.R. Adjt'. Board. </p>
			<p>58-60: Minutes of meetings, Committee and SUNA, New York, July 20 to Aug. 3, 1916 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Committee, conference at Chicago, Nov. 11-19, 1907 </p>
			<p>35: Report of Committee, Railways in Northwest, conference Nov. 19-23, 1909 St. Paul </p>
			<p>35: Preliminary report of Committee, conference Dec. 21, 1909 to Jan. 5, 1910,
				Chicago </p>
			<p>35: Final report of Committee, conference at Chicago, March 23, 1910 </p>
			<p>35: Correspondence SUNA movement, 1916 </p>
			<p>42-43-44: Proceedings of arbitration SUNA vs. various railroads March, 1910 </p>
			<p>66-69: Exhibits submitted by Conference Committee in SUNA arbitration, New York, 1916 </p>
			<p>66-69: Proposition No. 65; wage demands 1918, ORC-BRT and SUNA. Submission to
				committee, authorizations, representations and miscellaneous data </p>
			<p>  </p>
			<p>NON-OPERATING CRAFTS </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Clerks </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>42-43-44: Exhibits and arguments – Clerks' hearing before USRRLB April, 1922 Docket
				1300 </p>
			<p>45-46: Exhibits, briefs, correspondence, etc. Clerks hearing November 23, 24 and 25,
				1922 – USRRLB </p>
			<p>86-87-90: Exhibits, briefs, submissions, correspondence, rates and rules, Clerks July
				23, 24, 1923 – supplementary hearing </p>
			<p>66-69: Rates of pay February 29, 1920 and July 1, 1923, USRRLB, compilation Regional
				– five volumes </p>
			<p>82-83-85: Exhibits, briefs, etc., Clerks request for increase in rates. Hearings
				October 8, 9, 10, 1924, USRRLB – dockets 4214, 4215, decision 2776 </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Exhibits and award, arbitration, Clerks vs. Ill. Cent. 1927 </p>
			<p>53-55: Copy transcript Illinois Central Clerks' arbitration – Year 1927, Volumes 1 to
				25 inclusive </p>
			<p>59-61-64: Copy of transcript proceedings arbitration Clerks vs. NYC RR and Grand
				Central Terminal, February and March, 1927 </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Clerks vs. Southern Pacific (Texas &amp; La.) Supreme Court
				decision. Copies of injunction; briefs before Supreme Court, etc. Extra copies of
				circular 9-36, June 12, 1930. Complete set of circulars, briefs, injunction, etc. </p>
			<p>35: Intervening petition of the National Industrial Traffic League, Alabama
				&amp; Vicksburg Ry. Co. vs. Brotherhood Clerks, docket 1300 </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Transcript of arb. proceedings, Mo Pac vs Clerks (Aug. 1845) involving (1)
				weighing of cars by other than clerical forces; (2) Sat. Afternoon work </p>
			<p>52-54: Transcript of proceedings, Emergency Board, dispute Florida East Coast vs.
				Clerks (NMB Cases A-2072-2152-1125-1129-1132) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Dispatchers </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>53-55: Briefs, exhibits, submissions, circular letters, correspondence, train
				dispatchers hearing before Labor Board October 2, 1923 rates of pay, Decision 2053,
				USRRLB </p>
			<p>71-72-75: Transcript of hearing before Interstate Commerce Commission in Ex Parte 72,
				Washington, D.C. December 5 and 8, 1923. Dispatchers &amp; Supervisory
				Agents. </p>
			<p>86-87-90: Brief and exhibits – Dispatchers hearing in docket 1300, 1922 USRRLB </p>
			<p>33-34: Transcript of proceedings – hearing September 29, 1923, USRRLB, docket 3561,
				Dispatchers vs. AT&amp;SF Ry. </p>
			<p>62-63: Correspondence and data regarding rehearsing before Interstate Commerce
				Commission in Ex Parte 72, December 5 to 8, 1923 </p>
			<p>33-34: Transcript of proceedings (Volumes 1, 2, 3, and 4) Board of Arbitration,
				American Train Dispatchers Association vs. L&amp;N RR, September 1-8,
				1927 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Maintenance of Way Employees </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>62-63: Rates of pay – February 29, 1920 and December 1, 1923, compiled by USRRLB, 5
				volumes (Regional) </p>
			<p>58-60: Exhibits, briefs, correspondence, request for revision of rules and working
				conditions. M of W Employees. Docket 4040. Hearing June 24, 1924, decision 2687
				USRRLB </p>
			<p>59-61-64: Transcript of proceedings M of W Employees vs. C&amp;NW Ry.
				Arbitration, 1927 </p>
			<p>86-87-90: General file, request of Bro. of M. of W. Employees for changes in rules –
				1936 (Time and one-half after eight hours) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Shop Crafts </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>35: Railroads' position, application of Rule 6 – Sunday &amp; holiday
				service, 1921 </p>
			<p>67-68-70: Proceedings injunction hearing before Judge Wilkerson, U.S. vs. Shop
				Crafts, September 11 to 21, 1922 (Also opinion of Court) </p>
			<p>67-68-70: Brief in behalf of 15 standard recognized labor organizations covering
				request of National Industrial Traffic League to file intervening petition Docket
				1300 </p>
			<p>35: Shop Crafts rates of pay Eastern and Southeastern railroads – 1917 </p>
			<p>53-55: The problem of piece work (Jewell) Docket 475, hearing before Labor Board,
				January 1921 </p>
			<p>35: Demands of shop employees, 1916; 8 hour day; increase in hourly rates </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Shop Crafts request for increase in rates and revision of working
				conditions and agreements made year 1923 </p>
			<p>71-72-75: Miscellaneous data – Shop Crafts strike – 1922 </p>
			<p>65: Exhibits in arbitration, Railway Employees Department AF of L and New York
				Central Lines – December 1928 and January 1929 </p>
			<p>65: Complete set reporter's transcript of Arbitration Board proceedings Railway
				Employees Department AF of L and New York Central Volumes 1 to 25 inclusive,
				December 1928 and January 1929 </p>
			<p>53-55: 1 complete set of opening and closing arguments in arbitration proceedings
				Railway Employees Department of AF of L and New York Central, December 1928 and
				January 1929 </p>
			<p>56-57: 1 complete set mimeographed transcript of proceedings of Board of Arbitration
				(Volumes 1 to 15 inclusive) in case Southern and Allied Federated Shop Crafts vs.
				Southern Railway Lines May and June 1929 </p>
			<p>53-55: 1 complete set mimeographed transcript of proceedings of Emergency Board
				(Volumes 1 to 6 inclusive) appointed to hear case Louisiana &amp;
				Arkansas Ry. and Railway Employees Department AF of L, April 1931 </p>
			<p>86-87-90: Reporter's transcript, exhibits, Emergency Board report and miscellaneous
				correspondence case Louisiana &amp; Arkansas Ry. vs. AF of L Shop
				Crafts, 1931 </p>
			<p>52-54: Transcript of proceedings of investigation by the National Mediation Board of
				dispute concerning representation of Shop Employees of Atlantic Coast Line RR –
				Cases No. R-15, R-231 (Vols. 1 to 6, incl. [Nov. 11 to 24-1934] and Jan. 24
				&amp; 25, 1935); also copies of the various documents filed in the
				Supreme Court of the Dist. Of Columbia relative thereto </p>
			<p>95: 1 set of transcript (7 vols.) of MOBILE &amp; OHIO RR. hearings
				before Emergency Board 11/29/33 to 12/6/33, re: continuation of agreement providing
				for additional 10% deduction from payrolls of certain employees (Engine and Train
				Service, Dispatchers, Shop Crafts, M of W, etc.); also report of Emergency Board
				dated 12/9/33, together with other correspondence thereon. (C.O.O. Circulars Nos.
				115, 115-1, 115-2, 115-3 and 115-4) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Signalmen </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>96: Employees' presentation and exhibits. Hearing 1921. Rates of pay, docket 1300
				USRRLB </p>
			<p>33-34: Transcript of proceedings (Vols. I, II and III) Board of Arbitration, Signal
				Dept. Employees vs L&amp;N RR, Oct. 3-8, 1927 </p>
			<p>33-34: Transcript of proceedings Vols. I, II and III Board of Arbitration, Signal
				Dept. Employees vs. NC&amp;StL Ry. and Nashville Terminals, June 4, 6,
				7, 8 and 9, 1928 </p>
			<p>33-34: Transcript of proceedings, Board of Arbitration, February 1-2-3, 1927, in case
				of Bro. of RR Signalmen of America vs. SOU PAC-PAC SYSTEM </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Telegraphers (tentative reel assignments) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>66-69-71-72: Brief, exhibits, correspondence and submissions, data, hearing July 27,
				1923, decision No. 2025, USRRLB </p>
			<p>45-46: Exhibits and briefs. Request for increase in rates and revision of rules. I.C.
				Hearing November 17, 1924, docket 4377, Decision 2836 USRRLB </p>
			<p>82-83-85: Statement showing rates of pay telegraph department employees in effect
				December 1, 1926 – Summary of replies to circular CO-1926-7 (B) </p>
			<p>82-83-85: Statement showing rates of pay telegraph department employees in effect
				November 1, 1928 – Summary of replies to circular No. 11-16 </p>
			<p>56-57: 1 complete set mimeographed copy of transcript of hearings of Arbitration
				Board, ORT vs. Ill. Cent. System, July 17 to Aug. 1, 1931. (Vols. I to XII,
				Inclusive) 3 copies of award and circular 11-31 (a) </p>
			<p>86-87-90: Proceedings – Arbitration CRI&amp;P Ry and ORT – October, 1917 </p>
			<p>40-41: Comparison telegraphers schedules in effect January, 1916, certain Western
				roads </p>
			<p>40-41: Correspondence and data – Telegraphers hearing Feb. 21, 1922 USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Correspondence and data on Interpretation 8 to Supplement 13, G.O. 27 </p>
			<p>40-41: Correspondence and data on hearing October 16, 1922, application of rules 2 to
				8 decision 757, USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Transcript of proceedings – rehearing Feb. 15, 1923, decision 1448, USRRLB
				(Interpretation 8 to supplement 13 to G.O. 27) </p>
			<p>40-41: Average hourly rates of pay by distinctive classes, Sept. 1, 1924, compiled by
				USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Exhibits and briefs – request for increase in rates and revision of rules and
				working conditions MKT-OSL-OWRR&amp;N-StLSF. Hearing June 23, 1924,
				Docket 3366, Decision 2557, USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Exhibits and briefs – requests for increase in rates and revision of rules.
				IGN relief days – TRRA – hearing May 28, 1925. Dockets 4766, Decision 3888, Dockets
				4758-4759 and 4766 </p>
			<p>40-41: Exhibits and briefs – request for increase in rates and revision of rules,
				CB&amp;Q CGW hearing Sept. 24-25, 1925. Dockets 4879-4928-4896-4929
				USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Exhibits and briefs – request for increase in rates, AT&amp;SF,
				D&amp;RGW, Sou Pac-Pac, hearing October 14-15, 1925 – docket 4218,
				decision 2686 USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Exhibits and briefs – request for rates and rules revisions – hearing December
				11, 1925 – G&amp;SI, QO&amp;KC, CRI&amp;P –
				dockets 4990-4993-4993-4995-5009, decision 4197 USRRLB </p>
			<p>40-41: Transcript of proceedings Northern Pacific arbitration, March 1927 </p>
			<p>40-41: Extracts from transcript of proceedings of Board of Arbitration concerning
				request of employees for relief days and vacation with pay. Telegraphers vs.
				Washington Terminal – Arbitration September, 1927 (See circulars 11-10 and 11-10
				(a)) </p>
			<p>40-41: Stenographic transcript of arbitration proceedings between ORT and Midland
				Valley, KO&amp;G, July 16-17, 1928; also brief of ORT, brief of Carriers
				and reply brief of ORT </p>
			<p>40-41: 2 complete sets mimeograph copy of transcript of hearings of arbitration board
				(December, 1928) ORT vs Southern Ry. </p>
			<p>40-41: Proceedings – hearing before USRRLB March 18, 1922 – Interpretation 8 to
				supplement 13 – Docket 1300 </p>
			<p>40-41: Proceedings – hearing before USRRLB October 16 &amp; 17, 1922 –
				Telegraphers – Interpretation of application of Rules 2 to 8 inclusive of Decision
				757 </p>
			<p>40-41: Index compiled by B.I.E. Rys., covering decisions affecting telegraph
				employees as issued by the USRR Administrations, Ry. Bd. Of Adj't. #3, and the
				USRRLB Labor Board. (COO Circular 159(f)) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Yardmasters </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>45-46: Correspondence, data, regarding rates of pay and rules and working conditions
				of yardmasters </p>
			<p>33-34: Compilation rates of pay yardmasters as of February 29, 1920 and July 1, 1925
				USRRLB </p>
			<p>  </p>
			<p>GOVERNMENT AGENCIES </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Boards of Adjustment </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>53-55: 1 copy of Index to decisions of Train Service Board at Adj't. for the
				Southeastern Region – Cases 1 to 376, incl. as of January 1, 1929 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Federal Coordinator of Transportation </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>35: Spreading Employment – Suggestions of Federal Coordinator, September 1933 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Mediation Boards (U.S. Bd. of Mediation) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>35: Report and hearings before Committee on Interstate Commerce, 69th Congress – bill
				to provide for prompt disposition of disputes between carriers and employees </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Mediation Boards (U.S. Railroad Administration) </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>38-39: Supplement 15 – Memoranda 1 to 96 </p>
			<p>62-63: Data in connection with conference at Washington, 1919 between U.S.R.R.
				Administration and Executives of Train and Engine Service organization preliminary
				to issuance of Supplements 15 and 16 and interpretations </p>
			<p>62-63: Books containing official interpretations of rules of the National Agreement
				between U.S.R.R. Adm'n and Railway Employees Dept., AFL </p>
			<p>35: Books containing proclamation by President relating to U.S. Railroad
				Administration and general orders and circulars issued by Director General of
				Railroads January 1, 1919 to February 29, 1920 </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Awards and Findings – War Labor Board, 1917-18 </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Printed decisions of Boards of Adjustment Nos. 1, 3/22/18 to 4/1/20; 2,
				5/31/18 to 4/1/20; 3, 11/13/18 to 4/1/20. (Assembled by USRRLB but not bound) </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Printed decisions of Board of Adjustment No. 2, 5/31/18 to 4/1/20.
				(Assembled by USRRLB but not bound) </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Printed decisions of Board of Adjustment No. 3, 11/13/18 to 4/1/20.
				(Assembled by USRRLB but not bound) </p>
			<p>35: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, General Letters, Vol. </p>
			<p>78: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, General Letters, Vol. 2 </p>
			<p>78: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Geeral Letters, Vol. 3 </p>
			<p>78: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, General Letters, Vol. 4 </p>
			<p>78: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Inquiries, Vol. 1, Vol. 2 </p>
			<p>78: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Circulars, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>80: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Circulars, Vol. 2 </p>
			<p>80: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Appointments, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>80: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Bulletins, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>80: Northwestern Region, Regional Director, Car Distribution Notices, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>78: Northwestern Region, Regional Director Order No. 27, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>81: Western Region, Regional Director, General Letters, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>81: Western Region, Regional Director, Circulars, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>80: Director General Department, Dir. General Circulars, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>80: Director General Department, Divn. of Opr.; Divn. of Labor; Divn. of Traffic,
				Circulars, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>81: Director General Department, Divn. oLaw; Divn. of Cap Expes; Divn. of Fin. and ;
				Divn. of P.S. and ; Cent. Advsry Pchsg. Com. Circulars, Vol. 1 </p>
			<p>80: Director General Department, Director General Orders, Vol. </p>
			<p>38-39: Lane Commission – Data in connection with hearing before Wage Commission,
				February 1918 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>United State Railroad Labor Board </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>67-68-70: Average wage rates and general rules of railroad employees on Class I
				carriers – Wage series Report No. 5, USRRLB </p>
			<p>38-39: Report of USRRLB April 15, 1920 to December 31, 1925 </p>
			<p>38-39: Extra copies of Decision No. 147 </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Individual rates of pay of employees of American Ry. Express Co., December
				1, 1923 (USRRLB Compilation) </p>
			<p>66-69: Correspondence and data – Decision 119, addenda and interpretations thereto </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Correspondence and data, Decision 222 – Shop Crafts </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Rates of pay mechanics and helpers (MofE Dept.) and coach cleaners as of
				Dec. 1, 1925, USRRLB-Form RWME-2, All Territories </p>
			<p>45-46: Correspondence and data, all classes, wage hearings Mar. 6 to Apr. 24, 1922 </p>
			<p>56-57: Rates of pay (Shop Crafts), Feb. 29, 1920 and Dec. 1, 1923 – Eastern,
				Southeastern, Cent. Western, Southwestern and Northwestern Territories (Compiled by
				USRRLB) </p>
			<p>53-55: Earnings of Firemen – Pass., Frt. &amp; Yard, 1923 (Compiled by
				USRRLB, Vols. 8-9-10) </p>
			<p>49-50: Monthly and annual earnings of Train and Engine Service employees, 1923 Vol.
				12 (Compiled by USRRLB) </p>
			<p>47-48-51-71-72-75: Transcript of Proceedings Jan. 10, 1921 to May 12, 1921 – Dec.19,
				Dockets 1, 2 and 3 </p>
			<p>49-50: Memoranda – Wages in effect prior to Federal control, Association Western
				Railways meeting July 5, 1921 </p>
			<p>49-50: Printed proceedings – Hearings USRRLB, Rates of pay, docket 353, 1921 –
				Decision 147 </p>
			<p>35: Railroad hearings 1920-1921 – Statements made by Association of Railway
				Executives, Conference Committee of Managers (E.T. Whiter, Chairman) before USRRLB
				on rules and rates (8 volumes) </p>
			<p>71-72-75: Piecework exhibits submitted to USRRLB hearing January, 1921 </p>
			<p>67-68-70: Correspondence and data, all classes, wage hearings March 6 – April 24,
				1922 </p>
			<p>45-46: Digest of submissions of carriers and employees for decreases and increases
				rates of pay, wage hearings 1922, 2 volumes, USRRLB – Statistical Bureau </p>
			<p>96: Form 2, rates of pay in outside industries, December, 1921 – States </p>
			<p>94: Form 3, number of men at various rates of pay, outside industries, December, 1921
				(States and Cities) </p>
			<p>94: Index to Form 2 – Wisconsin, North Dakota, Kansas Cit hearings 1922 </p>
			<p>36-37: Correspondence – regarding compilation Forms 2, 2-A, 3 and 4, hearings, 1922 </p>
			<p>95: Form 2, rates of pay in outside industries, December, 1921 – Cities </p>
			<p>36-37: Forms 2, 2-A, 3 and 4, Chicago. Rates of pay in Chicago industries, December,
				1921. Work sheets </p>
			<p>36-37: Recommendations of committee – meeting of State and City Chairmen,
				Correspondence, etc. </p>
			<p>95: Wage – hearing – data and exhibits, Eastern railroads </p>
			<p>95: Savings – Statements Western railroads – savings on rates proposed by managements
				over rates established by decisions 2 and 147 </p>
			<p>94: Higgins' exhibit – rates of pay outside industries, States and Cities </p>
			<p>  </p>
			<p>MISCELLANEOUS </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>49-50: Howell-Barkley Bill-Hearings and correspondence – Senate No. 2646; House No.
				7358, year 1924 </p>
			<p>49-50: Brief and Arguments for plaintiff, AT&amp;SF Ry. vs. U.S. – 8-hour
				law violation (Yardmasters) No. 3475 </p>
			<p>38-39: Data on Watson-Parker Bill – "Railway Labor Act" S-2306: H.R.-7180 </p>
			<p>94: Association of Ry. Executives – Labor Committee 1920; correspondence with Labor
				organizations </p>
			<p>36-37: Statement submitted to the I.C.C. by the Assn. of Western Ry. Executives Oct.
				25, 1930 (Increase Freight Rate Case) </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Emergency R.R. Transportation Act – 1933 – hearings before Senate Committee
				and Miscellaneous Papers </p>
			<p>66-69: Representation of Red Caps (General File) </p>
			<p>59-61-64: Coordination allowance agreement of 5/21/36; Railway dismissal compensation
				correspondence and miscellaneous papers in regard thereto </p>
			<p>58-60: Transcript RyX Agency – Teamsters, July 1955 (AWR File 200-389) </p>
			<p>33-34: 1933 – 72d Cong. – 2d Session – HR-11012: Copies of hearing before Committee
				on Interstate and Foreign Commerce, House of Representatives, January 3, 4, 5, 1933 </p>
			<p>33-34: Transcript of hearings on train limit investigation – Illinois Commerce
				Commission – Vols. 1, to 43, incl. years 1934-35-36-37 (Vol. II missing) </p>
			<p>54-52: Eight-hour Law Case No. 797, in Supreme Court of U.S. Oct., Term, 1916 (F.M.
				Wilson, U.S. Att'y for the Western Dist. of Missouri, APPELLANT vs. Alexander New
				and H.C. Ferris, as Recrs. of MO&amp;G Ry. Co.) consisting of the
				following documents: (1) Supplemental Memorandum for Appellant; (2) Appendix "A" to
				a Brief for Appellees; (3) Supplemental Brief; (4) Brief for Appellees; (5) Brief
				for the United States; (6) Summary of Appellant's Argument; (7) Appellee's Reply to
				Supplemental Memorandum for Appellant; (8) Opinion of the Court – Chief Justice
				White; (9) Dissenting Opinion – Justice Pitney; (10) Concurring Opinion – Justice
				McKenna, Mar. 19, 1917; (11) Dissenting Opinion – Justice McReynolds; (12)
				Dissenting Opinion – Justice Day </p>
			<p>35: Hearing before Interstate Commerce Commission on threatened strike of railroad
				employees August 31, 1916 (Document No. 549) </p>
			<p>35: Complainant's Bill, in the Dist. Court of the U.S., Eastern Dist. of Penna. (M.F.
				Glessner vs. J.B. Hendricks, et al) </p>
			<p>35: Complainant's Bill, in the Dist. Court of the U.S., Eastern Dist. of Penna. (D.J.
				Burk vs. Wm. Whitman, et al) </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Complete set Railroad Exhibits with index (#1 to 49, incl., also 113-115) </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Complete set Employee Exhibits with Index (#50 to 112, incl.) </p>
			<p>35: Stet. </p>
			<p>91-92-93: Statement of J.W. Roberts appearing on behalf of BRT relative to Exhibits
				#69 to 82 </p>
			<p>33-34: Complete set supplemental exhibits filed with I.C.C. by Eastern, Western and
				Southeastern Bureaus </p>
			<p>35: Set original Western exhibits and supplemental statements thereto </p>
			<p>91-92-93: General File </p>
			<p>35: Six-Hour Day Bills introduced 73d Congress, March – April 1933 </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Six-Hour Day Legislation – 1934 (73d Congress – 2d Session) General File
				(Bills S-2519 and HR-7430) </p>
			<p>76-79-84: Six-Hour Day Legislation – 1936-37 (75th Congress – 1st Session – HR 1606
				and S-175) General File on six-hour day movement – 1936-37 </p>
			<p>33-34: Proceedings of the Conference between Representatives of Railroads and
				Representatives of Railroad employees, Washington – E.T. Whiter presiding March 22,
				1920 to April 1, 1920 </p>
			<p>33-34: Proceedings before Board of Railroad Wages and Working Conditions July 21,
				1919 to July 31, 1919 – Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen</p>
		</scopecontent>
		
		
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Railway Labor Conference (U.S.) </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects: </head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Railroads -- United States. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Railroads -- Employees -- Labor unions -- United
					States. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Collective bargaining -- Railroads -- United
					States. </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
					reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
					and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>National Railway Labor Conference Records on Microfilm #5205 mf. Kheel Center for
					Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<relatedmaterial>
			<head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
			<p>Related Collections:<lb/>
				<extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05205.html"> 5205:
					National Railway Labor Conference Additional Records</extref><lb/>
			</p>
		</relatedmaterial>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">33</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link8">Reel 33</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">34</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link9">Reel 34</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">35</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link10">Reel 35</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">36</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link11">Reel 36</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">37</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link12">Reel 37</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">38</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link13">Reel 38</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">39</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link14">Reel 39</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">40</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link15">Reel 40</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">41</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link16">Reel 41</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">42</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link17">Reel 42</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">43</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link18">Reel 43</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">44</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link19">Reel 44</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">45</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link20">Reel 45</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">46</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link21">Reel 46</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">47</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link22">Reel 47</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">48</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link23">Reel 48</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">49</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link24">Reel 49</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">50</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link25">Reel 50</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">51</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link26">Reel 51</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">52</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link27">Reel 52</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">53</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link28">Reel 53</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">54</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link29">Reel 54</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">55</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link30">Reel 55</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">56</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link31">Reel 56</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">57</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link32">Reel 57</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">58</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link33">Reel 58</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">59</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link34">Reel 59</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">60</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link35">Reel 60</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">61</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link36">Reel 61</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">62</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link37">Reel 62</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">63</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link38">Reel 63</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">64</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link39">Reel 64</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">65</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link40">Reel 65</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">66</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link41">Reel 66</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">67</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link42">Reel 67</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">68</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link43">Reel 68</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">69</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link44">Reel 69</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">70</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link45">Reel 70</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">71</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link46">Reel 71</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">72</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link47">Reel 72</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">73</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link48">Reel 73</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">74</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link49">Reel 74</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">75</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link50">Reel 75</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">76</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link51">Reel 76</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">77</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link52">Reel 77</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">78</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link53">Reel 78</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">79</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link54">Reel 79</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">80</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link55">Reel 80</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">81</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link56">Reel 81</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">82</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link57">Reel 82</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">83</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link58">Reel 83</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">84</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link59">Reel 84</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">85</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link60">Reel 85</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">86</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link61">Reel 86</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">87</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link62">Reel 87</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">88</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link63">Reel 88</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">89</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link64">Reel 89</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">90</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link65">Reel 90</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">91</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link66">Reel 91</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">92</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link67">Reel 92</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">93</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link68">Reel 93</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">94</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link69">Reel 94</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">95</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link70">Reel 95</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="reel">96</container>
					<unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
					<unittitle id="link71">Reel 96</unittitle>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>