<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-029::ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board Minutes.)//EN">KCL05780-029</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board Minutes</titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board Minutes</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by D. Mordente</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor- Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>April 02, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>April 02,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240223">02/23/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board Minutes</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780/029</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
                        Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>D. Mordente, January 14, 2004</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, April 02, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board
                Minutes, 
            </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1945-1968</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/029</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Montreal Dress Joint
                    Board</corpname>;
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">2 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:"> Minutes, correspondence .</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection contains meeting minutes of Montreal Joint
                Board's Board of Directors and the General Executive Board's Grievance and Appeal
                Committees, as well as of Local 262 of Montreal. Also included is some
                correspondence.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>, <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="fre">French</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>2 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>With the inclusion of the word "international" in its name, the ILGWU envisioned that
                Canada would become part of the union since its inception in 1900. While the
                official founding of a Toronto Union was in 1909, it was not until 1910 and 1911
                when locals became formally established, Cloak Local 14 and Pressers Local 92 in
                Toronto, and Cloak Cutters Local 19 and Coat Pressers Local 61 in Montreal. The
                Toronto Cloakmakers' Union was instituted in 1910 and the Toronto Joint Board and
                Montreal Joint Council were founded in 1911. But, it took until the 1930s for the
                irregular and infrequent organizing attempts to increase, and for real permanence
                for the ILGWU in Canada. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In Toronto in 1921, the manufacturers' association reintroduced piece work under the
                threat of a lockout. After a disastrous strike, a small group of members and locals
                remained faithful to the union, but were under considerable strain. ILGWU
                vice-president Saul Seidman was appointed in 1922 to handle the situation in Canada
                and increase organizing activity in Toronto and Montreal. The Toronto Joint Board
                put in place committees and chairmen in every shop to help efforts. Meanwhile, in
                Montreal, the cloak manufacturers proved difficult to negotiate with and hindered
                organizing in their shops. To combat the worsening situation in Canada, in 1924,
                Julius Hochman was appointed general organizer to build up the locals in Montreal
                and Toronto. Hochman held meetings and educated the workers. In the winter of 1925,
                the cloakmakers in Montreal and Toronto walked out of the shops. Manufacturers
                started signing agreements with the union and the workers remained on strike until
                all shops had satisfactorily signed up. And while conditions were far from ideal,
                the campaign created a more stable organization and union for the cloakmakers in
                Canada. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Toward the end of the decade, after the strikes and hardships, union standards were
                established in the industry and membership increased. Communist members in Montreal,
                including the majority of the Joint Board, caused internal strife forcing the
                closure of the Joint Board by 1927. While almost completely unionized, the industry
                in Toronto experienced difficulties as well. Yet, the Toronto Joint Board, led by
                Abraham Kirzner, fared far better than Montreal. Communist members in Toronto
                wreaked havoc in the Joint Board and locals, and it took a general strike in January
                1930, to renew the loyal members and organizing efforts of the union. The signed
                agreement called for union recognition in all shops, a 42 hour/5 day week, and
                minimum scales. A year later, in 1931, the manufacturers plotted to dissolve their
                association rendering the collective agreement with the union null and void and
                forcing the Toronto Joint Board to deal with individual shops. During this time, the
                dressmakers in Toronto began to organize and there was a strike in the dress shops
                in February 1931. The employers banded together and fought back. As the police
                arrested girls on the picket line, the union had to negotiate with individual firms.
                Managers of the Joint Board included Bernard Shane and Abraham Kirzner. Meanwhile,
                the union in Montreal was decimated until the end of 1929 when loyal cloakmakers
                began rebuilding their organization. A strike in the spring of 1930 ended quickly
                bringing gains of a 44 hour week, standard wage scales, union recognition and a
                collective agreement. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In 1932, Charles Kreindler was assigned to manage the Toronto Joint Board. With the
                union firmly established in the local market, the union now fought to protect
                workers' rights. Bernard Shane, a manager of Local 1, conducted strikes in Toronto
                in 1929-1931 and was later sent to Canada in 1934 to organize the Toronto
                cloakmakers. Soon after his arrival, he organized a strike for cutters and within
                five days had won a contract. With the threat of an industry wide strike, employers
                signed a collective agreement for all crafts in the cloak industry. A strike in
                January 1934 generated more gains for the now fully organized cloak market. The
                Toronto Joint Board celebrated its 25th anniversary in 1936 under the management of
                Samuel Kraisman. Attempts at bringing the Toronto dressmakers into the union finally
                succeeded when 800 workers joined Local 72. H. D. Langer replaced Kraisman as
                manager of the Toronto Joint Board in 1937. At the end of the decade, the Toronto
                Joint Board obtained the first collective agreement for the dress industry when it
                signed 50 shops representing 1,000 members. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Depression unfortunately caused years of poor seasons, low employment and minimal
                earnings for the cloakmakers of Montreal. Bernard Shane was sent to Montreal at the
                beginning of 1934 to increase organizing efforts. Shane mounted an effective
                organizing drive within the cutters and a strike led to wage increases. The union
                chartered Local 205 in 1934 for dress cutters as it attempted to organize the nearly
                8,000 dress workers in Montreal, the majority of which were French speaking women.
                An agreement was soon signed with the Montreal Dress Manufacturers' Guild. ILGWU
                vice-president Rose Pesotta arrived in 1936 to help organize the dress operators in
                Montreal, named "midinettes," after the practice of the women garment workers
                emerging from the factories at noon for a brief respite of air and sun. In January
                1937, Montreal Dressmakers Local 262 was chartered for the French speaking workers
                (Local 112 was the French local for the cloak industry). The Joint Council
                established an education department for the new local, produced special publications
                in French, and the campaign committee distributed literature and conducted
                publicity. A successful two week strike of 5,000 dressmakers in April 1937 led to an
                increase in wages, reduction in hours, and union recognition. In 1936, members of
                the Montreal Joint Council Cutters Local 19 and Pressers Local 61 celebrated their
                25th anniversary, and the union in Montreal found itself for the first time in
                fifteen years on a sound financial footing. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>A second general strike involving thousands of Montreal dressmakers also occurred in
                1940 which paralyzed the dress industry in Quebec and increased wages. Kraisman
                became assistant manager of the Montreal Joint Council, but retired in 1939, and was
                replaced by Isidore Stenzor. In 1937, the Montreal Joint Council began organizing
                the embroidery workers in the dress market, and later in the year, the union called
                a strike in the trade and an agreement was signed improving working conditions for
                Embroidery Workers' Local 315. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The dress and cloak industry in Montreal began enjoying prosperity during the 1940s.
                Montreal consisted of 8 locals (2 dress, 5 cloak, and 1 embroidery) headed by
                Bernard Shane. The Montreal Joint Board was composed of Dressmakers' Local 262 and
                Dress Cutters Local 205, whereas the cloakmakers functioned through the Joint
                Council (Locals 19, 43, 61, 112, and 342). During the 1940s, the industries expanded
                and contracts were renewed. There were 7 locals in Toronto (5 in the cloakmakers'
                union and 2 in dress and sportswear). The Toronto Cloak Joint Board consisted of the
                5 cloak locals, while Local 199 Sportswear Workers was also under the supervision of
                the Cloak Joint Board. A number of recent retirements had left a shortage of workers
                in the industry. Hyman Langer, who had been manager of the Board retired and Samuel
                Kraisman returned to take his place, being re-elected in 1947. The Joint Council of
                the Dressmakers' Union in Toronto was comprised of Locals 72 and 192 managed by
                Joseph Mack. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Canada market soon expanded to include Winnipeg and Vancouver. In 1952, the
                Montreal Dressmakers' union celebrated its 15th anniversary. Claude Jodoin was
                manager of the Dressmakers' Union in the 1950s. He was also president of the Trades
                and Labor Council of Montreal and vice-president (and later president) of the Trades
                and Labor Congress of Canada. The 1950s also saw an expansion of benefits including
                retirement, vacation, and health. Canada's first Union Health Center was dedicated
                in March 1955 in the new headquarters of the Montreal ILGWU. In 1956 Sam Kraisman
                managed the Toronto Cloak Joint Board, Joe Mack was manager of the Toronto
                Dressmakers, and Bernard Shane was general organizer of Canada. A growing number of
                non- union shops began appearing in smaller communities such as Saskatchewan and
                Alberta. In response, a large coast to coast organizing drive across Canada began in
                1955, with Samuel Herbst (manager of Winnipeg Joint Board) as coordinator to bring
                the thousands of new workers into the union. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>By 1959, the cross-Canada campaign had organized more than 3,500 new members and
                almost completely unionized the cloak industry in Canada. The 1960s saw a steadily
                growing Canadian apparel industry and the spreading use of the union label. 1960
                marked the 50th anniversary for Toronto Cloakmakers' Union and 1962 the 25th
                anniversary of Montreal Dressmakers' Union. A new ILGWU Center in Montreal opened in
                1964 in the middle of the garment area and also housed the ILGWU health center and
                welfare funds offices. At the end of the decade, Bernard Shane was director of ILGWU
                Canada and general manager for Montreal, the Montreal Dressmakers were managed by
                Maurice Manel and the Montreal Cloak Board was led by Sam Liberman; Sam Kraisman
                managed the Toronto Cloak Joint Board and Joseph Macks the Toronto Dress. Over the
                years, agreements for shorter work weeks and cost of living raises were achieved. In
                September 1970, Kraisman retired and the Dress and Cloak Boards of Toronto were
                merged into one unit under Joseph Macks who had been managing the Dress Joint Board
                for over 30 years. Bernard Shane retired in 1971, marking more than six decades with
                the ILGWU, nearly 40 of those working in Canada. Si Bresner took over as manager of
                the ILGWU in Montreal, becoming director of Canada and general manager of Montreal,
                with Maurice Manel manager of the Montreal Dress and Sam Liberman manager of the
                Montreal Cloak Board. Joseph Macks died in 1973, and William Villano became manager
                of the Toronto Cloak and Dress Joint Board. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In 1976, 100 delegates across Canada voted to officially establish the Canadian
                Region of the ILGWU, formalizing previously existing Canadian autonomy. ILGWU vice-
                president Si Bresner was elected as the Canadian director. In 1977 Stephen Perkal
                became manager of the Montreal Cloak Board and Luigi Infantino manager of the Quebec
                Province. Canadian garment workers took part in mass demonstrations to fight against
                the increase of foreign imports in Canada in 1977. In 1980, the Dress and Cloak
                Joint Boards of Montreal were merged into a new Montreal Joint Board with Robert
                Fontaine becoming the new general manager in the wake of Bresner's announced
                retirement in 1981. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>After an investigation by the Quebec Federation of Labor in the fall of 1981,
                recommendations for change and restructuring were recommended, with the QFL
                supervising the reform to create a union more democratic and responsive to the
                approximately 15,000 members. A meeting in March 1982 set the course for a
                restructuring and reorganization of the union in Quebec. A group of union activists,
                the "Democratic Action League," had spent years working toward an organization with
                a local leadership and active membership participation in union policies and
                procedures. At the March 1982 meeting, Gilles Gauthier became president of the ILGWU
                in Quebec and new by-laws were written. The first formal constitutional convention
                of the Quebec Joint Council Quebec was in February 1983, and Gauthier was elected
                president. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>At the end of the 1980s, Canada saw a drastic decline in textile and garment jobs,
                losing hundreds of thousands of workers. Gauthier resigned from his posts in May
                1984, and was replaced by Gerald Roy. Roy was officially elected president of the
                Quebec Joint Council and in 1986 elected Canadian director. Villano retired from
                Toronto in 1986 and Herman Stewart was elected the new manager. Tino Ciampanelli was
                elected president of the Quebec Joint Council in 1995. The North American Free Trade
                Agreement (NAFTA) and the Canada-U.S. Free Trade Agreement (FTA) continued to
                contribute to the loss of thousands of jobs in the garment industry in Canada.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>The records of the Montreal Joint Board consist of three series: minutes of the Board
                of Directors, minutes of the General Executive Board, and minutes of the Montreal
                Joint Board of Directors. The Board of Directors meeting minutes are bound books,
                and information included lists members of the board by election date beginning in
                1941-1957, 1962, and 1967. The minutes are in both French and English, and encompass
                the dates January 8, 1946-November 14, 1957, December 20, 1963, and December 12,
                1966. Subjects mentioned in the minutes include: the union label, shops organized,
                conferences, pensions, sick benefits, complaints, and scholarship funds. There is
                also business of a local and more intimate nature such as retirements, birthday and
                holiday celebrations, and announcements. Well documented is the incident of "The
                Trial of Seventeen Cutters" which was the investigation into the Cutters' Local
                election of 1965 in which individuals were barred entrance into a Union First Club
                meeting and began to picket. The picket signs contained messages that maligned the
                ILGWU and the event was televised. The seventeen members were found guilty and in
                the records are questions and answers from the charges, as well as their appeal. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The minutes of the Joint Board Dressmakers' include listings of members in the Joint
                Board Committee since 1938, elected officials, meeting attendance, information on
                minimum scales, contracts, automation, paid holidays, proposed amendments, and
                financial reports on the ILGWU Centre between the years January 3, 1945-December 13,
                1967. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Joint Board consisted of locals 205, 262, 438, 439, 485, 521 </p>
            <p>Joint Council Cloakmakers Union consisted of locals 19, 43, 61, 112, 342 (Cloak and
                Suit Makers Union)</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    -- Montreal Joint Board (Montreal, (Quebec)) </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Women's clothing industry -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Women's clothing industry -- Quebec (Province)
                    -- Montreal. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- United
                    States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Labor unions -- Clothing workers -- Quebec
                    (Province) -- Montreal. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Clothing workers -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Clothing workers -- Quebec (Province) --
                    Montreal. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Industrial relations -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Industrial relations -- Quebec (Province) --
                    Montreal. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>ILGWU Montreal Dress Joint Board Minutes #5780/029. Kheel Center for
                    Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            
            <p>Related Collections:
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780:
                    ILGWU records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-025.html">
                    5780/025: ILGWU Local 262 Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-026.html">
                    5780/026: ILGWU Local 315 Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-027.html">
                    5780/027: ILGWU Local 205 Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-028.html">
                    5780/028: ILGWU Montreal locals Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-030.html">
                    5780/030: ILGWU Montreal Joint Council Minutes</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-116.html">
                    5780/116: ILGWU Montreal Joint Board Records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-117.html">
                    5780/117: ILGWU Quebec Joint Council Records</extref>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Board of Directors. Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1946/1957" type="inclusive">1946-1957</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French with English Translation. Bound volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Board of Directors. Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1958/1963" type="inclusive">1958-1963</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French with English Translation. Bound volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Board of Directors. Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1964/1966" type="inclusive">1964-1966</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French with English Translation. Bound volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Board of Directors. Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1967">1967</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French with English Translation and The Trial of Seventeen Cutters in English
                        complete transcript. Bound volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Board of Directors. Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1965/1966" type="inclusive">1965-1966</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link13">General Executive Board. Grievance Committee.
                        Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1965">1965</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">General Executive Board. Appeal Committee.
                        Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1966/1968" type="inclusive">1966-1968</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French &amp; English</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link15">Montreal Joint Board. Board of Directors.
                        Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1945/1954" type="inclusive">1945-1954</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Local 262 Minutes in French with English Translation. Bound volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link16">Montreal Joint Board. Board of Directors.
                        Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1955/1962" type="inclusive">1955-1962</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French with English Translation. Bound volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">2</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link17">Montreal Joint Board. Board of Directors.
                        Minutes.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1963/1967" type="inclusive">1963-1967</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>French with English Translation and some Correspondence in English. Bound
                        volume.</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>