<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
		scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
			publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05370::Montgomery Ward and Company vs. Northern Pacific Terminal Company
of Oregon Records.)//EN"
			>KCL05370</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the Montgomery Ward and Company vs. Northern Pacific Terminal
					Company of Oregon Records<date> 1951-1953</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">Montgomery Ward and Company vs. Northern Pacific Terminal
					Company of Oregon Records</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by E. Parker</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
					University Library</publisher>
				<date>March 13, 2017</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 13,
					2017</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the Montgomery Ward and Company vs. Northern Pacific Terminal
				Company of Oregon Records<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 5370</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
						P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
						Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183> <extref
							href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center"
							>http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>E. Parker, February 28, 2017</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, March 13, 2017</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>&#169; 2017 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library </date>
			<sponsor>This collection was processed with the help of generous funding from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC).</sponsor>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Montgomery Ward and Company vs.
				Northern Pacific Terminal Company of Oregon Records, <unitdate
					encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1951-1953</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5370</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Montgomery Ward and
					Company</corpname>;<lb/>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Northern Pacific Terminal
					Company of Oregon (PTRC)</corpname>;<lb/>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 700" role="creator">Fee, James Alger,
					1888-1959.</persname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents) .</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
				Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">Brief, reply brief, and opinion argued before the United
				States District Court, District of Oregon [Civil Case No. 1686]. This suit was filed
				by Montgomery Ward to recover damages from motor carriers. The damages resulted from
				a strike and a secondary boycott of Montgomery Ward. The filings by the plaintifs
				and defendants date from 1951, the opinion of the presiding judge dates from
				1953.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
					encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		</did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
			<p>On December 7, 1940, the clerks and warehousemen at Montgomery Ward's Portland plant
				went on strike over the terms of settlement in a labor dispute. When the
				negotiations over the terms of settlement broke down on December 20, the Teamsters
				Union, representing the warehousemen, called for a general boycott of the goods
				being shipped to and from the plant. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>A contract clause in the Agreement between the Teamsters and the Carriers servicing
				Montgomery Ward stated that the Union was not in favor of sympathetic strikes and
				further provided that the Union would not interfere with interstate commerce or in
				the intrastate commerce moving over the lines of the operator. Despite the language
				in this provision, there were innumerable instances of direct coercion of employers
				and employees to restrict handling of Ward's merchandise. After a brief period of
				struggle with the boycott, the carriers abandoned all attempts to service Montgomery
				Ward. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In addition to the general boycott, a secondary boycott was developed against the
				company which exhibited equal strength. Major oil companies refused to sell or
				deliver fuel oil to the plant, longshoremen refused to handle Ward's merchandise,
				the Post Office refused to handle any more goods than had been customary before the
				strike, and railroads did not switch cars onto Ward's sidings. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Only after hearings before the Interstate Commerce Commission did the carriers resume
				service. Soon afterward, Ward's entered suit against the carriers involved in the
				strike and boycott in the District Court for recovery of damages that resulted. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Since the case was not ruled on until 1953, the decision was more concerned with
				carrier liability than with the actual award of damages. The judge, the Honorable
				James Alger Fee, ruled on the basis of common law that the "carriers were each
				responsible for the acts and defaults of their own servants...and that 'tertiary'
				boycotts to isolate a single business from the facilities of commerce...(is) against
				the labor policy of the United States." As the carriers had consciously withheld
				their services from use by Wards, they were in violation of the law and, as such,
				"they should pay for the natural and probable consequences of having failed their
				duty."</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Inclusive date range: 1951 - 1953 </p>
			<p>Bulk date: 1951 - 1953 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>This collection consists of the briefs filed in 1951 by the plaintiffs, Montgomery
				Ward, and the reply brief of the defendants, the Northern Pacific Terminal Company
				of Oregon and other rail carriers as well as the opinion of Judge James Alger Fee,
				who was the chief judge of the District Court of the United States for the District
				of Oregon at the time of this filing. The suit filed by Montgomery Ward was an
				attempt to gain recompense for damages suffered during a strike and secondary
				boycott that began in December 1940. Judge Fee ruled in favor of the plaintiffs in
				June 1953.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Montgomery Ward. </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Northern Pacific Terminal Company of Oregon. </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. District Court (Oregon) </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Brotherhood of Teamsters,
					Chauffeurs, Warehousemen, and Helpers of America </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects: </head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Arbitration, Industrial -- Oregon. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Strikes and lockouts -- Oregon. </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
				<genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655">Records (documents) </genreform>
			</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
					reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
					and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>Montgomery Ward and Company vs. Northern Pacific Terminal Company of Oregon
					Records #5370. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
					Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link8">Defendants' Brief</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Montgomery Ward &amp; Co., Inc. (Plaintiff) vs. The Northern Pacific
						Terminal Company of Oregon, et al., (Defendants). No. Civ. 1686. October
						1951.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link9">Reply of the Rail Carrier Defendants </unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Montgomery Ward &amp; Co., Inc. (Plaintiff) vs. The Northern Pacific
						Terminal Company of Oregon, et al., (Defendants). No. Civ. 1686. December
						1951.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle id="link10">Opinion of the Judge, James Alger Fee</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Montgomery Ward &amp; Co., Inc. (Plaintiff) vs. The Northern Pacific
						Terminal Company of Oregon, et al., (Defendants). No. Civ. 1686. June
						1953.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>
