<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-086amf::ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers Additional on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05780-086amf</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers
                    Additional on Microfilm<date> 1941</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers Additional
                    on Microfilm</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by R. Miles</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>April 11, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>April 11,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20231219">12/19/2023</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers Additional on
                Microfilm</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780/086a mf</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
                        Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>R. Miles, June 04, 2012</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, April 11, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">ILGWU Education Department, Jasper
                Peyton Papers Additional on Microfilm, 1941
            </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1941</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/086a mf</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Peyton, Jasper</persname>;
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">4 microfilm reels</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Papers (documents), microfilm .</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection consists of 4 microfilm copies of "Russian
                Development of a National Economic Plan, 1941" in Russian.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="rus">Russian</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.44 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>Jasper Peyton was born in Richmond, Virginia. Peyton studied at the University of the
                Philippines (Manila), graduated from City College (New York), and was adjunct
                professor at Fordham University. He attended New York Theological Seminary and was
                ordained in 1982. From 1950 to 1969, Peyton worked as a pleater and patternmaker,
                and from 1969 until 1995, he was on staff at the International's Education
                Department and for a time, serving as the Assistant Education Director. He currently
                lives in Brooklyn, New York.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>The Education Department records document activities across the entire period of the
                department's existence, with the bulk of the records covering the 1970s and 1990s.
                It contains papers from directors of the Education Department: Fannia Cohn, Mark
                Starr, Gus Tyler, and Kitty Krupat. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The earliest documentation of the department's work is found in the Fannia Cohn
                papers (5780/049, 5780/049 P); these contain correspondence, subject files,
                speeches, photographs, and printed material from her work as director of the
                Educational Department. A microfilm copy of the Fannia Cohn papers held at the New
                York Public Library (5998 mf) complements the Kheel Center's holdings. Documentation
                of the work of another longtime leader of the Education Department, Mark Starr, is
                contained in these records (5780/166, 5780/166 PUBS), as well as in a related
                collection from Starr on worker education programs (5243). </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Documentation of the work of Gus Tyler, who led the merged Education and Political
                Department after Mark Starr's retirement in 1960, is also contained in the ILGWU
                records (5780/052, 5780/088, 5780/096). Tyler's papers are complemented by those of
                Assistant Director Jasper Peyton (5780/086) and Special Projects Coordinator Beverly
                Shulman (5780/106). These collections contain routine correspondence and memoranda,
                reports, materials relating to training institutes, seminars, and conferences, and
                printed material. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The papers of Kitty Krupat, who was serving as Education Director at the time of the
                ILGWU/ACTWU merger in 1995, constitute the entirety of Education Department records
                from the 1990s. They include correspondence, memoranda, reports, and financial
                records relating to the ILGWU's independent and collaborative education projects,
                including the Worker-Family Education Program, the Joint Union- University Committee
                on Labor Education, and the Consortium for Worker Education, as well as numerous
                trainings, conferences, and seminars. Also included in the files are materials from
                local unions and regional departments of the ILGWU, files on the Internationals'
                conventions, and reports to the General Executive Board. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Local union's of the ILGWU established and maintained robust, ambitious educational
                departments early on in the international's history. As these groups grew in size
                and scope, the international office sought to coordinate and centralize educational
                programming for the union's members, culminating in the formation of the Educational
                Department in 1918. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The department's programming included courses at the Workers' University at the
                Washington Irving High School in New York City, lectures at Unity Centers and Unity
                Houses in the northeastern United States, and other events. The educational
                offerings of the International's Education Department were varied, as had been the
                education departments of the local unions, and included not only classes in labor
                studies but also courses in languages, music, and the arts. The ILGWU's 1937 musical
                "Pins and Needles" exemplified the diversity of the union's programs. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Directors of the Education Department, especially Fannia Cohn and Mark Starr, wrote
                extensively on the ILGWU's programs and worker education in general. Longtime
                director Gus Tyler not only directed the department, but also served as the ILGWU's
                on-staff scholar. In later years, the Education Department went beyond collaborating
                with other education organizations and arranging in-house programs to also
                supporting post-secondary education for union members and their families.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>This addition to the Jasper Peyton papers includes four microfilm copies of the
                "Russian Development of a National Economic Plan" from 1941. </p>
            <p>Duplicate copy available upon request.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Peyton, Jasper </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
                </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Economic policy </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">Russia </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers Additional on Microfilm
                    #5780/086a mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
                    Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            
            <p>Related Collections:
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780:
                    ILGWU records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-106.html">
                    5780/106: ILGWU Education Department, Beverly Shulman Papers</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-138.html">
                    5780/138: ILGWU Education Department, Kitty Krupat Papers</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-166.html">
                    5780/166: ILGWU Education Department Records</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-166pubs.html">
                    5780/166 PUBS: ILGWU Education Department Publications</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-086.html">
                    5780/086: ILGWU Education Department, Jasper Peyton Papers</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-049.html">
                    5780/049: ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn Papers</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-049p.html">
                    5780/049 P: ILGWU Education Department, Fannia Cohn Photographs</extref>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Russian Development of a National Economic
                        Plan.</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Государственный План Развития Народного Хозяйства СССР на 1941 год</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Russian Development of a National Economic
                        Plan</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Государственный План Развития Народного Хозяйства СССР на 1941 год</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Russian Development of a National Economic
                        Plan</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Государственный План Развития Народного Хозяйства СССР на 1941 год</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Russian Development of a National Economic
                        Plan</unittitle>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Государственный План Развития Народного Хозяйства СССР на 1941 год</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>