<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
 <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
  <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05863mf::Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05863mf</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm</titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
    <date>August 03, 2015</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>August 03, 2015</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240223">02/23/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm</titleproper>
   <num>Collection Number: 5863 mf</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, April 04, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Randall Miles, August 03, 2015</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2015 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   
   <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm</unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1914-1976</unitdate>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">5863 mf</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">U.S. Department of Justice</corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Industrial Workers of the World (IWW)</corpname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">15 microfilm reels</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records, microfilm..</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  <physdesc><extent>1.67 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   
   <p>The Industrial Workers of the World (IWW), commonly known as the Wobblies is an industrial union formed in Chicago in 1905. The IWW promotes the concept of 'One Big Union' and is considered a radical trade union, who opposes most of the policies of the
    American Federation of Labor. Membership does not require that one work in a represented workplace, nor does it exclude membership in another labor union. The Wobblies believe that all workers should organize as a class, not according to craft. The IWW
    emphasized rank- and-file organization as opposed to empowering leaders who would bargain with employers. </p>
   <p>The biggest contribution the IWW had on the labor movement was when founded it allowed everyone to join, women, immigrants, African Americans and Asians. </p>
   <p>As of 2005, the 100th Anniversary of its founding, the IWW had around 5,000 members.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <controlaccess>
   
   <controlaccess>
    
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Communist Party of America. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Industrial Workers of the World. </corpname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. Dept. of Justice. </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   
   <accessrestrict>
    
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    
    <p>Department of Justice Investigative Files on Industrial Workers of the World, Part 1 on Microfilm #5863 mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   
   <p>Related Collections:
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05177mf.html"> 5177 mf: Industrial Workers of the World Miscellany on Microfilm</extref>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05210.html"> 5210: IWW Records</extref>
    <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05210g.html"> 5210 G: IWW Graphics</extref>
   </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link7">0000. Industrial Workers of the World Activities in California and the Pacific Northwest. Case file 150139. Section 1. 206 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1910/1916" type="inclusive">1910-1916</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: E.P. Marsh; William D. Haywood; Hiram W. Johnson; James McGill; Woodrow W. Wilson; Thomas w. Gregory; Franklin K. Lane; Charles D. Hilles; George W. Wickersham; F. W. Estabrook. Subjects: Local union and mass meeting protests against Everett,
       Washington, massacre of Industrial Workers of the World members; Washington State Federation of Labor; Department of Justice investigation of activities of the Industrial Workers of the World in California Oregon, Utah, and Washington; Industrial
       Workers of the World membership statistics and publications; Commission on Immigration and Housing of California; free speech movement in San Diego, California; Republican National Committee; protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities;
       free speech movement in Spokane, Washington. For pages omitted after Frame 0064, see end of Reel 1.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link8">0206. Industrial Workers of the World Activities in California and the Pacific Northwest. Case file 150139. Section 2. 145 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1916/1917" type="inclusive">1916-1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Victor L. Berger. Subjects: Anti-war and selective service matters; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Minnesota and Wisconsin; Industrial Workers of the World publications; strikes; local union protests against Everett, Washington,
       massacre of Industrial Workers of the World members; Socialist party of America.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link9">0351. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case file 185354. Section 1. 208 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; J. Edward Morgan; Alexander Berkman; Emma Goldman; Harry Weinberger; Thomas W. Gregory; Woodrow W. Wilson; William B. Wilson; William D. Stephens; Samuel Gompers; Newton D. Baker. Subjects: Mass meeting
       and local union protests against prosecution of Mooney and Billings; Department of Justice investigation of California state prosecution; Industrial Workers of the World publications; protests against extradition of Alexander Berkman from New York to
       California; International Workers' Defense League publications.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link10">0559. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 1. Previously Restricted Material. 3 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Charles M. Fickert. Subject: Recall election of San Francisco, California, prosecuting attorney.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link11">0562. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 2. 207 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; A. Mitchell Palmer; W. Bourke Cockran. Subjects: Local union and mass meeting protests against prosecution of Mooney and Billings; International Workers' Defense League publications.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link12">0769. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 3. 200 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1933" type="inclusive">1919-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Roger N. Baldwin; Clarence Senior; Frances Perkins; Homer S. Cummings; Francis Ralston Welsh; Mattie L. Bretland; John Mooney. Subjects: Local union and mass meeting protests against imprisonment of Mooney
       and Billings; National Mooney-Billings Committee of the American Civil Liberties Union; Socialist party of America; supreme Court of California investigation of convictions of Mooney and Billings; Department of Justice investigation of John Mooney for
       alleged violations of United states Post Office Department regulations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link13">0969. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 3. Previously Restricted Materials. 10 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1930/1931" type="inclusive">1930-1931</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; J. Edgar Hoover; Francis Ralston Welsh. Subject: Mooney and Billings Case. For pages omitted after Frame 0978, see end of Reel 1.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link14">0979. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 4. 75 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings. Subject: Local union and mass meeting protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link15">1054. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 5. 17 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1933/1934" type="inclusive">1933-1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings. Subject: Local union and mass meetings protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link16">1071. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 6. 61 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings. Subject: Local union and mass meeting protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link17">1132. Industrial Workers of the World Activities in California and the Pacific Northwest. Case File 150139. Section 1. Pages omitted after Frame 0064 of Reel 1. 37 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1914/1915" type="inclusive">1914-1915</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Thomas J. Mooney. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World publications; International Workers' Defense League publications; insurance company statistics regarding arson and fires in California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link18">1169. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 3. Previously Restricted Material. Pages omitted after Frame 0978 of Reel 1. 10 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1929/1930" type="inclusive">1929-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Francis Ralston Welsh; J. Edgar Hoover. Subjects: Mooney and Billings case; Department of Justice investigation of Mooney and Billings case.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link19">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link20">0001. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 7. 98 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934">1934</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Louis Weinstock; Frank P. Walsh; John F. Finerty; George T. Davis; Upton Sinclair; Roger N. Baldwin. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings;
       American Federation of Labor Trades Union Committee for Unemployment Insurance ad Relief; opinions of United states District Court and United States Circuit Court of Appeals judges in Mooney habeas corpus proceedings; Tom Mooney Molders' Defense
       Committee; International Molders' Union of North America; National Mooney-Billings Committee of the American Civil Liberties Union.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link21">0099. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case file 185354. Section 8. 200 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1934/1935" type="inclusive">1934-1935</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; John Jenkins; Gardner Jackson; Homer S. Cummings; Rose Wortis; Louis Colman; e. Claude Babcock. Subjects: Citizen, United States congressman, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and
       Billings; Tom Mooney Defense Committee; International Labor Defense; Federated Moulders' (Metals) Union of Australia; Department of Justice investigation of Mooney and Billings case; Trade Union Unity Council; International Red Aid.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link22">0299. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 9. 269 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1935/1937" type="inclusive">1935-1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Thomas J. Connor; Gunnar Mickelsen. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, United States congressman, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; Department of Justice investigation of
       Mooney and Billings case; Tom Mooney Molders' Defense Committee; Workers Alliance of America; American Labor party; American Civil Liberties Union; Comintern publications; Farmer-Labor party; 1936 United States presidential elections.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link23">0568. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 10. 109 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; John H. Bollens. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; American Labor Party; Progressive Women's Council; Civil Rights Federation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link24">0677. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 11. 71 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937">1937</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Willard Uphaus. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; American League against War and Fascism; Religion and Labor Foundation; International
       Workers Order.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link25">0748. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Section 12. 143 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1937/1962" type="inclusive">1937-1962</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; J. Edgar Hoover; Martin L. Sweeney. Subjects: Requests for documents relating to Mooney and Billings case; citizen, mass meeting, United States congressman, and local union protests against imprisonment of
       Mooney and Billings; Workers Alliance of America; Works Progress Administration; International Workers Order; Communist Party of America.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link26">0891. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Protests. Section 1. 194 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; Socialist party of Kentucky; Socialist party of Indiana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link27">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link28">0001. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Protests. Section 2. 341 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Joseph F. Valentine. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; Socialist party of Wisconsin; Socialist party of Ohio; International Molders'
       Union of North America. For pages omitted after Frame 0075, see reel 3, Frame 1172.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link29">0342. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Special Section 1. 120 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; W.J. Durant. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; Socialist party of America.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link30">0462. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Special Section 2. 146 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; John A. Fitch. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings; National Labor Council; International Workers' Defense League; Tom Mooney Molders'
       Defense Committee; Socialist party of Mexico.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link31">0608. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Special Section 3. 329 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1938" type="inclusive">1918-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Homer S. Cummings; Theodore Debs; Eugene V. Debs; William Mitch; Simon J. Lubin; William Dobson. Subjects: Citizen, mass meeting, United States congressman, and local union protests against imprisonment of
       Mooney and Billings; International Workers Order; Railroad Employees' Committee for the Release of Thomas J. Mooney; San Francisco Bay Area American Federation of Labor Committee for the Freedom of Mooney and Billings; American Legion; Commission of
       Immigration and Housing of California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link32">0937. Industrial Workers of the World - General. Case File 186701. Section 1. 235 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Ralph M. Easley; David R. Francis; William English Walling; Carl Hayden; Adolph Germer; Samuel Gompers; Thomas W. Gregory; Woodrow W. Wilson; Leonard Foster. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World publications; citizen protest against
       Industrial Workers of the World activities; Great Britain and United States labor union protests against United States treatment of Industrial Workers of the World members; Industrial Workers of the World organization efforts among black Americans;
       Department of Justice review of espionage convictions and Industrial Workers of the World cases; National Civic Federation; proposed United States recognition of Soviet Russia; United States Post Office Department censorship; criminal prosecution of
       Industrial Workers of the World leadership; Socialist party of America; Council of National Defense; Employers' Association of the Inland Empire.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link33">1172. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Protests. Section 2. Pages omitted after Frame 0075 of Reel 3. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings. Subject: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">3</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link34">1191. Thomas J. Mooney and Warren K. Billings. Case File 185354. Special Section. Section 1. Pages omitted after Frame 0350 of Reel 3. 15 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings. Subject: Citizen, mass meeting, and local union protests against imprisonment of Mooney and Billings.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
     <unittitle id="link35">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link36">0000. Industrial Workers of the World - General. Case File 186701. Section 2. 23 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Roger N. Baldwin; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Requests for documents relating to Department of Justice raid on Industrial Workers of the World Chicago, Illinois, office; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities;
       United States Shipping Board investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities; American Civil Liberties Union; Department of Justice summary of the suppression of Industrial Workers of the World outbreaks.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link37">0023. Industrial Workers of the World - By States. Case File 186701. Section 2. Alaska. 15 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not Available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World activities in the Alaska Territory</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link38">0038. Industrial Workers of the World - General. Case File 186701. Section 2. Previously restricted Materials. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1928" type="inclusive">1917-1928</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Requests for documents relating to Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World leadership; Labour Defense Council of Great Britain protest against United States
       suppression of Industrial Workers of the World; citizen protests against alleged Industrial Workers of the World general strike plans.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link39">0057. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 3. Arizona. 16 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1924" type="inclusive">1919-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; Carl Hayden. Subjects: Citizen support for Department of Justice suppression of Industrial Workers of the World in Arizona; American Legion; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Bisbee, Arizona.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link40">0073. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 4. Arkansas. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: United States district attorney for the western district of Arkansas request for Secret Service investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Fort Smith and
       Mena, Arkansas.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link41">0080. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 5. California. 150 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1925" type="inclusive">1917-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A Mitchell Palmer; William D. Haywood; William D. Stephens; John W. Preston; Frederick H. Esmond; Thomas W. Gregory; J. Robert O'Connor; Newton D. Baker. Subjects: State and federal suppression of Industrial Workers of the World in California;
       Department of Justice investigations of Industrial Workers of the World activities; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Industrial Workers of the World General Defense Committee; Industrial Workers of the World songbook; citizen protests
       against Industrial Workers of the World activities; Sacramento, California, grand jury investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities; immigrant labor and strikes at mines in Shasta County, California; private detective agencies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link42">0230. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 6: Colorado. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Department of Justice investigations of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Colorado; Agricultural Workers Industrial Union 1919 convention in Sioux City, Iowa; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of
       the World activities; Comintern; Department of Justice cooperation with the President's Mediation Commission.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link43">0238. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 7. Connecticut. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Louis C. Fraina. Subject: Formation of the American Red Guard in New York City.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link44">0242. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 10. Florida. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Florida; American Legion.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link45">0246. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 13. Idaho. 80 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1921" type="inclusive">1917-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Alvin M. Owsley; Harry M. Daugherty; Louis F. Post; Thomas W. Gregory; David F. Houston. Subjects: Americanism Commission of the American Legion; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Idaho; Industrial Workers
       of the World activities in the United States Forest Service; state and Department of Justice suppression of the Industrial Workers of the World; department of Justice investigations of Industrial Workers of the World activities; United States Department
       of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; police brutality; protests against mass arrests; United States Department of Agriculture cooperation with department of Justice; Industrial Workers of the World publications; general strikes; state
       request for Secret Service investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link46">0326. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 14. Previously Restricted Materials. Illinois. 61 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917- 1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover; William J. Burns; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Illinois; Department of Justice raids against the Industrial Workers of the World, the Union
       of Russian Workers, the Communist Labor Party of America, and the Communist Party of America; Non-Partisan League; Department of Justice cooperation with the Department of Justice of Canada; Industrial Workers of the World activities in the United
       States and Canada; organization of the Industrial Workers of the World Division of the Radical Department of the Bureau of Investigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link47">0387. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 14, Part 1. Illinois. 170 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; George F. Vanderveer; William C. Fitts; Robert Lansing; Thomas W. Gregory; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; John L. Metzen; Kenesaw M. Landis; Adolph Germer. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial
       Workers of the World activities; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Railroad Workers Industrial Union; Agricultural Workers Industrial Union; requests for access to Industrial
       Workers of the World documents held by Judge Kenesaw M. Landis seized in Department of Justice raids; Department of Justice position regarding bail for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers
       of the World defendants in Illinois; bomb explosion in the United States Post Office Building, Chicago, Illinois; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of State; request from the Bulgarian Minister for special privileges for an
       immigrant Industrial Workers of the World defendant; press coverage of Industrial Workers of the World leadership trial; draft indictment against Adolph Germer, et al., Socialist Party of America, for pro-German matters.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link48">0557. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 14, Part 2. Illinois. 11 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1924" type="inclusive">1922-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Illinois.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">14</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link49">0568. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 15. Indiana. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1927" type="inclusive">1917-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William J. Donovan. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Indiana; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; American Legion; radical activities; strikes in
       Indiana coal fields.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">15</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link50">0587. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 16. Iowa. 10 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Iowa; 1919 Industrial Workers of the World convention in Sioux City, Iowa; state and federal conspiracy laws.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">16</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link51">0597. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 17. Kansas. 56 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Samuel B. Amidon; A. Mitchell Palmer; C. W. Anderson; George F. Vanderveer; Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Kansas; Department of Justice prosecution of C. W.
       Anderson, et al., Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World case; Department of Justice cooperation with state authorities; Agricultural Workers Industrial Union; Department of Justice position regarding bail for Industrial Workers of the World
       defendants.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">17</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link52">0653. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 18. Kentucky. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Department of Justice investigation of Espionage Act matters in Kentucky.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">18</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link53">0657. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 19. Louisiana. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1922" type="inclusive">1920-1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Lucille B. Milner; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Louisiana and Arkansas; Department of Justice raids; American Civil Liberties Union.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">19</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link54">0661. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 21. Maine and Maryland. 18 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1924" type="inclusive">1918-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Maine and Maryland; United States Department of Commerce cooperation with Department of Justice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">20</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link55">0679. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 22. Massachusetts. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: George W. Anderson; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members in Massachusetts; private detective agencies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">21</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link56">0687. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 23. Michigan. 60 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1921" type="inclusive">1917-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Charles Moyer; Arnold Petersen; S. G. Bargery; William C. Fitts; William B. Wilson; Thomas W. Gregory; William D. Haywood; Woodrow W. Wilson; John W. Davis; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Communist party of America mass meetings; citizen protests
       against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Michigan; eviction of International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers organizers from Grand Rapids, Michigan; American Protective League; Department of Justice cooperation with local
       authorities; Socialist Labor party; Department of Justice raids; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor alleged strike plans of miners in Minnesota and Michigan.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">22</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link57">0747. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 24. Minnesota. 26 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; Thomas C. Spelling; John Lind; Ambrose Tighe. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of deportation cases in Minnesota and Arizona; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities;
       miners strikes; illegal liquor traffic; Department of Justice cooperation with authorities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">23</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link58">0773. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 25. Mississippi. 3 pages.</unittitle>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Citizen protest against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Mississippi. No date.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">24</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link59">0776. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 26. Missouri. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1923" type="inclusive">1918-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Missouri; alleged general strike plans; Department of Justice prosecution of Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World
       defendants.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">25</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link60">0784. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 27. Montana. 147 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1932" type="inclusive">1917-1932</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; A. M. Briggs; Burton K. Wheeler; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Montana; habeas corpus proceedings; citizen and United
       States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; American Protective League; state legislation relating to arson, sabotage, and criminal syndicalism during World War I; Department of Justice investigation of Industrial
       Workers of the World activities in coal and lumber industries.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">26</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link61">0931. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 28. Nebraska. 81 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; Frank Little; William D. Haywood; William C. Fitts; Thomas S. Allen; George F. Vanderveer; Jane Street. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Nebraska;
       lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana; Industrial Workers of the World union organization; attempted plea bargain with Industrial Workers of the World Industrial Workers of the World
       defendants; Department of Justice raid on Industrial Workers of the World convention in Omaha; Industrial Workers of the World organization of domestic workers in Denver, Colorado, and Tulsa, Oklahoma.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">27</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link62">1012. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 29. Nevada. 11 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World strikes in Tonopah, Nevada, mining camps; wartime prosecution for unpatriotic remarks and utterances.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">28</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link63">1023. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 31. New Jersey. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: L. A. Sterne. Subjects: American Federation of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in New Jersey; protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; Industrial
       Workers of the World organization of metal and machinery workers; United States Post Office Department censorship of mails.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">29</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link64">1035. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 32. New Mexico. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in New Mexico.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">30</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link65">1037. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 33. New York. 27 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Louis Ratnofsky; William D. Haywood; a. Mitchell Palmer; J. Edgar Hoover; Francis Ralston Welsh; William C. Fitts; Charles W. Stockton. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in New York;
       Department of Justice raids; New York Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Industrial Workers of the World publications; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; Wells Fargo and Company cooperation with
       Department of Justice censorship; arrests of Industrial Workers of the World organizers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">31</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link66">1064. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 33. Special Section, Bureau Papers Only. New York. 181 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1921" type="inclusive">1920- 1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: L. J. Baley; George Hardy; J. Edgar Hoover; Charles Scully. Subjects: Military Intelligence Division informant reports on industrial unrest and Industrial Workers of the World activities in New York; strikes; union organization; mass meetings;
       publications; Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities among immigrants at Ellis Island; Industrial Workers of the World dissent with Comintern; convention of Hungarian-speaking members of the Industrial Workers
       of the World; private detective agencies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">4</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">32</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link67">1247. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 13. Pages omitted after Frame 0293 of Reel 4. Idaho. 28 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World publications; union organization.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
     <unittitle id="link68">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link69">0000. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 34. North Carolina. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in North Carolina.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link70">0004. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 35. North Dakota. 14 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. C. Townley; Kate Richards O'Hare. Subjects: Citizens and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans of agricultural workers in North Dakota; Farmers' Nonpartisan League of North
       Dakota.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link71">0017. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 35.Previously Restricted Materials. North Dakota. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski. Subject: Farmers' Nonpartisan League of North Dakota. Frames 0017 and 0018 are repeated.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link72">0018. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 36. Ohio. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Ohio; protest against Department of Justice raids; private detective agencies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link73">0025. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 37. Oklahoma. 76 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1921" type="inclusive">1917-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory; John L. Metzen. Subjects: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Oklahoma; Department of Justice investigation and
       prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World activities and pro-German matters in Oklahoma; Industrial Workers of the World General Defense Committee protest against events in Tulsa, Oklahoma, and Bisbee, Arizona; suppression of the Working Class
       Union in Oklahoma following alleged assassination attempt by four black members upon Seminole County officials.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link74">0101. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 38. Oregon. 129 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William c. Fitts; Elmer Sandstrom; William d. Haywood; Thomas W. Gregory; Henry J. Weeks; Charles Warren. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers; Industrial Workers of the World protests against activities of
       the Loyal Legion of Loggers and Lumbermen; state and federal suppression of Industrial Workers of the World offices in Oregon; Industrial Workers of the World Official Membership Book and papers; censorship of Industrial Workers of the War publications;
       wartime shipbuilding and lumber worker strikes; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; arrest of Industrial Workers of the World members in Klamath Falls following acts of sabotage and anti-war activities; Department of
       Justice enforcement of Espionage Act.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link75">0230. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 39. Pennsylvania. 45 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Charles Recht; Francis Fisher Kane; Claude r Porter; John Lord O'Brian; Alfred Bettman. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World Activities in Pennsylvania; Industrial Workers of the World publications; American
       Legion; request for return of Industrial Workers of the World papers and property seized in Department of Justice raids in Philadelphia; Military Intelligence Division and Naval Intelligence Division surveillance of labor conditions in Pittsburgh;
       Department of Justice raids in Philadelphia and Scranton.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link76">0275. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 41. Rhode Island. 9 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice raids in Rhode Island; inventory of Industrial Workers of the World and anarchist publications and papers seized in raids.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link77">0284. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 43. South Dakota. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against arson and Industrial Workers of the World activities in South Dakota; Agricultural Workers Industrial Union of the Industrial Workers of the World publications.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link78">0292. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 44. Tennessee. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Request for information regarding Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link79">0296. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 45. Texas. 13 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Texas; Industrial Workers of the World organization of Mexican-Americans.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link80">0309. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 49, Part 1. Washington. 230 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; Louis F. Post; Thomas W. Gregory; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; John Lord O'Brian; Thomas Tracy; Charles Warren; Newton D. Baker; Henry J. Weeks; Clarence L. Reames. Subjects: United States Department of Labor
       cooperation with Department of Justice suppression of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Washington; Industrial Workers of the World organization of immigrant labor, lumber workers, and agricultural workers; citizen and United States
       congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Washington and Michigan; Council of National Defense; The Minute Men of Seattle, Washington; Department of Justice censorship of Industrial Workers of the World publications;
       United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice in prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership; Arizona State Federation of Labor protest against events in Bisbee, Arizona; United States Department of the Interior
       cooperation with Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World; mass meeting protest against lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank H. Little in Butte, Montana; Everett, Washington, massacre of
       Industrial Workers of the World members; Socialist party of Washington; Department of Justice cooperation with state suppression of Industrial Workers of the World; People's Council of America; Chamber of Commerce resolutions urging legislation to
       suppress strikes and criminal syndicalism; conference of state and federal prosecutors regarding Industrial Workers of the World cases; use of state militia in quelling industrial disputes; proposed declaration of martial law in Washington; arrest of
       Industrial Workers of the World members in Klamath Falls, Oregon.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link81">0539. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 49, Part 2. Washington. 260 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas W. Gregory; Clarence L. Reames; George F. Vanderveer; Fred Lowery; Thomas J. Mooney; John Lord O'Brian; Claude R. Porter; A. S. Embree; William D. Haywood; Vincent St. John; Josephus Daniels; William C. Fitts; Leonard Foster; S. B.
       Phelan. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World member under immigration and deportation laws in Washington; habeas corpus proceedings; Industrial Workers of
       the World general strike plans; Military Intelligence Division surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice cooperation with state prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World members; conference of state and federal
       prosecutors; protest against California state prosecution of Mooney case; indictment of Industrial Workers of the World leadership for conspiracy to violate the neutrality laws; Seattle District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World;
       Bureau of Naval Intelligence cooperation with Department of Justice Industrial Workers of the World investigations in Washington and Alaska; Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers, cannery workers, and merchant marines; local
       police department raid on Industrial Workers of the World hall in Seattle; Bureau of Intelligence report on Industrial Workers of the World activities in Oregon; United States Army Department report on suppression of sedition and sabotage in the
       Northwest; United States Post Office Department cooperation with Department of Justice in censorship of Industrial Workers of the World publications; indictment of Industrial Workers of the World members for organizing among United States military
       forces; private detective agencies; Employers' Association of Washington; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">14</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link82">0799. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 49, Part 3. Washington. 100 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1929" type="inclusive">1918-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harlan F. Stone; George F. Vanderveer; A. Mitchell Palmer; John Thomas Taylor; Ole Hanson; Clarence L. Reames; Fred Lowery; William C. Redfield; John Lord O'Brian; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of
       lumber workers and cannery workers; protests against local police suppression of Industrial Workers of the World in Centralia, Washington; legal defense efforts; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World
       activities in Washington; American Legion; mass meetings; Loyal Legion of Loggers and Lumbermen; Industrial Workers of the World publications; state prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members; United States Department of Commerce cooperation
       with Department of Justice investigations of immigrant labor in fisheries of Washington and Alaska; state legislation against criminal syndicalism; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in the prosecution of
       immigration and deportation cases; habeas corpus proceedings; alleged illegal arrests by officers of the Bureau of Naval Intelligence.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">15</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link83">0899. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 50. West Virginia. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Local prosecutor's request for Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in coal mines.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">16</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link84">0901. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 51. Wisconsin. 31 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1914/1921" type="inclusive">1914-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: John Lord O'Brian; Roy Brown; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Military Intelligence Division cooperation with Bureau of Investigation; Citizens and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Wisconsin;
       Council of National Defense.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">17</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link85">0932. Industrial Workers of the World - By State. Case File 186701. Section 52. Wyoming. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts. Subjects: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Wyoming; Council of National Defense.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">18</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link86">0937. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 54. Frank Little matter. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1920" type="inclusive">1917-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Frank Little; Burton K. Wheeler; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Local union, mass meeting, and citizen protests against lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana; Socialist party of
       America; alleged involvement of military personnel in lynching of Frank Little.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">19</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link87">0949. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 55. Industrial Workers of the World Legislation. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United states Senate Judiciary Committee consideration of bills to restrict Industrial Workers of the World activities in the United States draft wartime
       legislation for public safety and against sedition.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">20</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link88">0968. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 56. Nolan Industrial Workers of the World Case, Western District of Washington. 32 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas Nolan; E. A. Matson; Robert Solen; Thomas Tracy; Louise Olivereau; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in
       Washington; Industrial Workers of the World organization of lumber workers; general strikes; alleged acts of sabotage.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">5</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">21</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link89">1000. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57, Part 1. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 147 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1921" type="inclusive">1917-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; George N. Murdock; John W. Preston; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts; William D. Stephens; P. H. Johnson; Frederick H. Esmond; Theodora Pollok; Woodrow W. Wilson; Frank K. Nebeker; Louis F. Post; George F. Vanderveer.
       Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against treatment of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in jail; assistant United States attorney criticism of the
       governor of California in the Sacramento Bee, alleging interference with Industrial Workers of the World prosecutions; California District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers
       of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas, and Chicago, Illinois; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
     <unittitle id="link90">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link91">0000. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57, Part 2. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 240 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; Robert Duncan; Edward Anderson; John W. Preston; Thomas W. Gregory; George N. Murdock; Elbert Coutts; Theodora Pollok; Charles M. Fickert; Francis Ralston Welsh; Thomas J. Mooney; Frederick H, Esmond; John Lord O'Brian; Louis
       Connolly; William C. Fitts; William Hood. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against prosecution of Theodora Pollok; California District Defense Committee of the
       Industrial Workers of the World; indictment of William Hood, et al.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link92">0240. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57. Previously Restricted Materials. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 46 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1921" type="inclusive">1918-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Godfrey Ebel; Frederick H. Esmond; John Dymond; Mortimer Downing; Claude R. Porter; George N. Murdock; Elbert Coutts; Charles M. Fickert; Edward Anderson; Theodora Pollok; John W. Preston; P. H. Johnson; George F. Vanderveer; John Lord
       O'Brian; William E. Cavanaugh; Clarence Darrow; J. B. McNamara; J. J. McNamara. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports regarding prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against treatment of
       Industrial Workers of the World defendants in jail; Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas, and Chicago, Illinois; protests against prosecution of Theodora Pollok; investigation of Espionage
       Act violations in Los Angeles, California; alleged jury tampering by Clarence Darrow in the McNamara case.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link93">0286. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 57, Part 3. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 70 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1930" type="inclusive">1919-1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Mitchell; William F. Petersen; Frederick H. Esmond; Anna Kaufman; Annette Abbott Adams; Roger N. Baldwin; Albert DeSilver; Harry M. Daugherty; James H. Manning; Caroline A. Lowe; Joseph McCarty; Thomas J. Mooney; Edward Anderson;
       William L. Frierson; Frank M. Silva; A. Mitchell Palmer; Joseph Harper; Godfrey Ebel; Alexander S. Lanier; William D. Haywood; Roy Dempsey. Subjects: Request for access to Department of Justice files regarding prosecution of Industrial Workers of the
       World defendants in Sacramento, California; release of insane prisoner from Saint Elizabeth's Hospital; United States Supreme Court denial of writ of certiorari in case o Edward Anderson, et al.; Department of Justice cooperation with United States
       Department of Labor in deportation and immigration cases; protests against conviction of Industrial Workers of the World defendants; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; United States War Department censorship of mail of
       prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link94">0356. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 58. Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 51 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; C.E.S. Wood; Louise Olivereau; Marie Equi; Anna Louise Strong; John Lord O'Brian; Alfred Bettman; Clarence L. Reames; Harry Weinberger; Thomas W. Gregory; Thomas Nolan. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of
       Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Seattle, Washington, and Saint Michael, Alaska; Espionage Act prosecutions; Department of Justice policies regarding clemency for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; surveillance and censorship of
       mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the Colorado State Penitentiary.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link95">0407. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 59. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World Cases. 129 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; Henry B. Twombly; Theodora Pollok; Claude R. Porter; Annette Abbott Adams; William Kent; W. C. Coghlan; G. S. Arnold; Robert Scott; Alfred Bettman; John W. Preston; Mortimer Downing; John Lord O'Brian; George M. La Monte;
       Louise Connolly; Jeannette Rankin; Thomas W. Gregory; Joseph P. Tumulty; Simon J. Lubin; George L. Bell; George N. Murdock; Woodrow W. Wilson; Robert Duncan; William C. Fitts; P. H. Johnson. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial
       Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California; protests against prosecution of Theodora Pollok; Department of Justice policies regarding clemency for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; California District Defense Committee of the
       Industrial Workers of the World.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link96">0536. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 5. Previously Restricted Materials. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; John W. Preston; Robert Duncan; George F. Vanderveer; George N. Murdock; P. H. Johnson; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California;
       Bureau of Investigation reports on progress of cases.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link97">0542. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 60. Detroit, Michigan, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 15 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: E. C. Davison; William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; Thomas W. Gregory; Arnold Petersen; S. G. Bargery. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Detroit, Michigan; International Association of
       Machinists complaints regarding seizure of local union records in Department of Justice raids; misuse of search warrants in Department of Justice raids on Socialist Labor party offices in Detroit, Michigan, and Columbus, Ohio.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link98">0557. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects. Case File 186701. Section 60. Previously Restricted Materials. Detroit, Michigan, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 45 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; William D. Haywood; S. G. Bargery; Delmas C. Stutler. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Detroit, Michigan, misuse of search warrants in Department of
       Justice raids on Socialist Labor party offices in Detroit, Michigan, and Columbus, Ohio.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link99">0602. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Russian Consul at Seattle, Washington. 30 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Fred H. Moore; Thomas W. Gregory; John Lord O'Brian; Frank L. Polk; William C. Fitts; Hugh C. Wallace; Woodrow W. Wilson, George F. Vanderveer; M. E. Saville. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Soviet Russian Consulate at
       Seattle, Washington; emigrants to Soviet Russia; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of State regarding complaints against activities of Soviet Russian Consulate at Seattle, Washington; Industrial Workers of the World and
       pro- German activities in the Pacific Northwest.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link100">0632. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 61. Previously Restricted Materials. Russian Consul at Seattle, Washington. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: John Lord O'Brian; A. B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts; Fred H. Moore. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Soviet Russian Consulate at Seattle, Washington; emigrants to Soviet Russia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link101">0634. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 62. Portland, Oregon, Industrial Workers of the World case. 3 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Emma Goldman; Alexander Berkman. Subject: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Portland, Oregon.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link102">0637. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 63. Fort Meade, Maryland, case. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Walter Mills Hinkle. Subject: Protest regarding radical enroute to Soviet Russia as employee of the Young Men's Christian Association.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link103">0639. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 64. Roanoke, Virginia, case. 3 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; Woodrow W. Wilson. Subject: Department of Justice policy regarding prosecution of remarks mage against President Wilson.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">14</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link104">0642. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 65. Marshfield, Oregon, case. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Workers Socialist Publishing Company, Duluth, Minnesota, foreign language circulars seized by United States Post Office Department in Marshfield, Oregon.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">15</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link105">0649. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 66. Coeur d'Alene, Idaho, Industrial Workers of the World case. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Neil Guiney; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude r. Porter. Subject: Department of Justice receipt of transcript of evidence in Idaho state Industrial Workers of the World prosecution.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">16</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link106">0656. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 67. Sheffield, Alabama, Industrial Workers of the World Case. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski. Subject: Citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Sheffield, Alabama.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">17</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link107">0661. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 68. S. 4471, 65th Congress, 2nd Session. 11 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William H. King; John Lord O'Brian. Subjects: Department of Justice policy regarding wartime anti-Industrial Workers of the World legislation before the United States Congress; Espionage Act prosecutions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">18</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link108">0672. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 70. Salt Lake City, Utah, Industrial Workers of the World case. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; Oscar W. Larson. Subjects: Department of Justice policy regarding the release of literature seized in Military Intelligence Division raids on Industrial Workers of the World offices in salt Lake City, Utah; mass meetings in
       Seattle, Washington.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">19</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link109">0679. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 71. Tacoma and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 21 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Robert C. Saunders; Claude R. Porter; Clarence L. Reames; A. Mitchell Palmer; Louis F. Hart. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in immigration and deportation cases; protests against Industrial
       Workers of the World activities in Tacoma, Washington; wartime activities of the Bureau of Investigation in Seattle, Washington; general strikes; planned Industrial Workers of the World activities at the Washington State Federation of Labor convention
       to be held in Bellingham, Washington.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">20</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link110">0700. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 73. E. F. Doree. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: E. F. Doree; A. Mitchell Palmer. Subject: Protest against planned Industrial Workers of the World General Defense Committee fund raising meeting in Devils Lake, North Dakota.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">21</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link111">0705. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 1. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 213 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. Mitchell Palmer; Anna B. Field; William D. Haywood; Louis F. Hart; Robert C. Saunders; Robert Scott; William B. Wilson; William Short; Samuel Gompers. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in
       Centralia and Seattle, Washington; veteran's organizations; Woman's International Union Label League; American Legion; Veterans of Foreign wars of the United States; Grand Army of the Republic; Department of Justice cooperation with United states
       Department of Labor in immigration and deportation cases; Department of Justice prosecution of the Seattle Union Record; general strikes; Industrial Workers of the World infiltration of the American Federation of Labor in the Pacific Northwest; protests
       against lynching of Wesley Everest in Centralia, Washington; protests against Department of Justice raid on Seattle Union Record office; conference of state, local, federal prosecutors in Washington; Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial
       Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; United States Post Office Department censorship of publications.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">6</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">22</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link112">0918. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 2. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 332 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1921" type="inclusive">1919-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Wesley Everest; E.T. Doran; William D. Haywood; George F. Vanderveer; Elmer S. Smith; Robert c. Saunders; Alexander C. King; E.P. Ault; George P. Listman; F.A. Rust; Anna Louise Strong; Joseph P. Tumulty; Charles D. Fullen; A. Mitchell Palmer;
       George Williams; Sidney L Gulick; Newton D. Baker; Josephus Daniels; Robert Scott; William Short; Paul U. Kellogg; Robert Minor. Subject: Protests against lynching of Wesley Everest and anti-Industrial Workers of the World activities in Centralia,
       Washington; mass meetings; General defense Committee and Northwest Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice Cooperation with Washington state prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia,
       Washington; Department of Justice prosecution of the Seattle Union Record; Espionage Act prosecutions; veteran's organizations; protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Centralia, Washington; requests for clemency in Department of
       Justice prosecution of Anna Louise Strong and other editors of the Seattle Union Record; American Legion; decisions on demurrers and indictments in Seattle Union record cases; general strikes; Washington State Federation of Labor.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
     <unittitle id="link113">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link114">0000. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 3. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 30 pages</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1924/1925" type="inclusive">1924-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William J. Donovan. Subjects: Protests against Washington state prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; requests for Department of Justice intervention and affidavits of jurors and witnesses in case;
       American Legion; veteran's organizations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link115">0030. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 75. Industrial Workers of the World propaganda in Mexico. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Industrial workers of the World propaganda and organization of coal miners in Coahuila, Mexico; United States Department of State cooperation with Department of Justice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link116">0034. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 76. Providence, Rhode Island. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Not available.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link117">0035. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 92. William z. Foster. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry M. Daugherty; Willis F. McCook; William Z. Foster. Subject: Protests against speaking tour of William Z. Foster.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link118">0039. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 103. Nicholas Radivoeff. 20 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1922" type="inclusive">1921-1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Nicholas Radivoeff; James J. Davis; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Butte, Montana, habeas corpus proceedings; Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in immigration and deportation cases.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link119">0059. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 104. Joseph Yeager. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Joseph Yeager. Subjects: Request for information regarding whereabouts of former Industrial Workers of the World and Western Federation Miners member from Arizona.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link120">0067. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 213. James Price. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James Price. Subject: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of Labor in immigration and naturalization cases.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link121">0072. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 227. Simon J. Lubin. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Simon J. Lubin; Thomas W. Gregory; Woodrow W. Wilson; George L. Bell. Subjects: State Commission of Immigration and Housing of California; requests for investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities in California; Pacific Coast
       governors request for suppression of the Industrial Workers of the World.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link122">0076. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 237. E.T. Doran. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: E.T. Doran. Subject: Planned speaking engagement of E.T. Doran at Centralia, Washington.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link123">0078. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 269. Ray Becker. 11 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1926/1927" type="inclusive">1926-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Ray Becker; George F. Vanderveer. Subjects: Protests against Washington State prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Centralia, Washington; prison conditions at Walla Walla, Washington, state penitentiary; legal defense
       efforts; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; pen pals of prisoners; American Legion.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link124">0089. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 276. Joe Dezelin. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Joe Dezelin; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in North Carolina; immigrant labor; labor agencies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link125">0094. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 319. Thomas Rimmer. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas Rimmer. Subjects: Department of Justice cooperation with United States Department of State; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Butte, Montana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link126">0096. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 355. C. R. James. 4 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.R. James. Subject: Protest against Industrial Workers of the World activities among blacks in New York City.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">14</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link127">0100. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 356. Railroad Travel Arrangements of Industrial Workers of the World organizers in Washington. 30 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Cooperation between railroad employees and Industrial Workers of the World organizers in securing free travel on freight trains in Washington; affidavits of hoboes regarding Industrial Workers of the World organization
       of hoboes and railroad employees; sale of Industrial Workers of the World membership cards to riders of freight trains.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">15</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link128">0130. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 357. G. Rudolph Bickert. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922">1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: G. Rudolph Bickert. Subject: Request for ruling of Department of Justice on legality of Industrial Workers of the World membership.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">16</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link129">0135. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 358. Industrial Workers of the World strike plans in California. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans among railroad employees in California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">17</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link130">0141. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 359. Industrial Workers of the World strike plans in California and Texas. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans among railroad employees in California and Texas. File folder omitted.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">18</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link131">0142. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 359. Previously Restricted Materials. Industrial Workers of the World Strike Plans in California and Texas. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans among railroad employees in California and Texas.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">19</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link132">0143. Industrial Workers of the World - Subject. Case File 186701. Section 360. Industrial Workers of the World activities among United States Veterans' Bureau hospital employees in Arizona. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subject: Industrial Workers of the World organization of United States Veterans' Bureau hospital employees in California and Texas.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">20</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link133">0148. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 5. California. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Frank K. Nebeker; J. Robert O'Connor; Thomas W. Gregory; John W. Preston. Subjects: Cooperation in Department of Justice prosecutions of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in California and Chicago, Illinois; immigrant labor in
       California; arson and acts of incendiarism in California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">21</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link134">0153. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 6. Colorado. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry B. Tedrow; William C. Fitts. Subject: Bureau of Investigation agents in Colorado; Department of Justice raids on Industrial Workers of the World offices in Denver.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">22</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link135">0158. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 15. Indiana. 3 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1927" type="inclusive">1917-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: George N. Murdock; A.B. Bielaski; J. Edgar Hoover; William J. Donovan. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation; coal mine operators; American Legion.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">23</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link136">0161. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 17. Kansas. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subjects: Department of Justice policy regarding Industrial Workers of the World publications; Department of Justice raids in Minnesota.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">24</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link137">0163. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 19. Louisiana. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subject: Department of Justice investigations of Industrial Workers of the World activities.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">25</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link138">0164. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 21. Maryland. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subject: Protests regarding Industrial Workers of the World activities in Maryland.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">26</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link139">0165. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 22. Massachusetts. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; George W. Anderson. Subjects: Private detective agencies; Bureau of Investigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">27</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link140">0167. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 24. Minnesota. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1920" type="inclusive">1918-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover; Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice raids in Minnesota; Industrial Workers of the World activities in Minnesota.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">28</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link141">0173. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 26. Missouri.3 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter; A.B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts; George F. Vanderveer; Antone Johanson; Frank P. Walsh. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil workers; Oil Workers Industrial Union; Industrial Workers of the World
       publications; Department of Justice raids; Bureau of Investigation; Department of Justice surveillance of mail of attorneys for Industrial Workers of the World defendants.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">29</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link142">0176. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 27. Montana. 32 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1921" type="inclusive">1917-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover; Benjamin H. Fletcher; George Hardy; Thomas W. Gregory; Burton K. Wheeler; Frank Little. Subjects: Department of Justice surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Butte, Montana; mass meetings; industrial
       unionism; organization of black Americans in Philadelphia, Pennsylvania; emigrants to Soviet Russia; Industrial Workers of the World factionalism and internal politics; Department of Justice cooperation with local prosecutions of Industrial Workers of
       the World defendants; Industrial Workers of the World organization of smelter workers, copper miners, coal miners, and lumber workers in Montana; Finnish immigrants; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World
       activities in Montana; protests against lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana; strikes.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">30</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link143">0208. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 28. Nebraska. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Nebraska and Kansas; Bureau of Investigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">31</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link144">0213. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 29. Nevada. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World organization of miners in Nevada; strike plans.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">32</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link145">0215. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 45. Texas. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1923" type="inclusive">1917-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William J. Burns; Arthur Caminetti; J. Edgar Hoover; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory; A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation; Department of Justice cooperation with local prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants
       and seizures of Industrial Workers of the World documents; Department of Justice cooperation with Military Intelligence Division; Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities among immigrant labor in Texas;
       Industrial Workers of the World organization of shipyard workers, seamen, and oil workers in Texas, Oklahoma, and Mexico; protests against enclosing of rangeland in Texas.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">33</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link146">0227. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 46. Utah. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Grover H. Perry. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities among mine workers, smelter workers, railroad workers, and agricultural workers in
       Utah and Arizona; strikes.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">34</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link147">0229. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 49. Washington. 16 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1921" type="inclusive">1917- 1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: L. J. Baley; George F. Vanderveer; J. Edgar Hoover; Alfred Bettman; A. B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Military Intelligence Division cooperation with Bureau of Intelligence; list of Industrial Workers of the World organizers in New
       Mexico, Colorado, Texas, Arizona, and Idaho; Bureau of Investigation surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Washington and Montana; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Italian immigrants; Industrial Workers of the World
       strike plans; antiwar activities; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities among lumber workers; travel of Industrial Workers of the World members and hoboes on freight trains.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">35</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link148">0245. Industrial Workers of the World - By States - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 51. Wisconsin. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski. Subject: Antiwar propaganda in Milwaukee, Wisconsin.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">36</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link149">0246. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 54. Frank Little matter. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Frank Little. Subject: Cover letters to photographs of body and warning placed on body after lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little in Butte, Montana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">37</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link150">0248. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 1. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 2 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover. Subjects: Espionage Act prosecutions; United States congressman protests against Department of Justice prosecution of editors of the Seattle Union Record.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">38</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link151">0250. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 74, Part 2. Centralia and Seattle, Washington, Industrial Workers of the World cases. 1 page.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Alanson Sessions. Subject: Bureau of Investigations memorandum regarding identity of Seattle Union Record editor Alanson Sessions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">39</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link152">0251. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 03. Nicholas Radivoeff. 36 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Nicholas Radivoeff; T.F. Nolan; A.S. Embree. Subjects: Transcript of hearing of United States Department of Labor Immigration Service held in Butte, Montana, in the case of Nicholas Radivoeff and Adolphus Stewart Embree; testimony of Bureau of
       Investigation special agent in case; deportations; immigrant labor; Industrial Workers of the World publications; private detective agencies; Department of Justice surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World activities in Montana and Idaho.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">40</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link153">0287. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 266, Special Section Bureau Papers Only. Industrial Workers of the World Situation, San Francisco District. 86
       pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Simon J. Lubin; J. Vance Thompson; Frederick H. Esmond. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports on surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World activities in San Francisco, California; Marine Transport Workers Union; California state
       criminal syndicalism laws and raids on Industrial Workers of the World union offices; Industrial Workers of the World organization and publications; California District Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; fund raising and legal
       defense efforts; strike plans of Oil Workers Industrial Union in California; mass meetings; United Communist party publications.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">41</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link154">0373. Industrial Workers of the World - Subjects - Enclosures. Enclosures to Case File 186701. Section 361. Werner Kauffeldt. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923/1930" type="inclusive">1923- 1930</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Werner Kauffeldt; Anna Lipton; J. Edgar Hoover. Subjects: Informant's reports to the Bureau of Investigation on Industrial Workers of the World activities and sabotage plans of Anna Lipton in New York City; Marine Transport Workers Union in
       Maryland.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">42</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link155">0380. Bisbee, Arizona, Deportations. Case File 186813. Section 1. 355 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: George W. P. Hunt; Thomas A. Flynn; William C. Fitts; John Lord O'Brian; Thomas W. Gregory; Joseph P. Tumulty; John W. Davis; Samuel Gompers; William B. Wilson; Woodrow W. Wilson; Frank K. Nebeker; Thomas E. Campbell; Harry C. Wheeler; Louis
       F. Post; A. B. Bielaski; A.S. Embree; William C. Redfield; Charles Warren; Grover H. Perry; Irwin St. John Tucker; S. Burkhart; Abner E. Woodruff; Joseph Cannon; George L. Bell; Emmett D. Boyle; Walter S. Gifford. Subjects: Industrial disputes at copper
       mines in globe and Miami, Arizona; Industrial Workers of the World organization and strike plans of mine workers in Arizona; Globe, Arizona, Home Guards; deployment of federal troops in Arizona; United States War Department cooperation with Department
       of Justice; Department of Justice prosecution plans and draft indictment of vigilantes and local officials involved in Bisbee, Arizona, deportations of Industrial Workers of the World members; citizen and United States congressman protests against
       Industrial Workers of the World activities among lumber workers in Arizona; summary of state laws regarding kidnapping; citizen and union protests against deportations of Industrial Workers of the World members from Bisbee, Arizona; United States
       Department of Labor interest in case; President's Mediation Commission; Loyalty League of America, Bisbee, Arizona; executive committee Bisbee Deportees; immigrant labor; United States War Department list and histories of Bisbee, Arizona, Industrial
       Workers of the World deportees held in Columbus, New Mexico; minutes of conference of Thomas E. Campbell, governor of Arizona, with Citizens' Committee of Bisbee, Arizona; lynching of Industrial Workers of the World executive board member Frank Little
       in Butte, Montana; finances of Industrial Workers of the World local union in Bisbee, Arizona; Socialist party of America; Industrial Workers of the World publications; private detective agencies; California Commission on Immigration and Housing; plan
       of governors of Western states for dealing with labor problems and Industrial Workers of the World activities; National Defense Council. Frames 0735-0872 are a partial duplication of Section 1.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">43</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link156">0873. Bisbee, Arizona, Deportations. Case File 186813. Section 2. 252 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1924" type="inclusive">1918-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas A. Flynn; Harry M. Daugherty; Walter Nelles; A. Mitchell Palmer; Harry C. Wheeler; Charles Evans Hughes; Alexander C. King; Wiley E. Jones; Claude R. Porter; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory; George W. P. Hunt; William C. Herron;
       Thomas E. Campbell. Subjects: Citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities in Arizona; vigilantes; Department of Justice prosecution of vigilantes and local officials involved in Bisbee, Arizona, deportations of Industrial Workers
       of the World members; President's Mediation Commission; union and citizen protests against Bisbee, Arizona, deportations of Industrial Workers of the World members; general strikes in Jerome, globe, and Miami, Arizona; Phelps-Dodge Corporation purchase
       of firearms used in Bisbee deportations; indictment and reply brief in case against Harry C. Wheeler, et al.; deployment of United States troops in Arizona mining centers.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">7</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">44</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link157">1125. Bisbee, Arizona, Deportations. Case File 186813. Section 2. Previously Restricted Materials. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: A. B. Bielaski; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation report on conditions in Bisbee, Arizona, prior to deportations of Industrial Workers of the World members; strikes; vigilantes; United States Post Office Department censorship
       of Industrial Workers of the World mail.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
     <unittitle id="link158">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link159">0001. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 1, Part 1. 199 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Meeker; Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; Charles Page; Josephus Daniels; Charles F. Clyne; John Lord O'Brian; Roger N. Baldwin; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Arturo Giovannitti; Carlo Tresca; Joseph
       Graber; Adolph Germer; Joseph J. Ettor; Kenesaw M. Landis; Clarence L. Reames; Grover H. Perry; Samuel Block; John L. Metzen; Charles Warren; Stanley J. Clark; Hinton Clabaugh. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial
       Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; United States Shipping Board; United States Navy Department; United States War Department; National Civil Liberties Bureau; arrest of Industrial Workers of the World defendants
       in case; Industrial Workers of the World publications; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice raids on
       Industrial Workers of the World offices and seizure of Industrial Workers of the World documents; citizen protests against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members and leadership list of defendants in case; draft
       indictment in case against William D. Haywood, et al.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link160">0200. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 1, Part 2. 233 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Alexander C. King; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Arturo Giovannitti; Carlo Tresca; Claude R. Porter; Charles F. Clyne; George F. Vanderveer; E.T. Doran; A.S. Embree; Benjamin H. Fletcher; Jacob Friedrich; Charles Recht; Francis
       G. Caffey; Thomas W. Gregory; Learned Hand; Frank K. Nebeker; John Lind; William C. Herron; George N. Murdock; William C. Fitts; Ralph M. Easley. Subjects: Department of Justice policies regarding the bail and parole of Industrial Workers of the World
       defendants; Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; Department of Justice seizure of Industrial Workers of the World documents; General Defense
       Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; surveillance of mails of Industrial Workers of the World members and Industrial Workers of the World lawyers; United States Post Office Department cooperation with Department of Justice; American
       Protective League surveillance of Industrial Workers of the World mailing procedures. Dates in Section 1, Part 2 correspond with those that would fall in Section 3 and so are presumed to be a misfile of Section 3.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link161">0433. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 1. Previously Restricted Materials. 32 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Thomas W. Gregory; Frank K. Nebeker; Carlton H. Parker; George F. Vanderveer; William C. Fitts; Hinton Clabaugh; A.B. Bielaski; Fred Hardy; Stanley J. Clark. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois prosecution of
       Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; Industrial Workers of the World fund raising and legal defense efforts; suggested methods of arranging Industrial Workers of the World evidence in case against
       William D. Haywood, et al.; Department of Justice wartime censorship of publications; sedition and Espionage Act prosecutions; list of potential Industrial Workers of the World detainees in the United States.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link162">0465. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 2. 396 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; Thomas W. Gregory; Kenesaw M. Landis; Newton D. Baker; Richard T. Ely; A.B. Bielaski; Charles F. Clyne; J. Robert O'Connor; Clarence L. Reames; George Andreytchine;
       Joseph J. Ettor; George N. Murdock; W. H. Lamar; Francis G. Caffey; John P. Feeny; George Hardy; Josephus Daniels; Joseph P. Tumulty; George F. Vanderveer; Roger N. Baldwin; Ralph M. Easley; George Creel; William B. Wilson; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Carlo
       Tresca; Arturo Giovannitti; Woodrow W. Wilson; George P. West. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; citizen protests against Industrial
       Workers of the World activities and against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members; Industrial Workers of the World publications; United States War Department and United States Navy Department cooperation with
       department of Justice; Espionage Act prosecutions; answer to petition for return of papers and petition for impounding order in case against William D. Haywood, et al.; affidavit as to documents seized by Department of Justice and lists of Industrial
       Workers of the World documents and publications in storage in case against William D. Haywood, et al.; United States Post Office Department cooperation with Department of Justice in censorship of Industrial Workers of the World publications; General
       Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; League for National Unity.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link163">0861. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 2. Enclosures. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William d. Haywood; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; special report regarding Industrial Workers of the
       World activities in Portland, Oregon; Industrial Workers of the World union organization; Espionage Act Prosecutions; Soviet Russian consulate in Seattle, Washington.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link164">0873. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 4. 263 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Charles F. Clyne; A. Mitchell Palmer; Claude R. Porter; Vincent St. John; Clarence Darrow; Raymond S. Fanning; George N. Murdock; Kenesaw M. Landis; George F. Vanderveer; Frank K. Nebeker; Francis G. Caffey; Harry
       Weinberger; George Andreytchine; John Lord O'Brian; Alexander C. King; David S. Cook; Louis F. Post; Charles Recht; Arturo Giovannitti; Alexander S. Lanier; Charles Ashleigh; Herman Richter; George W. Whiteside; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Carlo Tresca;
       Thomas W. Gregory; Alfred Bettman. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World
       activities and against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members; Industrial Workers of the World organization of black Americans; list of defendants released on bond; charge of Judge Landis to the jury in case against
       William D. Haywood, et al.; Department of Justice policies regarding bail and parole for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice; plans for disposition of Industrial Workers of the
       World documents and property seized by the department of Justice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">8</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link165">1136. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 5. 248 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1920" type="inclusive">1919-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Charles F. Clyne; David S. Cook; Robert P. Stewart; Frank K. Nebeker; A. Mitchell Palmer; George Andreytchine; Louis F. Post; Claude R. Porter; John L. Metzen. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution
       of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; citizen and United States congressman protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities; Industrial Workers of the World publications; General Defense
       Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; International Workers' Defense League; Department of Justice policies regarding bail and parole for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; plans for disposition of Industrial Workers of the World
       documents and property seized by the Department of Justice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
     <unittitle id="link166">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link167">0000. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 5. Previously Restricted Materials and Enclosures. 24 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Frank K. Nebeker; J. Edgar Hoover; Charles H. McKinnon; A. Mitchell Palmer; Benjamin H. Fletcher; A.B. Bielaski; George N. Murdock. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the
       World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; plans for disposition of documents and property seized by the Department of Justice; Industrial Workers of the World publications; citizen and United States congressman protests against
       Industrial Workers of the World activities; private detective agencies; United States Post Office Department censorship of Industrial Workers of the World mail.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link168">0024. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 6. 213 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1938" type="inclusive">1920-1938</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Arturo Giovannitti; J. Edgar Hoover; Homer S. Cummings; Joseph B. Fleming; Victor L. Berger; Forrest Edwards; Vincent St. John; Raymond S. Fanning; A. Mitchell Palmer; William L. Frierson; Francis Ralston Welsh; James H.
       Rowan; Louis F. Post; Frank K. Nebeker; David S. Cook. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; requests for access to Department of Justice
       files on case against William D. Haywood, et al.; Department of Justice request for United States Department of State verification of death of William D. Haywood in Russia; application for writ of certiorari before the United States Supreme Court;
       United States Circuit Court of Appeals hearings; surveillance of mail of prisoners in Leavenworth, Kansas, penitentiary; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; Department of Justice policies regarding parole and bail for
       Industrial Workers of the World defendants; Industrial Workers of the World fund raising, legal defense, and organization of agricultural workers in South Dakota; citizen protests against Industrial Workers of the World activities and against Department
       of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members; Industrial Workers of the World publications; plans for disposition of Industrial Workers of the World documents and property seized by the Department of Justice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link169">0237. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 7. 205 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1954" type="inclusive">1921-1954</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Thomas J.D. Salter; Samuel Gompers; J. Edgar Hoover; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles Moyer; Mabel Walker Willebrandt; Ralph Chaplin; Roger N. Baldwin; James A. Finch; Sara B. Field; Ida
       Palmer; E. F. Doree; Stanley J. Clark; Alexander S. Lanier; Rose Weiss; Harry Weinberger; Charles Ashleigh; Vincent St. John; Charles F. Clyne; John Pancner; Caroline A. Lowe; Robert P. Stewart; Joseph B. Fleming; Annette Abbott Adams. Subjects:
       Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; requests for access to Department of Justice files on case against William D. Haywood, et al; plans for
       disposition of Industrial Workers of the World documents seized by the Department of Justice; decision of United States Circuit Court of Appeals in case against William D. Haywood, et al.; dismissal of cases against remaining defendants; surveillance of
       mail of prisoners in Leavenworth, Kansas, penitentiary; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World; American Civil Liberties Union; forfeiture of bond by William D. Haywood; interview from Pravda given by William D. Haywood in
       Moscow regarding the present condition of the labor classes in the United States; United States Supreme Court denial of writ of certiorari in case against William D. Haywood, et al.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link170">0442. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Section 6-7. Previously Restricted Materials and Enclosures. 82 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1928/1955" type="inclusive">1928-1955</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; Herbert McCutcheon; Vincent St. John; William Stanley; J. Edgar Hoover; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World
       leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; dismissal of charges against fugitive Industrial Workers of the World defendant Herbert McCutcheon; decision of United States Circuit Court of Appeals in case against William D. Haywood, et al.;
       investigation of death of William D. Haywood in Moscow, Russia; copy of original indictment in case against William D. Haywood, et al.; attempted extradition of conspiracy defendants from Canada.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link171">0524. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Special Section. 20 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; William C. Fitts; Thomas W. Gregory; George F. Vanderveer; George Creel; Frank K. Nebeker; Lincoln Steffens; M. E. Saville. Subjects: Department of Justice Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World
       leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; Committee on Public Information; Industrial Workers of the World activities in the Pacific Northwest; Industrial Workers of the World legal defense efforts.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link172">0544. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. Special Section. Enclosures and Previously Restricted Materials. 14 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; A. B. Bielaski; Antone Johanson; Frank P. Walsh; George F. Vanderveer; Fred Hardy; Hinton Clabaugh; Roger N. Baldwin; J. A. Wagner. Subjects: Industrial Workers of the World activities in the Pacific Northwest; Industrial
       Workers of the World legal defense efforts; Office of Naval Intelligence surveillance of mail of Industrial Workers of the World attorneys; Soviet Russian consulate in Seattle, Washington; Civil Liberties Bureau of the American Union against Militarism
       and the formation of the American Civil Liberties Union or National Civil Liberties Bureau; American visitors to Soviet Russia.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link173">0558. William D. Haywood. Case File 188032. File regarding White E. Gibson, Special Assistant to the Attorney General. 125 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William D. Haywood; White E. Gibson; Thomas W. Gregory; Kenesaw M. Landis; William C. Fitts; Frank K. Nebeker; Claude R. Porter; Simon J. Lubin; George F. Vanderveer; George L. Bell; Samuel Gompers; Ralph M. Easley. Subjects: Department of
       Justice Chicago, Illinois; prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World leadership and Industrial Workers of the World members; Butte, Montana, miners strike and acts of incendiarism at Granite Mountain, Montana; attempts to establish overt acts of
       sabotage by the Industrial Workers of the World for the prosecution; investigation of Industrial Workers of the World activities on the Pacific Coast; Industrial Workers of the World lumber workers strike and union organization; eight-hour day proposal;
       National Civic Federation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link174">0684. F.W. Henshaw. Case File 188044. 66 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: F.W. Henshaw; Frank K. Nebeker; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts; J. C. Thompson; Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Charles M. Fickert; John W. Preston; A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Supreme Court of California Justice F.W. Henshaw
       allegations regarding Industrial Workers of the World activities in California; investigation of explosion at Mare Island, California, Navy Yard; Mooney-Billings case; district attorney for the city and county of San Francisco, California, public
       relations activities; International Workers' Defense League; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; immigration and naturalization cases.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link175">0750. Fresno, California, Industrial Workers of the World Case. Case File 188561. 113 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1922" type="inclusive">1917-1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Annette Abbott Adams; J. Edgar Hoover; Claude R. Porter; Elmer Anderson; J. Robert O'Connor; John W. Preston; Thomas W. Gregory; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Prison conditions at Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary; partial transcript of
       trial and indictment in case against Elmer Anderson, et al.; Department of Justice prosecution of Fresno an Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World defendants and Chicago, Illinois, prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World
       leadership; Industrial Workers of the World organization of agricultural workers and acts of sabotage in California.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">9</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link176">0863. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 1. 267 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1919" type="inclusive">1917-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; Albert DeSilver; Claude R. Porter; Fred Robertson; Thomas W. Gregory; John Lord O'Brian; George N. Murdock; George F. Vanderveer; Oliver E. Pagan; Frank K. Nebeker; William C. Fitts; A. B. Bielaski; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects:
       Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas; investigation of Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil field workers and agricultural workers; Industrial Workers of the World
       publications; National Civil Liberties Bureau; Department of Justice policies regarding bail for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice; indictment and complaint in case against C.
       W. Anderson, et al.; internment of aliens during World War I.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
     <unittitle id="link177">RG 60 - Straight Numerical File</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link178">0000. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 2. 201 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; A. Mitchell Palmer; Fred Robertson; Claude R. Porter; Oliver E. Pagan; John C. Pollock; George F. Vanderveer; Albert DeSilver; William C. Herron; John Lord O'Brian; Alfred Bettman; William L. Frierson. Subjects: Department of
       Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas, citizen protests against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants; decision and order of Judge Pollock regarding the return of
       Industrial Workers of the World documents seized by the Department of Justice, indictment, petition for return of papers, and motion to quash indictment, demurrer, and motion for bill of particulars in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; Industrial
       Workers of the World organization of oil field workers and agricultural workers; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Industrial Workers of the World legal defense efforts; Department of Justice raids in Kansas, Oklahoma, and Minnesota;
       National Civil Liberties Bureau; Department of Justice policies regarding bail for Industrial Workers of the World defendants; prison conditions of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners held in the county jails of Kansas.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link179">0201. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 3. 235 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1921" type="inclusive">1919-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; James M. Beck; Harry M. Daugherty; Fred Robertson; Robert P. Stewart; F.W. Galbraith, Jr.; Annette Abbott Adams; Samuel B. Amidon; George F. Vanderveer; A. Mitchell Palmer; Fred H. Moore; Caroline A. Lowe; J. Edgar Hoover; John
       C. Pollock; John H. Atwood; Frank J. Silsbee; Louis F. Post; Alexander Howat. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Wichita, Kansas; United States Supreme Court denial of writ of certiorari, United
       States Circuit Court of Appeals decision, motion for severance, and ruling of Judge Pollock on motion to quash indictment in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; American Legion; internment of aliens during World War I; Industrial Workers of the World
       publications; Industrial Workers of the World organization of oil field workers and agricultural workers; Industrial Workers of the World legal defense efforts; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; union protests
       against Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World members.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link180">0436. C. W. Anderson, et al. Case File 189152. Section 2 and 3. Previously Restricted Materials. 21 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1921" type="inclusive">1919-1921</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; J. Edgar Hoover; Claude R. Porter. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendant in Wichita, Kansas; Bureau of Investigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link181">0457. Spokane, Washington. Case File 189738. 13 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1917/1918" type="inclusive">1917-1918</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas W. Gregory; John Lord O'Brian; A. B. Bielaski; Claude R. Porter; William C. Fitts. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Spokane, Washington; Industrial Workers of the World
       strikes; private detective agencies.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link182">0470. Seattle, Washington. Case File 193498. 29 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1919" type="inclusive">1918-1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Thomas W. Gregory; Robert C. Saunders; Clarence L. Reames; Claude R. Porter; John Lord O'Brian. Subjects: Alleged illegal arrests and false imprisonment of Industrial Workers of the World members by special agents of the Department of Justice,
       United States Navy personnel, and local officials in Seattle, Washington; Office of Naval Intelligence; Seattle District Defense Committee and General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link183">0499. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 1. 143 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1920" type="inclusive">1918-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. Edgar Hoover; Baldwin Robertson; A. Mitchell Palmer; Edward C. Day; S.V. Stewart; Burton K. Wheeler; Robert P. Stewart; John Lord O'Brian; Victor Elting; Thomas W. Gregory; Newton D. Baker; A. B. Bielaski. Subjects: Department of Justice
       investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; citizen and United States congressman protests against Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin editorials regarding Industrial Workers of the World union organization, violence
       in labor disputes, and free speech; use of United States Guards in Butte, Montana, labor disputes; Espionage Act prosecutions; general strikes; American Protective League; governor of Montana requests for federal intervention in Butte, Montana; private
       detective agencies; United States War Department cooperation with Department of Justice; alleged illegal arrests and false imprisonments by United States Guard and local officials in Butte, Montana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link184">0642. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 1. Previously Unrestricted Materials. 69 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1920" type="inclusive">1918-1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Baldwin Robertson; J. Edgar Hoover; A. Mitchell Palmer; A.B. Bielaski. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; citizen protests against editorials and state
       prosecution of editors of the Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin; American Loyalty League; general strikes; use of United States Guards in Butte, Montana, labor disputes; alleged illegal arrests and false imprisonments by United States Guards and local
       officials in Butte, Montana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link185">0711. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 2. 56 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Baldwin Robertson; A. Mitchell Palmer. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; contempt of court and improper use of mail charges brought against editors of the Butte,
       Montana, Daily Bulletin; private detective agencies; violence in labor disputes; immigration and deportation cases.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link186">0767. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Section 2. Previously Restricted Materials. 45 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Baldwin Robertson; Robert P. Stewart; J. Edgar Hoover; A.S. Embree; Nicholas Radivoeff. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; immigration and deportation cases;
       investigation and prosecution of Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin editorials and use of mail; United States Post Office Department cooperation with Department of Justice; Bureau of Investigation report on Industrial Workers of the World activities in
       Butte, Montana.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link187">0812. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Subsection 1. 52 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Baldwin Robertson; A. Mitchell Palmer; Frank K. Nebeker; Robert P. Stewart; J. Edgar Hoover; Louis F. Post; William L. Frierson. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in
       Montana; Espionage Act prosecutions; Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin; American Legion; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link188">0864. Butte, Montana. Case File 195397. Subsection 2. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920">1920</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Baldwin Robertson. Subjects: Department of Justice investigation of Industrial Workers of the World and radical activities in Montana; alleged false affidavits made by managing editor of the Butte, Montana, Daily Bulletin.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">10</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link189">0870. James H. Rowan. Case File 210791. 178 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1927" type="inclusive">1920-1927</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James H. Rowan; Oscar R. Luhring; John G. Sargent; Charles F. Clyne; Roy C. Fox; John Marshall; J. Edgar Hoover; Donald F. Kizer; Edwin A. Olson; Roy A. Darling; H.S. Ridgely; Henry S. Huntington; Harlan F. Stone; Frank R. Jeffrey; Harry M.
       Daugherty; William C. Herron; Robert P. Stewart; Theodore G. Risley; Annette Abbott Adams; Louis F. Post; T. J. Spellacy. Subjects: Naturalization and immigration case involving convicted Industrial Workers of the World leader, whose sentence had been
       commuted; United States Department of Labor cooperation with Department of Justice; decision of United States Circuit Court of Appeals overturning decree cancelling certificate of naturalization; citizen and United States congressman protests against
       cancellation of citizenship of James H. Rowan.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container>
     <unittitle id="link190">RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link191">0001. Charles Ashleigh. Case File 35-362. 393 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919/1922" type="inclusive">1919-1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Charles Ashleigh; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; Harry Weinberger; George B. Christian; Jr.; Frank K. Nebeker; Elizabeth Gurley Flynn; Alexander S. Lanier; Mary Heaton Vorse; Robert H. Turner; Charles F. Clyne; A.
       Mitchell Palmer; Woodrow W. Wilson; Frank L. Polk. Subjects: Application for executive clemency in behalf of Charles Ashleigh; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Workers' Defense Union; Department of Justice recommendations
       regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; amnesty proposals in the United States
       Congress; amnesty laws in England, Canada, Italy, Belgium, and France; Espionage Act convictions; Industrial Workers of the World publications.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link192">0394. Carl Ahlteen, Ragner Johanson, and Sigfried Stenberg. Case File 36-52. 293 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1933" type="inclusive">1921-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Carl Ahlteen; Ragner Johanson; Sigfried Stenberg; James A. Finch; Lucille B. Milner; Harry M. Daugherty; Roger N. Baldwin; Charles Evans Hughes; Axel Wallenberg; A. Mitchell Palmer; Charles F. Clyne; Robert H. Turner; John Lord O'Brian; Morris
       L. Ernst; Arthur Garfield Hays; William D. Mitchell; Herbert C. Hoover; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Warren G. Harding; Mary Gertrude Fendall. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency in behalf of Carl Ahlteen, Ragner Johanson, and Sigfried Stenberg;
       appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; American Civil Liberties Union; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Espionage Act convictions; amnesty proposals in the United States Congress; Joint Amnesty Committee.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link193">0686. So-called Political Prisoner Cases. No Case File Number. 75 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1923" type="inclusive">1921-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Vincent St. John. Subjects: Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; general amnesty proposals in the United States and abroad; lists of Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners in the United States and summaries of cases; Espionage Act convictions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">11</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link194">0761. Charles L. Lambert, Sam Scarlett, and Aurelio V. Azuara. Case File 38-487. 284 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1923" type="inclusive">1921-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Charles L. Lambert; Sam Scarlett; Aurelio V. Azuara; Archibald R. Sinclair; Harry M. Daugherty; Warren G. Harding; James A. Finch; Charles F. Clyne; John Lord O'Brian; Newton D. Baker; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Mary Gertrude Fendall. Subjects:
       Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Charles L. Lambert, Sam Scarlett, and Aurelio V. Azuara; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers
       of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; general amnesty proposals; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union; lists of
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Industrial Workers of the World publications and union organization; Espionage Act convictions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
     <unittitle id="link195">RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link196">0001. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. General. 276 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1924" type="inclusive">1921-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Newton D. Baker; Warren F. Martin; Mary Gertrude Fendall; John C. Pollock; Edward Anderson; C.W. Anderson; Elmer Anderson; James A. Finch; Augustus T. Seymour; E.J. Henning; Harry F. Ward; Roger N.
       Baldwin; Charles F. Clyne; Claude R. Porter; Pierce C. Wetter. Subjects: General amnesty proposals; Espionage Act convictions; lists of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; applications for executive
       clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union; appeals, reports, and exhibits supporting applications; Department of Justice
       recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; partial transcript on
       appeal of case against Edward Anderson, et al.; Industrial Workers of the World publications; Wichita, Kansas, and Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World cases; General Defense Committee of the Industrial Workers of the World.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link197">0277. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (A). Bennett, Charles. 26 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1929" type="inclusive">1921-1929</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Charles Bennett; George Wharton Pepper; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of
       Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; general amnesty proposals in the
       United States; Espionage Act convictions.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link198">0303. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (B). Bourg, G. J.. 20 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1925" type="inclusive">1922-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: G.J. Bourg; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency in behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; deportations; Department of
       Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link199">0323. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (C). Brazier, Richard. 47 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1925" type="inclusive">1922-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Richard Brazier; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles F. Clyne; Pierce C. Wetter; William E. Borah. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with
       summaries of cases; deportations; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the
       World prisoners; Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World convictions; New York branch office of the General Defense Committee.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link200">0370. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (D). Chaplin, Ralph. 24 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Ralph Chaplin; James A. Finch; Robert T. Kerlin; Warren G. Harding; Mabel Walker Willebrandt; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency in behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with
       summaries of cases; censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners at Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports
       from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link201">0394. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (E). Cournos, Alexander. 10 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Alexander Cournos. Subjects: Applications for clemency in behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link202">0404. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (F). Davis, C.W.. 10 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Davis; C.H. Rice. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link203">0414. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (G). Doran, J.T.. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J. T. Doran. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link204">0421. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (H). Edwards, Forrest. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Forrest Edwards. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link205">0426. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (I) Foss, John. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: John Foss. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link206">0434. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (J) Graber, Joe. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Joe Graber. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link207">0439. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (K) Green, Peter. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Peter Green; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Charles F. Clyne. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice
       recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link208">0451. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (L). Kane, H.F.. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: H.F. Kane; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations
       regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners and censorship of mail.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">14</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link209">0458. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (M). Lloyd, Harry. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923/1925" type="inclusive">1923-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry Lloyd; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations
       regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">15</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link210">0466. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (N). Lorton, Burt. 12 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1925" type="inclusive">1922-1925</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Burt Lorton; James A. Finch; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice
       recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">16</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link211">0478. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (O). MacDonald, J.A.. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: J.A. MacDonald. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">17</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link212">0484. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (P). McKinnon, Charles H.. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Charles H. McKinnon; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice
       recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">18</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link213">0491. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (Q). Rowan, James. 9 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James Rowan; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations
       regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners and censorship of mail.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">19</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link214">0500. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (R). Sheridan, Don. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Don Sheridan. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">20</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link215">0507. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (S). Sinclair, Archie. 40 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Archie Sinclair; William J. Burns; James A. Finch; Pierce C. Wetter; Augustus T. Seymour; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; Robe Carl White. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; deportations; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding
       behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">21</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link216">0547. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (T). Slovick, James. 16 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923/1944" type="inclusive">1923-1944</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James Slovick; Roger N. Baldwin; Daniel M. Lyons; Isaac Shorr. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; American Civil Liberties Union;
       Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">22</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link217">0563. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (U). Thompson, James P.. 9 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James P. Thompson; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations
       regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">23</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link218">0572. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (V). Turner, John L.. 8 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: John L. Turner. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">24</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link219">0580. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. Political Prisoners. Haywood Case. 337 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; Charles F. Clyne; Albert DeSilver; Morris Hillquit; William D. Haywood. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with
       summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; lists of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners and summaries of cases; foreign and domestic precedents for a decree
       of general amnesty for political prisoners; partial transcript of trial on appeal in case against William D. Haywood, et al. File folder omitted.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">12</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">25</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link220">0917. Chicago, Illinois, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-240. (S). Archie Sinclair. Previously Restricted Materials. 28 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Archie Sinclair; Charlotte Anita Whitney. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports regarding Industrial Workers of the World activities in San Francisco, California; union organization state criminal syndicalism laws; Industrial Workers of
       the World fund raising and legal defense efforts.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
     <unittitle id="link221">RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link222">0001. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. General. 353 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James A. Finch; Elmer Anderson; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; A. Mitchell Palmer; Robert P. Stewart; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Newton D. Baker; Robert H. Turner; Ralph M. Easley; John W.
       Preston; Robert Duncan; Archibald Stevenson; Frank H. Rudkin; frank M. Silva; Anna C. Pollok; Theodora Pollok Rhoads; Charles M. Fickert; Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; Gilson Gardner; George Wharton Pepper; Elbert Coutts; Edward Anderson.
       Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union; National Civic Federation; Industrial Workers of the World
       publications and legal defense efforts; district attorney for the city and county of San Francisco, California; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link223">0354. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Anderson, Elmer. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Elmer Anderson; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice
       recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link224">0361. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. de Bernardi, Pete. 27 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Pete De Bernardi; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Roger N. Baldwin; John W. Preston; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of the Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in
       the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers
       of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link225">0388. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Brewer, Harry. 13 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry Brewer; Warren G, Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link226">0401. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Hood, William. 17 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: William Hood; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of
       Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link227">0418. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Connellan, Robert. 18 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1933" type="inclusive">1920-1933</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Robert Connellan; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States
       with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link228">0436. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Downing, Mortimer. 16 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Mortimer Downing; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link229">0452. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Gray, Harry. 18 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Harry Gray; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases;
       Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link230">0470. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Grave, John. 18 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: John Grave; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners
       in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link231">0488. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Hammer, Henry. 28 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Henry Hammer; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; Frank B. Kellogg; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with
       summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners;
       citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">11</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link232">0516. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Elliott, Frank. 15 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Frank Elliott; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">12</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link233">0531. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Luber, Chris A.. 15 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Chris A. Luber; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">13</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link234">0546. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. McLaughlin, Phil. 22 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Phil McLaughlin; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of
       Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary
       regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">14</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link235">0568. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. O'Connell, George. 14 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: George O'Connell; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">15</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link236">0582. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Potthast, John. 16 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: John Potthast; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World penitentiary.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">16</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link237">0598. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Quigley, Edward. 85 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Edward Quigley; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Mary Gertrude Fendall; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty; William J. Burns. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the
       World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the
       World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">17</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link238">0683. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Quigley, Edward. Previously Restricted Materials. 7 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922- 1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Edward Quigley; William J. Burns; Harry Weinberger. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports on physicians qualified to examine Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; Socialist Party of America.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">18</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link239">0690. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Quinlan, James. 14 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James Quinlan; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John_ Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">19</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link240">0704. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Santilli, Vincent. 34 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1924" type="inclusive">1920-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Vincent Santilli; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States
       with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners; deportations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">20</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link241">0737. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Sprague, Myron. 13 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Myron Sprague; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">21</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link242">0750. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Tabib, Caesar. 101 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Caesar Tabib; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Frank H. Rudkin; Robert Duncan; George B. Christian, Jr.; Harry M. Daugherty; William J. Burns; Roger N. Baldwin; (John) Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for
       executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from
       Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; Workers National Prison Comfort Club.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">22</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link243">0851. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Tabib, Caesar. Previously Restricted Materials. 5 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1921/1922" type="inclusive">1921- 1922</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Caesar Tabib; Roger N. Baldwin; Alexander S. Lanier. Subjects: Bureau of Investigation reports on physicians qualified to examine Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; citizen protests against continued
       incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">23</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link244">0856. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Tori, Jacob. 19 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1924" type="inclusive">1920-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Jacob Tori; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; Alexander S. Lanier; Harry M. Daugherty; Calvin Coolidge. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with
       summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers
       of the World prisoners; deportations.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">24</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link245">0875. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Voetter, George F. 17 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: George F. Voetter; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of
       cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">13</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">25</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link246">0892. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Price, James. 90 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1924" type="inclusive">1922-1924</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: James Price; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Augustus T. Seymour; Earl J. Davis; James A. Finch; Robert Duncan; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Warren F. Martin; Harry M. Daugherty; Harry Feinberg. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal
       penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; Industrial Workers of the World publications;
       California state criminal syndicalism law convictions; General Defense Committee.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
     <unittitle id="link247">RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">1</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link248">0001. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Connor, Roy P. 154 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Roy P. Connor; Warren G. Harding; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Roger N. Baldwin; Newton D. Baker; Thomas W. Hardwick; Harry M. Daugherty; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Clifford Walker; Thomas W. Hardwick; Robert Duncan; John W. Preston;
       Frank H. Rudkin; George Wharton Pepper; William E. Borah. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding
       executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior and censorship of mail of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen and United States congressman
       protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union; hunger strikes.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">2</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link249">0155. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. 234 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1923" type="inclusive">1918-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: George Wharton Pepper; Augustus T. Seymour; James A. Finch; Frank M. Silva; Robert Duncan; John W. Preston; P.H. Johnson; William D. Stephens; Charles M. Fickert; Thomas J. Mooney; Warren K. Billings; F.W. Henshaw; Harry M. Daugherty; Augustus
       T. Seymour; Mary Gertrude Fendall. Subjects: Department of Justice prosecution of Industrial Workers of the World defendants in Sacramento, California, and Chicago, Illinois, and recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the
       World defendants; citizen and United States congressman protests against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; American Civil Liberties Union publications regarding Industrial Workers of the World cases; Mooney-Billings
       case; district attorney for the city and county of San Francisco, California; Joint Amnesty Committee. File folder omitted.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">3</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link250">0389. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. Previously Restricted Materials. 112 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1974" type="inclusive">1922-1974</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Richard S. Street; James A. Finch; William J. Burns. Subjects: Request for access to Department of Justice files regarding Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World prosecutions; Department of Justice recommendations regarding
       executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Bureau of Investigation reports on executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">4</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link251">0501. Sacramento, California, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-241. General. 23 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Not available. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">5</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link252">0524. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. 88 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; Fred Robertson; Hendrik Shipstead; Knute Nelson; Frank B. Kellogg; James A. Finch; Mary Gertrude Fendall; Harry M. Daugherty; Roger N. Baldwin; Oscar E. Gordon. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of
       Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; citizen and United States congressman protests
       against continued incarceration of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Joint Amnesty Committee; American Civil Liberties Union. File folder omitted.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">6</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link253">0612. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Anderson, C.W. 244 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1918/1976" type="inclusive">1918-1976</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; Michael Sapper; Oscar E. Gordon; F.J. Gallagher; Wencil Francik; Phineas Eastman; Samuel B. Amidon; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Harry M. Daugherty; Augustus T. Seymour; John C. Pollock; Robert P. Stewart; Robert H. Turner; Warren G.
       Harding; James A. Finch; Fred Robertson; Thomas J. Howe. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; department of Justice recommendations regarding
       executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; decision, petition for rehearing, and petition for writ of error
       before the United States Circuit Court of Appeals in case against C. W. Anderson, et al.; indictment in United States Court in case against C.W. Anderson, et al.; requests for access to Department of Justice files relating to Industrial Workers of the
       World cases. File folder omitted.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">7</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link254">0856. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Francik, Wencil. 40 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1922/1923" type="inclusive">1922-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Wencil Francik; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Frank H. McFarland. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with
       summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World
       prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">8</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link255">0896. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Francik, Wencil. Previously Restricted Materials. 6 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Wencil Francik; James A. Finch. Subjects: Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; Bureau of Investigation.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">9</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link256">0902. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Gallagher, F.J. 50 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1920/1923" type="inclusive">1920-1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: F.J. Gallagher; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; A. Mitchell Palmer; Fred Robertson; Samuel B. Amidon; Caroline A. Lowe; (John) Calvin Coolidge; Frank H. McFarland. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial
       Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases; Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary
       regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">14</container>
      <unitid label="Item ">10</unitid>
      <unittitle id="link257">0952. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Sapper, Michael. 38 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1923">1923</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: Michael Sapper; Warren G. Harding; Harry M. Daugherty; James A. Finch; Frank H. McFarland. Subjects: Applications for executive clemency on behalf of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners in the United States with summaries of cases;
       Department of Justice recommendations regarding executive clemency for Industrial Workers of the World prisoners; reports from Leavenworth, Kansas, federal penitentiary regarding behavior of Industrial Workers of the World prisoners.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container>
     <unittitle id="link258">RG 204 - Pardon Attorney Files</unittitle>
    </did>
    <c02 level="file">
     <did>
      <container label="unspecified" type="reel">15</container>
      <unittitle id="link259">0001. Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of the World. Case File 39-242. Anderson, C.W. et al. Kansas City Industrial Workers of the World. 1129 pages.</unittitle>
      <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
     </did>
     <scopecontent>
      <p>People: C.W. Anderson; John C. Pollock; Fred Robertson; Samuel B. Amidon; Fred H. Moore; Caroline A. Lowe. Subjects: Transcript of trial in case against C.W. Anderson, et al.; Department of Justice prosecution of Wichita, Kansas, Industrial Workers of
       the World defendants; lists of exhibits, indexes, arguments, testimony, charge of the court, verdicts, and sentences in case before the United States District Court for the District of Kansas. File folder omitted. December 1-18, 1919.</p>
     </scopecontent>
    </c02>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>