<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05747mf::Operation Dixie: The CIO Organizing Committee Papers on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05747mf</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Operation Dixie: The CIO Organizing Committee Papers on
                        Microfilm<date> 1946-1953</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Operation Dixie: The CIO Organizing Committee Papers on
                    Microfilm</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 28, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 28,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Operation Dixie: The CIO Organizing Committee Papers on
                Microfilm</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5747 mf</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
                        Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 28, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 28, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Operation Dixie: The CIO
                Organizing Committee Papers on Microfilm, 1946-1953
            </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1946-1953</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5747 mf</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Congress of Industrial
                    Organizations (CIO)</corpname>;
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> CIO Organizing
                    Committee</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">75 microfilm reels</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Posters, microfilm.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">The papers include correspondence, addresses, minutes,
                memoranda, printed materials and miscellaneous documents. 
                 The "Operation Dixie" collection includes the records from four states-- North
                Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee and Virginia. Records from the other states
                involved in the campaign are no longer in existence. 
                 In addition to procedural matters delineating the business, personnel and
                financial policies of the Organizing Committee, the CIO's objectives, priorities and
                approaches to organizing and negotiating are apparent in correspondence, printed
                matter and publicity materials. National, state and local political issues,
                jurisdictional questions, including relations between the AFL and the CIO, improved
                labor and living conditions and relations with other departments of the CIO, as well
                as with a variety of social reform and friends of labor groups are documented. Legal
                materials include NLRB documents concerning unfair labor practices, elections, etc.
                Organizers reports and membership records are among the other types of materials
                found in the records.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>8.33 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>Lucy Mason, a social reformer, was concerned with such matters as civil rights, labor
                legislation, working hours for women, minimum wages, social security and rights of
                workers. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p> She served as southern public relations representative for the CIO for 16 years. She
                was involved in the campaigns of the Operation Dixie organizing drive. Mason was
                also General Secretary of the YWCA for a period of time and active in several other
                social and civic organizations.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>Operation Dixie was the name given to the CIO's program to bring unionism to the
                South. Under the direction of Van A. Bittner, the vice-president of the United
                Steelworkers of America, the CIO's Southern Organizing Committee was established in
                May 1946. Supported by contributions from some forty affiliated unions, the
                Committee established programs in twelve states throughout the South. Operation
                Dixie attempted to organize workers in diverse industries, concentrating on the
                textile, wood products, chemical, oil and iron and steel industries and on the
                largest and most resistant employers in a given area. </p>
            <p>While its primary purpose was "organizing the unorganized," the Southern Organizing
                Committee also cooperated with the CIO's Political Action Committees and State CIOs
                or Industrial Union Councils which sought to attain the parent organizations goals
                through state and national legislation and electoral reform. </p>
            <p>Although by February 1947 324 new locals had been established, the Committee's work
                was plagued with a variety of problems. Among these were charges of communist
                sympathies; opposition by the Ku Klux Klan and others to the CIO policy of
                establishing racially integrated locals; lack of financial support; and employer
                opposition which included violence, intimidation and collusion with public
                authorities. In 1953, the Southern drive was reorganized and most of the work of
                developing and servicing locals was turned over to the affiliated unions at that
                time. </p>
            <p>Consists in large part of the records of the CIO Organizing Committee campaigns to
                organize workers in four southern states: North Carolina, South Carolina, Tennessee
                and Virginia. Records from the other states involved in the campaign are no longer
                in existence. </p>
            <p>In addition to procedural matters delineating the business, personnel and financial
                policies of the Organizing Committee, the CIO's objectives, priorities and
                approaches to organizing and negotiating are apparent in correspondence, printed
                matter and publicity materials. National, state and local political issues,
                jurisdictional questions, including relations between the AFL and the CIO, improved
                labor and living conditions and relations with other departments of the CIO, as well
                as with a variety of social reform and friends of labor groups are documented. Legal
                materials include NLRB documents concerning unfair labor practices, elections, etc.
                Organizers reports and membership records are among the other types of materials
                found in the records.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>The "Operation Dixie" papers consist in large part of the records of the C.I.O.
                Organizing Committee campaigns in four southern states: North Carolina, South
                Carolina, Tennessee and Virginia. The papers are divided into eight series as
                follows: </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Series I: C.I.O. Organizing Committee. North Carolina, 1932-1958. </p>
            <p>Series II: C.I.O. Organizing Committee. South Carolina, 1941-1953. </p>
            <p>Series III: C.I.O. Organizing Committee. Tennessee, 1938-1953. </p>
            <p>Series IV: C.I.O. Organizing Committee. Virginia, 1937-1953. </p>
            <p>Series V: C.I.O. Organizing Committee. Lucy Randolph Mason, 1912-1954. </p>
            <p>Series VI: C.I.O. Political Action Committee. North Carolina, Tennessee and Virginia,
                1943-1954. </p>
            <p>Series VII: C.I.O. Publicity Department. North Carolina, 1946-1953. </p>
            <p>Series VIII: C.I.O. Industrial Union Councils. North Carolina, Tennessee and
                Virginia, 1938-1954. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Papers of the Organizing Committees, Publicity Department, Political Action
                Committees and Industrial Union Councils are arranged alphabetically by subject
                folder title. The reel list provides the title of each folder with inclusive dates
                for the contents. Many of the subject categories were established by the C.I.O.
                regional offices; others were added by the staff of the Manuscript Department of the
                William R. Perkins Library at Duke University in the process of integrating loose
                material. These records are frequently arranged under name of correspondent,
                organization or affiliate union. There are, however, some materials in each series
                that are collected under such general headings as "Correspondence", "Printed
                Material" and "Miscellaneous". Incoming and outgoing correspondence and related
                printed, typed and mimeographed items are interfiled in each folder in chronological
                order. The term printed material is loosely used in describing folder contents, and
                covers such varied items as collective bargaining agreements, petitions, membership
                records, flyers, research reports and newsletters produced and duplicated in a
                number of ways. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Oversize materials are arranged separately at the end of each series. Most of the
                subject headings appearing in the oversize section duplicate those used in the
                alphabetical reel list. Included among these materials are posters, flyers,
                newsletters, and a few items of correspondence that accompanied printed items or
                unfilmed clippings. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Lucy Randolph Mason papers are arranged in seven categories, each of which is
                organized chronologically. These categories are correspondence, addresses, minutes,
                memoranda, miscellany, printed materials and volumes. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The numbers in parentheses following names and folder titles in the series
                descriptions refer to the frame numbers of the microfilm edition and to the location
                of the material in the reel list. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>A complete description of the collection is available in a printed guide edited by
                Katherien F. Martin.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Martin, Katherine F. </persname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Mason, Lucy Randolph, 1882-1959. </persname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">C.I.O. Organizing Committee </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">North Carolina State Industrial Union Council </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">North Carolina State Industrial Union Council.
                    Political Action Committee. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">North Carolina State Industrial Union Council.
                    Publicity Dept. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Tennessee State Industrial Union Council </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Virginia State Industrial Union Council </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Virginia State Industrial Union Council.
                    Political Action Committee. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Labor unions--Southern States--Political
                    activity. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. Iron and steel workers. Southern
                    States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. North Carolina. Organizing. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. Oil industry workers. Southern
                    States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. South Carolina. Organizing. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. Southern States. Organizing. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade- unions. Tennessee. Organizing. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. Textile workers. Southern States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. Virginia. Organizing. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Trade-unions. Wood-pulp industry. Southern
                    States. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>Operation Dixie: The CIO Organizing Committee Papers on Microfilm #5747 mf. Kheel
                    Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
                    Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            
            <p>Related Collections:
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05242.html"> 5242:
                    National Child Labor Committee Publications</extref>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05619-008.html">
                    5619/008: ACWA Rieve-Pollock Foundation Files</extref>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="combined">
            
            <c01 level="series">
                <did>
                    <unittitle>The container list for this collecion can be found in the ProQuest Research Collection finding aid and is available <extref href="https://media2.proquest.com/documents/dixie.pdf">HERE.</extref></unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>