<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05315::NWLB Arbitration regarding Electrical Transcription Manufacturers and American Federation of Musicians.)//EN">KCL05315</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the NWLB Arbitration regarding Electrical Transcription
                    Manufacturers and American Federation of Musicians<date>
                    1942-1944</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">NWLB Arbitration regarding Electrical Transcription
                    Manufacturers and American Federation of Musicians</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 11, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 11,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the NWLB Arbitration regarding Electrical Transcription
                Manufacturers and American Federation of Musicians<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5315</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, July 08, 2014</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">NWLB Arbitration regarding
                Electrical Transcription Manufacturers and American Federation of Musicians,
                    <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1942-1944</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5315</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">U.S. National War Labor Board
                    (NWLB)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">2 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Records (documents).</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Arbitration files in the case of the American Federation of
                Musicians and Electrical Transcription Manufacturers.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
            <p>The American Federation of Musicians, AF of L, unilaterally decided the minimum terms
                and conditions of employment. They never negotiated a contract with a broadcasting,
                electrical transcription or recording company. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Union believed that mechanized music was displacing live musicians so they
                entered into conferences in 1937 with the broadcasting, recording and transcription
                companies concerning this matter. The conferences resulted in the broadcasting
                industry accepting the so-called quota agreement, under which the independent
                stations and stations affiliated with networks agreed to spend more money on staff
                musicians. The term of this agreement was set at two years, but in 1938 the
                Department of Justice advised the parties that the agreement was illegal. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In 1938, the Union adopted a policy of "licensing" recording and transcription
                companies. The license allowed union musicians to work </p>
            <p>for these companies on the condition that the companies limit the use of their
                products to non-commercial purposes. At no time-did the license contain any of the
                terms and conditions being fixed unilaterally by the union and all licenses being
                terminable at its will. The courts in RCA Mfg. Company vs Whiteman case held that
                the limitation on the use of phonograph records which the parties had agreed to
                could not be enforced. Therefore, the purpose of the license arrangement was largely
                defeated, but they continued to renew the license until 1942. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Musicians Union in 1942 decided that the only way to alleviate the unemployment
                of musicians caused by recorded music was to refuse to work for recording and
                transcription companies. The union made no demands on the employers, but on August
                1, 1942, all union members stopped making records and transcriptions. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Early in August 1942, the Department of Justice charged the union with violation of
                the anti-trust laws. The complaint was dismissed in </p>
            <p>the lower courts on the ground that the controversy was a labor dispute and the union
                was, therefore, immune from such prosecution. The Supreme Court affirmed this
                decision. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The next development was a hearing before a subcommittee of the Senate Committee on
                Interstate Commerce, pursuant to Senate Resolution 276, 77th Congress, second
                session, regarding the use of mechanical reproduction of music. The hearings were
                held on a number of days in September and then discontinued until February 1943. The
                February hearings disclosed for the first time the unions demands. The principle
                demand involved payment to the unions of an agreed sum on each recording made, and
                the fund thus created was to be used in various ways for the alleviation of
                unemployment. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The employers upon hearing the union demands rejected them and took steps to bring
                the controversy before the National War Labor Board on the grounds that the
                cessation of work constitutes a work stoppage seriously interfering with the war
                effort and they asked the Board to terminate the strike. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The War Labor Board refused to terminate the strike and set up a National War Labor
                Board Panel to conduct hearings. The Panel was composed of: Arthur S. Meyer,
                Chairman and Public Member; Max Zavitsky, Labor Member; Gilbert E. Fuller, Industry
                Member. The Panel started the hearings on September 7, 1943 and on September 9
                decided to adjourn until September 20, so as the Musician Union and World
                Broadcasting System could put their verbal contract agreement into written form. The
                hearing was reconvened on September 21 and then adjourned until September 27. On
                September 29 World Broadcasting System and Musicians Union signed an agreement. The
                Panel at this time adjourned until October 20, 1943 at the request of ths parties so
                that they could negotiate privately. The Panel on various occasions at the request
                of the parties acted as mediator. When the hearings were resumed on October 20,
                1943, six of the seven original companies had signed agreements with the union. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The remaining company, National Broadcasting Co., was joined at this time by two
                additional companies, RCA-Victor Division and Columbia Recording Corporation, to the
                proceeding. The Panel finished its hearings on November 22, 1943 and submitted its
                report and recommendations to the National War Labor Board on March 9, 1944. The
                National War Labor Board on June 15, 1944 issued its decision on this case. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The unions position in the hearings was that: the Board did not have jurisdiction
                because there was no strike, no substantial interference </p>
            <p>with the war effort, no labor dispute, and the members of the union are not the
                employees of the phonograph and transcription companies, but of the band leaders,
                contractors and symphony associations, none of whom are parties to this proceeding;
                the union demanded that the company pay money into the union's unemployment fund and
                that the union receive financial rrenumeration for phonograph records made for home
                consumption and used commercially. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The companies position in the hearing was that: how do you measure unemployment of
                musicians and to what extent is the nemployment of musicians due to records and
                transcriptions which fellow union members helped create; the use of an unemployment
                fund would aggravate rather than relieve unemployment due to the fact that the
                Musician Union is an open union; the com panies maintained that the unemployment
                fund is really a wage increase and is contrary to the Wage Stabilization Program;
                the adoption of the Union's demands would result in the creation of a private system
                of un employment relief and a undermining of our National Social Security System; </p>
            <p>the companies proposed that the Union and the companies unite in pressing for
                copyright legislation so as to prevent records designed for home use from being used
                commercially without remuneration. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The Panel besides having to evaluate the demands of both sides had to consider if the
                Unions demand for an unemployment fund was a "customary" demand or a usual and novel
                demand which the union was able to impose due to wartime conditions. The N.W.L.B.
                cannot impose on companies unusual and novel union demands which arise due to
                wartime conditions.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
            <p>Arbitration files in the case of the American Federation of Musicians and Electrical
                Transcription Manufacturers. </p>
            <p>Also included are files pertaining to the World Broadcasting System, Empire
                Broadcasting Corporation, Associated Music Publishers, Inc, Lan-Worth Feature
                Program, Inc., C.P. MacGregor, Standard Radio, Radio Recording Division, National
                Broadcasting Company, RCA-Victor Division, Radio Corporation of America, and
                Columbia Recording Corporation.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. National Labor Relations Board
                    (1942-1945) </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">American Federation of Musicians. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Electrical Transcription Manufacturers. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">World Broadcasting System. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Empire Broadcasting Corporation. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Associated Music Publishers. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Lang-Worth Feature Program, Inc. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">C. P. MacGregor Collection (Library of Congress) </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Standard Radio Transcription Services. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Radio Recording Division. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Broadcasting Company, inc. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">RCA-Victor Company, inc. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Columbia Recording Corporation. </corpname>
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Meyer, Arthur S. (Arthur Simon), 1880-1955. </persname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects: </head>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Arbitration, Industrial -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Collective bargaining -- Telecommunication --
                    United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Telecommunication -- Employees -- Labor unions --
                    United States. </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>NWLB Arbitration regarding Electrical Transcription Manufacturers and American
                    Federation of Musicians #5315. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation
                    and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Court Exhibits and Documents</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Court Exhibits and Documents</unittitle>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">Court Exhibits and Documents</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">General Union Documents</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942/1944">1942-1944</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Electrical Transcription Manufacturers v. American
                        Federation of Musicians, Memos</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link13">Newsletters</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1942/1943">1942-1943</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 1664-1900</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link15">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 1561-1603</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link16">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 1346-1560</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link17">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 1138-1345</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link18">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>916-1137</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link19">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 820-915</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link20">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 617-819</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link21">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 468-600</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">9</container>
                    <unittitle id="link22">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 449-467</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">10</container>
                    <unittitle id="link23">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>438-448</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link24">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 420-434</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">12</container>
                    <unittitle id="link25">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp.253-418</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">13</container>
                    <unittitle id="link26">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>149-252</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">14</container>
                    <unittitle id="link27">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>pp. 1-148</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">15</container>
                    <unittitle id="link28">Electrical Transmission Mfgers. v. American Federation of
                        Musicians, AFL</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">16</container>
                    <unittitle id="link29">Misc. Exhibits</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>