<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05102::Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records.)//EN">KCL05102</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records<date>
                    1960</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 07, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 07,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the
                Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5102</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, November 11, 2013</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 07, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Emergency Board No. 129, Long
                Island Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090,
                Records, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1960</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5102</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">Emergency Board No.
                    129</corpname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Long Island Railroad</corpname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Brotherhood of Railroad
                    Trainmen. Local 517</corpname>;<lb/>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator"> Brotherhood of Railroad
                    Trainmen. Local 1090</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Maps, reports (documents), transcripts .</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Documents include reports, recommendations and proposals of
                the Emergency Board and of the New York State Board of Inquiry; proposals of the
                carrier, union and National Mediation Board; carrier and union exhibits, statements
                and agreements.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.5 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <p>On April 19, 1960, the President of the U. S., acting under the authority given to
                him by the Railway Labor Act, created an Emergency Board to investigate and report
                on the dispute between the Long Island Rail Road and the Brotherhood of Railroad
                Trainmen Locals 517 and 1090. The members of the Board were Curtis G. Shake,
                Chairman, Lloyd H. Bailer, and Edward A. Lynch. </p>
            <p>The union's demands on the Long Island Rail Road which brought about the dispute
                were: </p>
            <p>1. Reduction of the six-day week to five days for passenger service trainmen, without
                a reduction in pay. </p>
            <p>2. Reduction of the work week for all men in local freight service to five days a
                week without loss of pay. The company contended that conductors and brakemen were
                required seven days a week. </p>
            <p>3. Payment of switchtenders at the higher brakemen's rate. </p>
            <p>4. Payment of the 95 cent daily allowance to yard trainmen not required to handle air
                hose for handling air hose. </p>
            <p>On May 18, 1960, the Emergency Board found that rates being paid to Long Island
                trainmen were higher than the standard rates on other Class I carriers. Average
                annual earnings for Long Island trainmen were $7,965 in 1959 compared with $7,263 on
                all other Class I carriers. </p>
            <p>The Railroad Trainmen then served an official notice on the Long Island Rail Road
                that they would go on strike at 12:01 A.M., Sunday, June 19. </p>
            <p>Two days before the strike was scheduled to begin, W. P. Kennedy, International
                President of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen, ordered locals 517 and 1090 to
                postpone the strike on an appeal by the National Mediation Board for a resumption of
                conferences "in the public interest." </p>
            <p>Efforts of the National Mediation Board to avert the strike collapsed one week later,
                which released the trainmen from their no strike pledge and a strike was tentatively
                set for Sunday, July 10 at 12:01 am. After authorization received from International
                President Kennedy, July 10 was confirmed as the strike date. </p>
            <p>On July 6, Governor Rockefeller took personal charge of efforts to prevent a strike
                on the Long Island Rail Road. He sent telegrams to company and union executives
                asking them to meet with George Moskowitz, Chairman of the State Mediation Board.
                Governor Rockefeller stepped in only after the union had rejected a plea by city,
                state and county officials for a two week postponement of the strike. </p>
            <p>The Governor was able to persuade the railroad to accept a five day work week, but
                only with the stipulation that the union agree to moves which would help keep the
                costs at a minimum. The union refused to accept any economy moves and the conference
                ended without success. </p>
            <p>The strike began, as scheduled, on Sunday morning, July 10. The State Public Service
                Commission immediately authorized all bus companies in Nassau and Suffolk counties
                and in Manhattan, Brooklyn and Queens to provide all possible transportation to the
                strike affected area. The Transport Workers Union supported the trainmen, refusing
                to work overtime and by not working on extra buses or subway trains in Queens or
                Long Island. </p>
            <p>Industrial Commissioner Martin P. Catherwood then appointed a State Board of Inquiry
                consisting of the Very Rev. Philip E. Dobson of Fordham University, Peter J.
                Keulemans of General Bronze Co., and Dean John W. McConnell of Industrial and Labor
                Relations School at Cornell University. The board was directed to study all factors
                necessary to guarantee safe and efficient commuter service "with benefit to the
                economy of the area and at prices the commuting public can afford," and to make
                recommendations to help end the strike. </p>
            <p>The Board of Inquiry proposed an arbitration plan on July 14 which called for a five
                day week with no cut in pay for the trainmen. Also included was a provision which
                would leave to final and binding arbitration the issue of how the shorter work week
                would be paid for. The union refused to accept binding arbitration. </p>
            <p>On July 20 the National Mediation Board proposed a plan whereby the BRT would agree
                to a 2 1/2 cent-an-hour wage cut to help pay for the increased cost of a five day
                week. This proposal was accepted by the union but the railroad rejected it saying
                that the increased costs would still necessitate higher fares for passengers. The
                company again suggested binding arbitration on the method of financing the shorter
                work week, but the union still refused. </p>
            <p>On August 3, 1960, Governor Rockefeller called the disputing parties together for a
                conference which lasted eleven and one-half hours before an agreement was reached.
                The three year agreement guaranteed a five day week. The cost of the shortened work
                week was set at $357,592, of which the company agreed to pay $162,041. The trainmen
                absorbed the remainder of the cost by agreeing to a 2 1/2 cent-an-hour wage cut and
                changes in work rules enabling more complete utilization of the existing work force.
                The union withdrew its demand for a five day week in freight service in return for a
                total of $53,040 in added compensation. The union won agreement to its other two
                demands. Yard service men will receive 95 cents per day for coupling air hose and
                switchtenders will receive extra pay when performing brakemen's duties.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <p>Emergency Board documents include carrier exhibits concerning the demands of the
                parties and the applicable rules of the existing agreement; and statements by
                officers of the Long Island Railroad. Union exhibits include local agreements
                (1953-1957) between the Long Island Railroad Company and road and yard conductors,
                ticket collectors, road and yard brakemen and switchtenders; and related Trainmen's
                publications. </p>
            <p>Additional materials include transcripts of hearings (8 vol.); report to the
                president; order establishing the New York State Board of Inquiry; interim report
                (with draft) and recommendations of the Board of Inquiry; mediation agreements
                (1957, 1960) between railroads represented by the Eastern, Western, and Southeastern
                Carriers' Conference Committees and the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen; also
                proposals of the union, carriers, and the National Mediation Board.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Eastern Carriers' Conference Committee </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Long Island Railroad Company </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Southeastern Carriers' Conference Committee </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. Emergency Board No. 129. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. National Mediation Board. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Western Carriers' Conference Committee </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Mediation and conciliation, Industrial--New York
                    (State)--Cases. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Mediation and conciliation, Industrial--United
                    States--Cases. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Railroad employees. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Railroad trainmen. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Collective labor agreements. Railroads. New York
                    (State) </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Hours of labor. Mediation and conciliation,
                    Industrial. United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Management rights. Mediation and conciliation,
                    Industrial. United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Mediation and conciliation, Industrial.
                    Railroads. United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Railroads. New York (State). State supervision. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Wages. Mediation and conciliation, Industrial.
                    United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Wages. Railroads. New York (State) </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 690">Work rules. Mediation and conciliation,
                    Industrial. United States.</subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <accessrestrict>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <p>Emergency Board No. 129, Long Island Railroad and the Brotherhood of Railroad
                    Trainmen, Locals 517 and 1090, Records #5102. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05021.html"> 5021:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05149.html"> 5149:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05149mb.html"> 5149 MB:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Memorabilia</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05149p.html"> 5149 P:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photographs</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05348.html"> 5348: W.P.
                    Kennedy as President of the Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen against the Long
                    Island Railroad Company Court Documents</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05446.html"> 5446:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Ledger</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05612.html"> 5612:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Moosic Tunnel Lodge no.93 Meeting
                    Minutes</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05623.html"> 5623:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Legislative Board of New York Files</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05631.html"> 5631:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Chicago, Milwaukee, St. Paul and Pacific
                    Railroad General Committee File</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05647.html"> 5647:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Joppa Lodge (Toledo, OH) Minute Books</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05894.html"> 5894:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Additional Railroad Booklets</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06268p.html"> 6268 P:
                    Joint Committee of Adjustment for the Rock Island System's Order of Railway
                    Conductors and Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Photograph</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06312p.html"> 6312 P:
                    Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen
                    Photographs</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06312pubs.html"> 6312
                    PUBS: Judith Sullivan Kowalczyk Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen
                    Publications</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06312m.html"> 6312m:
                    Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Annual Report of the Legislative Board</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL06405pubs.html"> 6405
                    PUBS: William Sharp Collection of The Railroad Trainmen's Journal</extref><lb/>
                6480 MB: Paul Berger Collection of Brotherhood of Railroad Trainmen Memorabilia<lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Reports and exhibits [folder 1 of 2]</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Reports and exhibits [folder 2 of 2]</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">John W. McConnell's notes</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1960">1960</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>