<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
	<eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
		<eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05269::United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen Records.)//EN">KCL05269</eadid>
		<filedesc>
			<titlestmt>
				<titleproper>Guide to the United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen
						Records<date> 1933-1958</date></titleproper>
				<titleproper type="sort">United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen
					Records</titleproper>
				<author>Compiled by Elizabeth Parker</author>
			</titlestmt>
			<publicationstmt>
				<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
					University Library</publisher>
				<date>December 05, 2017</date>
			</publicationstmt>
			<notestmt>
				<note audience="internal">
					<p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
				</note>
			</notestmt>
		</filedesc>
		<profiledesc>
			<creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Elizabeth Parker, <date>December
					05, 2017</date></creation>
		</profiledesc>
	</eadheader>
	<frontmatter>
		<titlepage>
			<titleproper>Guide to the United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen
				Records<lb/></titleproper>
			<num>Collection Number: 5269</num>
			<publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library </publisher>
			<list type="deflist">
				<defitem>
					<label>Contact Information:</label>
					<item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
						P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
						Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183&gt; <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
						<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
					</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>Compiled by:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, July 15, 2014</item>
				</defitem>
				<defitem>
					<label>EAD encoding:</label>
					<item>Kheel Staff, December 05, 2017</item>
				</defitem>
			</list>
			<date>© 2017 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
				University Library </date>
			<sponsor>This collection was processed with the help of generous funding from the National Historical Publications and Records Commission (NHPRC).</sponsor>
		</titlepage>
	</frontmatter>
	<archdesc level="collection">
		<did>
			<head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
			<unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">United National Association of
				Post Office Craftsmen Records, <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1933-1958</unitdate>
			</unittitle>
			<unitid label="Collection Number:">5269</unitid>
			<origination label="Creator:">
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">United National Association of
					Post Office Craftsmen</corpname>
			</origination>
			<physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">2 linear ft.</physdesc>
			<physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Minutes (administrative records).</physdesc>
			<repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
				Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
			<abstract label="Abstract:">The collection chiefly consists of the minutes of the
				Executive Committee of the United National Association of Post Office Clerks (later
				the United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen) from 1941-1958. Also
				included are minutes of the National Legislative Council of Federal Employee
				Organizations, of which the United National Association of Post Office Clerks was a
				member.</abstract>
			<langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
			</langmaterial>
		<physdesc><extent>2 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
		<bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
			<head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
			<p>The National Association of Post Office Craftsmen was founded in 1882 when J. Holt
				Greene, a clerk in the Louisville, Kentucky, post office began corresponding with
				other post offices throughout the country in an effort to promote a national
				convention of postal clerks to be held in Washington. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Between 1882 and 1890, several local organizations of postal clerks were established
				and two conventions were called to establish contacts between the independent
				associations. In 1890, the New York organization issued a call to all first-class
				post offices to send delegates to a national convention. Delegates assembled in
				Washington and formed the National Association of Post Office Clerks [NAPOC].
				Eight-hour day, fifteen-day vacation, and salary classification bills were drawn and
				submitted to Congress. The vacation bill was passed that same year, but the hours
				and classification bills could not get out of committee. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>At the second convention of the NAPOC in 1891, a legislative committee was created to
				lobby on the organization's behalf. The legislative committee of NAPOC lobbied
				vigorously and persistently during 1892 and 1903, but with little success. Their
				efforts led to the Postmaster General to issue an order forbidding any "Postmaster,
				Post-office Clerk, Letter Carrier, Railway Postal Clerk, or other postal employee"
				from travelling to Washington to lobby Congress. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>During the convention of 1897, a factional dispute arose in the NAPOC that arose in
				part because of the NAPOC's failure to secure legislation and disagreement on how
				best to circumvent the Postmaster General's order. The granting of membership to
				supervisory employees was also an issue. Locals from Chicago, Philadelphia,
				Pittsburgh, and San Francisco withdrew from the National Association and together
				with a large group from New York formed the United Association of Post Office
				Clerks. In 1899 the two groups merged back into one organization, now called the
				United National Association of Post Office Clerks [UNAPOC]. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In 1900, a group of Chicago postal workers organized and affiliated themselves with
				the AFL; because of this affiliation, the Chicago local was denied entrance to
				UNAPOC. UNAPOC refused to affiliate with the larger labor movement both because of
				their status as federal employees and because they preferred to work "in such a way
				as to conciliate and never embarrass the [Postal] Department." However, this became
				problematic when President Theodore Roosevelt issued an executive order forbidding
				federal employees to lobby for pay raises or benefits except through their
				departmental supervisors. This became known as the "gag order" and essentially
				stopped UNAPOC's lobbying efforts entirely. The "gag order" was strengthened by
				Roosevelt in 1906 and was later reinforced by President Taft. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>The 1905 convention was marked by factional strife and the delegates of thirty-five
				locals withdrew from the convention. It was felt that since UNAPOC was silenced in
				Congress, the clerks should find another way to represent their interests. In August
				1906, locals in San Francisco, Milwaukee, and Louisville, joined the independent
				Chicago group and formed the National Federation of Post Office Clerks [NFPOC]. They
				were granted a charter by the AFL. The "gag order" was repealed in 1912 under the
				Lloyd-LaFollette Act, leaving UNAPOC and NFPOC in competition and hostile towards
				each other. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In 1917, the Brotherhood of Railway Postal Clerks merged with the National Federation
				in the AFL and from this time on, the Federation claimed to be the leading clerks
				organization with UNAPOC dwindling slowly over the years. The National Association
				of Letter Carriers and the Railway Mail Association also affiliated with the AFL in
				1917. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>During the 1920s, the AFL postal groups actively opposed the Postal Department while
				advocating for their members; UNAPOC assumed a conciliatory attitude. The Harding
				Administration had placed itself on record as opposing AFL affiliation for
				government employees and UNAPOC adopted policies calculated to win Departmental
				favor. For many years UNAPOC considered itself a "professional organization" and not
				a "trade union." </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In 1931, UNAPOC and the NFPOC again met in merger discussions initiated by UNAPOC.
				The Association had for many years advocated one big union of all postal employee as
				a matter of principle, but these discussions fell apart because of the Association's
				insistence that a merged organization would have to abandon the AFL. However, the
				1930s and 1940s were marked by a decline in membership even as UNAPOC continued to
				lobby on behalf of its members and to provide them with benefits. It also lost lost
				its enmity toward the labor movement and took its place as a genuine independent
				union. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In 1948, UNAPOC again called for a single union for all postal employees and opened
				its membership to other postal employees. In 1956, the name of the organization was
				changed to the United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen to more
				accurately describe its scope and ambition. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>In 1961, UNAPOC and the NFPOC merged to close the split of over fifty years in the
				ranks of the post office clerks. They were joined by the United Postal Workers and
				the National Postal Transport Association and together they formed the United
				Federation of Post Office Clerks, AFL-CIO.</p>
		</bioghist>
		<scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
			<head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
			<p>Inclusive date range: 1933-1958 </p>
			<p>Bulk dates: 1941-1958 </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>The collection is mostly comprised of the minutes of the Executive Committee of the
				United National Association of Post Office Clerks, held annually during their
				conventions. All years except for 1942 and 1957 are in this collection. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>The minutes contain discussions on pay restoration; retirement; hours of work; the
				promotional system; the merit system and actions to eradicate it; the O'Mahoney-La
				Follette Bill, providing for retirement with right of appeal by employees; the civil
				service system; group insurance and hospitalization plans; if and how to merge or
				amalgamate with the AFL affiliated union of postal clerks; bonding and retirement
				legislation; and changing the name of the organization to United National
				Association of Post Office Craftsmen. Additionally, remarks that were expunged from
				the minutes of the 1941 convention are found in this collection. </p>
			<p> </p>
			<p>Also found in this collection is a bound volume containing the By-Laws of the
				National Legislative Council of Federal Employee Organizations; correspondence of
				John J. Barrett, president, United National Association of Post Office Clerks, with
				officers of the National Association of Postal Supervisors, National Association of
				Letter Carriers of the United States of America, Railway Mail Association, and
				National Association of Post Office Laborers, regarding the creation of a national
				advisory council; press releases from the National Legislative Council of Federal
				Employee Organizations; and an outline of purposes and goals of the Legislative
				Committee by W.G. Armstrong, secretary, National Legislative Council of Federal
				Employee Organizations.</p>
		</scopecontent>
		<controlaccess>
			<head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Names: </head>
				<persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Barrett, John J. 1945. </persname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Association of Letter Carriers of the
					United States of America </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Association of Postal Supervisors </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Association of Post Office Laborers </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Legislative Council of Federal Employee
					Organizations </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">National Rural Letter Carriers' Association </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">Railway Mail Association </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United National Association of Post Office
					Craftsmen </corpname>
				<corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610">United States Postal Service. </corpname>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				<head>Subjects: </head>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil service--United States--Political activity. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil service reform--United States. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil service retirement--United States. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Hours of labor. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Postal service--Employees. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Postal service -- Employees -- Labor unions --
					United States. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Wages -- Civil service -- United States </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Postal service -- Employees -- Salaries, etc. </subject>
				<subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Civil service retirement -- United States. </subject>
			</controlaccess>
			<controlaccess>
				</controlaccess>
		</controlaccess>
		<descgrp>
			<head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
			<accessrestrict>
				<head>Access Restrictions:</head>
				<p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
					reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
			</accessrestrict>
			<userestrict>
				<head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
				<p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
					and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
			</userestrict>
			<prefercite>
				<head>Cite As:</head>
				<p>United National Association of Post Office Craftsmen Records #5269. Kheel Center
					for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
			</prefercite>
		</descgrp>
		<dsc type="in-depth">
			<head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link8">Executive Committee 1942</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1942">1942</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link9">Executive Committee Closed Meeting - 1943</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle id="link10">Executive Committee Open Sessions - 1943</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1943">1943</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle id="link11">Executive Committee Closed Sessions - 1944</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle id="link12">Executive Committee Open Session - 1944</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1944">1944</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unittitle id="link13">Executive Committee - 1945</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1945">1945</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unittitle id="link14">Executive Committee - 1946</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1946">1946</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle id="link15">Executive Committee - 1947</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1947">1947</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unittitle id="link16">Executive Committee Vol. 1 - 1948</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle id="link17">Executive Committee Vol 2 - 1948</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">11</container>
					<unittitle id="link18">Executive Committee Vol. 3 - 1948</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1948">1948</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">12</container>
					<unittitle id="link19">Executive Board - 1949</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1949">1949</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">1</container>
					<container type="folder">13</container>
					<unittitle id="link20">Executive Committee - 1950</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1950">1950</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">1</container>
					<unittitle id="link21">Executive Committee - 1951</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1951">1951</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">2</container>
					<unittitle id="link22">Executive Committee - 1952</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1952">1952</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">3</container>
					<unittitle id="link23">Executive Board - 1953</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1953">1953</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">4</container>
					<unittitle id="link24">Executive Committee - 1954</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1954">1954</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">5</container>
					<unittitle id="link25">Executive Board - 1955</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1955">1955</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">6</container>
					<unittitle id="link26">Executive Board - 1956</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1956">1956</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">7</container>
					<unittitle id="link27">Executive Board - 1958</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">8</container>
					<unittitle id="link28">Executive Board (Copy 2)</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1958">1958</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">9</container>
					<unittitle id="link29">National Legislative Council Meeting</unittitle>
					<unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1933/1943">1933-1943</unitdate>
				</did>
				<scopecontent>
					<p>Contains By-Laws and amended drafts of By-Laws, 1933; correspondence with
						other labor organizations and elected officials, 1933-1943; press releases,
						1933-1943; minutes of council meetings, 1934-1943.</p>
				</scopecontent>
			</c01>
			<c01 level="file">
				<did>
					<container type="box">2</container>
					<container type="folder">10</container>
					<unittitle id="link30">37th Biennial Convention Expunged Record,
						1941</unittitle>
					<unitdate normal="1941">1941</unitdate>
				</did>
			</c01>
		</dsc>
	</archdesc>
</ead>