<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05471mf::Max S. Hayes Papers on Microfilm.)//EN">KCL05471mf</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Max S. Hayes Papers on Microfilm<date>
                    1816-1949</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Hayes, Max S. Papers on Microfilm</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>March 13, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>March 13,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Max S. Hayes Papers on Microfilm</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5471 mf</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University
                        Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, May 20, 2014</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, March 13, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Max S. Hayes Papers on Microfilm
                    1816-1949
            </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1816-1949</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5471 mf</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Hayes, Max S.</persname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">2 microfilm reels</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Papers (documents), microfilm.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor- Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">These papers consist primarily of correspondence. Also
                included are newspaper clippings, an autograph book, and a typed copy of tributes to
                Hayes.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.22 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>Maximilian Sebastian-Hayes (May 25, 1866 -October 11, 1945) was born in a cabin at
                Havana, Huron County, Ohio. Hayes obtained his limited formal education in the rural
                schools of Huron County (1871-1881). </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>While still in his teens, Hayes moved to Cleveland. There he worked on the Cleveland
                Press (1881-1890). At this time the young Hayes also obtained an apprenticeship with
                Typographical Union 53. He took an active part in the union and at one time or other
                held most of the offices both in the local union and in the Central Labor Union.
                Hayes also served as a delegate from Cleveland to AFL conventions. In 1903 the AFL
                elected Hayes as a delegate to the British Trade Union Congress in London, England,
                where his speech gained international attention. Eight years later (1911) Hayes ran
                for president of the AFL against Samuel Gompers. Although Gompers won, Hayes
                received one third of the votes. </p>
            <p>His interest in the organized labor movement led him to establish a newspaper to
                promote its cause. Thus, on January 31, 1891, Hayes became the founder-editor of the
                Cleveland Citizen the earliest extant local weekly newspaper in the United States to
                be dedicated to the movement. When he first started out, Hayes had a small, shabby
                office and thirty dollars in capital. Within four years, however, the Citizen had
                gained such wide recognition as a voice for the working classes that the American
                Federation of Labor felt compelled to establish The American Federationist or else
                acknowledge the Citizen as the official labor newspaper in the United States. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p> A Populist newspaper until 1896, in that year it became the trade union organ of the
                Cleveland Federation of Labor, the local council of the American Federation of
                Labor. Hayes was its editor for almost fifty years, until incapacitated by illness
                in 1939. Under his editorship the Citizen dealt with the primary issues of labor
                including better working conditions, higher wages, and shorter hours. Hayes,
                himself, took the time to appear before legislative committees at Columbus to voice
                his support of legislation to improve the lot of the working man. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Active in the Socialist movement too, Hayes belonged to the Populist Party
                (1890-1896) and the Socialist Labor Party (1897-1900) before joining the Socialist
                Party in 1900. He was a Socialist Party candidate for Congress in 1900 and for
                Secretary of State of Ohio in 1902. The Socialist Labor Party nominated him for Vice
                President of the United States at its National Convention at Rochester, New York
                (February 2, 1900). Hayes, however, resigned from the ticket a couple of months
                later when the Socialist Labor Party joined with the Social Democratic Party to form
                the Socialist Party. Subsequently chairman of the Executive committee of the
                National Labor Party (1919) his final campaign was in 1920 when he ran for the Vice
                President of the United States on the Farmer-Labor ticket. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In Cleveland Hayes was a leader in Community affairs. In 1904, for example, Hayes and
                a group of Cleveland doctors and citizens formed the Anti-tuberculosis League in
                which he played an active part. In Ohio he was labor's representative on the
                Consumer's League of Ohio beginning in 1900. He served on the Metropolitan Housing
                Authority, 1933-1937. In 1934 he was appointed to the State Adjustment Board (NRA). </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Hayes married Dora Schneider December 11, 1900. They had one child, a daughter,
                Maxine Elizabeth, who married A.I. Davey Jr. in 1931. Davey became editor of the
                Citizen when Max Hayes retired.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>The papers of Max S. Hayes consist primarily of correspondence. Also included are
                newspaper clippings, an autograph book, and a typed copy of tributes to Hayes. They
                span the period 1891-1949 with the bulk period covering 1900-1928. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Boxes 1-5 (1891-1949) consist mainly of correspondence. Many of the letters are from
                Hayes to his wife, Dora, and a few to their daughter Maxine. Also found here are
                letters to Hayes from numerous friends and associatesA.M. Simons (editor, The
                International Socialist Review) Henry L. Slobodin (of the Socialist Labor Party),
                and others. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Box 6 contains newspaper clippings relating to Hayes, a few printed items, and an
                autograph book. Also included here is a copy (tvpewritten/52 pages) of tributes paid
                to Hayes at the Fiftieth Anniversary Dinner honoring his founding of the Cleveland
                Citizen-Cleveland, Ohio, February 1, 1941. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>The papers relate both to his personal life and to his work. Although many of Hayes'
                letters are to his wife, Dora, they offer not only a glimpse into his private life,
                but also into his life-long work in the local and national AFL and in the Socialist
                movement. For he frequently wrote to his wifewhen away from homeabout his opinions
                of particular speaking tours, his activities at conventions, </p>
            <p>or his current ideas and impressions. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Correspondence.with other persons also relates to his activities in the labor and
                socialist movements. Socialist sentiments, American Federation of Labor affairs, and
                interest in the National Labor Party all appear in the letters to Hayes. Also found
                here are letters that touch on Hayes' civic work. In addition, there are letters to
                Mrs. Hayes from family and friends, plus a few from her to her husband.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hayes, Max S., 1866-1945 </persname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>Max S. Hayes Papers on Microfilm #5471 mf. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Correspondence, 1891-1915 (Items 1-282)</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1891/1915" type="inclusive">1891-1915</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>positive</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="reel">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Correspondence, 1816-1949 (Items 283-519); Newspaper
                        clippings, printed items, and autograph book</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1816/1949" type="inclusive">1816-1949</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>positive</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>