<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8'?>
<ead>
 <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1" scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
  <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06036-006::Pins &amp; Needles, An Oral History by Harry M. Goldman..)//EN">KCL06036-006</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the Pins &amp; Needles, An Oral History by Harry M. Goldman.<date>
      1977-1977</date></titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">Pins &amp; Needles, An Oral History by Harry M. Goldman.</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
     Library</publisher>
    <date>January 11, 2013</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p>
      <subject>Labor</subject>
     </p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kathryn Dowgiewicz, <date>January 11,
     2013</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 </eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the Pins &amp; Needles, An Oral History by Harry M.
    Goldman.<lb/></titleproper>
   <num type="kidb_reference_number" id="kc482">Collection Number: 6036/006</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
    Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin P. Catherwood
      Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/> Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607)
      255-3183<lb/>
      <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
      <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, January 11, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 11, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2013 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
    Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
   <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">Pins &amp; Needles, An Oral History by
    Harry M. Goldman., <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1977-1977</unitdate>
   </unittitle>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">6036/006</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Goldman, Harry M.</persname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">0.5 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence,
    photographs.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
    Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">The collection contains both a bound and unbound version of Harry M.
    Goldman's dissertation "Pins and Needles: An Oral History."</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  </did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
   <p>Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the
    northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political
    influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century.
    Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and
    living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs,
    health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In
    1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form
    the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <head id="a4" altrender="biography">BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE </head>
   <p>Harry Goldman taught drama at the New York School of Art and Design and was an assistant
    professor at the Developmental Research School at Florida State University.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
   <p>"Sing me a song with social significance"began the musical comedy revue "Pins and Needles."
    Produced by the Educational Department of the International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union
    (ILGWU), the show with an amateur cast of garment workers won critics and audiences to become
    the longest running musical of the 1930s. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>The Educational Department began to expand beyond its original function of educating workers
    in labor culture, and soon started to offer recreational outlets for members including art,
    music and dance. In 1934, the department was reorganized under new director Mark Starr to create
    three divisions, Cultural, Recreational and Education, managed by Julius Hochman, Louis
    Schaffer, and Starr respectively. The Cultural Division offered classes in drama, acting, dance
    and music, and also organized a chorus and orchestra composed of union members. For years
    members had been trying to develop and present labor themed plays, and while many locals were
    successful in staging small productions, the drama department became formally established in the
    fall of 1934. With Schaffer joining the staff of the ILGWU in October 1934, a dramatic group,
    the ILGWU Players, was formed from members of several locals. Professionals were recruited to
    instruct the classes, and Schaffer envisioned broadening the scope of the department to create a
    venture that brought the labor movement to Broadway. At the American Federation of Labor (AFL)
    Convention in 1935, Schaffer, with the encouragement of ILGWU President David Dubinsky,
    introduced the idea of establishing founding a theater company for New York City's labor
    movement. With enthusiastic support, Labor Stage, Inc. a non-profit with revenue supporting the
    Educational Department, was established in 1935 with financial backing from the ILGWU. The union
    leased the Princess Theatre and began renovating the space to become Labor Stage, housing an
    intimate auditorium, studio and rehearsal space and dressing rooms, with a dedication in January
    1936. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Schaffer soon set to work to make his vision, "Pins and Needles," a realitya revue style
    production that slyly satirized politics and the elite while skewering current events staged for
    working men and women. Harold Rome was brought in to write the music and lyrics, numerous
    writers contributed sketches, and Charles Friedman was hired to direct (though he would later be
    replaced by Robert Gordon). Union members and others active in the Educational Department were
    encouraged to audition, and a cast of fifty five garment workers were selected and began
    extensive rehearsals. The performers were not professionals, and in addition to learning their
    lines and songs, were also instructed in the fundamentals of acting and basic stage movement. In
    June of 1936, Schaffer staged an early version of "Pins and Needles" using a professional cast
    to demonstrate the numbers, and though well received, Schaffer chose the unorthodox decision to
    proceed with the cast of untrained garment workers. The official opening was delayed for almost
    a year and a half to make sure the performers, who were still working in the factories during
    the day, had sufficient time to practice and rehearse. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>On July 4, 1937, the cast traveled to Unity House, the union's vacation resort in the Poconos,
    for additional rehearsals that lasted ten days and concluded with a close to completion trial
    performance of the show. After numerous adjustments and fine tuning, "Pins and Needles" held its
    first invitation only performance at Labor Stage on November 6, 1937. After additional
    postponements, finally, on Saturday, November 27, 1937, "Pins and Needles" opened to the public.
    The critics were favorable and with good reviews and word of mouth, the show became an instant
    hit. The box office was busy and tickets in high demand, and by January 1938, performances were
    sold out. Since the performers were still working full time in the garment factories, initially
    the show only played on the weekends. The garment workers were given leaves of absence from
    their factory jobs to become full-time actors with pay to accommodate the increased show
    schedule which now included nightly performances. When the primary target audience, union
    members, found it difficult to obtain tickets to see the show, a second performing company was
    organized to provide daily late afternoon matinees for the workers. Close to fifty skits were
    created during the course of "Pins and Needles," of which nineteen to twenty-two were performed
    at each performance, including such favorites as "Sunday in the Park," "One Big Union for Two,"
    and "Lesson in Etiquette." Revisions were continually made throughout the three editions, with
    sketches and songs added and deleted as the show evolved to adjust and adapt and remain current
    and timely. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>While the show ignored references to racial issues on the stage, behind the scenes racial
    inequality abounded. Olive Pearman was the first African American cast in the show and initially
    only had a supporting role and worked as the seamstress on the road. Additional African American
    cast members were added later after pressure on Schaffer, including Dorothy Tucker and Dorothy
    Harrison, but no Hispanics appeared in the productions. Other cast members were pressured to
    suppress their Jewish ethnicities and forgo religious observances during performance schedules,
    some changing names and a few altering their appearances. On the road during the touring
    productions, the African American cast members were often forced to follow local segregation
    laws in the cities where they were performing and encountered prejudice in finding
    accommodations, eating with the cast in a restaurant, or in the extreme case, being unable to
    perform. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>To bring the show to audiences outside of New York City, a ten month national tour of "Pins
    and Needles" began in April 1938 visiting cities Philadelphia, Boston, Los Angeles, San
    Francisco, and Chicago, as well as smaller towns in between as the cast made their way across
    the United States. For many cast members, this was their first time traveling away from New York
    and their families, and especially traversing the country on train. Stays in the larger cities
    were often extended, and in many instances the cast was greeted by members from local unions.
    Multiple companies were formed to accommodate the expanding schedule between touring, evenings
    and matinees. The original company went on the national road tour, second and third companies
    formed to perform the evening shows and matinees for union members. As the cast multiplied, so
    did the number of "ringers," or semi-professionals. Schaffer started adding "ringers," talented
    ILGWU members, and individuals with aspirations to become professional actors to replace the
    initially amateur cast, which created tensions among the various companies. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>In March 1938 in the East Room of the White House, a smaller cast performed for President
    Franklin Roosevelt and Eleanor, whom had already seen the show several times. Afterward, the
    cast and crew performed another condensed version of "Pins and Needles" for the twenty-fifth
    anniversary of the U.S. Department of Labor. The first road show ended on January 30, 1939 after
    319 performances in 34 cities across the country. The original company that was still remaining
    headed back to New York to find the new casts filling all the roles and numerous new numbers
    added to show. Unfortunately, most of the original and road show cast were forced to return back
    to their jobs in the garment factories as many became phased out by semi-professional
    replacements. The second and revamped edition of "Pins and Needles" debuted on April 21, 1939
    and on June 26, 1939, the show moved to the larger Windsor Theatre. The new edition proved
    successful, and finally, a third edition of the show, "New Pins and Needles," opened on November
    20, 1939. After 1,108 performances, "Pins and Needles" closed in New York City on June 22, 1940.
    The second national tour began a month later and toured the country before playing its last show
    in Los Angeles on May 31, 1941. After the end of "Pins and Needles," Labor Stage did not put on
    another play and closed. The actors returned to the shops and factories, with only a few trying
    to turn their experience into a career in show business. "Pins and Needles" challenged the idea
    of labor sponsored entertainment to become a popular hit with memorable lyrics, hummable tunes,
    and a social message that appealed to a broad audience.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
   <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
   <p>The collection contains the dissertation entitled "Pins and Needles: An Oral History" written
    by Harry Merton Goldman in 1977 to complete his degree at New York University. The dissertation
    chronicles the musical "Pins and Needles" by providing a comprehensive account of the show from
    its inception through the final performance. A significant strength and component of the
    dissertation includes oral histories from the individuals who were involved with "Pins and
    Needles," including writers, directors, set designers and actors. The end of the dissertation
    provides an extensive bibliography of both published and unpublished material, the itinerary for
    the National Tour providing the dates, locations and theaters for each stop on the tour, and a
    listing of songs and sketches for all three editions of the show. Information discussed in the
    dissertation as stated in the table of contents include: origins, description of the show, the
    economic, political, social and theatrical influences, cast of characters, the history of Labor
    Stage, the show and performances, legal and managerial difficulties, the performance at the
    White House, the road shows, racial prejudice on the road, political and social significance of
    the musical, the time on Broadway, and "Pins and Needles" final conclusion.</p>
  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
   <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Names: </head>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Goldman, Harry </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Rome, Harold, -- 1908-1993. -- Pins and needles. </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Alfasa, Joe </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Appel, Lou </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Barry, Gene </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Bergersen, Baldwin </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Bregman, Elise </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Brown, Anne </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Cahn, Sylvia </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Castellano, Wally </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Charmat, Alma </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Corey, Irwin </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Diamond, Adele </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Eben, Al </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Edwards, Sherman </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Elbaum, Ruth </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Fox, Irene </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Friedman, Charles </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Gardner, Hy </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Gerber, Ella </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Goldstein, Eugene </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Gould, Berni </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Harary, Nettie </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Jaffee, Lynne </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Jerome, Adele </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Kaufman, Rose </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Klein, Manny </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Kushner, Ethel </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Levy, Al </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Mandel, Ida </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Mann, Danny </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Meyers, Don </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Morrison, Lee </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Newdell, Sam </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Newmark, Rose </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Nicita, Jean </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Pearman, Olive </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Pedi, Tom </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Rosenblum, Manny </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Rotsten, Herman </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Rubin, Hilda </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Rubinstein, Ruth </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Savage, Archie </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Scrank, Joseph </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Seymour, Paul </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Strasberg, Lee </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Syrjala, Sointu </persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Tucker, Dorothy </persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    <head>Subjects: </head>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Musical revues, comedies, etc. -- United States -- History
     and criticism. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Clothing workers -- United States -- Drama -- History and
     criticism. </subject>
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- Drama --
     History and criticism. </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
   <accessrestrict>
    <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference
     archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and
     Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    <head>Cite As:</head>
    <p>Pins &amp; Needles, An Oral History by Harry M. Goldman. #6036/006. Kheel Center for
     Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
   <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
    <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU
    records</extref><lb/> 6036/031: International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. Pins and Needles.
    Additional Scrapbooks, 1935-1942.<lb/> 6036/077: Rose Newmark Collection on the ILGWU Musical
    Pins and Needles<lb/> 6036/081 AV: Ruth Graeber interview on "Pins and Needles"<lb/>
   </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">Pins and Needles, pages 1-113</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1977">1977</unitdate>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">2</container>
     <unittitle id="link9">Pins and Needles, pages 114-262</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1977">1977</unitdate>
    </did>
   </c01>
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container type="box">1</container>
     <container type="folder">3</container>
     <unittitle id="link10">Pins and Needles, bound volume</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1977">1977</unitdate>
    </did>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>