<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
 <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
  <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06036-024::Springer Kemp, Maida. Oral History Interview..)//EN">KCL06036-024</eadid>
  <filedesc>
   <titlestmt>
    <titleproper>Guide to the Springer Kemp, Maida. Oral History Interview</titleproper>
    <titleproper type="sort">Springer Kemp, Maida. Oral History Interview.</titleproper>
    <author>Compiled by Kheel Staff</author>
   </titlestmt>
   <publicationstmt>
    <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
     Library</publisher>
    <date>January 10, 2013</date>
   </publicationstmt>
   <notestmt>
    <note audience="internal">
     <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
    </note>
   </notestmt>
  </filedesc>
  <profiledesc>
   <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kathryn Dowgiewicz, <date>January 10,
     2013</date></creation>
  </profiledesc>
 <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240223">02/23/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
 <frontmatter>
  <titlepage>
   <titleproper>Guide to the Springer Kemp, Maida. Oral History Interview.</titleproper>
   <num id="kc452" type="kidb_reference_number">Collection Number: 6036/024</num>
   <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
    Library </publisher>
   <list type="deflist">
    <defitem>
     <label>Contact Information:</label>
     <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood
      Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607)
      255-3183
      <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
<extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel</extref>
     </item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>Compiled by:</label>
     <item>Kheel Staff, January 10, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
    <defitem>
     <label>EAD encoding:</label>
     <item>Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013</item>
    </defitem>
   </list>
   <date>© 2013 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University
    Library </date>
  </titlepage>
 </frontmatter>
 <archdesc level="collection">
  <did>
   
   <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Springer Kemp, Maida. Oral History
    Interview., 
   </unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1978-1978</unitdate>
   <unitid label="Collection Number:">6036/024</unitid>
   <origination label="Creator:">
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Springer Kemp, Maida</persname>
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Balanoff, Elizabeth</persname>
   </origination>
   <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">0.333333333333333 linear ft.</physdesc>
   <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence,
    photographs.</physdesc>
   <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives,
    Cornell University Library </repository>
   <abstract label="Abstract:">This collection consists of a transcript of an interview with Maida
    Springer Kemp, conducted by Elizabeth Balanoff in 1977. The interview was part of The 20th
    Century Trade Union Woman: Vehicle for Social Change Oral History Project, in cooperation with
    The Black Woman Oral History Project, the Schlesinger Library, Radcliffe College.</abstract>
   <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
   </langmaterial>
  <physdesc><extent>0.33 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   
   <p>Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the
    northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political
    influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century.
    Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and
    living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs,
    health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In
    1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form
    the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).</p>
  </bioghist>
  <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
   
   <p>Maida Springer Kemp was born on May 12, 1910 in Panama and moved to New York City at the age
    of seven with her mother. After receiving an education in where she attended a black boarding
    school, Kemp became a licensed beautician, though never worked in that trade. Her earliest
    experience in the garment industry was when she worked as a pinker while in school. Because of
    the Depression, in 1932 as a young wife with a small child, Kemp became employed as a finisher
    doing hand sewing in a garment shop and joined the ILGWU. During the 1933 general strike, she
    was a member of a strike committee. She continued to work in the shop for the next eight years
    and became very active in the union. Kemp held various roles in Local 22 of the Dressmakers'
    Union, including executive board member, chairman of the education committee and shop
    representative. In 1942, Kemp became union staff and was appointed education director of Local
    132, the Plastic Button and Novelty Workers' Union (an accessory local of the ILGWU) focusing on
    educating the new membership that consisted of refugees, recently released prisoners, women and
    minorities. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Kemp became the first black business agent of ILGWU Local 22 in 1947 and held that position
    for thirteen years. As a business agent, she was often sent out as a representative or attended
    educational programs. Kemp developed international interests and studied and traveled to
    increase her knowledge of the world labor movement. She received an American Scandinavian
    Foundation scholarship to study workers' education in Sweden and Denmark and through an Urban
    League fellowship studied at Ruskin College at Oxford. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>During her tenure with the ILGWU, Kemp devoted time to other organizations as well. She often
    worked on projects for A. Philip Randolph, such as helping with a City Council campaign and
    putting on a rally in Madison Square Garden for the Fair Employment Practices Commission. Kemp
    became the first black woman to represent American labor abroad when the AFL sent her to England
    in 1945. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>In 1955, Kemp was sent as an AFL representative to an International Confederation of Free
    Trade Unions conference in Africa for a three week seminar. Inspired, Kemp soon became tireless
    in her work in Africa. She developed training programs for workers, secured funds for
    constructing trade union centers such as the Solidarity House in Nairobi, and educating the
    leadership of the African labor movement. Her extensive travel to Africa prompted her to
    intermittently live in Dar es Salaam, Tanzania. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Kemp received many awards and honors during her lifetime and was a member of numerous
    organizations including the NAACP, National Organization of Women (NOW), the Coalition of Labor
    Union Women (CLUW), the National Council of Negro Women, and the Urban League. Kemp died on
    March 29, 2005 at the age of 94.</p>
  </bioghist>
  <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
   
   <p>The collection contains the bound oral history of Maida Springer Kemp. The interview was
    conducted by Elizabeth Balanoff as part of the oral history project "The 20th Century Trade
    Union Women: Vehicle for Social Change" in cooperation with "The Black Women Oral History
    Project" of the Schlesinger Library at Radcliffe College. The oral history took place over the
    course of multiple interviews beginning on January 4, 1977. Kemp discusses her family background
    and early history of coming from Panama and the alienation of being both a foreigner and black.
    She comments on the closeness with her mother and their introduction into America and its
    culture, and early influences, especially in the black community. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Kemp recounts her early work history and how she became involved with the ILGWU, her activism
    and participation within the union and the various positions she held and roles she played. She
    focuses on the importance of social issues of the union including health and education. Kemp
    also touches on subjects such as racial and sex discrimination. Contacts and acquaintances of
    the women from other unions and labor, including Pauline Newman and Rose Schneiderman are
    mentioned. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Her work outside the ILGWU is examined, including the early trips overseas for the AFL, and
    projects with A. Philip Randolph. Much emphasis in the interview is placed on Kemp's
    international efforts, especially Africa. Discussed is the labor movement in Africa and the
    support and organization by American labor in those efforts, the importance of workers'
    education, the progress made in educating the leadership of the African labor movement, and the
    building and organizing of trade union centers, mainly Solidarity House in Nairobi. </p>
   <p> </p>
   <p>Kemp provides her personal thoughts on the women's movement, she states that she is a
    supporter but not an activist, and believes it is misunderstood in a similar way as the labor
    movement. The interviewer asks Kemp what she would have told or done if she had a daughter, and
    the conversation turns to advice for young women regarding education, career, sex and marriage.
    Other topics discussed in detail include Kemp's involvement in organizations such as the NAACP
    and the Urban League.</p>
  </scopecontent>
  <controlaccess>
   
   <controlaccess>
    
    <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600"> Kemp, Maida Springer. </persname>
    <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    
    <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Women labor union members -- United States -- History --
     Sources. </subject>
   </controlaccess>
   <controlaccess>
    </controlaccess>
  </controlaccess>
  <descgrp>
   
   <accessrestrict>
    
    <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference
     archivist for access to these materials.</p>
   </accessrestrict>
   <userestrict>
    
    <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and
     Procedures for Document Use.</p>
   </userestrict>
   <prefercite>
    
    <p>Springer Kemp, Maida. Oral History Interview. #6036/024. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
     Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
   </prefercite>
  </descgrp>
  <relatedmaterial>
   
   <p>Related Collections:
    <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780: ILGWU records</extref>
    <extref href="rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-062.html"> 5780/062: ILGWU.
     International Relations Department records</extref>
   </p>
  </relatedmaterial>
  <dsc type="in-depth">
   
   <c01 level="file">
    <did>
     <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
     <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
     <unittitle id="link6">Oral History Interview with Maida Springer Kemp, International Ladies'
      Garment Workers' Union by Elizabeth Balanoff</unittitle>
     <unitdate normal="1977">1977</unitdate>
    </did>
   </c01>
  </dsc>
 </archdesc>
</ead>