<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b" relatedencoding="MARC21" repositoryencoding="iso15511" scriptencoding="iso15924">
        <eadid countrycode="us" mainagencycode="nic" publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL06902g::Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of Textile Related Graphics.)//EN">KCL06902g</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of Textile Related Graphics</titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of Textile Related Graphics</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by R. Miles</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library</publisher>
                <date>December 11, 2017</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Randall Miles, <date>December 11, 2017</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    <revisiondesc>
<change>
  <date calendar="gregorian" era="ce" normal="20240221">02/21/2024</date>
  <item>This resource was modified by the ArchivesSpace Preprocessor developed by the Harvard Library (https://github.com/harvard-library/archivesspace-preprocessor)</item>
</change>

</revisiondesc></eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of Textile Related Graphics</titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 6902 G</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu">kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center">http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>R. Miles, October 16, 2017</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Randall Miles, December 11, 2017</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>© 2017 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            
            <unittitle encodinganalog="MARC 245$a" label="Title:">Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of Textile Related Graphics 1783</unittitle><unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1783</unitdate>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">6902 G</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 100" role="creator">Watkins, Susan Finlay</persname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc encodinganalog="MARC 300" label="Quantity:">0.1 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:">Engraving.</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Series of 12 engravings by William Hincks that illustrate the various stages of the preparation of linen in Ireland.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        <physdesc><extent>0.11 cubic feet</extent></physdesc></did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            
            <p>William Hincks was born in Waterford, Ireland. He was a self-taught artist, creating portraits in crayon, oils, and chalk. While in Dublin in 1780, Hincks illustrated an edition of "Tristram Shandy." His twelve-plate series on linen production
                was originally published in 1782. It was later republished in 1791 by R. Pollard, Spafields, London.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            
            <p>Series of 12 engravings that illustrate the various stages of the preparation of linen in Ireland, from sowing the flax seed to the sale of the bleached cloth. Original engravings published by Hincks in London in 1783. Date of this reproduction
                is unknown. </p>
            <p>William Hincks delin. et sculp. (drawn and engraved by William Hincks). </p>
            <p>Plate VIII is missing from this set.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            
            <controlaccess>
                
                <persname encodinganalog="MARC 600">Hincks, William (1794-1871) </persname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Flax </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Linen </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Textile manufacturers -- Ireland </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Textile machinery </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Textile workers </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 651">Ireland </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            
            <accessrestrict>
                
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                
                <p>Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of Textile Related Graphics #6902 G. Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            
            <p>Related Collections: 6902: Susan Finlay Watkins Collection of TWUA Documents
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                    <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">Linen Production in Ireland</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                </did>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link9">Item 1: This View taken near Scarva in the County of Downe, representing Ploughing, Sowing the Flax Seed and Harrowing</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate I. Engraving. Image shows farmer harrowing field with four horses; man on right sows flax seed. Several women and children sit in lower left foreground; house visible in upper left background. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link10">Item 2: This View taken near Hillsborough in the County of Downe, representing Pulling the Flax when grown, Hooking or putting it up to Dry, Ripling or saving the Seed, and Boging or burying it in
                            Water</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate II. Engraving. Image shows flax being pulled from the ground (right background); in foreground a woman draws the flax through a ripple (large metal comb) to remove the seed; in the foreground a man places the flax in water to
                            soak it. Landscape is very romantic; church steeple visible in left background. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link11">Item 3: This View taken in the County of Louth Representing taking the Flax out of the Bog when it has lain a sufficient time to seperate the Rind, (which is the Flax) from the Stem &amp;amp; strengthen it,
                            spreading it to dry, stoving, beetling, and breaking it</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate III. Engraving. Image shows a man in the foreground removing the flax from the water. In the center, a woman lays bundles of flax over a hot kiln to dry them; a man beats the flax bundles. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link12">Item 4: This Plate, representing the common Method of Beetling, Scutching and Hackling the Flax...</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate IV. Engraving. Image shows a young woman seated on the left beetling the flax; the woman seated on the left is scutching the flax with a long wooden blade as is the woman on the right in the background. The man on the right is
                            drawing the flax through a series of blocks containing different size hackle pins to remove any pieces of straw from the flax. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link13">Item 5: This Plate representing a Perspective View of a Scutch Mill, with the Method of Breaking the Flax with groved Rollers, and Scutching it with Blades fixt on a Shaft, both turn'd by the Main
                            Wheel</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate V. Engraving. Image shows water wheel that turned the scutching blades (visible in left background). Woman with child in left foreground; man seated in right foreground. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link14">Item 6: This Plate, taken on the spot in the County of Downe, Representing Spinning, Reeling with the Clock Reel, and Boiling the Yarn</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate VI. Engraving. Image shows young woman at left and elderly woman in center right spinning flax yarn. Woman at right winds yarn on clock reel. Woman in background boils the yarn in a pot over the fire. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link15">Item 7: This Plate, representing Winding, Warping with a new improved Warping Mill, and Weaving</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate VII. Engraving. Image shows man in center winding yarn off a rack of bobbins onto a warp mill by using a pulley. The weaver at left is using a simple treadle loom and a curved shuttle. The boy in the background is winding pirns
                            on a prin winder. 49.5 x 42.5 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link16">Item 8: This Plate representing a complete Perspective View of all the machinery of a bleach mill, upon the Newest and most approved Constructions, consisting of the Wash Mill, Rubbing Boards moved by a Crank, and
                            Beetling Engine for Glazing the Cloth, with a Vie</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate IX. Engraving. Image shows a worker in the foreground twisting the cloth to get the moisure out ?); worker on the right is finishing (?) the cloth. 49.5 x 43 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link17">Item 9: This Perspective View of a Bleach Green taken in the County of Downe, Shewing the methods of Wet &amp;amp; Dry Bleaching, and the outside View of a Bleach Mill, on the most approved
                            construction</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate X. Engraving. Image shows cloth laid out on a village green (regularly watered, this was wet bleaching) with workers soaking the cloth in a trough; bleach mill visible on side of river; young couple in foreground. 50 x 43
                            cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link18">Item 10: This Plate representing a Perspective View of a Lapping Room, with the Measuring, Crisping or Folding the Cloth in Lengths, Picking the Laps or Lengths, Tying in the Clips, acting by the Mechanic power of
                            the Laver to press the Cloth round &amp;amp; firm, and Sea</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate XI. Engraving. Image shows linen cloth being folded and pressed by workers. 50 x 43 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
                <c02 level="file">
                    <did>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="box">1</container>
                        <container label="unspecified" type="folder">1</container>
                        <unittitle id="link19">Item 11: This Perspective View of the Linen Hall in Dublin with the Boxes and Bales of Linen ready for Exportation, the Emblems of their Industry</unittitle>
                        <unitdate normal="1783">1783</unitdate>
                        <physdesc label="Format:">Graphics</physdesc>
                    </did>
                    <scopecontent>
                        <p>Plate XII. Engraving. Image shows the exterior of the LInen Hall in Dublin, Ireland, where bales and boxes of linen cloth were ready for exportation. 49.5 x 43 cm.</p>
                        
                    </scopecontent>
                </c02>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>