<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ead>
    <eadheader repositoryencoding="iso15511" relatedencoding="MARC21" countryencoding="iso3166-1"
        scriptencoding="iso15924" dateencoding="iso8601" langencoding="iso639-2b">
        <eadid mainagencycode="nic" countrycode="us"
            publicid="-//Cornell University::Cornell University Library::Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives//TEXT(US::NIC::KCL05780-174::ILGWU Cleveland Office Records.)//EN"
            >KCL05780-174.xml</eadid>
        <filedesc>
            <titlestmt>
                <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Cleveland Office Records<date>
                    1914-1929</date></titleproper>
                <titleproper type="sort">ILGWU Cleveland Office Records</titleproper>
                <author>Compiled by C. Berne</author>
            </titlestmt>
            <publicationstmt>
                <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                    University Library</publisher>
                <date>April 15, 2019</date>
            </publicationstmt>
            <notestmt>
                <note audience="internal">
                    <p><subject>Labor</subject></p>
                </note>
            </notestmt>
        </filedesc>
        <profiledesc>
            <creation>Finding aid encoded by KIDB, Ead McTaggart, and Kheel Staff, <date>April 15,
                    2019</date></creation>
        </profiledesc>
    </eadheader>
    <frontmatter>
        <titlepage>
            <titleproper>Guide to the ILGWU Cleveland Office Records<lb/></titleproper>
            <num>Collection Number: 5780/174</num>
            <publisher>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </publisher>
            <list type="deflist">
                <defitem>
                    <label>Contact Information:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives<lb/> Martin
                        P. Catherwood Library<lb/> 227 Ives Hall<lb/> Cornell University<lb/>
                        Ithaca, NY 14853<lb/> (607) 255-3183<lb/>
                        <extref href="mailto:kheel_center@cornell.edu"
                            >kheel_center@cornell.edu</extref><lb/>
                        <extref href="http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center"
                            >http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center</extref>
                    </item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>Compiled by:</label>
                    <item>C. Berne, July 27, 2009</item>
                </defitem>
                <defitem>
                    <label>EAD encoding:</label>
                    <item>Kheel Staff, April 15, 2019</item>
                </defitem>
            </list>
            <date>&#169; 2019 Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives, Cornell
                University Library </date>
        </titlepage>
    </frontmatter>
    <archdesc level="collection">
        <did>
            <head id="a1">DESCRIPTIVE SUMMARY</head>
            <unittitle label="Title:" encodinganalog="MARC 245$a">ILGWU Cleveland Office Records,
                    <unitdate encodinganalog="MARC 245$f">1914-1929</unitdate>
            </unittitle>
            <unitid label="Collection Number:">5780/174</unitid>
            <origination label="Creator:">
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 110" role="creator">International Ladies' Garment
                    Workers' Union (ILGWU)</corpname>
            </origination>
            <physdesc label="Quantity:" encodinganalog="MARC 300">1 linear ft.</physdesc>
            <physdesc label="Forms of Material:"> Records (documents).</physdesc>
            <repository label="Repository:">Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and
                Archives, Cornell University Library </repository>
            <abstract label="Abstract:">Contains reports on arbitration hearings and related
                material, as well as minutes of the Joint Board of Cloak and Skirt Makers'
                Unions.</abstract>
            <langmaterial label="Language:">Collection material in <language
                    encodinganalog="MARC 041" langcode="eng">English</language>
            </langmaterial>
        </did>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a2" altrender="organizational history">ILGWU ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY</head>
            <p>The International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union was once one of the largest labor
                unions in the United States founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing
                about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States. It was one of the
                first U.S. Unions to have a membership consisting of mostly females, and it played a
                key role in the labor history of the 1920s and 1930s. The union is generally
                referred to as the "ILGWU" or the "ILG". The ILGWU grew in geographical scope,
                membership size, and political influence to become one of the most powerful forces
                in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's
                garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its
                members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care
                facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. The
                ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union in 1995 to form
                the Union of Needle trades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE). UNITE merged
                with the Hotel Employees and Restaurant Employees Union (HERE) in 2004 to create a
                new union known as UNITE HERE. The two unions that formed UNITE in 1995 represented
                only 250,000 workers between them, down from the ILGWU's peak membership of 450,000
                in 1969.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <bioghist encodinganalog="MARC 545">
            <head id="a5" altrender="organizational history">ORGANIZATIONAL HISTORY </head>
            <p>Cleveland had a garment industry very early on, in fact, a Cloak Pressers' Protective
                Union was formed in 1899, before the founding of the ILGWU. The early Cleveland
                Joint Board consisted of Cloak and Suit Tailors 26, Skirt and Dress Makers 27, Women
                Garment Makers 29, Ladies' Garment Pressers 37, Ladies' Garment Cutters 42, Sample
                and Ladies Tailors 94. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Strikes and low membership decimated the union in Cleveland from the strike of 1911
                until the near closure of the Joint Board in 1916. The union had a difficult time
                gaining a position in the cloak and suit trade of the city. By the summer of 1917,
                membership in the Joint Board had risen significantly and in 1918, the union and the
                Joint Board submitted demands to the Cleveland Garment Manufacturers' Association
                for a wage increase. After a strike, a Board of Referees was established to hear the
                controversy and render decisions. Relations between manufacturers and the Joint
                Board were strained, but in 1919, a collective agreement was signed by the
                manufacturers' associations and the Cleveland Joint Board finally and firmly
                establishing the union in Cleveland after a decade of struggle. During this time,
                Charles Kreindler was the manager of the Joint Board. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In the 1920s, Cleveland was one of the only large cities that did not subscribe to a
                44 hour week and week-work in the garment industry. Instead, the shops that
                manufactured medium priced garments utilized the section system, which required less
                skilled labor and posed a challenge for the Cleveland cloakmakers. An investigation
                by Cleveland Joint Board and the Cloak Manufacturers'' Association established
                standards of production. In 1932, there was the Cleveland Cloak and Dress Strike.
                Hearings were conducted in 1938 before an impartial chairman to eliminate
                differences between the New York and Cleveland Cloak markets. By 1944, the Joint
                Board had established vacations with pay for all garment workers in the market, as
                well as adding a health plan with medical care, sick benefits and life insurance.
                The Joint Board was comprised of Locals 26, 27, 29, 37, 42, 44, 52, 207, 209, 211,
                300, 358, and 368. The Joint Board and Ohio district were headed by Abraham
                Katovsky, who had been a business agent under Kreindler, and helmed the Cleveland
                Joint Board until his death in 1945. He was succeeded by Nathan Solomon as the new
                manager. Solomon had been serving as the secretary treasurer for many years.
                Approximately 1,000 knitgood workers in Cleveland were organized into four locals
                comprising the Cleveland Knitgoods Council. This Council was supervised by the head
                of the Cleveland Joint Board. During the early 1950s, Louis Friend managed the Joint
                Board, and Nicholas Kirtzman was the director of the Cleveland and Ohio-Kentucky
                Region. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>A new headquarters for the Cleveland ILGWU Health Center and Ohio-Kentucky regional
                headquarters was dedicated in 1951. David Solomon manager of the Joint Board for
                many years after Friend, retired April 1956, and the organizer of the Joint Board,
                Julius Guralnik, took over duties as manager of the Cleveland Joint Board. From 1959
                into the 1960s, with the Cleveland cloak market declining into insignificance, a
                shift in the Ohio-Kentucky Region took place from an emphasis on the cloak industry
                towards sportswear, knitgoods, and dresses. The Cleveland Knitgoods Council made
                significant membership gains. By 1962, Kirtzman became director and manager of the
                Joint Board, with Edward Milano the assistant director, and the steady decline in
                membership in Cleveland within the shrinking cloak and dress industry began to
                stabilize. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Kirtzman, an ILGWU vice-president and regional director since 1950, died in March
                1963. Sam Janis, who was previously an assistant general manager of the Eastern
                Region, succeeded Kirtzman as the new Ohio-Kentucky Region director and was also
                elected manager of the Cleveland Joint Board. In 1968, Janis and the Joint Board
                were involved in the successful campaign for Carl Stokes election as mayor of
                Cleveland. Stokes was the first African American mayor of a large U.S. city, and
                Manager Janis was appointed to the mayor's commission as a labor representative to
                study the welfare crisis in the city. During the 1970s, the Joint Board was involved
                in community and political activities, including submitting a proposal to ease
                procedures for voter registration. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>In 1978, there was a realignment of the Ohio-Kentucky Region and all Ohio locals
                became part of the Northeast and Western Pennsylvania Department, renamed the
                Northeast, Western Pennsylvania and Ohio Department. Sam Janis retired in May 1978
                and Al Gargiulo, who had been the assistant regional director, became the manager of
                the Cleveland Joint Board, as well as the Knitgoods Council and the Ohio
                District.</p>
        </bioghist>
        <scopecontent encodinganalog="MARC 520">
            <head id="a3">COLLECTION DESCRIPTION</head>
            <p>The collection predominantly consists of the Cleveland Garment Industry Arbitration
                in 1919. The records contain transcripts of the hearings between the Cleveland
                Locals and the Cleveland Cloak, Suit, Skirt and Dress Manufacturers' Association.
                Manufacturers wanted a reduction in wages. The records begin in 1918, and by 1921
                advances in the industry included the establishment of a standard wage scale
                affecting all shops and classes of workers, as well as an adopted standard of
                production. Also contained in the files are the award summary, memorandum,
                arbitration, back pay, wage adjustment, and wage comparisons. The hearings between
                union and manufacturers include exhibits showing increases in living, inflation, and
                wages and industry reports and wage studies for the Cleveland area. </p>
            <p> </p>
            <p>Additionally, the collection contains early meeting minutes from 1917.</p>
        </scopecontent>
        <controlaccess>
            <head id="a8">SUBJECTS</head>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Names: </head>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union. </corpname>
                <corpname encodinganalog="MARC 610"> International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union.
                    -- Cleveland Office. </corpname>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Subjects: </head>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Women's clothing industry -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Women's clothing industry -- Ohio -- Cleveland. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Clothing workers --Labor unions -- United
                    States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650">Clothing workers --Labor unions -- Ohio --
                    Cleveland. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Clothing workers -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Clothing workers -- Ohio -- Cleveland. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Industrial relations -- United States. </subject>
                <subject encodinganalog="MARC 650"> Industrial relations -- Ohio -- Cleveland.
                </subject>
            </controlaccess>
            <controlaccess>
                <head>Form and Genre Terms: </head>
                <genreform encodinganalog="MARC 655"> Records (documents)</genreform>
            </controlaccess>
        </controlaccess>
        <descgrp>
            <head id="a10">INFORMATION FOR USERS</head>
            <accessrestrict>
                <head>Access Restrictions:</head>
                <p>Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a
                    reference archivist for access to these materials.</p>
            </accessrestrict>
            <userestrict>
                <head>Restrictions on Use:</head>
                <p>This collection must be used in keeping with the Kheel Center Information Sheet
                    and Procedures for Document Use.</p>
            </userestrict>
            <prefercite>
                <head>Cite As:</head>
                <p>ILGWU Cleveland Office Records #5780/174. Kheel Center for Labor-Management
                    Documentation and Archives, Cornell University Library.</p>
            </prefercite>
        </descgrp>
        <relatedmaterial>
            <head id="a6">RELATED MATERIALS</head>
            <p>Related Collections:<lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780.html"> 5780:
                    ILGWU records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-048.html">
                    5780/048: ILGWU Cleveland Joint Board Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-183.html">
                    5780/183: ILGWU Ohio Kentucky Region Records</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-183av.html">
                    5780/183 AV: ILGWU Ohio Kentucky Region Audio-Visual Materials</extref><lb/>
                <extref href="http://rmc.library.cornell.edu/ead/htmldocs/KCL05780-183p.html">
                    5780/183 P: ILGWU Ohio Kentucky Region Photographs</extref><lb/>
            </p>
        </relatedmaterial>
        <dsc type="in-depth">
            <head>CONTAINER LIST</head>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link8">In the Matter of the Cleveland Garment Industry
                        Arbitration</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link9">Hearing to Decide Matters in Controversy Between Cleveland
                        Locals of the ILGWU and the Cleveland Cloak, Suit, Skirt, and Dress
                        Manufacturers' Association</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>July 14-15</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link10">In the Matter of the Cleveland Cloak, Suit, Skirt, and
                        Dress Industry</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>July 15</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link11">Memorandum in the Matter of the Arbitration in the Cloak,
                        Suit, Skirt, and Dress Industry</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>January 18</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link12">Award by the Board of Referees in the Matter of the
                        Cleveland Garment Industry</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>December 27</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link13">Hearing Before Referees Appointed by Honorable Newton D.
                        Baker, Secretary of War</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>August 21</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link14">Award in the Matter of the Cleveland Cloak, Suit, Skirt,
                        and Dress Industry</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>July 15</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">8</container>
                    <unittitle id="link15">Proceedings Pursuant to the Request of Thirty-Nine Cloak,
                        Suit, Skirt, and Dress Manufacturers of Cleveland</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>April 6</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">9</container>
                    <unittitle id="link16">Decision of Board of Referees in the Cloak, Suit, and
                        Skirt Industry</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>Cleveland, April</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">10</container>
                    <unittitle id="link17">Award on Wage Question</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">11</container>
                    <unittitle id="link18">ILGWU Questionnaire on Unemployment Insurance</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1929">1929</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>May</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">12</container>
                    <unittitle id="link19">Hearing to Investigate and Report as to the Matter of the
                        Workers Excluded from Work</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>August 21</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">13</container>
                    <unittitle id="link20">Cloak and Shirtmaker Unions Joint Board
                        Correspondence</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1914/1919">1914-1919</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">14</container>
                    <unittitle id="link21">Cleveland Joint Board 1</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">1</container>
                    <container type="folder">15</container>
                    <unittitle id="link22">Cleveland Joint Board 2</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1917">1917</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">1</container>
                    <unittitle id="link23">Report of Board of Referees</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>October 19</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">2</container>
                    <unittitle id="link24">Report of Board of Referees and Supplementary
                        Award</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>August 12</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">3</container>
                    <unittitle id="link25">Report of Board of Referees Supplementary Award and
                        Continuing Agreement between ILGWU and the Cleveland Garment Manufacturers'
                        Association</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1919">1919</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">4</container>
                    <unittitle id="link26">In the Matter of Cleveland Garment Manufacturers'
                        Association</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1918">1918</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>November 7</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">5</container>
                    <unittitle id="link27">Cleveland Memorandums</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
                </did>
                <scopecontent>
                    <p>April</p>
                </scopecontent>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">6</container>
                    <unittitle id="link28">Cleveland Data</unittitle>
                    <unitdate type="inclusive" normal="1920/1921">1920-1921</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
            <c01 level="file">
                <did>
                    <container type="box">2</container>
                    <container type="folder">7</container>
                    <unittitle id="link29">Cleveland Proceedings</unittitle>
                    <unitdate normal="1921">1921</unitdate>
                </did>
            </c01>
        </dsc>
    </archdesc>
</ead>
